<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>曝 DeepSeek 新旗舰模型 V4 计划春节前后推出</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝-DeepSeek-新旗舰模型-V4-计划春节前后推出</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/cf1de003-ba31-427f-bd79-4dd02923bdb9.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from &quot;The Information&quot; and Reuters, DeepSeek plans to launch its next-generation flagship large model, DeepSeek-V4, in mid-February, with a focus on strengthening code generation and long code context processing capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《The Information》和路透社报道，深度求索 DeepSeek 计划于 2 月中旬推出下一代旗舰大模型 DeepSeek‑V4，重点强化代码生成与长代码上下文处理能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            DeepSeek-V4 is another significant upgrade following the release of V3.2 last December.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            DeepSeek‑V4 是继去年 12 月发布的 V3.2 之后的又一次重要升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Multiple sources familiar with the matter revealed that DeepSeek's internal benchmark tests show V4's performance in coding tasks has surpassed Anthropic's Claude series and OpenAI's GPT series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多名知情人士透露，DeepSeek 内部基准测试显示，V4 在代码任务上的表现已超越 Anthropic 的 Claude 系列以及 OpenAI 的 GPT 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, long code prompt processing capability is considered a key breakthrough in this iteration, capable of providing more stable reasoning and structured output in complex software engineering scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，长代码提示处理能力被视为本次迭代的关键突破，可在复杂软件工程场景中提供更稳定的推理与结构化输出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            One of the sources stated that users will noticeably find V4's answers more organized, indicating that the new version has stronger reasoning capabilities and is more reliable for handling complex tasks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中一位知情人士表示，用户将能明显感受到 V4 的回答更有条理，这说明新版本的推理能力更强，对于处理复杂任务也更可靠。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            DeepSeek plans to release V4 around the Lunar New Year, a strategy similar to the release time of its R1 model last year. R1, as an open-source inference model, garnered global attention and is expected to drive a wave of open-source competition among Chinese large model manufacturers in 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            DeepSeek 计划将 V4 的发布时间安排在农历新年前后，这一策略与去年 R1 模型的发布时间类似。R1 作为开源推理模型曾在全球范围引发关注，并推动中国大模型厂商在 2025 年掀起开源竞赛潮。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that DeepSeek has intensively launched multiple models in the past two years, including DeepSeek‑Coder, DeepSeek‑V2, DeepSeek‑V3, DeepSeek‑R1, etc., covering various directions such as code, mathematics, multimodal, and inference.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开资料显示，DeepSeek 在过去两年间密集推出多款模型，包括 DeepSeek‑Coder、DeepSeek‑V2、DeepSeek‑V3、DeepSeek‑R1 等，覆盖代码、数学、多模态与推理等多个方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Insiders say that V4 adopts a new architectural design during training, enabling the model to maintain its data pattern understanding ability without degradation during long-sequence training, and to achieve more efficient training under limited computing power.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士称，V4 在训练过程中采用了新的架构设计，使模型能够在长序列训练中保持数据模式理解能力不衰减，并在有限算力条件下实现更高效的训练。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>外卖竞争调查启动，美团淘宝京东御三家表态</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">外卖竞争调查启动，美团淘宝京东御三家表态</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/bddaee3f-f7df-4741-993e-63fcc7552d7a.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to China News Service, the Office of the Anti-Monopoly and Anti-Unfair Competition Commission of the State Council recently launched an investigation and assessment of the market competition status in the food delivery platform service industry, in accordance with the &quot;Anti-Monopoly Law of the People's Republic of China&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据中国新闻社报道，国务院反垄断反不正当竞争委员会办公室近日依据《中华人民共和国反垄断法》，对外卖平台服务行业的市场竞争状况启动调查、评估。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Office of the State Council's Anti-Monopoly and Anti-Unfair Competition Commission pointed out that the food delivery industry has recently seen irrational competition phenomena such as &quot;price wars, subsidy wars, and traffic control,&quot; which disrupt market order and affect the healthy development of the industry. This investigation aims to clarify the industry's competitive landscape, promote platform enterprises to fulfill their primary responsibilities, and maintain a fair competitive environment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            国务院双反委员会办公室指出，外卖行业近期出现「拼价格、拼补贴、控流量」等非理性竞争现象，扰乱市场秩序，影响行业健康发展。此次调查旨在厘清行业竞争态势，推动平台企业落实主体责任，维护公平竞争环境。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, several platforms successively issued statements, expressing their active cooperation with the relevant work.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，多家平台陆续发声表态，将积极配合相关工作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meituan stated that it &quot;resolutely supports&quot; this investigation and has long opposed &quot;involutionary&quot; competition in the industry. Meituan emphasized that it will take this opportunity to work with industry platforms to promote innovation and healthy development of food delivery services;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taobao Flash Sale also expressed support, stating that fair competition is the foundation for continuous innovation in the food delivery industry. The platform strictly adheres to the &quot;Anti-Monopoly Law,&quot; &quot;Anti-Unfair Competition Law,&quot; and &quot;Basic Requirements for Food Delivery Platform Service Management&quot; in merchant management, pricing behavior, and delivery personnel rights protection, and will actively cooperate with the investigation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JD Waimai (JD Food Delivery) emphasized that it will promote the development of &quot;quality food delivery&quot; through supply chain model innovation, resist malicious competition within the industry, and support this investigation and assessment work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that recently, Taobao Flash Sale disclosed that it experienced strong growth in the fourth quarter of 2025 and has set its primary goal for this year as &quot;market share growth,&quot;
            &lt;strong&gt;
             planning to increase investment to achieve &quot;absolute first&quot; in the market
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，就在最近，淘宝闪购披露，其在 2025 年四季度迎来强劲增长，并将今年的首要目标定为「份额增长」，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             计划加大投入以达到市场「绝对第一」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>苹果 Apple Watch「房颤历史」功能过审</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果-Apple-Watch「房颤历史」功能过审</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b6365e10-9640-4d32-a2ac-c817852d3a63.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple Watch's &quot;AFib History&quot; feature has been approved by the National Medical Products Administration, obtaining Class II qualification for imported medical devices (registration).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果 Apple Watch 的「房颤历史」功能已获国家药品监督管理局批准，取得进口医疗器械（注册）第二类资质。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to public information from the National Medical Products Administration, the registered name of this feature is &quot;Mobile Pulse Rate AFib Indication Recording Software,&quot; with an approval date of December 26 last year and registration certificate number &quot;Guo Xie Zhu Jin 20252210606&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据国家药监局公开信息，该功能的注册名称为「移动脉率房颤迹象记录软件」，批准日期为去年 12 月 26 日，注册证编号为「国械注进 20252210606」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The software consists of Apple Watch and iPhone applications, suitable for patients aged 22 and above diagnosed with AFib, used to retrospectively estimate the proportion of possible AFib episode durations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该软件由 Apple Watch 端与 iPhone 端应用组成，适用于 22 岁及以上已确诊房颤的患者，用于回顾性估算可能的房颤发作时长比例。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regulatory information clearly indicates that this product does not provide separate AFib indication alerts and cannot replace traditional diagnostic methods or AFib monitoring methods.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            监管信息明确显示，该产品不提供单独的房颤迹象提示，也不能替代传统诊疗方法或房颤监控方式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple states that the AFib History (AFH) feature is an over-the-counter software medical application that identifies irregular heart rate episodes with AFib indications based on pulse rate data and estimates the user's AFib burden during past Apple Watch wear.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果方面介绍称，房颤历史记录功能（AFH）是一款非处方软件医疗应用，会基于脉搏率数据识别具有房颤迹象的不规则心率发作，并为用户估算过去佩戴 Apple Watch 期间的房颤负荷。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This feature also generates trends over time and visualizes them in conjunction with lifestyle data, helping users understand the potential impact of their habits on AFib.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该功能还会生成随时间变化的趋势，并结合生活方式数据进行可视化，帮助用户理解生活习惯对房颤的潜在影响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>拼多多春节加班激励曝光：综合收入最高可破 1.1 万</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">拼多多春节加班激励曝光：综合收入最高可破-1.1-万</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/325f424d-46bd-41bc-9474-b4b81adfbe93.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Bianews, Pinduoduo recently issued an overtime recruitment notice for its internal employees during the Spring Festival period, simultaneously announcing detailed salary subsidies and incentive schemes. This year's Spring Festival holiday is from February 15th to February 23rd, a total of 9 days.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据鞭牛士报道 ，拼多多近日面向内部员工发布了春节期间的加班征集通知，并同步公布了详细的薪资补贴与激励方案。今年春节假期为 2 月 15 日至 2 月 23 日，共 9 天。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the disclosed information, Pinduoduo offers 3 times the daily wage for overtime work from Lunar New Year's Eve to the third day of the Lunar New Year, which includes normal daily pay and a daily minimum subsidy of 400 yuan; overtime pay from the fourth to the seventh day is 2 times the daily wage, including a daily minimum subsidy of 200 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据披露的信息，拼多多在除夕至初三期间提供当日工资 3 倍的报酬，其中包含正常日薪与每日保底 400 元补贴；初四至初七期间的加班报酬为当日工资 2 倍，并包含每日保底 200 元补贴。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In February this year, the company will also abolish the piece-rate salary cap rule, encouraging employees to earn more for more work. After comprehensive calculation, Spring Festival overtime income can range from 4,900 yuan to over 11,000 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 2 月，公司还将取消计件薪资封顶规则，鼓励员工多劳多得，综合计算后，春节加班收入区间可达 4900 元至 11000 元以上。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to statutory holiday subsidies, Pinduoduo has also set up extra attendance incentives. For warehouse, quality inspection line employees, and reserve team leaders and above management personnel, a one-time incentive of 500 yuan will be granted if they accumulate 9 days of attendance from February 1st to February 11th; if they continuously attend from February 12th to 14th on top of that, they can receive another 500 yuan incentive.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除法定假期补贴外，拼多多还设置了额外出勤激励。面向仓内、质检线员工及储备组长及以上管理人员，若在 2 月 1 日至 2 月 11 日累计出勤 9 天，可获得一次性 500 元激励；若在此基础上于 2 月 12 日至 14 日连续出勤，还可再获得 500 元激励。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Employees participating in Spring Festival overtime are required to comply with scheduling and attendance regulations. Subsidies will be uniformly distributed on March 15th with this year's February salary.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司要求参与春节加班的员工需服从排班并符合考勤规定，补贴将随今年 2 月薪资于 3 月 15 日统一发放。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>库克去年薪酬 7429 万美元，苹果加速 CEO 继任计划</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">库克去年薪酬-7429-万美元，苹果加速-CEO-继任计划</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c6898233-b0bc-46e9-9d2d-b1432609778b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Apple CEO Tim Cook's total compensation last year was $74.2948 million, a slight decrease from the previous year, while discussions surrounding his successor and future role have continued to heat up this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，苹果 CEO 蒂姆・库克去年总薪酬为 7429.48 万美元，较前一年略有下降，同时围绕其接班人与未来角色的讨论在今年持续升温。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Documents filed by Apple with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) show that Cook's $74.2948 million compensation last year included a $3 million base salary, $57.5 million in stock awards, $12 million in performance incentives, and approximately $1.7 million in other compensation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果向美国证券交易委员会（SEC）提交的文件显示，库克去年获得的 7429.48 万美元薪酬包括 300 万美元基本工资、5750 万美元股票奖励、1200 万美元绩效激励，以及约 170 万美元的其他补偿。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Cook issued a thank-you letter to shareholders, stating that he has &quot;never been more optimistic&quot; about Apple's future prospects. Apple's annual shareholder meeting will be held on February 24.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，库克向股东发布感谢信，称自己对苹果未来的发展前景「从未如此乐观」。苹果年度股东大会将于 2 月 24 日举行。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Discussions surrounding Cook's future role are also accelerating. The New York Times reported that Cook had told company executives he felt tired and wanted to reduce his workload, potentially transitioning to a chairman position after retirement, with Senior Vice President of Hardware Engineering John Ternus being considered one of the potential successors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            围绕库克未来角色的讨论也在加速。《纽约时报》报道称，库克曾向公司高层表示自己感到疲惫，希望减少工作量，并可能在退休后转任董事长职位，而硬件工程高级副总裁约翰・特努斯（John Ternus）被视为潜在接班人之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ternus joined Apple in 2001, initially working on Mac screen development. He steadily rose through the ranks, becoming head of iMac hardware engineering in 2005, and taking overall responsibility for the Mac and iPad teams in 2013.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            特努斯 2001 年加入苹果，最初参与 Mac 屏幕开发。他逐步晋升，2005 年成为 iMac 硬件工程负责人，2013 年开始负责 Mac 和 iPad 团队的整体工作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to informed sources, Ternus also participated in the research and development exploration of Apple's foldable phone and frequently spent extended periods in Asia dealing with manufacturers, gaining an in-depth understanding of supply chain operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据知情人士透露，特努斯还参与了苹果可折叠手机的研发探索，并多次长期驻扎亚洲与制造商打交道，深入了解供应链运作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, sources also indicated that Cook is grooming several other internal executives as alternatives, including:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，知情人士同时表示，库克也在培养其他几位内部高管作为备选，包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Craig Federighi, Head of Software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eddy Cue, Head of Services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greg Joswiak, Head of Worldwide Marketing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deirdre O’Brien, Head of Retail and Human Resources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Cook has met Apple's internal conditions for retirement eligibility, including being over 60 years old and having served the company for more than 10 years. Apple emphasized in its filing that the board continues to be involved in succession planning and has set retirement vesting terms for Cook to ensure stability in management transition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，库克已满足苹果内部关于退休资格的条件，包括年满 60 岁及在公司服务超过 10 年。苹果在文件中强调，董事会持续参与接班人规划，并为库克设定了退休归属条款，以确保管理层过渡的稳定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>美国参议员致信苹果、Google，要求下架 Grok</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">美国参议员致信苹果、Google，要求下架-Grok</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f96726d4-350d-46bd-92d3-257d773460ab.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, U.S. Democratic Senators Ron Wyden, Ben Ray Lujan, and Ed Markey recently sent a letter to Apple CEO Tim Cook and Google CEO Sundar Pichai, demanding the removal of the social media app X from their respective app stores.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，美国民主党参议员 Ron Wyden、Ben Ray Lujan 和 Ed Markey 近日致信苹果 CEO Tim Cook 和 Google CEO Sundar Pichai，要求将社交媒体应用 X 从各自的应用商店中下架。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The senators noted in the letter that X's AI chatbot Grok recently generated a large number of non-consensual nude images of women, and even sexualized content targeting minors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            议员们在信中指出，X 旗下的 AI 聊天机器人 Grok 近期生成了大量未经同意的女性裸体图像，甚至包含针对未成年人的性化内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The senators believe that X's generation of these harmful and potentially illegal depictions demonstrates a &quot;complete disregard&quot; for app store distribution terms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            议员们认为，X 生成这些有害且可能非法的描述，显示出对应用商店分发条款的「完全无视」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the specific details of policy violations, the senators cited Google's terms of service, which state that apps will face removal if they fail to prohibit users from creating, uploading, or distributing content that &quot;facilitates child exploitation or abuse.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对违反政策的具体细节，议员们引用了 Google 的服务条款，条款规定若应用未能禁止用户创建、上传或分发「助长剥削或虐待儿童」的内容，将面临下架。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, the letter also pointed out that Apple's policy explicitly prohibits &quot;offensive&quot; or &quot;egregiously creepy&quot; apps. As of now, Apple and Google have not responded as to whether X complies or if they plan to remove it.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，信中也指出苹果的政策明确禁止「冒犯性」或「纯粹令人毛骨悚然」的应用。截至目前，苹果和 Google 尚未就 X 是否合规或是否计划将其下架作出回应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, the senators also accused the two companies of having &quot;double standards&quot; in their review criteria.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，议员们还指责两家公司在审核标准上存在「双重标准」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, under government pressure, Apple and Google removed apps like ICEBlock and Red Dot, which were primarily used to anonymously report the whereabouts of Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agents.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，在政府压力下，苹果和 Google 下架了 ICEBlock 和 Red Dot 等应用，这些应用主要用于匿名报告移民和海关执法局（ICE）特工的行踪。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The letter argued that, unlike the &quot;disgusting&quot; content generated by Grok, the aforementioned app itself did not create or host harmful or illegal content, yet it was removed for allegedly posing a risk to law enforcement personnel.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            信中辩称，与 Grok 生成的「令人作呕」的内容不同，上述应用本身并未创建或托管有害非法内容，却因被指给执法人员带来风险而被移除。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The letter concluded by warning that if Apple and Google fail to take action against X, it would weaken their core argument in antitrust defense, namely that &quot;app stores provide a safer user experience than users directly downloading apps.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            信中最后警告称，如果苹果和 Google 未能对 X 采取行动，将削弱其在反垄断辩护中的核心论点，即「应用商店能提供比用户直接下载应用更安全的用户体验」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This argument has been a key reason for both companies to oppose legislative reforms and maintain their market power over payment systems.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这一论点一直是两家公司反对立法改革、维护其支付系统市场权力的关键理由。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>王腾公布新公司招聘细节：初期不招应届生、主攻研发团队</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">王腾公布新公司招聘细节：初期不招应届生、主攻研发团队</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/84b7cb7a-3224-4441-9ebd-aad2eb205fa6.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Teng, former General Manager of Xiaomi China Marketing Department and General Manager of REDMI brand, after officially announcing the establishment of his new company &quot;Today is a Good Day to Rest&quot; (今日宜休), once again posted yesterday to disclose details about the company's recruitment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            原小米中国区市场部总经理、REDMI 品牌总经理王腾在官宣成立新公司「今日宜休」后，于昨天再度发文披露公司招聘相关细节。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Teng posted on his personal Weibo, stating that the company's headquarters are in Beijing, and it will consider establishing branches in Shenzhen and Hangzhou in the future. Employees are required to work in Beijing for one year, after which they can choose to work in a nearby city.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            王腾在其个人微博发文表示，公司总部位于北京，未来将考虑在深圳、杭州设立分部。员工需在北京工作一年，之后可选择就近城市办公。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding compensation and benefits, he emphasized that they will &quot;largely benchmark against major companies&quot; and focus more on equity incentives, hoping employees can gain higher returns as the company grows with the company.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            薪酬与福利方面，他强调将「基本对标大厂」，并更侧重股权激励，希望员工能在公司成长过程中获得更高回报。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Addressing external concerns such as &quot;not hiring fresh graduates&quot; and &quot;marketing and sales positions not yet open,&quot; Wang Teng explained that at the current stage, the company is focusing on building its product R&amp;amp;D team, and positions in marketing, sales, service, and finance will gradually open for recruitment after the Spring Festival.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而针对外界关注的「不招应届生」与「暂未开放市场销售岗位」等问题，王腾解释称，当前阶段公司正重点组建产品研发团队，市场、销售、服务及财务等岗位将于春节后陆续启动招聘。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that a startup team needs experienced members who can quickly jump into action, and fresh graduates will be welcomed once the business matures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，初创团队更需要具备经验、能快速投入战斗的成员，待业务发展成熟后将欢迎应届生加入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Teng also reiterated the company's advocacy for a &quot;sleep anywhere, anytime&quot; culture. He stated that this entrepreneurial direction stems from the desire to help professionals improve their energy levels, allowing employees to rest whenever they feel tired, but they must wear the company's product for sleep data collection.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            王腾还再次强调公司倡导「随地大小睡」的文化。他表示，这一创业方向源于希望帮助职场人改善精力状态，员工在困倦时可随时休息，但需佩戴公司产品以便进行睡眠数据采集。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to public recruitment information, &quot;Today is a Good Day to Rest&quot; (今日宜休) currently has open positions on BOSS Zhipin for Senior Industrial Designer, Senior RTOS BSP System Development Engineer/Expert, and Algorithm Expert, with salary ranges covering 25–50k for 14 months to 30–40k for 18 months, all emphasizing experience in smart hardware, consumer electronics, and biological signal processing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据公开招聘信息，「今日宜休」目前在 BOSS 直聘开放了高级工业设计师、资深 RTOS BSP 系统开发工程师/专家及算法专家等岗位，薪酬区间覆盖 25–50k14 薪至 30–40k18 薪不等，均强调智能硬件、消费电子及生物信号处理等相关经验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jiemian News pointed out that the company primarily develops sleep health-related products, with core team members from technology companies like Xiaomi and Huawei. It is currently in the formation stage, and its funding status has not yet been announced.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            界面新闻指出，该公司主要研发睡眠健康相关产品，核心团队成员来自小米、华为等科技企业，当前仍处于组建阶段，融资情况尚未公布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google 云营销负责人跳槽英伟达，直接向黄仁勋汇报</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Google-云营销负责人跳槽英伟达，直接向黄仁勋汇报</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9fba7f15-c703-42b5-b8aa-91538c817a7b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Wall Street Journal, Nvidia has poached Alison Wagonfeld, a veteran marketing executive from Google, to serve as the company's first-ever CMO.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《华尔街日报》报道，英伟达已从 Google 挖来资深营销高管艾莉森・瓦贡菲尔德（Alison Wagonfeld），出任公司历史上的首位 CMO。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sources familiar with the matter said Wagonfeld will report directly to Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang and officially take office in February this year, at which point Nvidia's global marketing and communications teams will all report to her.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士称，瓦贡菲尔德将直接向英伟达 CEO 黄仁勋汇报，并在今年 2 月正式上任，届时英伟达的全球市场与传播团队将统一向其汇报。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wagonfeld announced on LinkedIn that she would be ending her nearly decade-long tenure at Google, leaving her role in charge of Google Cloud marketing to join Nvidia.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            瓦贡菲尔德在领英上宣布，她将结束在 Google 近十年的任职，离开负责 Google 云业务营销的岗位，加入英伟达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As AI tools and services have rapidly expanded since OpenAI launched ChatGPT last year, Nvidia has achieved high-speed growth thanks to its core position in advanced AI computing chips, and its marketing demands have increased accordingly.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着 AI 工具和服务自去年 OpenAI 推出 ChatGPT 以来迅速扩张，英伟达凭借在先进 AI 计算芯片领域的核心地位实现高速增长，其市场营销需求也随之提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report pointed out that Nvidia's business expansion over the past three years has made Jensen Huang one of the most representative public figures in the AI boom. At CES 2026 this year, Huang introduced the next-generation AI server system earlier than in previous years, stating that huge market demand is driving accelerated industry iteration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，英伟达在过去三年间的业务扩张，使黄仁勋成为 AI 热潮中最具代表性的公众人物之一。在今年 CES 2026 上，黄仁勋比往年更早介绍了下一代 AI 服务器系统，并表示巨大的市场需求正推动行业加速迭代。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated at the event: &quot;The AI race has begun, and everyone is striving towards the next frontier.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他在现场表示：「AI 竞赛已经开始，每个人都在努力迈向下一个前沿。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Nvidia's latest quarterly financial report shows that the company achieved $57 billion in revenue, a 62% year-over-year increase, exceeding analysts' expectations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英伟达最新一季度财报显示，公司实现 570 亿美元营收，同比增长 62%，超出分析师预期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>微软否认「数万人裁员」传言：高管称「百分之百虚构」</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微软否认「数万人裁员」传言：高管称「百分之百虚构」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1d0f2cf8-310f-4916-a7e2-7168914fe40d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Microsoft recently encountered an online rumor about &quot;large-scale layoffs,&quot; causing market fluctuations and employee unease. The rumor claimed that Microsoft was &quot;considering&quot; cutting 11,000 to 22,000 jobs this month, affecting Azure cloud services, Xbox, and global sales teams.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微软近日遭遇一则关于「大规模裁员」的网络传言，引发市场波动与员工不安。传言称，微软「正在考虑」在本月裁减 11000 至 22000 个岗位，涉及 Azure 云服务、Xbox 以及全球销售团队。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The related content initially appeared on overseas forums like Reddit and Blind, then spread across social platforms such as Bluesky and X, causing Microsoft's stock price to plummet quickly after the market opened on Thursday ET, ultimately closing down 1%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相关内容最初出现在 Reddit、Blind 等海外论坛，随后在 Bluesky 与 X 等社交平台扩散，导致微软股价在美东时间周四开盘后迅速下挫，最终收跌 1%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Facing the fermenting public opinion, Microsoft executives quickly came forward to clarify. Frank Shaw, Microsoft's Chief Communications Officer, stated on X that these rumors are '100% fictitious / speculative / false'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            面对舆论发酵，微软高管迅速出面澄清。微软首席传播官弗兰克·肖（Frank Shaw）在 X 上表示，这些传言「百分之百是虚构的／是猜测的／是错误的」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also responded sarcastically to a post suggesting layoffs would happen within weeks, saying, 'I can't wait'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他还对一则暗示裁员将在数周内发生的帖子作出带有讽刺意味的回应，称「我迫不及待地等着」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Cailian Press pointed out that despite official denials, external doubts have not completely dissipated.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财联社指出，尽管官方明确否认，但外界疑虑并未完全消散。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last year, Microsoft conducted multiple rounds of layoffs, cumulatively cutting over 15,000 employees from May to September last year, with approximately 9,000 layoffs in July alone. Phil Spencer, head of Xbox, stated in an internal memo at the time that these adjustments were to 'improve flexibility and efficiency'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年，微软已进行多轮裁员，从去年 5 月至 9 月累计裁减超过 15000 名员工，其中 7 月单月裁员约 9000 人。Xbox 负责人菲尔·斯宾塞（Phil Spencer）当时在内部备忘录中称，这些调整是为了「提高灵活性和效率」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In recent years, Microsoft has continuously increased its investment in artificial intelligence infrastructure, spending $88 billion on AI infrastructure in fiscal year 2025 alone, ending last June, with capital expenditures still growing this year. Against the backdrop of high investment, the market generally worries that the company might balance expenditures by cutting other costs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微软近年来持续加大对人工智能基础设施的投入，仅在截至去年 6 月的 2025 财年便斥资 880 亿美元用于 AI 基建，今年资本支出仍在增长。在高额投入背景下，市场普遍担忧公司可能通过削减其他成本来平衡支出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Microsoft has not released further explanations, but judging from public statements by executives, the possibility of large-scale layoffs this month is low. However, against the backdrop of AI investment pressure and intensified industry competition, Microsoft's future human resources strategy still warrants continuous attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，微软方面尚未发布进一步说明，但从高管公开表态来看，本月出现大规模裁员的可能性较低。然而，在 AI 投资压力与行业竞争加剧的背景下，微软未来的人力策略仍值得持续关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>继 Pixel 10 后，Pixel 9 也将获得 AirDrop 更新</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">继-Pixel-10-后，Pixel-9-也将获得-AirDrop-更新</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7bb2f5a6-d0da-4068-9ac7-341a3358ce61.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Android Authority, Google is accelerating the expansion of cross-platform file transfer capabilities to more devices. AirDrop's 'Quick Share', previously exclusive to the Pixel 10 series, is coming soon to the Pixel 9 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Android Authority 报道，Google 正在加速将跨平台文件互传功能扩展到更多设备，此前 Pixel 10 系列独占支持的 AirDrop「快速分享」（Quick Share）即将登陆 Pixel 9 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the latest Android Canary version (ZP11.251212.007), developers discovered that the Pixel 9 series firmware has added the Quick Share system components required to support sending files to iPhones.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在最新的 Android Canary 版本（ZP11.251212.007）中，开发者发现 Pixel 9 系列固件已加入支持向 iPhone 发送文件所需的 Quick Share 系统组件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            These files were not previously present in the firmware of older models like Pixel 8 and Pixel 8 Pro, and Pixel 9a does not yet include relevant content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这些文件此前并未出现在 Pixel 8、Pixel 8 Pro 等旧款机型的固件中，Pixel 9a 也暂未包含相关内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When Google announced Quick Share's interoperability with Apple AirDrop last year, it was positioned as a launch feature for the Pixel 10 series, but no specific timeline for pushing it to older devices was announced.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Google 去年宣布 Quick Share 与苹果 AirDrop 实现互操作时，曾将其定位为 Pixel 10 系列的首发功能，但并未公布向旧款设备推送的具体时间表。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This Canary version update means that Google has begun laying the groundwork for the Pixel 9 series, and the widespread adoption of cross-platform file transfer may be faster than expected.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次 Canary 版本的更新意味着 Google 已开始为 Pixel 9 系列铺设底层支持，跨平台文件互传的普及速度可能会快于预期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the official release time, Android Authority speculates that the feature might be pushed with Android 16 QPR3, or it could be scheduled for Android 17.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            正式版推送时间方面，Android Authority 推测该功能可能会随 Android 16 QPR3 推送，也可能被安排至 Android 17。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YouTube 将允许用户在搜索结果中隐藏短视频</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">YouTube-将允许用户在搜索结果中隐藏短视频</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0713d1d5-eb3a-48ac-8b30-337474a35d35.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, YouTube is rolling out a search filter update this year, renaming and adjusting existing filter options, and adding new filtering methods that are more aligned with user needs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，YouTube 正在今年推出一项搜索过滤功能更新，对现有筛选项进行重命名、调整，并新增更贴近用户需求的过滤方式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This YouTube update allows users to explicitly filter for 'Videos' (long videos) or 'Shorts' (short videos) in search results. In the new filter, 'Videos' will only display long video content, while 'Shorts' will only present a list of short videos, avoiding browsing interference caused by mixed content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            YouTube 此次更新允许用户在搜索结果中明确筛选「Videos」（长视频）或「Shorts」（短视频）。在新版过滤器中，「Videos」将仅显示长视频内容，而「Shorts」则只呈现短视频列表，避免两种内容混杂带来的浏览干扰。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, YouTube has removed the 'Sort by upload time' and 'Sort by rating' options. Officials stated that these filters 'did not work as expected and caused user complaints'. Other upload time filter options such as 'Today', 'This week', 'This month', and 'This year' will still be retained.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，YouTube 移除了「按上传时间排序」与「按评价排序」两个选项。官方表示，这些过滤器「未能如预期工作，并引发用户投诉」。其他上传时间筛选项如「今天」「本周」「本月」「今年」仍将保留。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding sorting methods, YouTube is replacing the original 'number of views' with a new 'Popularity' filter. Officials explained that this filter will combine video watch counts with other relevance signals (such as watch time) to determine the popularity of a search result.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在排序方式上，YouTube 用全新的「受欢迎程度」（Popularity）过滤器取代原有的「播放数」。官方解释称，该过滤器会综合视频观看次数与其他相关性信号（如观看时长）来判断某条搜索结果的热门程度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小米 17 系列官宣首次降价，最高下调 300 元</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小米-17-系列官宣首次降价，最高下调-300-元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/14306e0d-6929-44c0-bd42-6c5f0c06890e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the Xiaomi 17 series saw its first official price reduction approximately four months after its release. Three mainstream configurations of the standard version were temporarily lowered by 200 to 300 yuan, with the promotion lasting until January 31st.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小米 17 系列在发布约四个月后迎来首次官方降价，标准版三款主流配置限时下调 200 至 300 元，活动将持续至 1 月 31 日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This price adjustment covers three versions: 12GB+256GB, 12GB+512GB, and 16GB+512GB. After the price reduction, they are priced at 4299 yuan, 4499 yuan, and 4799 yuan respectively; the 16GB+1TB version remains unchanged at 5299 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次调价覆盖 12GB+256GB、12GB+512GB 与 16GB+512GB 三个版本，降价后售价分别为 4299 元、4499 元与 4799 元；16GB+1TB 版本维持 5299 元不变。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jiemian News pointed out that in early December last year, Apple also conducted year-end promotions in the domestic market, with the iPhone 17 Pro and iPhone 17 Pro Max seeing a price drop of 300 yuan after coupons. With additional subsidies in some regions, the final price further decreased.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            界面新闻指出，去年 12 月初，苹果也曾在国内市场开展年末促销，iPhone 17 Pro 与 iPhone 17 Pro Max 券后降幅达 300 元，叠加部分地区补贴后，终端价格进一步下探。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Omdia data, Apple ranked third in smartphone shipments in mainland China in the third quarter of last year, with Xiaomi closely following in fourth place.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据 Omdia 数据，去年三季度苹果在中国大陆智能手机出货量中位列第三，小米紧随其后排名第四。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi Group President Lu Weibing revealed last October that the overall sales of the Xiaomi 17 series increased by 30% year-on-year, with the Pro version accounting for over 80%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米集团总裁卢伟冰曾在去年 10 月透露，小米 17 系列整体销量同比增长 30%，其中 Pro 版本占比超过 80%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to previous flagship model price adjustments, this 300 yuan price reduction is a regular promotion. The previous Xiaomi MIX Fold 3 had accumulated price reductions of 2000 yuan twice in 2024.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比此前旗舰机型的调价幅度，此次 300 元的降幅属于常规促销。过去的小米 MIX Fold 3 曾在 2024 年两次累计降价 2000 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this promotion does not include the Xiaomi 17 Ultra and Xiaomi 17 Ultra Leica Edition, with their starting prices remaining at 6999 yuan and 7999 yuan respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，此次促销未包含 Xiaomi 17 Ultra 与 Xiaomi 17 Ultra 徕卡版，两者起售价仍分别为 6999 元与 7999 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reports cite industry insiders pointing out that due to rising memory prices, the mobile phone market is facing upward price pressure, and some manufacturers have already experienced memory shortages.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道援引业内人士指出，受内存价格上涨影响，手机市场面临涨价压力，部分厂商已出现内存短缺。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since last October, new models from brands like Xiaomi, OPPO, vivo, and Honor have generally seen price increases of 100 to 600 yuan across different configurations compared to their predecessors, with the starting price of the Xiaomi 17 Ultra increasing by 500 yuan over the previous generation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自去年 10 月以来，小米、OPPO、vivo、荣耀等品牌的新机在不同配置上较上代普遍上涨 100 至 600 元，其中小米 17 Ultra 起售价较上一代提升 500 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MiniMax 正式在港交所挂牌上市</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MiniMax-正式在港交所挂牌上市</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0c7dd3da-d169-4623-a073-02fdd904d43e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, MiniMax Xiyu Technology officially listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，MiniMax 稀宇科技正式在港交所上市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            MiniMax founder and CEO Yan Junjie stated at the listing ceremony that the true value of an artificial intelligence company lies in &quot;providing a continuous stream of advanced intelligence that can be used by people.&quot; He emphasized that the company will continue to promote the advancement of intelligent technology and contribute to social and economic development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            MiniMax 创始人兼 CEO 闫俊杰在上市仪式上表示，一家人工智能公司的真正价值在于「提供源源不断的先进智能，并为人所用」。他强调，公司将持续推动智能技术进步，并为社会与经济发展贡献力量。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             On its first day of trading, MiniMax performed strongly, closing up 109.09% at HK$345, with its total market capitalization rising to HK$105.4 billion, making it one of the largest AI companies by IPO scale in history.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             上市首日，MiniMax 交易表现强劲，收盘大涨 109.09%，报 345 港元，总市值升至 1054 亿港元，成为目前史上 IPO 规模最大的 AI 公司之一。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the prospectus, MiniMax is currently the Chinese large model company with the highest international revenue, with revenue growth exceeding 170% year-on-year in the first 9 months of 2025, and overseas market revenue accounting for over 70%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            招股书信息显示，MiniMax 是当前国际化收入最高的中国大模型公司，2025 年前 9 个月营收同比增长超过 170%，其中海外市场收入占比超过 70%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this IPO, the company introduced 14 cornerstone investors, including ADIA, Aspex, Eastspring, Mirae Asset, Alibaba, and E Fund, with a total subscription amount of HK$2.723 billion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次 IPO 中，公司引入 ADIA、Aspex、Eastspring、Mirae Asset、阿里巴巴、易方达等 14 家基石投资者，合计认购金额达 27.23 亿港元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曝 Strava 秘密提交 IPO 申请，最快今年春季上市</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝-Strava-秘密提交-IPO-申请，最快今年春季上市</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5379385e-ab0c-4821-abb2-e5709251d58c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to &quot;The Information&quot;, fitness social app Strava secretly filed for an IPO several weeks ago and hired Goldman Sachs to handle the listing. Sources say Strava is meeting with potential investors and could officially enter the capital market as early as this spring.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《The Information》报道 ，健身社交应用 Strava 已在数周前秘密提交 IPO 申请，并聘请高盛负责上市事宜。知情人士称，Strava 正与潜在投资者会面，最快可能于今年春季正式登陆资本市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Strava was founded in 2009 and is headquartered in San Francisco. Sources revealed that the company's revenue grew by over 50% year-on-year last year and it achieved profitability, but its overall scale is still smaller than most listed consumer internet companies, with revenue less than $500 million last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Strava 成立于 2009 年，总部位于旧金山。知情人士透露，该公司去年营收同比增长超过 50%，并实现盈利，但整体规模仍小于多数上市消费互联网公司，去年营收不足 5 亿美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last spring, The Wall Street Journal reported that Strava's valuation was approximately $2.2 billion (including debt).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年春季，《华尔街日报》曾报道 Strava 的估值约为 22 亿美元（含债务）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This IPO will also provide an exit opportunity for its long-term investors, including institutions such as Sequoia Capital and TCV. It is currently unclear what Strava's planned fundraising size and target valuation after listing will be.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次 IPO 也将为其长期投资方，包括红杉资本与 TCV 等机构提供退出机会。目前尚不清楚 Strava 计划募资规模及上市后的目标估值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Strava is one of several internet companies in recent years that took over a decade to go public. Its listing performance will depend on whether investors believe its stock price can be closer to Reddit, which saw its stock price rise more than 7 times after listing last year, rather than the lackluster performance of Klarna or StubHub after their listings.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Strava 是近年来多家耗时十余年才走向公开市场的互联网公司之一。其上市表现将取决于投资者是否相信其股价能更接近去年上市后股价上涨超过 7 倍的 Reddit，而非上市后表现疲软的 Klarna 或 StubHub。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report also noted that Discord, another long-established internet company, also plans to go public in the coming months.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道同时指出，另一家成立已久的互联网公司 Discord 也计划在未来数月内上市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Part of Strava's growth came from a surge in users during the pandemic, with its model combining exercise tracking and social networking attracting a large number of running and cycling users, especially favored by Generation Z.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Strava 的增长部分来自疫情期间用户激增，其将运动记录与社交网络结合的模式吸引大量跑步与骑行用户，尤其受到 Z 世代青睐。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company's official website shows that its app has over 150 million active users in 185 countries worldwide, with basic features free and paid subscriptions offering more training and analysis tools.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司官网显示，其应用在全球 185 个国家拥有超过 1.5 亿活跃用户，基础功能免费，付费订阅提供更多训练与分析工具。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Strava has expanded its features through acquisitions in recent years, including the acquisition of British running coach app Runna and cycling training platform The Breakaway.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，Strava 近年来通过收购扩展功能，包括去年收购英国跑步教练应用 Runna 以及自行车训练平台 The Breakaway。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>特斯拉开源全系车衣设计模板</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">特斯拉开源全系车衣设计模板</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ffb82d85-04d8-4f0c-958f-fe5ab3841b8a.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Tesla officially launched PNG files of vehicle wrap templates for all Model S / 3 / X / Y and Cybertruck models (including all model years) on GitHub, and simultaneously enabled related features with this year's software update (version 2025.44.25.11), allowing owners to create and apply personalized vehicle wrap designs at lower cost and with higher precision.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，特斯拉正式在 GitHub 上线 Model S / 3 / X / Y 及 Cybertruck 全系车型（含历年车型）的车衣模板 PNG 文件，并随今年软件更新（版本 2025.44.25.11）同步开放相关功能，使车主能够以更低成本、更高精度制作并应用个性化车衣设计。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to information provided by Tesla, car owners can directly download corresponding vehicle templates from GitHub, complete their designs in image editing software, and then import them via a USB drive. After the vehicle is upgraded to 2025.44.25.11, users can apply the materials to the central control 3D model on the vehicle's infotainment system, achieving complete visual synchronization from the car to the mobile App.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据特斯拉提供的信息，车主可直接从 GitHub 下载对应车型模板，并在图像编辑软件中完成设计后导入 U 盘。车辆升级至 2025.44.25.11 后，用户可在车机将素材应用到中控 3D 模型，实现从车机到手机 App 的完整视觉同步。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The GitHub repository page shows that Tesla provides independent templates for different car models and specifies detailed guidelines such as USB directory structure, file format, and resolution. Users can load up to 10 custom images simultaneously, and the system will provide a selection entry in the &quot;Paint Shop&quot; interface.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GitHub 仓库页面显示，特斯拉为不同车型提供了独立模板，并给出了 USB 目录结构、文件格式、分辨率等详细规范。用户最多可同时加载 10 张自定义图片，系统将在「喷漆车间」（Paint Shop）界面中提供选择入口。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            💻 GitHub:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/teslamotors/custom-wraps&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/teslamotors/custom-wraps
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            💻 GitHub：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/teslamotors/custom-wraps&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/teslamotors/custom-wraps
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 戴尔：AI 不是 PC 用户的核心诉求</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-戴尔：AI-不是-PC-用户的核心诉求</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c23f0571-7d32-4fea-b41b-797cf94db797.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 9to5Mac, Dell recently admitted in public communications that actual buyers in the current PC market do not view AI as a primary reason for purchase, a stark contrast to the industry's large-scale promotion of &quot;AI PCs&quot; over the past year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 9to5Mac 报道，戴尔近日在公开沟通中承认，当前 PC 市场的实际购买者并未将 AI 视为主要购买理由，这与过去一年行业大规模推动「AI PC」的营销方向形成鲜明对比。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dell stated that the company has not given up on advancing local AI capabilities in its products, but a marketing strategy that continuously uses AI as a core selling point has not effectively boosted sales and may even have a counterproductive effect on some user groups.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            戴尔方面表示，公司并未放弃在产品中推进本地 AI 能力，但持续以 AI 作为核心卖点的营销策略并未有效促进销量，甚至可能在部分用户群体中产生反效果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that Dell has realized internally that consumers are more concerned with traditional metrics such as price, performance, battery life, and reliability when purchasing PCs, rather than the NPU or local AI acceleration capabilities emphasized by manufacturers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，戴尔内部已意识到，消费者在选购 PC 时更关注价格、性能、续航与可靠性等传统指标，而非厂商强调的 NPU 或本地 AI 加速能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            9to5Mac noted that among users outside the tech industry, AI has not sparked significant interest; instead, it more often elicits skepticism or concern. This further confirms Dell's assessment of market feedback: there is a disconnect between the industry's pace of promoting AI PCs and users' actual needs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9to5Mac 指出，在非科技行业用户中，AI 并未激发明显兴趣，反而更常引发怀疑或担忧情绪。这也进一步印证了戴尔对市场反馈的判断：行业对 AI PC 的宣传节奏与用户实际需求之间存在落差。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, PC manufacturers generally view AI as an important direction for driving replacement cycles, but based on Dell's statements, whether AI can become a true consumer-level selling point still requires time to verify.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，PC 厂商普遍将 AI 视为推动换机周期的重要方向，但从戴尔的表态来看，AI 能否成为真正的消费级卖点仍需时间验证。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>电子计价秤新规正式实施，非法拆卸改装将自动锁机</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">电子计价秤新规正式实施，非法拆卸改装将自动锁机</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b9cc110f-d24c-4dc7-a2c9-3f155d35b8a9.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV, the &quot;Outline for Type Evaluation of Electronic Pricing Scales (Trial)&quot; recently issued by the State Administration for Market Regulation has officially come into effect. It targets electronic pricing scales with a maximum weighing capacity not exceeding 100 kg and accuracy levels of medium or ordinary grade, focusing on strengthening anti-cheating capabilities from a technical perspective. The new regulations require:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视报道，近日，市场监管总局发布的《电子计价秤型式评价大纲（试行）》正式实施，面向最大秤量不超过 100 kg、准确度等级为中等级或普通级的电子计价秤，重点从技术层面强化防作弊能力。新规要求：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic pricing scales must have &quot;shell-opening lock, authorized unlock&quot; capability. Once the casing is illegally opened, the device will automatically lock and can only be unlocked by authorized personnel using a highly secure dynamic password. This mechanism aims to block acts such as disassembling for modification or implanting cheating programs at the source, significantly reducing the scope for fraud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearly implement the &quot;one scale, one code&quot; system. Each electronic pricing scale must have unique identification information such as a production code and maintenance code, and undergo online verification during mandatory inspection. Products with inconsistent information are not allowed to enter the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implement the &quot;three codes, one seal&quot; mechanism, meaning that the production code, maintenance code, verification code, and lead seal must be complete and valid for inspection. Manufacturing enterprises must complete technical upgrades and obtain type approval before January 8th of this year; sales enterprises are not allowed to sell products that have not been approved or have incomplete identity information; user units must conduct self-inspections of equipment in use and select products that comply with specifications when adding or replacing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CCTV News quoted a relevant official from the State Administration for Market Regulation as saying that the new regulations, through technical means such as encrypted authentication and dynamic passwords, form a &quot;dynamic locking, identity traceability&quot; combination, which will effectively curb fraudulent behavior in electronic pricing scales.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            央视新闻援引市场监管总局相关负责人表示，新规通过加密认证、动态密码等技术手段，形成「动态锁定、身份追溯」的组合拳，将有效遏制电子计价秤作弊行为。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As of now, over 90% of manufacturing enterprises nationwide have completed technical upgrades, and products complying with the new specifications are gradually being put into production.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            截至目前，全国 90% 以上生产企业已完成技术改造，符合新规范的产品正在陆续投产。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the national smart metrology supervision platform for electronic pricing scales is being accelerated, which will cover full lifecycle information from type approval, production, verification, to use, achieving full-process traceable management of electronic pricing scales in the market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，全国电子计价秤智慧计量监管平台正在加紧建设，将覆盖从型式批准、生产、检定到使用的全生命周期信息，实现市场上在用电子计价秤的全流程可追溯管理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>海底捞回应「尿不湿扔锅」：已报警，监护人被处理</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">海底捞回应「尿不湿扔锅」：已报警，监护人被处理</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a316ffda-4944-456f-b415-bb1ab5101c9c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a report by The Beijing News, Haidilao recently became a topic of public discussion again due to an incident where a &quot;diaper was thrown into a hotpot base.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《新京报》报道，海底捞近日因「尿不湿被扔进火锅锅底」事件再次登上舆论场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Haidilao responded that the incident occurred on December 31 last year at the Haidilao Yunlong Wanda Plaza store in Xuzhou, Jiangsu, where a two-year-old child threw a diaper into a pot being used by customers at the same table. The store subsequently discarded the pot and reported the incident to the police, and the local police have taken appropriate action against the guardian present that day.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            海底捞方面回应称，事件发生于去年 12 月 31 日，地点为海底捞江苏徐州云龙万达广场店，一名两岁儿童将尿不湿扔入同桌顾客正在使用的锅具内。门店随后对锅具进行废弃处理并报警，属地警方已对当日监护人作出相应处理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this is the second time Haidilao has attracted attention due to a similar incident recently. Just recently, the People's Court Daily published an apology statement from Mr. Tang and his parents, who were involved in the previous &quot;urination incident.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，这已是海底捞近期第二次因类似事件引发关注。就在最近，《人民法院报》刊登了此前「小便门」事件当事人唐某及其父母的道歉声明。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The incident occurred in February last year, when two minors urinated into a hotpot in a Haidilao private room and filmed it. The court ultimately ruled that both sets of parents were liable for a total compensation of 2.2 million yuan. In his statement, Mr. Tang expressed &quot;profound realization of the mistake&quot; and apologized to the relevant company.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该事件发生于去年 2 月，两名未成年人在海底捞包间内向火锅内小便并拍摄视频，最终被法院判决由双方父母承担共计 220 万元赔偿。唐某在声明中表示「深刻认识到错误」，并向相关公司致歉。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>海南航空回应百元「bug」机票：系统故障，已出票机票全部有效</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">海南航空回应百元「bug」机票：系统故障，已出票机票全部有效</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/bdfb7f68-676a-40df-9542-ed2cdbe67665.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, yesterday, many netizens reported on social media that they had purchased &quot;bug-priced&quot; abnormally low-cost airline tickets through third-party platforms, including &quot;Beijing to Shenzhen for 130-200 yuan,&quot; &quot;Chengdu to Shenzhen for 80 yuan,&quot; and some travelers even claimed &quot;Guangzhou to Chengdu for 270 yuan, tickets issued.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，昨天，多位网友在社交平台反馈称，通过第三方平台购买到「bug 价」异常低价机票，包括「北京至深圳 130-200 元」「成都至深圳 80 元」等，还有旅客称「广州飞成都 270 元，已出票」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hainan Airlines stated that its system experienced a temporary malfunction around 10 AM yesterday, causing abnormal display of ticket prices for some routes. The company said it completed troubleshooting and repair immediately, and the system has now returned to normal.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             The announcement emphasized that all tickets sold during the malfunction period are valid, and passengers can travel as planned.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            海南航空表示，昨日上午 10 时左右，其系统因临时故障导致部分航线机票价格显示异常。公司称已在第一时间完成排查与修复，系统现已恢复正常。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             公告强调，在故障期间已售出的机票全部有效，旅客可按原计划出行。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            HNA Holdings' third-quarter report last year showed that the company achieved operating revenue of 53.438 billion yuan and net profit attributable to the parent company of 2.845 billion yuan in the first three quarters, a year-on-year increase of 30.93%; revenue passenger kilometers for international routes increased by 47.79% year-on-year, and international passenger traffic increased by 46.83% year-on-year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            海航控股去年三季报显示，公司前三季度实现营业收入 534.38 亿元，归母净利润 28.45 亿元，同比增长 30.93%；国际航线收入客公里同比增长 47.79%，国际旅客运输量同比增长 46.83%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COSTA 普洱茶保质期 100 年，客服：越陈越香</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">COSTA-普洱茶保质期-100-年，客服：越陈越香</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a6f86118-138b-4e0c-9f9b-8ce51912780a.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to China News Service, recently, some consumers reported that the production date marked on the packaging of the COSTA Organic Pu-erh Tea (ripe tea) compressed tea product they purchased on an e-commerce platform was October 1, 2025, with an expiration date of October 1, 2125, indicating a shelf life of 100 years, which has attracted attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据中新经纬报道，近日有消费者反映，其在电商平台购买的 COSTA 有机普洱茶（熟茶）紧压茶产品包装上标注的生产日期为 2025 年 10 月 1 日，保质到期日为 2125 年 10 月 1 日，保质期长达 100 年，引发关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When consumers consulted the customer service of the COSTA Coffee flagship store, the customer service stated that the product was a tea cake and claimed that &quot;the older the tea, the better.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            消费者向 COSTA 咖啡旗舰店客服咨询时，客服表示该产品为茶饼，并称「茶越久越好」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding whether it can truly be stored for 100 years, customer service stated that it can be stored long-term under conditions such as avoiding light and at room temperature, but did not provide clear explanations for the shelf life basis or experimental certification, only emphasizing that the packaging label should be followed. Customer service also did not provide further explanation regarding whether there was a printing error.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于是否真的能保存 100 年，客服称在避光、常温等条件下可长期保存，但未就保质期依据或实验认证给出明确说明，仅强调以包装标注为准。对于是否存在印刷错误，客服同样未给出进一步解释。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, when Jiemian News checked Tmall's &quot;COSTA Official Flagship Store&quot; and JD.com's &quot;COSTA COFFEE Coffee Flagship Store,&quot; no related Pu-erh tea products were found. Platform customer service stated that there is currently no Pu-erh tea in the store. Tmall customer service said the product &quot;was probably delisted some time ago,&quot; while JD.com customer service stated that it was &quot;automatically delisted due to no stock.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，界面新闻查询天猫「COSTA 官方旗舰店」及京东「COSTA COFFEE 咖啡旗舰店」时，均未发现相关普洱茶产品。平台客服表示目前店内没有普洱茶，天猫客服称该产品「应该是前段时间下架的」，京东客服则表示「无货自动下架」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Life Times previously introduced that Pu-erh tea is divided into raw tea (sheng cha) and ripe tea (shu cha). Raw tea, which has not undergone artificial rapid fermentation, has better storage resistance, and its color, aroma, taste, and quality can improve with longer storage time; ripe tea, on the other hand, becomes milder in nature due to the wet piling process.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《生命时报》此前介绍，普洱茶分为生茶与熟茶。生茶未经人工快速发酵，耐储藏性更好，随着储藏时间延长，色香味及品质可提升；熟茶则因渥堆工艺使茶性更温和。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lin Zhi, Director of the Science and Technology Department of the Tea Research Institute of the Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences, pointed out that the optimal shelf life for Pu-erh tea is about 10 years, and the saying &quot;the older, the more fragrant&quot; only applies within the shelf life and under the premise of qualified quality and proper storage. If the initial quality is poor or storage is improper, longer storage time will not improve the quality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国农业科学院茶叶研究所科技处处长林智指出，普洱茶的最佳保质期约为 10 年，「越陈越香」仅适用于保质期内，且需在质量合格与储存得当的前提下。如果初始品质不佳或储存不当，存放时间再长也不会提升品质。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>稚晖君携「装进背包的人形机器人」启元 Q1 亮相 CES 2026</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">稚晖君携「装进背包的人形机器人」启元-Q1-亮相-CES-2026</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/55475cbf-e5d4-4a29-85de-9ceda1373431.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At this year's CES exhibition, UWIN Robotics unveiled its Q1 humanoid robot, the world's first full-body force-controlled small-sized humanoid robot, becoming one of the most anticipated new categories of consumer robots at the exhibition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 CES 展会上，上纬启元携全球首款全身力控小尺寸人形机器人启元 Q1 亮相，成为今年展会最受关注的消费级机器人新品类之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Peng Zhihui (Zhihui Jun), Chairman of UWIN Robotics, stated at the scene that true technological progress should be &quot;not just seen, but also experienced.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上纬启元董事长彭志辉（稚晖君）在现场表示，真正的科技进步应当「不止看见，更可体验」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Q1 is designed for individual users, emphasizing the product philosophy of being ownable, usable, and creatable. By opening up SDK/HDK interfaces and open-source external structural components, it allows developers, students, and creators to conduct long-term experiments and personalized development in everyday environments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            启元 Q1 面向个人用户设计，强调可拥有、可使用、可创作的产品理念，并通过开放 SDK/HDK 接口与开源外观结构件，让开发者、学生与创作者能够在日常环境中进行长期实验与个性化开发。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The core breakthrough of the Q1 comes from its extreme miniaturization engineering capabilities. The team compressed the QDD quasi-direct drive joints used in traditional full-sized robots to &quot;smaller than an egg,&quot; while retaining force control performance and high dynamic response. Officially, it is positioned as a &quot;mobile laboratory&quot; for researchers, a &quot;curious playmate&quot; for children, and a &quot;creative canvas&quot; for geeks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            启元 Q1 的核心突破来自其极致的小型化工程能力。团队将传统全尺寸机器人使用的 QDD 准直驱关节压缩至「比鸡蛋还小」，同时保留力控性能与高动态响应，官方将其定位为科研者的「移动实验室」、孩子的「好奇玩伴」、极客的「创意画布」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During its CES debut, the Q1 became the most popular check-in spot in the humanoid robot exhibition area. From Pepcom Media Day to the public open day, the booth remained crowded, with many visitors saying it was &quot;the first robot companion they wanted to take home.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 CES 首秀期间，启元 Q1 成为人形机器人展区最火爆的打卡点。从 Pepcom 媒体日到公众开放日，展台持续拥挤，不少参观者表示这是「第一次想带回家的机器人伙伴」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On social media platforms, the Q1 also sparked discussion. Suzanne Kantra, editor-in-chief of Techlicious, called it &quot;the most exciting robot of CES 2026.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            社交平台上，启元 Q1 同样引发讨论。Techlicious 主编 Suzanne Kantra 称其为「CES 2026 最有看头的机器人」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            North American basketball rookie champion player Aaliyah Nye shared a video of her touring the exhibition with the Q1, calling it her &quot;mini MVP,&quot; further boosting topic dissemination.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            北美篮球新秀冠军球员 Aaliyah Nye 分享了与启元 Q1 的逛展视频，称它是自己的「迷你 MVP」，进一步带动话题传播。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhou Bin, Director, Co-CEO, and CTO of UWIN Robotics, stated in an official CES interview that the company's vision is to bring embodied AI into every home, allowing everyone to own a personal robot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上纬启元董事、联席 CEO 兼 CTO 周斌在 CES 官方采访中表示，公司愿景是让具身智能走进每个家庭，让人人都拥有一个个人机器人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            UWIN Robotics likened &quot;Zhihui Jun putting a robot in a backpack&quot; to &quot;Steve Jobs putting a laptop in an envelope,&quot; emphasizing that technological progress consistently simplifies complexity and makes the future tangible.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上纬启元将「稚晖君把机器人放进背包」比喻为「乔布斯把笔记本装进信封」，强调科技的进步始终在让复杂变简单，让未来变得触手可及。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Fun Thing｜小米 17 Pro 将更新背屏「录像提词器」功能</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">One-Fun-Thing｜小米-17-Pro-将更新背屏「录像提词器」功能</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4ea938e4-e958-4353-8bce-6f6c8cb90164.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Lu Weibing, Partner and President of Xiaomi Group, announced on Weibo that the Xiaomi 17 Pro series will receive a back screen function update, adding a &quot;video teleprompter&quot; capability to further enhance the practicality of the back screen in video shooting scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小米集团合伙人、总裁卢伟冰在微博宣布，小米 17 Pro 系列将获得背屏功能更新，新增「录像提词器」能力，进一步强化背屏在视频拍摄场景中的实用性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi stated that this feature has been gradually pushed to users and is expected to be fully launched by mid-to-late January. After the update, users can simultaneously scroll and display custom text while recording videos with the back screen, and adjust the scrolling speed to reduce expressive pressure and minimize forgetting lines during shooting.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米表示，该功能已陆续向用户推送，预计将在一月中下旬完成全量上线。更新后，用户在使用背屏录制视频时，可同步滚动显示自定义文案，并可调节滚动速度，以降低拍摄时的表达压力，减少忘词情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi previously revealed that the R&amp;amp;D investment for this back screen reached 1 billion yuan, and it will continue to be retained in the next generation of models. In recent months, Xiaomi has successively added features such as dialogue translation, selfie sticker mode, dynamic photo/video wallpapers, and framed screenshots to the back screen, gradually expanding its usage scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米此前透露，这块背屏的研发投入达到 10 亿元，并将在下一代机型中继续保留。过去数月，小米已为背屏陆续加入对话翻译、大头贴模式、动态照片 / 视频壁纸、带壳截屏等功能，逐步扩展其使用场景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to the teleprompter, Phoenix Network Technology pointed out that this HyperOS 3.0.40.0.WPBCNXM update also brings multiple system functions such as stock market data, quicksand effects, New Year flags, and New Year personalized signature wallpapers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除提词器外，凤凰网科技指出，本次 HyperOS 3.0.40.0.WPBCNXM 更新还带来股票行情、流沙动效、新年 flag、新年个性签名壁纸等多项系统功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>周末看什么｜《寻秦记》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">周末看什么｜《寻秦记》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/face8d6b-9bd9-4667-b98a-17be74337b80.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After the film version of &quot;A Step into the Past&quot; officially premiered on December 31st, it continued to spark intense discussion and drove box office performance with a nostalgia-driven viewing trend, breaking records in multiple markets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电影版《寻秦记》在 12 月 31 日正式上映后，持续引发强烈讨论，并以情怀驱动的观影潮带动票房表现，在多个市场刷新纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film stars the original cast including Louis Koo, Raymond Lam, Jessica Hsuan, Sonija Kwok, and Joyce Tang, with a production cost of HK$350 million. The film continues from the ending of the 2001 TVB series of the same name, with the story set 20 years after the series finale, revolving around the renewed confrontation between Xiang Shaolong and Ying Zheng during the late Warring States period.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电影由古天乐、林峯、宣萱、郭羡妮、滕丽名等原班人马主演，制作成本达 3.5 亿港元。影片承接 2001 年 TVB 同名剧集的结局，故事设定在剧集终章 20 年后，围绕项少龙与嬴政在战国末期的再度交锋展开。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On its opening day, &quot;A Step into the Past&quot; recorded 1481 screenings in Hong Kong, setting a record for the most opening day screenings in local film history, and became the highest-grossing opening day film in Hong Kong history with over HK$11 million in box office revenue. As of early January this year, the cumulative box office in Hong Kong and Macau exceeded HK$40 million.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上映当天，《寻秦记》在香港录得 1481 场开画场次，创下当地电影史上首日最多场次纪录，并以逾 1100 万港元票房成为香港史上首日最高开画票房冠军。截至今年 1 月初，港澳累计票房突破 4000 万港元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the mainland market, the film's box office exceeded 40 million RMB on its opening day, surpassed 50 million RMB on the second day, and reached a cumulative box office of 112 million RMB in three days. According to Maoyan Pro data, the film currently ranks fourth in this year's overall movie ticket chart.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在大陆市场，影片上映首日票房突破 4000 万元人民币，次日突破 5000 万元，三天累计票房达 1.12 亿元人民币。根据猫眼专业版数据，影片在今年电影票总榜中暂列第四。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            From audience feedback, the film's discussion popularity is primarily driven by &quot;nostalgia.&quot; A large number of post-80s and post-90s audiences view it as a continuation of their childhood memories, with the theme song &quot;Heaven's Will is Highest&quot; becoming an emotional trigger when it played in the cinema.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从观众反馈来看，影片的讨论热度主要由「情怀」驱动。大量 80 后、90 后观众将其视为童年记忆的延续，主题曲《天命最高》在影院响起时成为情绪触发点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some viewers stated that the film is more like a &quot;completion&quot; of the TV series' open ending, providing a sense of &quot;finally concluded&quot; emotional resolution.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分观众表示，电影更像是对剧版开放式结局的「补完」，带来一种「终于完结」的情绪落点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>买书不读指南｜《旷野的慰藉》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">买书不读指南｜《旷野的慰藉》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6d7e176c-1717-4822-acc0-daf60e9ec6af.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;The Solace of Open Spaces&quot; chronicles author Gretel Ehrlich's long-term experiences living in Wyoming since 1975:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《旷野的慰藉》记录了作者格蕾特尔 · 埃里克（Gretel Ehrlich）自 1975 年起在怀俄明州的长期生活经历：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            She came to the area to film a documentary but experienced the death of her partner during filming. She then brought her grief to this desolate, vast, and storm-ridden land, finding self-healing through ranch work and the changing seasons.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            她因拍摄纪录片来到当地，却在拍摄期间遭遇伴侣离世，随后将哀恸带入这片荒凉、辽阔、风暴频仍的土地，并在牧场劳作与四季更迭中完成自我修复。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The book is structured with 12 essays forming a loose yet coherent narrative, covering topics such as the daily life of shepherds, cowboy culture, working animals, survival experiences in the West, and the shaping influence of the natural environment on the human spirit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            书中以 12 篇散文构成松散而连贯的叙事结构，内容涵盖牧羊人日常、牛仔文化、工作动物、在西部的生存经验，以及自然环境对人类精神的塑形作用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wyoming is described as a &quot;moon-like desolate&quot; landscape, where wind is the eternal protagonist, and fossils, agates, and animal carcasses are scattered throughout; ranch life is rough, direct, and closely intertwined with flesh and blood, cold, and loneliness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            怀俄明被描述为「如月球般荒凉」的地貌，风是永恒的主角，化石、玛瑙与动物尸体散落其间；牧场生活粗粝、直接，与血肉、寒冷和孤独紧密相连。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this extreme environment, the author gradually comes to understand that &quot;loss is a strange fullness&quot; and regains the strength of life through nature's lessons of impermanence.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在这种极端环境中，作者逐渐理解「失去是一种奇怪的充实」，并在自然的无常之课中重新获得生命的力量。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>游戏推荐｜《空洞骑士：丝之歌》：Steam 年度最佳游戏奖得主</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">游戏推荐｜《空洞骑士：丝之歌》：Steam-年度最佳游戏奖得主</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260110_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/727b829d-f485-4eb2-a5c5-1cc0fa7742c4.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Hollow Knight: Silksong&quot; is the official sequel to &quot;Hollow Knight&quot; developed by Team Cherry. As a Metroidvania action game, this title stars the previous game's character &quot;Hornet,&quot; focusing on her escape and exploration after being abducted to the unfamiliar kingdom of &quot;Pharloom.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《空洞骑士：丝之歌》是樱桃游戏工作室推出的《空洞骑士》正统续作。作为一款类银河战士恶魔城动作游戏，本作以前作角色「大黄蜂」为主角，围绕其被绑架至陌生王国「纺络」后的逃脱与探索展开。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Players must advance the story through a multi-layered ecosystem ruled by silk and song, gradually uncovering the truth behind Hornet's origins and the kingdom's decline.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            玩家需在由丝与歌统治的多层生态中推进剧情，逐步揭开大黄蜂身世与王国衰败的真相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of gameplay, this title has undergone significant reconstruction based on its predecessor. Hornet's core weapon system revolves around needle and thread, with new mechanics such as grappling hooks and aerial dash chain movements, making combat and platforming emphasize speed and rhythm even more.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            玩法方面，本作在前作基础上进行了大幅重构。大黄蜂以针线为核心武器体系，新增抓钩、空中突刺链式移动等机制，使战斗与平台跳跃更强调速度与节奏感。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Players can collect silk for skill casting and health recovery, craft items, and challenge over 150 types of enemies and more than 40 bosses. The quest system has been expanded to include categories such as hunting, collecting, pathfinding, and grand hunts, further increasing the density of the gameplay.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            玩家可收集丝线用于技能施放与回血，并可制造道具、挑战超过 150 种敌人及 40 余个 boss。任务系统扩展为狩猎、收集、寻路与大狩猎等类别，进一步提升流程密度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After its release, &quot;Silksong&quot; garnered strong global attention. Its peak concurrent players on Steam reached 530,000, ranking third across the entire platform; within three days of launch, players across all platforms exceeded 5 million, with Steam sales surpassing 3 million copies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            发售后，《丝之歌》在全球范围内获得强势关注。Steam 同时在线人数峰值达 53 万人，位列全站第三；上市三天内全平台玩家突破 500 万，其中 Steam 销量超过 300 万份。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of reviews, the initial positive rating among all language players on Steam reached 92% (&quot;Very Positive&quot;), and it was awarded &quot;Game of the Year&quot; on the Steam platform.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            评价方面，Steam 全语言玩家中初期好评率达 92%「特别好评」，并获得 Steam 平台「年度最佳游戏」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            IGN gave it a &quot;Superb&quot; rating of 9/10, considering it a &quot;challenging sequel that reinvents and evolves on almost every level,&quot; and emphasized that its level design, narrative pacing, and combat system are all more mature than its predecessor.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            IGN 则给出 9/10 分「奇佳」评价，认为本作为「在几乎所有层面重塑与进化的高难度续作」，并强调其关卡设计、叙事节奏与战斗系统均较前作更成熟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
