<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>曝苹果陷入供应链危机，全球芯片巨头争夺「玻璃布」</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝苹果陷入供应链危机，全球芯片巨头争夺「玻璃布」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/250ac700-ae4f-44be-a570-afc5cd3af108.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Nikkei Asia, as the global AI wave drives up demand for high-performance chips, Apple is facing a rare and increasingly urgent supply chain crisis: a severe shortage of the critical material high-end glass fiber fabric (T-glass), which could put pressure on this year's iPhone 18 series and related chip production.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《日本经济新闻》报道，随着全球 AI 浪潮推高高性能芯片需求，苹果正面临一场罕见且愈发紧迫的供应链危机：关键材料高端玻璃纤维布（T‑glass）出现严重短缺，或对今年的 iPhone 18 系列及相关芯片生产造成压力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, this type of glass fiber fabric is deeply embedded within chip substrates and is a core structural material for high-end BT substrates and PCBs, requiring extremely high rigidity, low thermal expansion coefficient, and zero defect characteristics.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，这类玻璃纤维布被深埋于芯片基板内部，是高端 BT 载板与 PCB 的核心结构材料，需具备极高刚性、低热膨胀系数及零瑕疵特性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Its manufacturing difficulty is extremely high; the fibers must be finer than hair and completely free of bubbles. Currently, the world's most advanced T-glass is almost monopolized by Japan's Nittobo, with limited production capacity and a long expansion cycle. New capacity is not expected to be truly released until the second half of next year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其制造难度极高，纤维需比头发更细且完全无气泡。目前，全球最先进的 T‑glass 几乎由日本日东纺（Nittobo）垄断，产能有限且扩产周期漫长，新产能预计要到明年下半年才能真正释放。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, the explosion in AI computing demand has led companies like Nvidia, Google, Amazon, AMD, and Qualcomm to flock to the same supply pool, further squeezing Apple's ability to acquire materials. Multiple supply chain sources describe it as &quot;one of the biggest bottlenecks in the electronics and AI industries in 2026.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，AI 计算需求的爆发，使英伟达、Google、Amazon、AMD、高通等企业纷纷涌入同一供应池，进一步挤压了苹果的材料获取能力。多家供应链人士将其形容为「2026 年电子与 AI 行业最大的瓶颈之一」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Facing the tense situation, Apple has taken several unusual measures. Last autumn, Apple dispatched employees to Mitsubishi Gas Chemical (MGC) to ensure its priority in the supply of BT substrate materials.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            面对紧张局势，苹果已采取多项罕见措施。去年秋季，苹果派遣员工进驻三菱瓦斯化学（MGC），以确保其在 BT 基板材料供应中的优先级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple has also communicated with Japanese government officials, hoping for assistance in coordinating critical material supplies. Concurrently, Apple is attempting to verify alternative suppliers, including contacting Chinese manufacturer Grace Fabric Technology, and has requested MGC to help improve its quality, but progress has been slow.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果还与日本政府官员沟通，希望协助协调关键材料供应。与此同时，苹果正尝试验证替代供应商，包括接触中国厂商宏和科技（Grace Fabric Technology），并要求 MGC 协助其提升品质，但进展缓慢。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Industry insiders point out that because T-glass is deeply embedded within the chip substrate and cannot be repaired or replaced after assembly, major chip manufacturers are generally unwilling to adopt low-spec materials, even as a temporary solution, as it would require significant verification time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            业内人士指出，由于 T‑glass 深埋于芯片基板内部，无法在组装后修复或替换，因此主要芯片制造商普遍不愿采用低规格材料，即便作为临时方案也需耗费大量验证时间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to Apple, Qualcomm has also visited Japanese supplier Unitika, hoping to alleviate pressure, but its production capacity is far lower than Nitto Denko. As AI server boards become thicker and harder, there are also potential shortages of PCB-related materials such as drilling equipment, drill bits, and solder resist ink, further tightening the supply chain.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除苹果外，高通也已拜访日本供应商 Unitika，希望缓解压力，但其产能远低于日东纺。随着 AI 服务器板材变得更厚、更硬，钻孔设备、钻头、焊阻油墨等 PCB 相关材料也出现潜在短缺，进一步加剧供应链紧绷。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Analysts believe that the aggressive procurement by AI giants is reshaping the material supply landscape, and consumer electronics manufacturers will face greater pressure. Even Apple, with its strong purchasing power, has been impacted, and the situation for other manufacturers may be even more severe.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析人士认为，AI 巨头的强势采购正在重塑材料供应格局，消费电子厂商将面临更大压力。即便拥有强大采购能力的苹果也受到冲击，其他厂商的处境可能更为严峻。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>西贝将大规模关停 102 家门店，贾国龙：从来不是预制菜，却遭网红恶意污蔑</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">西贝将大规模关停-102-家门店，贾国龙：从来不是预制菜，却遭网红恶意污蔑</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/69b07c9e-703a-4244-a995-308834d16b34.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, Xibei Catering is facing its largest store contraction in recent years. An internal meeting document and closure list leaked on social media yesterday show that Xibei plans to close 102 stores nationwide at once, accounting for about 30% of its total stores and involving approximately 4,000 employees.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，西贝餐饮正面临近年来最大规模的门店收缩。社交平台昨日流出的一份内部会议资料及闭店清单显示，西贝计划一次性关闭全国 102 家门店，占其门店总数约三成，涉及约 4000 名员工。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A screenshot of Jia Guolong's Moments circulating online yesterday confirmed this statement. He stated that the online information was &quot;basically accurate.&quot; He emphasized that the closure of these 102 stores would be completed gradually in the first quarter, all employees who have to leave will &quot;not miss a single penny of their salary,&quot; customer stored-value cards can continue to be used at other stores, and if a refund is chosen, it can be processed &quot;immediately.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天网上流传的贾国龙朋友圈截图印证了这一说法。他表示，网传信息「基本准确」。他强调，此次关闭的 102 家门店将于一季度陆续完成，所有不得不离职的员工「工资一分钱不会差」，顾客储值卡可在其他门店继续使用，若选择退卡可「立刻退」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For some stores that have already taken New Year's Eve dinner orders, Xibei will remain open until after the fulfillment of these orders before closing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于部分已接下年夜饭订单的门店，西贝将坚持营业至履约完成后再关店。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that in his response, Jia Guolong once again mentioned the continuous impact of the public opinion incident in September last year, stating that Xibei suffered &quot;overwhelming slander for 125 days,&quot; and emphasized that Xibei &quot;has never been pre-made dishes,&quot; and that central kitchen preparations were &quot;maliciously confused&quot; with meal kits.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，贾国龙在回应中再次提及去年 9 月舆论事件带来的持续冲击，称西贝遭遇「铺天盖地的污蔑 125 天」，并强调西贝「从来不是预制菜」，中央厨房备菜被「恶意混淆」为料理包。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that after the incident, employees continued to face cyberattacks, and the brand image was significantly affected.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，事件后员工持续遭遇网络攻击，品牌形象受到显著影响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            From the disclosed list of store closures, this round of closures is mainly concentrated in first- and second-tier cities. Among them, Shanghai has the most affected stores, with 19; Beijing, Shenzhen, and Guangzhou closed 10, 8, and 5 stores respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从已披露的闭店名单来看，此轮关店主要集中在一、二线城市。其中，上海涉及门店数量最多，为 19 家；北京、深圳、广州分别关闭 10、8、5 家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hangzhou, Wuhan, and Changsha each have 4 stores; Chengdu, Foshan, Kunming, and Suzhou each have 3 stores, totaling approximately 66 stores in these cities. Additionally, cities such as Dongguan, Guiyang, and Hefei are also on the list, with 1-2 stores closed per city, totaling approximately 36 stores.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            杭州、武汉、长沙各 4 家，成都、佛山、昆明、苏州各 3 家，上述城市合计约 66 家门店。此外，东莞、贵阳、合肥等城市亦在名单中，单城关闭 1—2 家不等，总计约 36 家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some stores have confirmed their closure to the media, for example, the Shanghai Baoshan Wanda store explicitly stated it would cease operations soon. However, other stores claim to be still in the negotiation phase, such as the Shanghai Zijing Plaza store, which stated it is communicating about early rent reduction and has not yet received a closure notice.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分门店已向媒体确认闭店，例如上海宝山万达店明确表示即将停止营业。但也有门店称仍在谈判阶段，例如上海紫荆广场店表示正在就提前降租进行沟通，尚未收到闭店通知。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to previous reports by &quot;LatePost,&quot; Xibei had approximately 370 stores around the time of the public opinion crisis in September last year, with a net closure of about a dozen stores by year-end. The original plan was to eliminate 50-60 loss-making stores around the Lunar New Year, but the leaked figure of 102 closures is almost double that.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《晚点 LatePost》此前报道，西贝在去年 9 月舆论危机前后拥有约 370 家门店，年底净关店数约十几家。原计划在春节前后淘汰 50—60 家亏损门店，而此次流出的 102 家闭店数字几乎翻倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            If fully implemented, Xibei's national stores will be reduced to approximately 268.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            若全部执行，西贝全国门店将减少至约 268 家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            High rent and labor costs are the main sources of pressure currently faced by Xibei. In the closure list, the recommendation for many stores is &quot;negotiate rent reduction, close if not successful,&quot; and some city stores are in a state of overall transfer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高昂的租金与人力成本是西贝当前面临的主要压力来源。闭店清单中，多家门店的建议为「谈降租，降不下来就闭店」，部分城市门店处于整体转让状态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xibei previously stated that customer traffic significantly declined after the September incident last year, but with continuous menu adjustments and promotional activities, traffic began to recover from late September. In October, traffic was higher than in previous years due to coupon promotions, and after promotions ended in November, traffic was basically on par with the same period last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            西贝方面曾表示，去年 9 月事件后客流明显下滑，但在持续调改菜品与优惠活动推动下，客流自 9 月下旬开始回升，10 月因赠券活动客流高于往年，11 月优惠停止后客流与去年同期基本持平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hongcan Industry Research Institute predicts that the average lifespan of catering stores last year may have dropped to around 15 months. Wang Puzhong, CEO of Meituan's core local commerce, stated that the average per-table spending for dine-in customers this year is close to 2015 levels, meaning the industry's profit margins are further compressed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            红餐产业研究院预计，去年餐饮门店平均存续周期或降至 15 个月左右。美团核心本地商业 CEO 王莆中表示，今年堂食客单价已接近 2015 年水平，意味着行业利润空间被进一步压缩。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xibei adjusted its brand positioning from Northwestern cuisine to &quot;Family Fun Restaurant&quot; at the end of 2024, but the impact of public opinion incidents on brand image, coupled with rising costs, has made its operations more cautious.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            西贝在 2024 年底将品牌定位从西北菜调整为「家庭欢乐餐厅」，但舆论事件对品牌形象的冲击叠加成本上升，使其经营更趋谨慎。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>萝卜快跑低调在全国落地近 20 城，广东就占 1/4</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">萝卜快跑低调在全国落地近-20-城，广东就占-1/4</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3d092988-faeb-44be-9e58-c4d350157c3d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to LanJing Auto, Baidu's autonomous driving mobility service &quot;Apollo Go&quot; (Luobo Kuaipao) is currently operating or conducting demonstration projects in approximately 20 cities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据蓝鲸汽车报道，百度旗下自动驾驶出行服务「萝卜快跑」当前已在约 20 座城市开展运营或示范项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report cites multiple filing records stating that Apollo Go's deployment in Guangdong is particularly dense, covering Guangzhou, Foshan, Dongguan, Shenzhen, Jiangmen, and other areas, with the total investment in related projects exceeding 100 million yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道援引多项备案信息称，萝卜快跑在广东的布局尤为密集，已覆盖广州、佛山、东莞、深圳、江门等地，相关项目投资总额超过亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since late November last year, Apollo Go has filed for intelligent connected vehicle road testing and demonstration application projects in multiple locations in Guangdong:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年 11 月下旬以来，萝卜快跑在广东多地通过智能网联汽车道路测试与示范应用项目备案：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jiangmen project has a total investment of 50 million yuan and plans to deploy no less than 90 intelligent connected vehicles;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dongguan project has a total investment of 70 million yuan and plans to purchase 1,000 autonomous driving vehicles, as well as build an autonomous driving base, including an intelligent connected monitoring and command center and a Greater Bay Area &quot;Cloud Car&quot; center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, the LuobokuaiPao South China Operations Headquarters project has completed registration in Shunde, Foshan, with a total investment of approximately 18 million yuan. It plans to build facilities such as research and study areas, exhibition halls, 5G cloud warehouses, office areas, and operation and maintenance workshops, aiming to create a demonstration headquarters for unmanned ride-hailing services relying on intelligent algorithms and vehicle-road coordination technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，萝卜快跑华南运营总部项目已在佛山顺德完成备案，项目总投资约 1800 万元，规划建设研学、展厅、5G 云仓、办公区及运维车间等设施，旨在打造依托智能算法与车路协同技术的无人驾驶网约车示范总部。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that the Greater Bay Area has become an important hub for Robotaxi companies. Headquarters of companies like WeRide, Pony.ai, and Ruqi Mobility are all located in Guangdong, and Didi Autonomous Driving also announced the launch of all-day, fully unmanned passenger tests in some areas of Guangzhou at the end of last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，大湾区已成为 Robotaxi 企业的重要集聚地。文远知行、小马智行、如祺出行等企业总部均位于广东，滴滴自动驾驶也在去年底宣布在广州部分区域开启全天候、全无人载客测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ruqi Mobility stated that as of the end of last December, its Robotaxi service had covered Nansha in Guangzhou, Bao'an and Nanshan in Shenzhen, and the Guangdong-Macao In-depth Cooperation Zone in Hengqin.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            如祺出行方面表示，截至去年 12 月底，其 Robotaxi 服务已覆盖广州南沙、深圳宝安与南山，以及横琴粤澳深度合作区。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Industry competition is shifting from &quot;verifying technical feasibility&quot; to &quot;large-scale commercial implementation.&quot; Jiang Hua, CEO of Ruqi Mobility, previously pointed out that whether large-scale operations can be achieved will determine if companies can remain in the race.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            行业竞争正从「验证技术可行性」转向「规模化商业落地」。如祺出行 CEO 蒋华此前指出，能否实现规模化运营，将决定企业能否继续留在赛道中。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Pony.ai, on the other hand, stated that its goal this year is to increase the Robotaxi fleet size to 3,000 vehicles, emphasizing that network effects will be key to future growth.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小马智行方面则提出，今年目标是将 Robotaxi 车队规模提升至 3000 辆，并强调网络效应将成为未来增长关键。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the global market, WeRide has entered more than 10 core cities and achieved fully unmanned commercial operations in Guangzhou, Beijing, and Abu Dhabi, with the Abu Dhabi fleet soon to achieve single-vehicle break-even.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在全球市场，文远知行已进入 10 余座核心城市，并在广州、北京及阿布扎比实现纯无人商业化运营，阿布扎比车队即将实现单车盈亏平衡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Multiple financial reports last year indicated that Baidu would accelerate the global expansion of LuobokuaiPao. According to its Q3 2025 financial report, LuobokuaiPao's fully unmanned autonomous driving operational orders reached 3.1 million, a year-on-year increase of 212%; in October 2025, its weekly average fully unmanned order volume exceeded 250,000.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年多份财报均显示百度将加速萝卜快跑的全球扩张。根据其 2025 年第三季度财报，萝卜快跑全无人自动驾驶营运订单达到 310 万单，同比增长 212%；2025 年 10 月，其每周平均全无人订单量超过 25 万单。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>清华姚班陈立杰加盟 OpenAI，16 岁保送清华，30 岁拿下 UC 伯克利助理教授</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">清华姚班陈立杰加盟-OpenAI，16-岁保送清华，30-岁拿下-UC-伯克利助理教授</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7b553e05-365b-451e-91ae-d4b872e46150.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to &quot;Qubit&quot; reports, Chen Lijie, a renowned alumnus of Tsinghua's &quot;Yao Class&quot; and an Assistant Professor at UC Berkeley EECS, has confirmed joining OpenAI to lead research in mathematical reasoning. This news comes from &quot;Top Chinese Community&quot; channels and has been confirmed internally by OpenAI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据「量子位」报道，清华「姚班」知名校友、UC Berkeley EECS 助理教授陈立杰已确认加入 OpenAI，负责数学推理方向研究。该消息来自「Top 华人社」渠道，且 OpenAI 内部已确认。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Insiders revealed that Chen Lijie has joined OpenAI as a full-time researcher. Meanwhile, his current status at Berkeley is On Leave (sabbatical without pay), meaning he has retained his university faculty position and has not resigned.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士透露，陈立杰此次是以全职身份加入 OpenAI 开展研究工作。与此同时，他目前在伯克利的状态为 On Leave（停薪留职），即他保留了在大学的教职，并未离职。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chen Lijie was born in 1995. At the age of 16, he won a gold medal in the National Olympiad in Informatics and was admitted to Tsinghua University without examination, making him one of the most representative young scholars of the Yao Class.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            陈立杰出生于 1995 年，16 岁获得全国信息学奥赛金牌并保送清华大学，是姚班最具代表性的青年学者之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During his undergraduate studies, he published multiple papers at important conferences such as AAAI, AAMAS, COLT, and CCC, and in 2017, he became the first Chinese undergraduate to publish a paper at FOCS.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本科期间，他在 AAAI、AAMAS、COLT、CCC 等重要会议发表多篇论文，并在 2017 年成为首位在 FOCS 发表论文的中国本科生。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, he pursued his Ph.D. at MIT, focusing his research on computational complexity theory and fine-grained complexity theory, and repeatedly won Best Student Paper awards at STOC and FOCS.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后，他赴 MIT 攻读博士，研究方向集中于计算复杂性理论与细粒度复杂度理论，并多次获得 STOC、FOCS 最佳学生论文奖。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After graduating with his Ph.D. in 2022, he joined the UC Berkeley Miller Institute as a postdoctoral researcher, with collaborators including Umesh V. Vazirani, a pioneer in quantum computing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2022 年博士毕业后，他加入 UC Berkeley Miller 研究所担任博士后研究员，合作导师包括量子计算奠基人 Umesh V. Vazirani。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last year, he officially became an Assistant Professor at UC Berkeley EECS and taught the graduate course &quot;Computational Complexity Theory.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年，他正式成为 UC Berkeley EECS 助理教授，并主讲研究生课程《Computational Complexity Theory》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of research direction, Chen Lijie has long focused on core problems in theoretical computer science such as P vs. NP, circuit complexity, derandomization, and algorithmic lower bounds, making systematic contributions in areas like Hardness Magnification. He has also introduced complexity theory methods into cutting-edge fields such as quantum physics and AI safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在研究方向上，陈立杰长期聚焦 P 与 NP、电路复杂性、去随机化、算法下界等理论计算机科学核心问题，并在复杂性难度放大（Hardness Magnification）等方向做出系统性贡献。他也将复杂性理论方法引入量子物理与 AI 安全等前沿领域。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that OpenAI's paper &quot;Why Language Models Hallucinate,&quot; published last September, cited another study co-authored by Chen Lijie: &quot;Why and How Large Language Models Hallucinate: A Mechanism Analysis Based on Subsequence Association.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，OpenAI 去年 9 月发表的论文《为什么语言模型会产生幻觉》引用了陈立杰参与的另一篇研究《大型语言模型为何以及如何产生幻觉：基于子序列关联的机制解析》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, he has also participated in research related to Diffusion Language Models, closely following the latest evolutionary trends in generative models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近期，他也参与扩散语言模型（Diffusion Language Models）相关研究，紧贴生成式模型的最新演进趋势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Chen Lijie's personal homepage has not yet been updated with information about joining OpenAI. He maintains a low profile on multiple platforms, only showcasing his latest research papers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，陈立杰的个人主页尚未更新加入 OpenAI 的信息。他在多个平台仍保持低调，仅展示最新论文成果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 前高管新公司「痛失」两名核心成员，回归 OpenAI</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-前高管新公司「痛失」两名核心成员，回归-OpenAI</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0f024e2a-1ee7-41b3-bc50-e7dc17ba1c77.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to TechCrunch, two co-founders of &quot;Thinking Machines Lab,&quot; a startup founded by former OpenAI executive Mira Murati, have successively resigned and will return to OpenAI, with several other core members also having departed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 TechCrunch报道，前 OpenAI 高管米拉・穆拉蒂（Mira Murati）创办的初创公司「思维机器实验室」（Thinking Machines Lab）两位联合创始人相继离职，并将重返 OpenAI，另有多名核心成员亦已离队。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Murati announced on social media on Wednesday local time that the company's co-founder and CTO, Barret Zoph, has resigned and Soumith Chintala will take over as CTO.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            穆拉蒂于当地时间周三在社交媒体上宣布，公司联合创始人兼首席技术官巴雷特・佐夫（Barret Zoph）已离职，并由索密斯・钦塔拉（Soumith Chintala）接任 CTO 职位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            She stated on X that Chintala has been deeply involved in the field of artificial intelligence for over a decade and is a crucial technical pillar of the team.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            她在 X 上表示，钦塔拉在人工智能领域深耕十余年，是团队的重要技术支柱。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, Murati's statement did not mention other departing personnel. Just 58 minutes after her announcement, Fidji Simo, CEO of OpenAI's consumer business, announced on the X platform that Zoph, Luke Metz, and Sam Schoenholz would return to OpenAI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，穆拉蒂的声明并未提及其他离职人员。就在她发布消息的 58 分钟后，OpenAI 应用业务 CEO 菲吉・西莫（Fidji Simo）在 X 平台宣布，佐夫、卢克・梅茨（Luke Metz）及山姆・舍恩霍尔茨（Sam Schoenholz）三人将回归 OpenAI。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Metz was also a co-founder of Thinking Machines Lab, and all three had worked at OpenAI for many years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            梅茨同为思维机器实验室联合创始人，三人均曾在 OpenAI 任职多年。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public records show that Zoph previously served as OpenAI's VP of Research and, before that, as a research scientist at Google. After Murati stepped down as OpenAI CTO in September 2024, she co-founded Thinking Machines Lab with Zoph and Metz, taking on the role of CEO.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开资料显示，佐夫曾任 OpenAI 研究副总裁，更早前在 Google 担任研究科学家。穆拉蒂于 2024 年 9 月卸任 OpenAI CTO 后，与佐夫、梅茨共同创立思维机器实验室，并出任 CEO。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since its inception, the company has raised substantial funding: in July 2024, it completed a $2 billion seed round, valuing it at $12 billion, with investors including Andreessen Horowitz, Accel, Nvidia, AMD, and Jane Street Capital, among others.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该公司自成立以来融资规模巨大：2024 年 7 月完成 20 亿美元种子轮融资，估值达 120 亿美元，投资方包括安德森・霍洛维茨基金、Accel、英伟达、AMD 及简街资本等。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wired magazine reported that Zoph's departure from Thinking Machines Lab was not amicable. Murati's minimal mention of his resignation in her public statement is also seen as a sign of strained relations between the two parties.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《连线》杂志报道称，佐夫与思维机器实验室的分手并不愉快。穆拉蒂在公开声明中对其离职着墨甚少，也被视为双方关系紧张的迹象。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            While talent mobility among Silicon Valley AI giants is common, it is still rare for a startup less than a year old to experience a mass departure of co-founders.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管硅谷 AI 巨头之间的人才流动已属常态，但一家成立不足一年的初创公司遭遇联合创始人集体出走仍属罕见。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Thinking Machines Lab had previously assembled a star research team from OpenAI, Meta, and Mistral AI. The simultaneous departure of the CTO and co-founders is widely seen as a significant blow to the company's strategic progress.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            思维机器实验室此前集结了来自 OpenAI、Meta 与 Mistral AI 的明星研究团队，而 CTO 与联合创始人同时离职，被外界普遍视为对公司战略推进的重大打击。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to Zoph and Metz, another co-founder of the company, Andrew Tulloch, moved to Meta in October 2024.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除佐夫与梅茨外，公司另一位联合创始人安德鲁・塔洛克（Andrew Tulloch）已于 2024 年 10 月跳槽至 Meta。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 Related Reading:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/taPTTeKp6q9z_tpP-XAIKw&quot;&gt;
             GPT-4 Tech Veteran Allegedly Fired for Leaking Secrets, OpenAI Startup &quot;Dream Team&quot; Plays &quot;Infernal Affairs&quot;
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 相关阅读：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/taPTTeKp6q9z_tpP-XAIKw&quot;&gt;
             GPT-4 技术功臣疑似泄密被开除，OpenAI 系创业天团上演「无间道」
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>李斌新年内部讲话：蔚来成立人工智能技术委员会，押注 2026 全链路 AI 落地</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">李斌新年内部讲话：蔚来成立人工智能技术委员会，押注-2026-全链路-AI-落地</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Leifeng.com, William Li, founder, chairman, and CEO of Nio, explicitly stated at an internal company meeting on January 14th that Nio will significantly increase its investment in artificial intelligence in 2026 and promote the implementation of AI across its entire business chain to enhance overall operational efficiency and product competitiveness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据雷峰网报道，蔚来创始人、董事长兼 CEO 李斌于 1 月 14 日在公司内部会议上明确提出，将在 2026 年全面加大人工智能投入，并推动 AI 在全业务链落地，以提升整体经营效率与产品竞争力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the meeting, Li Bin systematically reviewed the operating performance of 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            李斌在会上系统复盘了 2025 年的经营表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that Nio has moved from a Q1 loss to potential profitability in Q4, with a significant improvement in overall operational quality for the year. Driven by models like the Ledao L90 and the new ES8, Nio's sales performance was stable in the second half of the year, and the mass-market Firefly series also exceeded internal expectations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，蔚来已从 Q1 的亏损走向 Q4 的潜在盈利，全年经营质量明显改善。在乐道 L90、全新 ES8 等车型带动下，蔚来下半年销量表现稳健，面向大众市场的 firefly 萤火虫系列也超出内部预期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the Nio, Ledao, and Firefly three-brand system gradually takes shape, coupled with channel penetration and overseas market expansion, he has set a target of maintaining an annual growth rate of approximately 40%-50% for the next 3-5 years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着蔚来、乐道、firefly 三品牌体系逐步成型，叠加渠道下沉与海外市场拓展，他将未来 3-5 年的目标定为每年保持约 40%-50% 的增速。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the technology and product level, Li Bin particularly emphasized the strategic importance of AI. He revealed that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Nio internally announced the establishment of the &quot;Artificial General Intelligence Committee&quot; (AGI Committee) on January 5th
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , with its first batch of members comprising approximately 30 AI technical experts from 15 first-level departments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在技术与产品层面，李斌特别强调 AI 的战略地位。他透露，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             蔚来已于 1 月 5 日内部宣布成立「人工智能技术委员会」（AGI Committee）
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，首批成员来自 15 个一级部门、约 30 名 AI 技术专家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The committee will undertake three core tasks:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该委员会将承担三项核心任务：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To gain insight into industry AI technology trends and provide references for the company's medium-to-long-term technology roadmap;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build a company-wide AI capability map, identifying key capabilities from infrastructure to business applications;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operate a company-wide AI technology and talent community, promoting experience reuse and cross-departmental collaboration, avoiding &quot;fighting alone&quot; style redundant investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Bin pointed out that Nio will focus its investment on two major directions in 2026:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            李斌指出，蔚来将在 2026 年重点投入两大方向：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full-stack R&amp;amp;D for intelligent driving, including key technology modules such as self-developed chips, operating systems, and world models, and plans to regain its position in the industry's first tier for core capabilities like high-speed navigation assisted driving, urban commuting scenarios, and parking through three major version updates within the year;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Promote the implementation of AI across the entire business chain, enhancing collaborative efficiency in R&amp;amp;D, manufacturing, supply chain, sales, and service links through data-driven process restructuring and tool platform development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that if AI can improve efficiency by 3% in each link, the cumulative effect will lead to a company-wide efficiency increase far exceeding this figure, making AI Nio's &quot;infrastructure&quot; for future operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，如果 AI 能让每个环节提效 3%，叠加效应将使全公司效率提升远超这一数字，AI 将成为蔚来未来经营的「基础设施」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the operational level, Li Bin proposed three major goals for 2026: maintaining robust growth of 40%-50%, increasing gross profit margins for vehicle and non-vehicle businesses, and strictly controlling sales and administrative expenses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在经营层面，李斌提出 2026 年的三大目标：保持 40%-50% 的稳健增长、提升整车与非车业务毛利率，以及严格控制销售管理费用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that non-vehicle businesses (including NIO Life, car mall, and external technology and service collaborations) are expected to achieve annual revenue exceeding 10 billion yuan, becoming a crucial growth driver supporting the company's profit structure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，非车业务（包括 NIO Life、车商城及对外技术与服务合作）全年收入有望突破 100 亿元，成为支撑公司盈利结构的重要增长点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Discussing the market competition environment, Li Bin pointed out that the current Chinese new energy vehicle market is intensely competitive, with price wars and an &quot;arms race&quot; in intelligence occurring simultaneously, and the industry has entered a stage of &quot;dual competition in efficiency and technology.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            谈及市场竞争环境时，李斌指出，当前中国新能源汽车市场竞争激烈，价格战与智能化「军备竞赛」并行，行业进入「效率与技术双重比拼」阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In his view, Nio's market share in China is still less than 2%, implying at least 5 times more room for growth, but this also places higher demands on organizational execution and technological investment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在他看来，蔚来在中国市场份额仍不足 2%，意味着至少还有 5 倍以上的成长空间，但这也对组织执行力与技术投入提出更高要求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that the biggest challenge in 2026 is not the market or products, but mindset. The team needs to maintain the resilience of &quot;building strong fortresses, fighting protracted battles, making steady progress, and achieving long-term success,&quot; truly embedding AI capabilities as the organization's long-term competitiveness, rather than short-term &quot;fad&quot; projects.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，2026 年最大的挑战不是市场或产品，而是心态，团队需要继续保持「结硬寨、打呆仗、日拱一卒、久久为功」的韧性，将 AI 能力真正沉淀为组织的长期竞争力，而不是短期「风口」式的项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of internal management and organizational culture, Li Bin requested management to embrace AI with a more open attitude, viewing it as a &quot;workbench for everyone&quot; rather than an exclusive tool for a few technical teams.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在内部管理与组织文化方面，李斌要求管理层以更开放的姿态拥抱 AI，将其视作「每个人都要用的工作台」，而非少数技术团队的专属工具。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He encouraged frontline teams to proactively propose business scenario requirements, with the &quot;Artificial Intelligence Technology Committee&quot; taking the lead, collaborating with various departments to co-create solutions, and accelerating implementation through pilot projects, review, and promotion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他鼓励一线团队主动提出业务场景需求，由「人工智能技术委员会」牵头，联合各部门共建解决方案，并通过试点—复盘—推广的方式加速落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also reminded that AI projects should adhere to long-termism, avoiding the pursuit of only short-term visible &quot;show-off&quot; effects while neglecting substantial improvements to core business indicators.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他同时提醒，AI 项目要坚持长期主义，避免只追求短期可见的「炫技」效果，而忽视对核心业务指标的实质改善。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>顺丰与星动纪元达成合作，具身智能将加速进入仓储与中转环节</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">顺丰与星动纪元达成合作，具身智能将加速进入仓储与中转环节</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8e34f093-536c-4328-aa91-d21cb69a1fc1.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to NetEase Tech, embodied AI company Xingdong Jiyuan and SF Technology officially signed a cooperation agreement yesterday. The two parties will jointly promote the R&amp;amp;D and large-scale implementation of embodied intelligent robot technology in logistics scenarios such as express delivery and warehousing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据网易科技报道，具身智能公司星动纪元与顺丰科技于昨天正式签署合作协议，双方将围绕快递、仓储等物流场景，共同推进具身智能机器人技术的研发与规模化落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            SF Technology has long-term technological accumulation in the field of logistics technology, while Xingdong Jiyuan's self-developed end-to-end VLA embodied model ERA‑42, bipedal humanoid robot Xingdong L7, and torso module M7, among other products, have formed embodied intelligent warehousing and logistics solutions covering links such as sorting, scanning, and feeding.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            顺丰科技在物流科技领域具备长期技术积累，而星动纪元自研的端到端 VLA 具身模型 ERA‑42、双足人形机器人星动 L7 及半身模块 M7 等产品，已形成覆盖分拣、扫码、供件等环节的具身智能仓储物流解决方案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Both parties plan to address common issues in the logistics industry, such as labor shortages and insufficient flexibility of traditional automation, through joint development and implementation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            双方计划通过联合开发与落地推广的方式，解决物流行业普遍面临的人力短缺与传统自动化柔性不足等问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the cooperation plan, embodied intelligent robots will first be piloted in warehousing and express transit links, and gradually expanded to broader business processes such as delivery and verification, to improve operational efficiency and quality. Both parties also stated that they will jointly promote the formulation of industry standards for embodied intelligent robots in the logistics sector.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据合作规划，具身智能机器人将率先在仓储、快递中转等环节进行试点应用，并逐步扩展至配送、核验等更广泛的业务流程，以提升作业效率与质量。双方还表示，将共同推动具身智能机器人在物流领域的行业标准制定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the company's official website, Beijing Xingdong Jiyuan Technology Co., Ltd. was established in 2023, incubated by Tsinghua University's Institute for Interdisciplinary Information Sciences, and is the only humanoid robot company in which Tsinghua University holds shares. Founder Chen Jianyu is a doctoral supervisor and assistant professor at Tsinghua University.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司官网资料显示，北京星动纪元科技有限公司成立于 2023 年，由清华大学交叉信息研究院孵化，也是唯一一家清华大学占股的人形机器人企业。创始人陈建宇是清华大学博士生导师、助理教授。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>游戏主机三巨头任天堂、索尼与微软联合更新「更安全游戏」原则</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">游戏主机三巨头任天堂、索尼与微软联合更新「更安全游戏」原则</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9d0805ae-e84b-46ea-81a9-2fe5748502a1.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Nintendo, Sony, and Microsoft jointly announced an update to their &quot;Safer Gaming&quot; joint principles, first released in 2020. They emphasized that the three parties will continue to strengthen the player safety system in three major areas: prevention, partnership, and responsibility, with a particular focus on protecting underage players.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，任天堂、索尼与微软共同发文宣布，更新了自 2020 年首次发布的「更安全游戏」联合原则，强调三方将在预防、伙伴关系与责任三大方向持续强化玩家安全体系，尤其聚焦未成年玩家的保护。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The three parties reiterated in their statement that &quot;gaming is for everyone&quot; and stated that as technology evolves and the industry's regulatory environment changes, safety strategies also need to be upgraded accordingly. The three core directions include:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            三方在声明中重申「游戏属于每个人」，并表示随着技术演进及行业监管环境变化，安全策略也需同步升级。三大核心方向包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prevention : Provide players and parents with easier-to-understand and easier-to-operate safety control tools, including game experience customization, parental supervision settings, code of conduct notification, and violation handling mechanisms. All three companies pointed out that safety features must be &quot;easy to use and transparent,&quot; and promised to continuously strengthen relevant guidelines on platforms, customer service channels, official websites, and retail ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partnership : The three parties will continue to cooperate with industry organizations, regulatory bodies, law enforcement agencies, non-profit organizations, and research institutions to promote the establishment of online safety standards. Cooperation partners include Family Online Safety Institute, Thriving in Games Group, ESRB, PEGI, and Tech Coalition, among others. The three parties also stated that they will promote more forward-looking safety technologies through shared research and industry collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responsibility : The three companies committed to strengthening the violation reporting mechanism, improving processing efficiency, and taking measures such as content removal and account restrictions when necessary. The statement pointed out that the platforms will comply with local laws and promptly notify law enforcement agencies when illegal activities are discovered or players face urgent risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The three parties stated at the end of the declaration that they will continue to invite more industry partners to join in the future to jointly enhance the safety and well-being of global players.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            三方在声明结尾表示，未来将继续邀请更多行业伙伴加入，共同提升全球玩家的安全与福祉。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>监管介入后，Grok 宣布限制图像编辑能力</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">监管介入后，Grok-宣布限制图像编辑能力</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0073d4f4-1b9e-4bd9-8ec8-b6a6d0fc74c9.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from CNBC and Reuters, following the California Attorney General's announcement of an investigation, Elon Musk's xAI yesterday announced a further tightening of Grok's image generation capabilities on the social platform X, prohibiting all users from generating or editing sexually suggestive images based on real people, and limiting related features to paid subscribers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 CNBC 和路透社报道，继加州司法部长宣布介入调查后，马斯克旗下 xAI 于昨天宣布进一步收紧 Grok 在社交平台 X 上的图像生成功能，禁止所有用户基于真实人物生成或编辑带有性暗示的图像，并将相关功能限定为付费订阅者可用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            xAI issued a statement saying that it has deployed technical measures to prevent Grok from editing photos of &quot;real people in revealing clothing (such as bikinis),&quot; and this restriction applies to all users, including paid users.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            xAI 发布声明称，已部署技术措施阻止 Grok 对「真实人物穿着暴露服装（如比基尼）」的照片进行编辑，该限制适用于所有用户，包括付费用户。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, users could generate sexualized or violent images based on real people, including minors, through simple text prompts. Grok was therefore identified by multiple governments as a high-risk source of &quot;deepfake inappropriate content.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，用户可通过简单文本提示生成基于真实人物的性化或暴力图像，其中包括未成年人，Grok 因此被多国政府点名为「深度伪造不当内容」的高风险源头。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            California Attorney General Rob Bonta stated yesterday that his office has launched an investigation into xAI, focusing on its &quot;mass generation of non-consensual deepfake intimate images.&quot; California Governor Gavin Newsom also publicly criticized Grok's behavior of generating and disseminating content related to minors as &quot;egregious.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            加州总检察长 Rob Bonta 昨天表示，其办公室已对 xAI 展开调查，关注其「大规模生成未经同意的深度伪造亲密影像」的行为。加州州长 Gavin Newsom 亦公开批评称，Grok 生成并传播未成年人相关内容的行为「恶劣」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reuters pointed out that California officials have requested xAI to provide a clear rectification plan and emphasized that the spread of such content must be immediately stopped.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            路透社指出，加州官员已要求 xAI 提供明确整改方案，并强调必须立即阻止此类内容的扩散。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to the United States, regulatory bodies in multiple countries, including India, Malaysia, Indonesia, Ireland, the UK, France, and Australia, have recently launched investigations. Indonesia and Malaysia have already imposed temporary bans on Grok. The European Commission is also monitoring related risks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除美国外，印度、马来西亚、印尼、爱尔兰、英国、法国及澳大利亚等多国监管机构近期均已启动调查，其中印尼与马来西亚已对 Grok 实施临时封禁。欧洲委员会也在关注相关风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Before public pressure escalated, Musk had encouraged users on X to &quot;challenge Grok's image moderation&quot; and claimed that in NSFW mode, Grok could generate &quot;fictional adult characters with bare torsos,&quot; but not involving real people.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在舆论压力升高前，马斯克曾在 X 上鼓励用户「挑战 Grok 的图像审核」，并声称在 NSFW 模式下，Grok 可生成「虚构成年角色的上半身裸露图像」，但不得涉及真实人物。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also stated that content restrictions in different regions would be adjusted according to local laws.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他同时表示，不同地区的内容限制将依据当地法律调整。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reuters added that although X had restricted some users from publicly generating or editing images last week, Grok could still generate sexualized content on demand in private chats before xAI's new rules were released. Musk responded by saying he &quot;was unaware&quot; that images related to minors had been generated.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            路透社补充称，尽管 X 上周已限制部分用户公开生成或编辑图像，但在 xAI 发布新规前，Grok 仍可在私聊中按需生成性化内容。马斯克则回应称自己「并不知情」有未成年人相关图像被生成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Earlier, Apple and Google were also asked by US lawmakers to remove the X and Grok apps until the platforms could effectively prevent the generation of non-consensual sexualized content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            更早前，苹果与 Google 也被美国议员要求下架 X 与 Grok 应用，直至平台能有效阻止未经同意的性化内容生成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google 提交新电池专利，想让维修更简单</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Google-提交新电池专利，想让维修更简单</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1006a63b-7457-4e4e-97df-921f72cafacd.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Android Authority, Google recently filed a new battery design patent with the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO), aiming to make batteries in electronic devices such as mobile phones and tablets easier to remove and repair without sacrificing the device's slimness, water resistance, and wireless charging capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Android Authority 报道，Google 近日向美国专利商标局（USPTO）提交了一项新的电池设计专利，旨在在不牺牲设备轻薄、防水与无线充电能力的前提下，让手机、平板等电子设备的电池更易拆卸与维修。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The patent proposes replacing traditional strong adhesive fixing methods with a metal frame, achieving a balance between repairability and structural reliability through structural reinforcement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该专利提出以金属框架替代传统强力胶固定方式，通过结构强化实现可维修性与结构可靠性的平衡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Patent documents show that most current high-end devices, in order to maintain body sealing and slim design, generally use a large amount of glue to firmly adhere the battery inside the device, which makes it difficult and risky for users and repair centers to replace batteries.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            专利文件显示，当前多数高端设备为了保持机身密封性与纤薄设计，普遍采用大量胶水将电池牢固粘在机身内部，这使得用户与维修机构在更换电池时面临较高难度与风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the patent, Google proposes a new solution where the battery is placed in a removable metal sub-assembly and secured inside the device through mechanical structures such as &quot;shear stops,&quot; &quot;mechanical interlocks,&quot; and &quot;guided load paths.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Google 在专利中提出新的方案，将电池置于一个可拆卸的金属子组件中，并通过「shear stops」「mechanical interlocks」与「guided load paths」等机械结构将其固定在机身内部。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            These structures can disperse stress when the device is bent, twisted, or dropped, thereby protecting the battery itself.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这些结构可在设备弯折、扭转或跌落时分散应力，从而保护电池本体。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to traditional adhesive solutions, this design allows for easier and safer battery removal during repair, potentially reducing repair costs and electronic waste. At the same time, Google emphasizes in the patent that this structure will not affect the device's wireless charging, water and dust resistance, nor will it significantly increase the body thickness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比传统胶水方案，这种设计可在维修时更容易、安全地移除电池，有望降低维修成本并减少电子垃圾。同时，Google 在专利中强调，该结构不会影响设备的无线充电、防水防尘能力，也不会导致机身厚度明显增加。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Patent illustrations and descriptions also indicate that this design is not only suitable for conventional smartphones but may also extend to various product forms such as foldable devices, tablets, laptops, and wearable devices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            专利图示与描述还表明，这一设计不仅适用于常规智能手机，也可能扩展至折叠屏设备、平板电脑、笔记本电脑、可穿戴设备等多种产品形态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, the report also points out that patents do not represent mass production plans, and Google has had numerous patents in the past that did not reach the final product stage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，报道也指出，专利并不代表量产计划，Google 过往亦有大量专利未进入最终产品阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 汇丰分析师：2040 年全球智能眼镜市场价值将达 2000 亿美元</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-汇丰分析师：2040-年全球智能眼镜市场价值将达-2000-亿美元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/88a68a1f-d7db-4d8c-bb9c-bef2b52ca1a2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Bloomberg, HSBC Holdings' latest research report shows that the smart glasses market is entering an accelerated expansion phase, with the industry's long-term outlook significantly upgraded.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据彭博社报道，汇丰控股最新研报显示，智能眼镜市场正进入加速扩张阶段，行业长期前景被显著上调。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The analyst team raised the projected global smart glasses market size to $200 billion by 2040, a significant increase from previous forecasts, primarily based on the strong early market performance of the Ray-Ban Meta smart glasses, a collaboration between EssilorLuxottica and Meta.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析师团队将 2040 年全球智能眼镜市场规模预期提升至 2000 亿美元，较此前预测大幅增加，核心依据是依视路陆逊梯卡与 Meta 合作的 Ray-Ban Meta 智能眼镜在早期市场表现强劲。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            HSBC analyst Anne-Laure Bismuth pointed out that with intensifying competition, maturing ecosystems, and increased R&amp;amp;D investment, the smart glasses user base will experience explosive growth in the next decade or so.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            汇丰分析师安妮‑洛尔・比斯穆特指出，随着竞争加剧、生态成熟以及研发投入提升，智能眼镜用户规模将在未来十多年内迎来爆发式增长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report estimates that by the end of the 2030s, global smart glasses users will reach 289 million, an increase of more than 18 times compared to approximately 15 million users last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报告预计，到 2030 年代末，全球智能眼镜用户将达到 2.89 亿人，相比去年约 1500 万用户增长超过 18 倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Influenced by this assessment, HSBC upgraded EssilorLuxottica's stock to &quot;Buy&quot; after maintaining a &quot;Hold&quot; rating for nearly two years, with its share price rising by 2.9% at one point after the news was announced.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            受此判断影响，汇丰在维持近两年「持有」评级后，将依视路陆逊梯卡股票上调至「买入」，其股价消息公布后一度上涨 2.9%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Bloomberg reported that as Ray-Ban Meta sales continue to climb, EssilorLuxottica and Meta are evaluating doubling AI smart glasses production capacity as early as the end of this year to seize the demand window and suppress potential competitors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            彭博社称，随着 Ray-Ban Meta 销量持续攀升，依视路陆逊梯卡与 Meta 正评估最早于今年年底前将 AI 智能眼镜产能翻倍，以抢占需求窗口并压制潜在竞争者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            HSBC also favors Meta's strategic position in the smart glasses computing platform, believing it can deeply integrate its software and service advantages with high-end hardware. The report also expects Apple, Samsung, or Amazon to enter the smart glasses market between this year and next, further promoting the industry's scaled development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            汇丰同时看好 Meta 在智能眼镜计算平台中的战略地位，认为其可将软件与服务优势与高端硬件深度结合。报告还预计，苹果、三星或亚马逊有望在今年至明年进入智能眼镜赛道，进一步推动行业规模化发展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Analysts emphasize that the more sufficient the competition, the faster the market is likely to grow, attracting more R&amp;amp;D resources and ultimately benefiting all participants.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析师强调，竞争越充分，市场越可能快速做大，并吸引更多研发资源，最终让所有参与者受益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2399 元起，iQOO Z11 Turbo 正式发布</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2399-元起，iQOO-Z11-Turbo-正式发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/60f4930e-0ecc-4027-ae07-56e2cc7f85ce.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, iQOO officially released the Z11 Turbo phone, positioned as a mid-range all-rounder, focusing on a balanced experience of performance, battery life, and texture, available in four colors: &quot;Canglang Fuguang&quot; (Wave Light), &quot;Guangyun Fen&quot; (Halo Pink), &quot;Tianguang Bai&quot; (Sky White), and &quot;Jiye Hei&quot; (Polar Night Black).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，iQOO 正式发布 Z11 Turbo 手机，定位中端全能机型，主打性能、续航与质感的均衡体验，提供「沧浪浮光」「光晕粉」「天光白」「极夜黑」四种配色。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Specific configuration parameters are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            具体配置参数如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Snapdragon 8 Gen5 platform + Gaming Core Q2, LPDDR5X Ultra + UFS4.1;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 6.59-inch 1.5K 144Hz LTPS OLED screen, with an instantaneous touch sampling rate of 3200Hz and a global peak brightness of 1800nits;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;200MP 1/1.56-inch f/1.88 main camera + 32MP 0.8x f/2.2 front camera + 8MP f/2.2 ultra-wide angle;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in 7600mAh battery, supports 100W wired charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body material is metal frame + glass back cover, supports IP68 / IP69 dust and water resistance, 7.9mm thick, 202g weight;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing, the iQOO Z11 Turbo's initial sale price from January 15th to 21st starts at 2399 yuan (12GB + 256GB), with the top-end 16GB + 1TB model priced at 3699 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，iQOO Z11 Turbo 1 月 15 日至 21 日首销售价 2399 元起（12GB + 256GB），顶配 16GB + 1TB 售价 3699 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3099 元起，大疆发布 RS 5 稳定器 强化智能跟拍体验</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3099-元起，大疆发布-RS-5-稳定器-强化智能跟拍体验</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8367bbae-ad9d-4308-b882-80aa9c514e12.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, DJI officially released the lightweight commercial gimbal DJI RS 5, which for the first time supports direct tapping or boxing to select a follow target on the gimbal's touchscreen.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，DJI 大疆正式发布轻量商拍稳定器 DJI RS 5，首次支持在稳定器触控屏上直接点选或框选跟随目标。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The RS 5 can be paired with the new RS Enhanced Intelligent Tracking Module, extending the follow range to people, vehicles, pets, or any object. For tracking people, the recognition distance reaches 10 meters, and if a person briefly leaves the frame (within 2 seconds), they can be reacquired.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            RS 5 可搭配全新 RS 增强智能追踪模块，跟随范围扩展至人、车、宠物或任意物体。针对人物跟拍，识别距离达 10 米，若人物短暂离开画面（2 秒内）可重新找回。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of hardware, the DJI RS 5 body, along with the handle and quick release plate, weighs 1.46 kg, has a load capacity of 3 kg, and is equipped with a full fine-tuning knob and Teflon sandwich structure for quick leveling. The motor's peak torque has increased by 50%, and with the fifth-generation stabilization algorithm, stability in vertical shooting and sports scenes has been optimized.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            硬件方面，DJI RS 5 本体连同手柄及快装板重 1.46 千克，负载能力为 3 千克，配备全微调平旋钮与特氟龙夹层结构，便于快速调平。电机峰值扭矩提升 50%，配合第五代增稳算法，优化了竖拍和运动场景下的稳定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of battery life and control, the stabilizer's charging speed is 60% faster than its predecessor, fully charging in 1 hour, and the standard battery life is about 14 hours. A new Z-axis stability indicator has been added to the body to help users adjust their pace.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            续航与操控上，该稳定器充电速度较前代提升 60%，1 小时可充满，标配电池续航约 14 小时 。机身新增 Z 轴稳定指示器，辅助用户调整步伐。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the DJI RS 5 natively supports DJI Focus Pro motors and DJI SDR video transmission, and provides an RSA communication interface for compatibility with third-party accessories.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，DJI RS 5 原生支持 DJI Focus Pro 电机及 DJI SDR 图传，并提供 RSA 通信接口以兼容第三方配件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The standalone DJI RS 5 is priced at 3099 yuan, and the combo version is priced at 3899 yuan. Pre-orders are now open.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            DJI RS 5 单机售价 3099 元，套装版售价 3899 元，目前已开启预约。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REDMI Turbo 5 Max 将首发天玑 9500s</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">REDMI-Turbo-5-Max-将首发天玑-9500s</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/dbba0454-bdb9-4e37-8940-294362b2942e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, MediaTek officially released the Dimensity 9500s chip. Lu Weibing, Partner and President of Xiaomi Group, subsequently announced that the REDMI Turbo 5 Max will be the first to feature this chip, making its debut this month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，联发科正式发布天玑 9500s 芯片，小米集团合伙人、总裁卢伟冰随后官宣 REDMI Turbo 5 Max 将首发搭载该芯片，在本月亮相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, the Dimensity 9500s uses TSMC's N3E second-generation 3nm process. The CPU consists of 1 ultra-large 3.73GHz Cortex‑X925 core, 3 large Cortex‑X4 cores, and 4 Cortex‑A720 cores, with a total system cache of 29MB;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍， 天玑 9500s 采用台积电 N3E 第二代 3nm 工艺，CPU 由 1 颗 3.73GHz Cortex‑X925 超大核、3 颗 Cortex‑X4 大核及 4 颗 Cortex‑A720 组成，系统缓存总量达到 29MB；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The GPU is Immortalis‑G925 MC12. From an architectural and frequency perspective, this chip is similar to the previous Dimensity 9400+, but the official statement emphasizes further optimization in its AI engine and overall energy efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GPU 为 Immortalis‑G925 MC12。从架构与频率来看，该芯片与此前的天玑 9400+ 接近，但官方强调其在 AI 引擎与整体能效方面进行了进一步优化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi stated that the REDMI Turbo 5 Max's AnTuTu V11 comprehensive performance score exceeds 3.61 million, positioning it higher than the previous generation Pro models, and marking the first time the Turbo series features a mainstream Dimensity flagship chip.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米方面表示，REDMI Turbo 5 Max 的安兔兔 V11 综合性能跑分突破 361 万，定位高于上一代 Pro 机型，是 Turbo 系列首次搭载天玑正代旗舰芯片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to leaked online information, the core configurations of the Turbo 5 Max include:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据网传信息，Turbo 5 Max 的核心配置包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.9-inch 1.5K flat screen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9000mAh-class large battery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundred-watt fast charging&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasonic fingerprint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metal frame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full-level waterproofing capability&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>千问 App 上线 AI 购物功能，全面整合阿里生态</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">千问-App-上线-AI-购物功能，全面整合阿里生态</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d1e342f8-eb7e-4afe-8379-8789198368b8.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the Qianwen App officially launched over 400 'service functions,' including AI shopping, marking a complete transition from previous 'chat conversations' to the 'AI service era'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，千问 App 正式上线包括 AI 购物在内的 400 余项「办事功能」，从此前的「聊天对话」全面迈入「AI 办事时代」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Based on the deep integration of Qwen's most powerful model and Alibaba's ecosystem, the Qianwen App for the first time opens up AI shopping and lifestyle service capabilities to all users, such as ordering takeout, buying goods, booking flights, and reserving hotels.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            基于 Qwen 最强模型与阿里生态的深度整合，千问 App 首次向所有用户开放点外卖、买东西、订机票、订酒店等 AI 购物与生活服务能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This update to the Qianwen App covers multiple services including Taobao, Alipay, Taobao Flash Sale, Fliggy, and Amap, enabling intelligent processing across various scenarios from consumption and travel to government affairs:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            千问 App 此次更新覆盖淘宝、支付宝、淘宝闪购、飞猪、高德等多项业务，实现从消费、出行到政务的多场景智能办理：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the support of Taobao Flash Sale and Alipay AI Pay, users can complete 'AI food delivery' within the Qianwen chat interface, without needing to jump to another app;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After integrating with Taobao, Qianwen introduces the 'AI Shopping' function, which can automatically filter products based on demand and complete the ordering process;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on Gaode's street sweep list, Qianwen has launched &quot;AI Phone Call Restaurant Booking,&quot; which can automatically dial and complete reservations;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of government services, Qianwen is deeply integrated with Alipay, covering 50 public services such as visas, household registration, and housing provident funds, and provides direct access to application portals;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Fliggy, users can generate travel plans with a single sentence and automatically complete operations such as booking flights, hotels, and tickets;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newly added &quot;Task Assistant&quot; feature has started targeted invitation testing on both App and Web, capable of executing multi-step complex tasks such as application development, Office work, consulting and research, and daily life errands;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In learning scenarios, Qianwen has launched features such as &quot;Find Exam Papers,&quot; &quot;Explain Difficult Problems,&quot; and &quot;Practice Wrong Questions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Alibaba stated that these capabilities stem from Qianwen's technological breakthroughs in AI Coding, full-modal understanding, and ultra-long context processing, enabling it to build tools in real-time, understand complex tasks, and maintain execution continuity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            阿里方面表示，这些能力来自千问在 AI Coding、全模态理解与超长上下文处理上的技术突破，使其能够实时构建工具、理解复杂任务并保持执行连续性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12999 元，理光发布 GR IV Monochrome</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">12999-元，理光发布-GR-IV-Monochrome</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c34a4fe6-b222-4ebb-af2d-19c3b425953f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Ricoh announced the launch of the new &quot;RICOH GR IV Monochrome,&quot; priced at 12,999 yuan. Its overall specifications are largely consistent with the existing GR IV, with key differences focused on imaging style and body tuning direction:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，理光宣布推出全新「RICOH GR IV Monochrome」，售价为 12999 元，在整体规格上与现有 GR IV 基本保持一致，主要区别集中在成像风格与机身调校方向：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with an APS-C format monochrome-specific CMOS sensor, with an effective pixel count of 25.74 million;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in non-interchangeable equivalent 28mm lens, with a maximum aperture of f/2.8;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capable of recording up to 1080P 60fps video;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lens unit has a built-in red filter, which the official claims &quot;can achieve dramatic image expression&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exclusive &quot;grain-free&quot; and &quot;grainy&quot; image effects;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the electronic shutter, the shutter speed can be increased to a maximum of 1/16000 second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that Ricoh stated the electronic shutter function, with a maximum speed of 1/16000 second, will be &quot;released&quot; to GR IV models via a subsequent update.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，理光表示，最高 1/16000 秒的电子快门功能将通过后续更新「下放」至 GR IV 机型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iQOO 15 Ultra 获 3C 认证，支持 100W 快充</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">iQOO-15-Ultra-获-3C-认证，支持-100W-快充</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/250edfb4-c60c-400a-9da5-d0c456414357.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the iQOO 15 Ultra completed 3C certification, with model number &quot;V2546A.&quot; Positioned as this year's first &quot;Performance Ultra&quot; flagship, its core upgrades focus on heat dissipation and gaming experience, and it will officially debut before the Spring Festival. Online rumors and leaks are summarized below:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，iQOO 15 Ultra 完成 3C 认证，型号为「V2546A」，定位今年首款「性能 Ultra」旗舰，核心升级集中在散热与游戏体验，将于春节前正式亮相。网传爆料整理如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Qualcomm's fifth-generation Snapdragon 8 Extreme Edition and a self-developed Q3 e-sports chip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 6.85-inch 2K Samsung flat screen;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with an active cooling fan and gaming shoulder buttons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features an IMX882 3X periscope telephoto lens;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battery capacity exceeds 7000 mAh, supporting 100W wired flash charging and wireless charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>「明日达」覆盖全国，拼多多推出共享仓服务</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">「明日达」覆盖全国，拼多多推出共享仓服务</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3faec5d2-1348-45ad-a2a3-786b70b1d938.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Ebrun, Pinduoduo recently launched a shared warehouse and distribution service, further strengthening its capabilities in the logistics fulfillment process.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据亿邦动力报道，近日，拼多多推出共享仓仓配服务，进一步强化其在物流履约环节的能力布局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This service is jointly provided by Pinduoduo and large warehouse and distribution service providers, offering merchants an integrated 'warehousing + fulfillment' solution that covers the entire process of warehousing management, order fulfillment, and logistics delivery, enabling nationwide next-day/day-after-tomorrow delivery.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该服务由拼多多联合大型仓配服务商共同提供，面向商家提供「仓储 + 履约」一体化解决方案，覆盖仓储管理、订单履约、物流配送全流程，可实现全国范围的次日达 / 后天达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to the previous model, which relied on merchants' own warehouses and could only display 'next-day delivery' or 'day-after-tomorrow delivery' labels in surrounding areas, the shared warehouse system achieves nationwide coverage through multiple distributed warehouses, enabling more products to offer broader time-sensitive delivery commitments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比此前依赖商家自有仓库、仅能在周边区域展示「明天达」「后天达」标签的模式，共享仓体系通过多地分仓实现全国布点，使更多商品具备更广覆盖的时效承诺能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Products participating in the service will display 'next-day delivery,' 'day-after-tomorrow delivery,' or 'guaranteed delivery' labels in areas such as the homepage special zone, 10-billion-subsidy zone, product detail page, and pending payment page, and will receive traffic weighting to boost order conversion rates.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            参加服务的商品将在首页专区、百亿补贴专区、商品详情页、待支付页等位置展示「明天达」「后天达」「承诺送达」标识，并获得流量加权，提升下单转化率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding fulfillment responsibilities, the shared warehouse model provides merchants with stronger custodial assurance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在履约责任方面，共享仓模式为商家提供了更强的托管保障。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Fulfillment violations such as delayed shipment, false shipment, fraudulent shipment, delayed delivery, and false tracking are all borne by the shared warehouse service provider, and merchants are not held responsible; however, if merchants additionally promise earlier shipping deadlines in scenarios such as stores, product pages, or live streams, they must bear the relevant responsibilities themselves.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            延迟发货、虚假发货、欺诈发货、延迟送达、虚假轨迹等履约违规均由共享仓服务商承担，商家无需担责；但若商家在店铺、商品页面或直播等场景额外承诺更早发货时限，则需自行承担相关责任。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>麦当劳 CEO 预测 2026 年快餐新方向</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">麦当劳-CEO-预测-2026-年快餐新方向</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/55c853df-0986-4c6b-bcb0-4dee05283594.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, McDonald's CEO Chris Kempczinski recently posted three food trend predictions for this year on Instagram, stating that these trends will dominate the fast-food industry in 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道 ，麦当劳 CEO Chris Kempczinski 日前在 Instagram 上发布今年的三项食品趋势预测，称这些趋势将主导 2026 年的快餐行业。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that his predictions last year regarding protein, AI, and sauces have all come true, thus he is more confident in this year's judgments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，自己去年关于蛋白质、AI 与酱料的预测均已应验，因此对今年的判断更具信心。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Kempczinski pointed out that the most noteworthy trends this year include dietary fiber, sweet and spicy flavor combinations, and beverage innovation.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Kempczinski 指出，今年最值得关注的趋势包括膳食纤维、甜辣风味组合以及饮品创新。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated in the video that dietary fiber 'will be very popular' and mentioned the rising popularity of the 'fibermaxxing' diet trend over the past year. Nutritionists generally believe that increasing dietary fiber intake helps improve gut health, lower cholesterol, and reduce the risk of colon cancer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他在视频中表示，膳食纤维「会很火」，并提到过去一年流行的「fibermaxxing」饮食趋势持续升温。营养师普遍认为，增加膳食纤维摄入有助于改善肠道健康、降低胆固醇并减少结肠癌风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            PepsiCo CEO Ramon Laguarta also expressed a similar view in a Q3 earnings call last October, stating that 'fiber will be the next protein.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            百事可乐 CEO Ramon Laguarta 也曾在去年 10 月的财报电话会上提出类似观点，称「纤维将成为下一个蛋白质」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding flavor trends, Kempczinski believes that the combination of sweet and spicy will become mainstream this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在风味趋势方面，Kempczinski 认为甜辣结合将成为今年的主流。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In 2025, chain brands such as Chipotle, KFC, and Taco Bell have launched multiple hot honey dipping sauces, continuing his judgment from last year that 'sauces are more important than main dishes.' McDonald's also currently offers a sweet and spicy 'creamy chili sauce.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2025 年，Chipotle、肯德基与 Taco Bell 等连锁品牌已推出多款热蜂蜜蘸酱，延续了他去年关于「酱料比主菜更重要」的判断。麦当劳目前也提供甜辣风味的「奶油辣椒醬」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, he predicts that beverage innovation will explode this year. Over the past year, several fast-food brands have accelerated the launch of new beverages, even opening independent beverage sub-brands, such as Taco Bell's Live Más Café and Chick-fil-A's Daybright, which focus on coffee and fruit-flavored drinks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，他预计饮品创新将在今年迎来爆发。过去一年，多家快餐品牌加速推出新饮品，甚至开设独立饮品子品牌，例如 Taco Bell 的 Live Más Café 与 Chick-fil-A 的 Daybright，主打咖啡与水果风味饮品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He believes that Gen Z's reduced alcohol consumption and preference for novel non-alcoholic beverage combinations are important reasons driving this trend.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他认为，Z 世代减少饮酒、偏好新奇无酒精饮品组合，是推动这一趋势的重要原因。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>爱马仕悠悠球要价 18400 元，官方：部分地区卖断货</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">爱马仕悠悠球要价-18400-元，官方：部分地区卖断货</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ed7fa208-c4f0-4e5e-a784-b62eb8f7a2a2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, a Hermès yo-yo priced at 18,400 yuan recently garnered significant attention on social media, with many netizens questioning its pricing and even jokingly asking, 'Isn't this just a wheel taken from an unsold suitcase with a string attached?'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，近日，法国奢侈品牌爱马仕一款售价高达 18400 元的悠悠球在社交平台上受到大量关注，不少网友质疑其定价，甚至调侃称「这真不是卖不出的行李箱上拆下来的轮子加根绳吗」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to information on Hermès' mini-program page, this yo-yo comes with a Mysore goatskin storage box, with its design inspired by the metal axle wheels of R.M.S luggage; the handle features saddle stitching, it is made in France, and measures 4.5 cm in length and 3.5 cm in diameter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据爱马仕小程序页面信息，这款悠悠球配有 Mysore 山羊皮收纳盒，设计灵感来自 R.M.S 行李箱的金属轴滑轮；手柄采用马鞍针法缝线，产地为法国，长 4.5 厘米、直径 3.5 厘米。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hermès' official customer service told the media that the product is a recently launched new model, featuring leather and saddle stitching design, and the storage box material is natural and precious. Currently, online stock is very limited, with Shenzhen and Guangzhou regions already out of stock, and replenishment from France will occur irregularly in the future.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            爱马仕官方客服向媒体表示，该产品为近期推出的新款，采用皮革与马鞍针缝线设计，收纳盒材质天然且珍贵。目前线上库存极少，深圳、广州地区已断货，后续将不定时从法国补货。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The yo-yo is both a sport and considered a highly skillful hand art, with a history dating back to the 18th century, having been popular in both the UK and France. In contrast, mainstream yo-yos in China typically range from 9 to 150 yuan, with professional competition yo-yos priced around 138 yuan, made of ABS engineering plastic alloy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            悠悠球既是一项运动，也被视为技巧性极高的手上技艺项目，历史可追溯至 18 世纪，在英国与法国均曾流行。相比之下，国内主流悠悠球价格多在 9 元至 150 元之间，专业比赛用球售价约 138 元，材质为 ABS 工程塑料合金。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some consumers believe that as a top luxury brand, Hermès products possess unique design, craftsmanship, and materials, and their brand added value itself represents status and taste, thus the high price is not incomprehensible.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分消费者认为，作为顶奢品牌，爱马仕产品的设计、工艺与材质具有独特性，其品牌附加值本身即代表身份与品味，因此高价并非不可理解。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Hermès' stainless steel dog bowls, priced over 20,000 yuan, also sparked similar discussions.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             In late November last year, the brand launched two dog bowls on its official website, priced at 18,300 yuan (small) and 20,600 yuan (large) respectively, also attracting attention due to their price.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，爱马仕推出的售价超过 2 万元的不锈钢犬类餐碗也曾引发类似讨论。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             去年 11 月底，该品牌在官网上架两款犬类餐碗，定价分别为 18300 元（小号）与 20600 元（大号），同样因价格引起关注。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Financial report data shows that Hermès' sales in the third quarter of this year reached 3.9 billion euros, a year-on-year increase of 10% at constant exchange rates, outperforming some analysts' previous expectations, with improvements in the European, American, and Asian markets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财报数据显示，爱马仕今年第三季度销售额达 39 亿欧元，按固定汇率计算同比增长 10%，表现优于部分分析师此前预期，欧洲、美洲与亚洲市场均有所改善。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《极限审判》发布中国独家预告，1 月 23 日上映</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《极限审判》发布中国独家预告，1-月-23-日上映</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/86e1bf1b-c137-4df2-80d8-b5b1983907a7.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the suspense crime film 'The Extreme Trial' released its exclusive Chinese trailer, set to be released nationwide on January 23rd this year, with advance screenings held in 140 cities across the country on January 20th and 21st.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，悬疑犯罪影片《极限审判》发布中国独家预告，将在今年 1 月 23 日于全国上映、1 月 20 日与 21 日于全国 140 个城市举行提前观影活动。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The exclusive Chinese trailer released this time showcases the film's core narrative: Detective Raven is accused by AI of murdering his wife, and he must prove his innocence within 90 minutes, or face execution.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次发布的中国独家预告展示了影片核心叙事：警探雷文被 AI 指控杀害妻子，他需在 90 分钟内自证清白，否则将被处决。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the trailer, multiple pieces of evidence, including footprints at the scene, surveillance footage, and communication records, all point to Raven, but he insists on his innocence and uses the 'Sky Eye' system to search for evidence in reverse, attempting to find the real killer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            预告中，现场足迹、监控片段与通讯记录等多项证据均指向雷文，但他坚持无罪，并利用「天眼」系统反向搜证，试图找出真正的凶手。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film's narrative continues the multi-screen, multi-device perspective structure of 'Searching', and further expands to multi-source footage such as phone cameras, doorbell surveillance, drones, and GoPros, building a comprehensive information network and presenting a crime-solving model under a near-future surveillance system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片在叙事上延续《网络谜踪》的多屏幕、多设备视角结构，并进一步扩展至手机镜头、门铃监控、无人机与 GoPro 等多源画面，构建全方位信息网，呈现近未来监控体系下的破案模式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《庇护之地》定档 1 月 30 日</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《庇护之地》定档-1-月-30-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c4fe6bcb-e578-4f56-b497-e3d4ad6f24db.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The action thriller 'Shelter' is officially set to be released simultaneously with North America on January 30th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            动作惊悚片《庇护之地》（Shelter）正式定档 1 月 30 日同步北美上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of a mysterious man living in seclusion on a remote Scottish island. One day, he rescues a girl who drifts ashore from a storm, triggering a series of dangerous events. Ultimately, his home is also attacked, forcing him to confront his chaotic past.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片故事讲述一个神秘男人隐居在苏格兰的一座偏僻小岛上，某天他从风暴中的海上救起一个漂流到此的女孩，引发一系列危险事件，最终他的家也遭到袭击，迫使他不得不面对自己混乱的过去。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《熊出没 · 年年有熊》春节档上映</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 04:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《熊出没-·-年年有熊》春节档上映</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20250116_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/601bfebd-38ad-4790-a357-5c5eee427292.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the family-friendly animated film 'Boonie Bears: Bears Year After Year' released its official trailer and poster, announcing its release during the Spring Festival holiday.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，合家欢动画电影《熊出没 · 年年有熊》发布定档预告及海报，宣布将于春节档上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the film, Briar, Bramble, and Vick awaken mysterious powers and gain new elemental abilities: Bramble grows two horns, his strength surging like a mountain; Vick's fluffy long hair 'grows wild', surrounded by lightning; Briar's body shows golden patterns, but his abilities are yet to be revealed, with the suspense reserved for the main feature.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片中，熊大、熊二与光头强因神秘力量觉醒获得全新属性之力：熊二头生双角、力量翻涌成山；光头强蓬松长发「野蛮生长」，周身雷电环绕；熊大身上金色纹路浮现，但其能力仍未揭晓，悬念保留至正片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            'Boonie Bears: Bears Year After Year' is jointly produced by Fantawild Animation (Shenzhen) Co., Ltd. and several other organizations. The official statement indicates that this year's new work will continue to accompany audiences with its lighthearted, fantasy, and family-friendly positioning to welcome the New Year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《熊出没·年年有熊》由华强方特（深圳）动漫有限公司等多家机构联合出品。官方表示，今年新作将继续以轻松、奇幻与合家欢定位陪伴观众迎接新春。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
