<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>黄仁勋：下一代英伟达 AI 芯片已进入「全面生产」阶段</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">黄仁勋：下一代英伟达-AI-芯片已进入「全面生产」阶段</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d613dac1-3383-40c3-86cb-697bd280d04a.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Reuters, today, at the CES consumer electronics show held in Las Vegas, Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang announced in his keynote speech that the company's next-generation chip, named &quot;Rubin,&quot; has entered the &quot;full production&quot; phase.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据路透社报道，今天，于拉斯维加斯举办的 CES 消费电子展上，英伟达 CEO 黄仁勋在主题演讲上宣布，该公司下一代名为「Rubin」的芯片已进入「全面生产」阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jensen Huang revealed that the Rubin chip will be officially launched later this year. When running chatbots and other AI applications, the chip's AI computing performance is 5 times that of the previous generation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            黄仁勋透露，Rubin 芯片将于今年晚些时候正式推出。该芯片在运行聊天机器人及其他 AI 应用程序时，其 AI 计算性能是上一代产品的 5 倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The current Vera Rubin platform consists of 6 independent Nvidia chips, with the flagship device containing 72 graphics processing units (GPUs) and 36 new central processing units (CPUs). These chips can be connected to form clusters (Pods) containing over 1000 Rubin chips.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前的 Vera Rubin 平台由 6 款独立英伟达芯片组成，其中旗舰设备包含 72 个图形处理单元（GPU）和 36 个新型中央处理器（CPU）。这些芯片可连接成包含超过 1000 个 Rubin 芯片的集群（Pods）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Although the transistor count is only 1.6 times that of the previous generation, Nvidia has achieved a huge performance leap by adopting a proprietary data format. Nvidia executives confirmed to Reuters that these chips are currently in their labs and being tested by AI company clients.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管晶体管数量仅为前代的 1.6 倍，但通过采用一种专有的数据格式，英伟达实现了巨大的性能飞跃。英伟达高管向路透社证实，这些芯片目前已在其实验室中，由 AI 公司客户进行测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding technical details, Jensen Huang highlighted two key innovations:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在技术细节方面，黄仁勋重点介绍了两项关键创新：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context Memory Storage: Designed to help chatbots respond more quickly to long conversations initiated by millions of users simultaneously, improving concurrent processing capabilities;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-packaged Optics: A new generation of network switch technology, crucial for connecting thousands of machines, and will compete with similar products from Broadcom and Cisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the field of autonomous driving, Nvidia announced it would more broadly release software named &quot;Alpamayo&quot; and its training data. This software helps autonomous vehicles make path decisions and provides decision-making basis for engineers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在自动驾驶领域，英伟达宣布将更广泛地发布名为「Alpamayo」的软件及其训练数据。该软件能帮助自动驾驶汽车进行路径决策，并为工程师提供决策依据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jensen Huang stated: &quot;We not only open-source models, but also open-source the data used to train these models, because only then can you truly trust the source of the model.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            黄仁勋表示：「我们不仅开源模型，还开源用于训练这些模型的数据，因为只有这样，你才能真正信任模型的来源。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that while Nvidia still dominates the AI model training market, it is facing increasingly fierce competition in the inference end (delivering model results to end-users) from traditional rivals like AMD and customers like Google.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，虽然英伟达在 AI 模型训练市场仍占据主导地位，但在推理端（即将模型成果交付给终端用户）正面临来自 AMD 等传统竞争对手以及 Google 等客户日益激烈的竞争。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last December, Nvidia absorbed talent and chip technology from startup Groq, including executives who previously helped Google design AI chips, to counter the threat from Google, Meta, and other companies attempting to undermine Nvidia's dominance in AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年 12 月，英伟达吸收了初创公司 Groq 的人才和芯片技术，其中包括曾协助 Google 设计 AI 芯片的高管，以应对 Google 联合 Meta 等公司试图削弱英伟达 AI 统治地位的威胁。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蚂蚁、美团入局 AI 硬件， Looki 完成超 2000 万美元 A 轮融资</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蚂蚁、美团入局-AI-硬件，-Looki-完成超-2000-万美元-A-轮融资</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/04eed35e-5d12-4090-98c3-56f53d79c601.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Founder Park, AI hardware startup Looki has completed an A round of financing exceeding $20 million, led by Ant Group, with Meituan Longzhu, Walden, and Zhongguancun Capital as co-investors. Existing shareholder BAI Capital made two consecutive over-allotment follow-on investments, and Alpha Public and Tongge Ventures continued to increase their stakes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Founder Park 报道，AI 硬件创业公司 Looki 已完成超 2000 万美元 A 轮融资，由蚂蚁集团领投，美团龙珠、华登、中关村资本跟投，老股东 BAI 资本连续两轮超额追投，阿尔法公社与同歌创投继续加码。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Upon completion of this round of financing, Looki will focus on organizational talent development, model iteration, product research and development, and supply chain integration, accelerating its technological accumulation and exploration of next-generation interaction entry points in the AI-native hardware track.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本轮融资完成后，Looki 将重点投入组织人才建设、模型迭代、产品研发及供应链整合，加速其在 AI 原生硬件赛道的技术积累与下一代交互入口探索。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Looki was founded in May 2024 and has completed 4 consecutive rounds of financing to date. The company was co-founded by two Carnegie Mellon University alumni. CEO Sun Yang previously served as Head of Smart Hardware at Meituan, Senior R&amp;amp;D Director at Momenta, and was also one of the founding members of Google Assistant;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Looki 成立于 2024 年 5 月，截至目前已连续完成 4 轮融资。公司由两位卡内基梅隆大学校友联合创办，CEO 孙洋曾任美团智能硬件负责人、Momenta 高级研发总监，也是 Google Assistant 创始成员之一；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CTO Liu Bocong previously served as Head of Autonomous Driving Algorithms at Meituan and a founding member of Pony.ai. Team members come from prestigious institutions such as Tsinghua University, Peking University, University of Toronto, University of Illinois, and London School of Economics, possessing rich experience in AI algorithms, AI products, and hardware engineering.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            CTO 刘博聪则曾任美团自动驾驶算法负责人、Pony.ai 创始成员。团队成员来自清华大学、北京大学、多伦多大学、伊利诺伊大学、伦敦政经等院校，具备丰富的 AI 算法、AI 产品与硬件工程经验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last August, Looki released its first wearable multimodal AI hardware, Looki L1 International Edition, with thousands of units quickly selling out. In December of the same year, the domestic version was launched on JD.com, and global cumulative sales have now approached ten thousand units.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年 8 月，Looki 发布首款可穿戴多模态 AI 硬件 Looki L1 国际版，数千台备货迅速售罄；同年 12 月，国内版本在京东上线，目前全球累计销量已接近万台。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Looki L1 focuses on daily recording and companionship, capturing life fragments through video, images, and audio, and generating daily summary vlogs, life insight analyses, and serialized comics based on user behavior and emotions. These features are widely shared in Discord and Xiaohongshu communities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Looki L1 主打日常记录与陪伴，通过视频、图片与音频等方式捕捉生活碎片，并基于用户行为与情绪生成每日总结 vlog、生活洞察分析与连载漫画等内容，这些功能在 Discord 与小红书社区受到广泛分享。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At this year's CES, Looki will release a new Proactive AI feature. Compared to existing Reactive AI, Proactive AI can actively provide reminders and suggestions after understanding real-time user behavior. In the CES scenario, Looki will also automatically record the user's exhibition visit, analyze points of interest, and offer exhibition recommendations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在今年 CES 上，Looki 将发布全新主动式 AI（Proactive AI）功能。相比现有的响应式 AI（Reactive AI），主动式 AI 能够在理解用户实时行为后主动提供提醒与建议，在 CES 场景中，Looki 还将自动记录用户逛展过程、分析兴趣点并提供参展建议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Looki stated that the Proactive AI feature will officially debut at CES and will be rolled out to global Looki L1 users shortly thereafter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Looki 表示，主动式 AI 功能将在 CES 正式亮相，并将在不久后向全球 Looki L1 用户推送。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>雷军回应 YU7 「丢轮保车」设计：奔驰 1959 年即采用类似结构</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">雷军回应-YU7-「丢轮保车」设计：奔驰-1959-年即采用类似结构</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/99857c8a-662d-4bb9-95a7-2e209bafe304.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Lei Jun, founder and CEO of Xiaomi Group, responded to discussions sparked by the safety design, crash test details, and car dismantling live stream of the Xiaomi SU7, further emphasizing Xiaomi's investment and technical approach to automotive safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小米集团创办人、CEO 雷军围绕小米 YU7 的安全设计、碰撞测试细节及拆车直播引发的讨论发布多条微博进行回应，进一步强调小米在汽车安全性上的投入与技术路径。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lei Jun stated that &quot;wheel detachment for cabin protection&quot; is a safety design concept that is already quite mature in luxury car models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            雷军表示，「丢轮保车」是一项在豪华车型中已相当成熟的安全设计理念。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that he originally thought the technology was first proposed by Volvo, but the latest verification shows that Mercedes-Benz was the first to adopt this idea, introducing crumple zones and controlled deformation structures in its 1959 W111 model, forming the prototype of &quot;wheel detachment for cabin protection.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，原以为该技术最早由沃尔沃提出，但最新查证显示，最早采用这一思路的是奔驰，其在 1959 年的 W111 车型上引入了溃缩吸能区与可控变形结构，形成了「丢轮保车」的雏形。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The core of this design is to allow the wheels and suspension to detach along a predetermined path during severe frontal or offset collisions, thereby preventing structural components from being squeezed into the passenger compartment, maximizing the protection of body integrity and occupant safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这一设计的核心在于：在严重正面或偏置碰撞中，让车轮与悬架沿既定路径脱离，从而避免结构件被挤压进乘员舱，最大限度保护车身完整性与乘员安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the Xiaomi SU7 car dismantling live stream the day before yesterday, Xiaomi showcased footage of a 25% offset crash test. After the impact, the vehicle bounced to the left, and the wheels were thrown outwards.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在前天的小米 YU7 拆车直播中，小米展示了 25% 偏置碰撞测试画面。车辆在撞击后出现向左弹开的动作，车轮外抛。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Engineers explained that this is to dissipate force through body sliding and multi-path force transmission under offset conditions where the longitudinal beam's energy absorption is limited, preventing the A-pillar from bearing excessive impact. Lei Jun emphasized that this type of design is not a marketing gimmick, but a safety strategy widely adopted in the industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            工程师解释称，这是在纵梁吸能有限的偏置工况下，通过车体滑移与多路径传力来卸力，避免 A 柱承受过大冲击。雷军强调，这类设计并非营销噱头，而是行业普遍采用的安全策略。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to offset collisions, Lei Jun also introduced the structural design for frontal collisions on Weibo, including front longitudinal beam collapse for energy absorption, multiple force transmission paths to disperse impact, and structural reinforcement schemes such as 2200 MPa &quot;embedded roll cages&quot; for A/B pillars.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除偏置碰撞外，雷军还在微博中介绍了前向碰撞的结构设计，包括前纵梁溃缩吸能、多条力传导路径分散冲击，以及 A/B 柱 2200 MPa「内嵌式防滚架」等结构强化方案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             He emphasized that Xiaomi made it clear from the very beginning of car manufacturing that 'safety is the foundation, safety is the prerequisite.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             他强调，小米在造车之初就明确「安全是基础、安全是前提」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding whether the vehicle disassembled during the live broadcast can be reassembled, Lei Jun responded that engineers confirmed it could be reassembled within a few days and would undergo strict quality inspection, but the vehicle would not enter sales channels and would be used for subsequent tests.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对直播拆解后的车辆是否能重新组装的问题，雷军回应称，工程师确认可以在几天内完成装回，并会经过严格质检，但该车辆不会进入销售渠道，将用于后续试验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Lei Jun also mentioned that the YU7 adopts a 3.11 square meter all-aluminum &quot;clamshell hood&quot; and demonstrated its weight control and manufacturing difficulty during the live broadcast.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，雷军还提到 YU7 采用全铝 3.11 平米「蚌式大机盖」，并在直播中展示了其重量控制与工艺难度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lei Jun stated that communicating with users in an open and transparent manner is the direction Xiaomi Auto hopes to adhere to. He pointed out that technological innovation and product quality are the foundation of the automotive industry, and the purpose of the car disassembly live broadcast is precisely to allow the industry and consumers to more clearly understand product structure and safety design.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            雷军表示，以开放透明的方式与用户沟通，是小米汽车希望坚持的方向。他指出，技术创新与产品质量才是汽车产业的根基，拆车直播的目的正是让行业与消费者更清晰地理解产品结构与安全设计。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>雷鸟 CEO：充话费送眼镜的时代要来了</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">雷鸟-CEO：充话费送眼镜的时代要来了</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/73347639-55db-4c21-908c-d5bf320d93f3.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Blue Whale News, Rokid recently completed a new round of financing jointly invested by funds under China Mobile and China Unicom.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据蓝鲸新闻报道 ，雷鸟创新近日完成由中国移动与中国联通旗下基金联合投资的新一轮融资。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Hongwei, founder and CEO of Rokid, stated in an interview that at this year's CES, the company will release its first dual-eye full-color AR glasses equipped with eSIM, meaning AR devices will for the first time truly break free from reliance on mobile phones and possess independent communication capabilities. He called this a critical juncture for AR glasses to move towards a 'complete form'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            雷鸟创始人兼 CEO 李宏伟在接受采访时表示，今年 CES 上公司将发布首款搭载 eSIM 的双目全彩 AR 眼镜，意味着 AR 设备将首次真正摆脱对手机的依赖，具备独立通讯能力。他称这是 AR 眼镜走向「完整形态」的关键节点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Li Hongwei pointed out that operators are promoting the implementation of a 'get glasses by topping up phone credit' model, which is highly similar to the path before the popularization of smartphones. He judged that starting next year,
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             AR
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             will accelerate its integration into the lives of ordinary users, and the entry of operators is an important signal.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             李宏伟指出，运营商正推动「充话费送眼镜」模式落地，这与智能手机普及前夜的路径高度相似。他判断，明年起
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             AR
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             将加速融入普通用户生活，而运营商的入局是重要信号。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Rokid has received intensive financing in recent years, which Li Hongwei attributed to accelerating industry competition and the company's need to reserve R&amp;amp;D resources in advance. In 2025, Rokid maintained its position as the top seller in the global AR glasses market; according to Counterpoint data, for every 4 AR glasses sold globally in Q3 last year, 1 came from Rokid.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            雷鸟近年来密集获得融资，李宏伟称原因在于行业竞争加速，公司需提前储备研发资源。2025 年，雷鸟在全球 AR 眼镜市场保持销量第一，根据 Counterpoint 数据，去年 Q3 全球每售出 4 副 AR 眼镜，就有 1 副来自雷鸟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When discussing industry competition, Li Hongwei frankly stated that '90% of participants have no substantial meaning,' believing that there are not many companies truly dedicated to technology and products. He said that Rokid's strategy is to choose direct competition or a differentiated route based on industry development logic, rather than simply starting from a competitive perspective.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在谈及行业竞争时，李宏伟直言「90% 的参与者没有实质意义」，认为真正深耕技术与产品的企业并不多。他表示，雷鸟的策略是基于行业发展逻辑选择正面竞争或差异化路线，而非单纯从竞争视角出发。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the upcoming eSIM full-color AR glasses, he explained that the dual-eye full-color solution is not a short-term experience trade-off, but a choice based on long-term ecological value. Color display can support more core application scenarios, such as red envelope colors, stock red and green displays, etc.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            关于即将亮相的 eSIM 全彩 AR 眼镜，他解释称，双目全彩方案并非短期体验权衡，而是基于长期生态价值的选择。彩色显示才能承载更多核心应用场景，例如红包颜色、股票红绿显示等。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He revealed that Rokid has achieved multiple technological breakthroughs in the field of color MicroLED optical waveguides and will significantly reduce the cost of using color solutions in this year's products.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他透露，雷鸟在彩色 MicroLED 光波导领域已实现多项技术突破，并将在今年产品中显著降低彩色方案的使用成本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Looking ahead to 2026, Li Hongwei stated that Rokid will enter a 'lightning growth' phase, but the primary task is to refine the product experience to perfection. He expects shipments to exceed one million units this year and emphasized that the company will focus on creating products that exceed user expectations in iconic scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在展望 2026 年时，李宏伟表示雷鸟将进入「闪电增长」阶段，但首要任务是将产品体验打磨到极致。他预计今年出货量将突破百万台，并强调公司将聚焦在标志性场景中打造超越用户预期的产品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MiniMax 与智元机器人合作落地全流程语音 AI</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MiniMax-与智元机器人合作落地全流程语音-AI</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Shangguan News, MiniMax Shanghai Xiyu Technology and Zhiyuan Robotics announced a partnership. MiniMax will provide Zhiyuan Robotics with full-process AI technical support for text-to-speech, and will promote the upgrade of robot voice interaction experience with a customized persona system and multimodal model capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据上观新闻报道，MiniMax 上海稀宇科技与智元机器人宣布达成合作，MiniMax 将为智元机器人提供文本到语音的全流程 AI 技术支持，并以定制化人设体系与多模态模型能力，推动机器人语音交互体验升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The cooperation between the two parties was disclosed yesterday. According to the report, MiniMax has built an exclusive persona system tailored to Zhiyuan Robotics' product positioning and functional characteristics, and based on this, formulated prompt strategies to enable the robot to generate personalized voices for users, achieving a 'thousand faces, thousand voices' speech synthesis effect.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            双方合作于昨天披露。根据报道，MiniMax 已针对智元机器人的产品定位与功能特性，构建专属人设体系，并基于此制定提示词策略，使机器人能够为用户生成个性化音色，实现「千人千面」的语音合成效果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to speech synthesis, MiniMax has also introduced its self-developed music generation model into the Zhiyuan Robotics system, providing support for expanding entertainment scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除语音合成外，MiniMax 还将其自研音乐生成模型引入智元机器人体系，为其拓展娱乐场景玩法提供支持。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report further pointed out that MiniMax has currently formed a general large model matrix covering multimodal directions such as text, speech, and music, including MiniMax M2.1, Hailuo 2.3, Speech 2.6, and Music 2.0, making it one of the few companies globally to enter the first tier of full-modality AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道进一步指出，MiniMax 当前已形成覆盖文本、语音、音乐等多模态方向的通用大模型矩阵，包括 MiniMax M2.1、Hailuo 2.3、Speech 2.6 与 Music 2.0 等，是全球少数进入全模态第一梯队的公司之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>波士顿动力全电动 Atlas 机器人首次「进厂干活」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">波士顿动力全电动-Atlas-机器人首次「进厂干活」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7ced3067-a753-43c7-a315-8248234bb071.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Today, Boston Dynamics released the latest demo video of its next-generation all-electric humanoid robot Atlas, and made its first public appearance at the Hyundai Motor Group's press conference at CES 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天，波士顿动力发布了其下一代全电动人形机器人 Atlas 的最新演示视频，并在 CES 2026 的现代汽车集团发布会上完成首次公开亮相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to the previous hydraulic version, the new Atlas has undergone significant upgrades in structure, materials, power system, and intelligent capabilities, and has already entered Hyundai Motor's factory in Georgia, USA, to perform real manufacturing tasks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比此前的液压版本，新版 Atlas 在结构、材料、动力系统与智能能力上均实现大幅升级，并已进入现代汽车位于美国佐治亚州的工厂执行真实制造任务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adopts an all-electric drive system, abandoning the old hydraulic structure, with a body made of lightweight aluminum-titanium alloy composite materials;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 1.88 meters tall and weighs about 90 kilograms;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possesses 56 degrees of freedom, with joints capable of omnidirectional rotation, enabling it to perform complex maneuvers such as backflips and cartwheels, and to flexibly execute tasks like sorting and handling in factory environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the latest video, Atlas demonstrated its 4-hour sustainable battery system, which supports quick replacement for continuous operation. The robot can carry a maximum load of 110 pounds (approximately 50 kg), has a continuous load capacity of 66 pounds (approximately 30 kg), and can extend its body up to 7.5 feet to adapt to different working conditions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在最新视频中，Atlas 展示了其可持续 4 小时的电池系统，并支持快速更换以实现连续运行。机器人可承载最高 110 磅（约 50 公斤）负重，持续承重能力为 66 磅（约 30 公斤），并可将身体伸展至最高 7.5 英尺以适应不同工况需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the perception and operation level, Atlas continuously assesses its surroundings, adjusting its posture, balance, and grasping actions in real-time. Its three-fingered manipulator can be reconfigured according to task requirements, and tactile sensors provide real-time feedback on pressure and contact data to the system, ensuring appropriate force is applied.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在感知与操作层面，Atlas 持续评估周围环境，实时调整姿态、平衡与抓取动作。其三指机械手可根据任务需求重新配置，触觉传感器会将压力与接触数据实时反馈至系统，以确保施加恰当力度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Leveraging a virtual reality supervised learning and simulation training system, operators can demonstrate actions via a remote control system, which Atlas can then autonomously replicate.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            依托于虚拟现实监督学习与模拟训练体系，操作人员可通过遥控系统示范动作，Atlas 随后可自主复现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The &quot;brain&quot; of the new Atlas is powered by Nvidia chips, giving it stronger reasoning and autonomous learning capabilities, enabling it to quickly master new tasks in complex industrial environments. Footage previously shot by the American CBS program &quot;60 Minutes&quot; in a Hyundai factory showed that Atlas is already capable of handling parts like roof racks on a real production line.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新版 Atlas 的「大脑」由英伟达芯片驱动，具备更强的推理与自主学习能力，使其能够在复杂工业环境中快速掌握新任务。美国 CBS 节目《60 Minutes》此前在现代工厂拍摄的画面显示，Atlas 已能在真实生产线上处理车顶行李架等部件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Boston Dynamics' parent company, Hyundai Motor Group, announced its group-level AI robotics strategy at this year's CES 2026, planning to fully integrate robots like Atlas and Spot into its Software-Defined Factory (SDF) system to promote the automation of manufacturing processes and deepen human-robot collaboration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，波士顿动力的母公司现代汽车集团已在今年 CES 2026 上公布集团级 AI 机器人战略，计划将 Atlas、Spot 等机器人全面纳入其 Software‑Defined Factory（SDF）体系，以推动制造流程自动化与人机协作的深化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>能帮你做家务的机器人 LG CLOiD 首次亮相 CES</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">能帮你做家务的机器人-LG-CLOiD-首次亮相-CES</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/73f809bf-3f68-493e-80eb-f7e3c911e153.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, LG officially demonstrated the actual operation of its home robot CLOiD during its CES keynote speech, positioning it as a crucial component in creating a &quot;zero-labor home.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，LG 在 CES 主题演讲中正式展示了其家务机器人 CLOiD 的实际运行效果，LG 将其定位为打造「零劳动家庭」的重要组成部分。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CLOiD made its debut on stage by waving its hands, then, under the instruction of Brandt Varner, LG Home Appliance Business Division's VP of Sales, demonstrated the complete process of putting a wet towel into a washing machine.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            CLOiD 在舞台上以双手挥动的方式亮相，随后在 LG 家电事业部销售副总裁 Brandt Varner 的指令下，示范了将一条湿毛巾放入洗衣机的完整流程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After the washing machine door automatically opened, the robot extended its left arm and placed the towel into the drum. The entire process took approximately 30 seconds, demonstrating its basic household task execution capability, though there is still room for efficiency improvement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            洗衣机门自动打开后，机器人伸出左臂，将毛巾放入滚筒。整个过程耗时约 30 秒，展示了其具备基础家务执行能力，但效率仍有提升空间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the latter half of the speech, CLOiD reappeared, handing a water bottle to Steve Scarbrough, Senior Vice President of LG HVAC Business Division, and proactively offered help after discerning his needs from his tone, even completing a fist bump, emphasizing its certain emotional interaction capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在演讲后半段，CLOiD 再次登场，为 LG HVAC 事业部高级副总裁 Steve Scarbrough 递上水瓶，并根据其语气判断需求后主动提供帮助，甚至完成了拳碰动作，强调其具备一定的情感交互能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            LG had previously announced that the robot possesses multiple household capabilities, including retrieving milk from the refrigerator, baking croissants in the oven, and folding clothes. This demonstration further showcased its potential applications in a home setting. However, LG has not yet announced CLOiD's release date or whether it will truly be sold to consumers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            LG 此前已预告该机器人具备多项家务能力，包括从冰箱取牛奶、在烤箱中烤可颂、叠放衣物等。此次演示进一步展示了其在家庭场景中的潜在应用。不过，LG 仍未公布 CLOiD 的上市时间或是否会真正面向消费者销售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>胖东来就「茶叶有苍蝇」致歉：客服处理失当，商品已下架复核</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">胖东来就「茶叶有苍蝇」致歉：客服处理失当，商品已下架复核</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7adb2aff-da45-4c76-be31-55b32d3b1775.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, yesterday, in response to a customer's feedback on Douyin about &quot;Pang Dong Lai tea having flies,&quot; Pang Dong Lai issued a statement, announcing the immediate formation of a special investigation team to verify the matter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，昨天，针对顾客在抖音反馈「胖东来茶叶有苍蝇」一事，胖东来发布情况说明，宣布立即组建专项调查小组进行核实。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the implicated product has been removed from shelves for investigation, and the company's quality management department has visited the manufacturer to conduct a full-process review of production qualifications, production processes, and inspection and testing procedures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，涉事商品已被下架排查，公司品质管理部已前往厂家对生产资质、生产过程及检验检测等环节进行全流程复核。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Pang Dong Lai admitted in the statement that customer service personnel did not follow standard company procedures when handling the feedback, resulting in a poor customer experience, and expressed apologies for this.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            胖东来在声明中承认，客服人员在处理该反馈时未遵循公司标准流程，导致顾客体验不佳，对此表示歉意。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company stated that it would disclose the results as soon as the investigation is clear and urged the public to remain rational before the truth is uncovered to avoid causing online harm to others.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司表示将在调查清楚后第一时间公示结果，并呼吁公众在真相查明前保持理性，避免对他人造成网络伤害。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to data released by Pang Dong Lai Commercial Group on January 1st, as of December 31, 2025, the group's total sales for 2025 exceeded 23.531 billion yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据胖东来商贸集团 1 月 1 日公布的数据，截至 2025 年 12 月 31 日，集团 2025 全年销售额超 235.31 亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among these, the supermarket format ranked first with sales of 12.643 billion yuan, followed by jewelry and department store formats in second and third place, respectively. Looking back, Pang Dong Lai's sales have maintained rapid growth, climbing from approximately 7 billion yuan in 2022 and 10.7 billion yuan in 2023 to 17 billion yuan in 2024.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，超市业态以 126.43 亿元销售额居首，珠宝和百货业态分列二三位。回顾过往，胖东来销售额保持高速增长，从 2022 年的约 70 亿元、2023 年的约 107 亿元，一路攀升至 2024 年的 170 亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kimi K2-VL 提前现身？神秘模型引发开发者关注</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Kimi-K2-VL-提前现身？神秘模型引发开发者关注</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f7a48336-803d-49d5-b872-10ec5824421c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from &quot;Sci-Tech Innovation Board Daily,&quot; a mysterious model codenamed &quot;Kiwi-do&quot; recently appeared in the globally renowned arena LMArena and passed the VPCT benchmark test.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《科创板日报》报道，近日，一个代号为 「Kiwi-do」 的神秘模型出现在全球知名竞技场 LMArena，并通过了 VPCT 基准测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to analysis by multiple developers, this model is very likely the K2-VL multimodal new model that Moonshot AI mentioned in an AMA, meaning that K2-VL is on the verge of official release.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据多位开发者分析，该模型极有可能就是月之暗面（Moonshot AI）曾在 AMA 中提到的 K2-VL 多模态新模型，这意味着 K2-VL 距离正式发布已迫在眉睫。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, there were reports that Moonshot AI plans to launch a new model this month, possibly K2.1 or K2.5, which will be another significant update following the industry buzz generated by Kimi K2 and Kimi K2 Thinking.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前有消息指出，月之暗面计划于本月上线新模型，型号可能为 K2.1 或 K2.5，这将是继 Kimi K2 和 Kimi K2 Thinking 引发行业热议后的又一次重要更新。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曝小红书内测长文付费功能，进军付费网文市场</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝小红书内测长文付费功能，进军付费网文市场</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sina Tech, Xiaohongshu recently began internal testing of a paid long-form content feature, further clarifying its direction towards entering the paid online literature market. Yesterday afternoon, details of the internal test were exposed for the first time, showing that the platform is attempting to provide new content monetization paths for photographers, artists, and long-form content creators.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪科技报道 ，小红书近日正在内测长文付费功能，进一步明确其进军付费网文市场的方向。昨天下午，相关内测细节首次曝光，显示平台正尝试为摄影师、画师及长文创作者提供新的内容变现路径。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The &quot;Paid Notes&quot; feature in this internal test includes three modes:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次内测的「付费笔记」功能包含三种模式：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One is paid download of high-definition original images, where users can pay to obtain watermark-free original files;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second is for long-form and story creators, supporting paid unlocking of the full text after a trial read;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third is a paid collection mode for notes, mainly targeting serialized novels and series columns, where users can unlock all content at once after reading some chapters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaohongshu customer service stated that this feature currently operates on an invitation-only basis by the platform, and is not yet open to all users, but the invitation scope will be gradually expanded later.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小红书客服表示，该功能目前采取平台邀约制，尚未面向所有用户开放，后续将逐步扩大邀约范围。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaohongshu launched a novel reading section as early as last year, including free novels from third-party platforms, but the entry point is relatively hidden, requiring users to actively search for the &quot;Silent Impact&quot; mini-program to access it.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小红书早于去年已上线小说阅读板块，收录来自第三方平台的免费小说，但入口较为隐蔽，需要用户主动搜索「无声冲击」小程序才能访问。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, ByteDance launched its independent paid reading app &quot;Hongzhu Novel&quot; in December last year, clearly distinguishing between free and member-only sections, focusing on premium content. The combined actions of both indicate that the competition between community platforms and content platforms in the paid online literature sector is accelerating.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，字节跳动去年 12 月推出独立付费阅读 App「红烛小说」，明确区分免费与会员专区，主攻精品内容。两者动作叠加，显示社区平台与内容平台在付费网文领域的竞争正在加速升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>微信推出 AI 小程序成长计划，提供 1 亿 token 免费算力与变现支持</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微信推出-AI-小程序成长计划，提供-1-亿-token-免费算力与变现支持</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/02e52264-d31c-4bd7-be01-1232f6c45dee.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, WeChat officially launched the &quot;AI Application and Online Tool Mini-Program Growth Plan,&quot; providing developers with cloud development resources, AI computing power, traffic incentives, and commercialization support, aiming to make 2026 the &quot;Year One of Mini-Program AI Applications.&quot; The incentive period for this plan covers the entire current year, ending on December 31st.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，微信官方正式启动「AI 应用及线上工具小程序成长计划」，为开发者提供云开发资源、AI 算力、流量激励及商业化支持，旨在推动 2026 年成为「小程序 AI 应用元年」。该计划激励期覆盖今年全年，至 12 月 31 日结束。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newly registered developers can get 6 months of free access to the personal version of WeChat Cloud Development environment, while existing developers can receive large resource deduction coupons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free provision of a total of 100 million tokens for Tencent Hunyuan 2.0 text-to-text large model, and 10,000 images for Hunyuan text-to-image model, with the latest models to be launched successively later;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free access to We Analytics Professional Edition for one year, and providing traffic exposure for quality products in entry points such as &quot;Discover - Mini-Programs&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, regarding monetization methods, WeChat has opened virtual payment and membership subscription capabilities across Android, iOS, and HarmonyOS terminals, and offers limited-time preferential rates for AI and tool-type mini-programs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，变现方式上，微信已开放安卓、iOS、鸿蒙全终端虚拟支付与会员订阅能力，并为 AI 与工具类小程序提供限时优惠费率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For ad monetization, a &quot;development-free smart access mode&quot; has been launched, where the system can automatically analyze mini-program pages and recommend ad placements, supporting real-time preview and one-click launch for developers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            广告变现推出「免开发智能接入模式」，系统可自动分析小程序页面并推荐广告位，支持开发者实时预览与一键上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding participation, all developers of online tools, AI-native, and entertainment mini-programs can participate in the plan through the &quot;Industry Capabilities - AI Mini-Program Growth Plan&quot; entry in the WeChat Mini-Program backend.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            参与方式上，所有线上工具、AI 原生及娱乐类小程序开发者均可通过微信小程序后台的「行业能力-AI 小程序成长计划」入口参与该计划。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>周冠宇加盟凯迪拉克 F1：出任 2026 赛季官方储备车手</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">周冠宇加盟凯迪拉克-F1：出任-2026-赛季官方储备车手</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/226c0ed5-6fc1-4b2b-ac05-d8b7a4436674.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Driver Zhou Guanyu officially announced on Weibo yesterday that he has joined the Cadillac F1 team and will serve as the team's official reserve driver for this F1 season. This means he will be on standby as the &quot;third driver&quot; after main drivers Perez and Bottas.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            车手周冠宇昨天在微博官宣加盟凯迪拉克 F1 车队，并将在今年 F1 赛季担任车队官方储备车手。这意味着他将在主力车手佩雷兹与博塔斯之后，作为「第三车手」随时待命。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last year, Zhou Guanyu served as a reserve driver for the Ferrari F1 team, during which he completed SF-25 tire tests and participated in multiple TPC old car test missions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年，周冠宇效力于法拉利 F1 车队，担任替补车手，期间完成 SF‑25 轮胎测试，并参与多款 TPC 旧车测试任务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ferrari posted a message at the beginning of this year expressing gratitude to him, officially ending their collaboration. Zhou Guanyu's studio later responded, saying, &quot;Thank you to the Ferrari F1 team for their trust in the 2025 season,&quot; and wished the team success in the future.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            法拉利在今年年初发文向其表达感谢，双方合作正式结束。周冠宇工作室随后回应称「感谢法拉利 F1 车队在 2025 赛季的信任」，并祝福车队未来顺利。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that Zhou Guanyu was born in Shanghai in 1999. In 2021, he signed with Alfa Romeo based on his F2 performance, becoming China's first official F1 driver.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开资料显示，周冠宇 1999 年出生于上海，2021 年凭借 F2 表现签约阿尔法 · 罗密欧，成为中国首位 F1 正式车手。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>广汽集团与华为终端签约，拓展智能座舱与 AI 技术合作</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">广汽集团与华为终端签约，拓展智能座舱与-AI-技术合作</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d897f6f1-11ad-4a89-9201-1337d3556b99.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Yu Chengdong, Huawei's Executive Director, Director of the Product Investment Review Committee, and Chairman of Terminal BG, visited GAC Group's Panyu headquarters with his delegation. The two parties officially signed a comprehensive cooperation framework agreement between GAC Group and Huawei Terminal.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，华为常务董事、产品投资评审委员会主任、终端 BG 董事长余承东一行到访广汽集团番禺总部，双方正式签署广汽集团与华为终端全面合作框架协议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Following this signing, the scope of cooperation between the two parties has further expanded to include the co-building of the HarmonyOS ecosystem and joint innovation in AI technology. GAC Group Chairman Feng Xingya, General Manager Ge Xianqing, and Huawei Terminal Cloud Service President Zhu Yonggang, among others, attended and witnessed the signing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次签约后，双方合作范围进一步扩展至鸿蒙生态共建与 AI 技术联合创新。广汽集团董事长冯兴亚、总经理閤先庆及华为终端云服务总裁朱勇刚等共同出席并见证签约。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the agreement, the two parties will deepen collaboration in areas such as new energy vehicle manufacturing, operating systems, intelligent cockpits, and global services, focusing on the implementation of the HarmonyOS ecosystem and joint innovation in cutting-edge AI technologies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据协议，双方将在新能源汽车制造、操作系统、智能座舱及全球化服务等领域深化协同，重点围绕鸿蒙生态落地与 AI 前沿技术展开联合创新。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of ecosystem co-building, GAC Group will work with Huawei Terminal to promote the deep application of the HarmonyOS ecosystem in enterprise office and user service scenarios, aiming to improve business efficiency and user experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在生态共建方面，广汽集团将与华为终端推进鸿蒙生态在企业办公与用户服务场景的深度应用，以提升业务效率与用户体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of technology co-creation, the two parties will further expand the scope of cooperation based on existing HMS for Car and HarmonyOS cockpit collaborations, strengthen collaborative R&amp;amp;D in the AI field, and promote the deep integration of Xiaoyi intelligent agents in intelligent cockpits to create a more perceptive and interactive in-car experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在技术共创方面，双方将在既有 HMS for Car、鸿蒙座舱合作基础上进一步拓展合作边界，强化在 AI 领域的协同研发，并推动小艺智能体在智能座舱中的深度集成，打造更具感知力与交互力的车载体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            GAC Group stated that in the future, it will combine its brand model positioning and user needs to jointly develop distinctive applications and services with Huawei Terminal, enriching the full-scenario intelligent mobility experience under the HarmonyOS ecosystem, and accelerating the layout of the overseas intelligent mobility market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            广汽集团表示，未来将结合旗下品牌车型定位与用户需求，与华为终端共同开发特色应用与服务，丰富鸿蒙生态下的全场景智能出行体验，并加速海外智能出行市场布局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This cooperation also echoes GAC Group's previously released 'Intelligent Mobility 2027' action plan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次合作也与广汽集团此前发布的「智行 2027」行动计划相呼应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The plan proposes to continuously strengthen the three major technical foundations—GAC AI large model platform, GAC Xingling electronic and electrical architecture, and GAC connected big data platform—within three years, promoting rapid iteration of intelligent driving assistance and intelligent cockpits, and driving enterprise transformation and upgrading through technological innovation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该计划提出，将在三年内持续夯实广汽 AI 大模型平台、广汽星灵电子电气架构及广汽网联大数据平台三大技术基础，推动智能驾驶辅助与智能座舱的快速迭代，以科技创新驱动企业转型升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>杜比视界与抖音达成合作</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">杜比视界与抖音达成合作</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2d22886a-f8c9-4cfa-ab0f-106f8d587a60.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Dolby Laboratories and Douyin announced a partnership to bring Dolby Vision into the Douyin ecosystem, providing creators with an end-to-end high-quality visual experience covering creation, editing, sharing, and viewing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，杜比实验室与抖音宣布达成合作，将杜比视界带入抖音生态，为创作者提供覆盖创作、编辑、分享与观看的端到端高画质体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, iPhone users can share and watch Dolby Vision videos within the Douyin app, and can use Douyin's built-in editing tools or third-party software like CapCut for Dolby Vision content creation. Douyin stated that related support for Android will also be launched soon.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，iPhone 用户已可在抖音 app 内分享和观看杜比视界视频，并可使用抖音内置编辑工具或剪映等第三方软件进行杜比视界内容创作。抖音方面表示，Android 端的相关支持也将很快上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            John Couling, Senior Vice President of the Entertainment Business Group at Dolby Laboratories, stated that short video platforms are changing the way people connect with each other and share stories, and Douyin allows creators to present content with more authentic detail.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            杜比实验室娱乐事业部高级副总裁古令江（John Couling）表示，短视频平台正在改变人们连接彼此与分享故事的方式，而抖音让创作者能够以更真实的细节呈现内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that this collaboration reflects Dolby's commitment to bringing exceptional experiences to more creators and viewers worldwide.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，此次合作体现了杜比将卓越体验带给全球更多创作者与观众的承诺。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A relevant person in charge at Douyin pointed out that Dolby Vision has become an industry benchmark for picture quality, widely adopted by professional creators globally.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            抖音相关负责人指出，杜比视界已成为行业画质标杆，被全球专业创作者广泛采用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            By introducing Dolby Vision, Douyin hopes to further enhance users' video experience, allowing creators to present visuals with richer details and a stronger sense of realism when recording daily life, food, travel, beauty, fashion, and other content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            通过引入杜比视界，抖音希望进一步提升用户的视频体验，让创作者在记录日常、美食、旅行、美妆、时尚等内容时，以更丰富的细节和更强的真实感呈现画面。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>历史重演：《英雄联盟》服务器因证书未续签宕机数小时</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">历史重演：《英雄联盟》服务器因证书未续签宕机数小时</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/97edcc40-7676-4f9d-bb46-0292a923ddab.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a report from Blue Point Network, Riot Games failed to renew the digital certificate for its League of Legends servers in time, leading to widespread connection disruptions, with player clients unable to establish normal HTTPS connections for several hours.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据蓝点网报道，拳头游戏因未及时为《英雄联盟》服务器续签数字证书，导致大面积连接中断，玩家客户端在数小时内无法通过 HTTPS 建立正常连接。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The expired certificate was precisely the 10-year self-signed certificate that Riot replaced in 2016.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次过期的证书正是拳头在 2016 年更换、有效期 10 年的自签名证书。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report pointed out that Riot Games had experienced service interruptions for the same reason a decade ago, and employees at the time stated that certificates should automatically renew, but this year's incident shows that the relevant process has still not been fundamentally resolved.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，拳头游戏在十年前曾因同样原因导致服务中断，当时员工曾表示证书应会自动续订，但今年的事故显示相关流程仍未得到根本解决。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Because all HTTPS requests were rejected after the certificate expired, the League of Legends client could not connect to the server. Some players still encountered an 'unknown player' prompt even after service was restored, requiring a client update and restart to resume normal experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            由于证书过期后所有 HTTPS 请求被拒绝，《英雄联盟》客户端无法连接服务器，部分玩家即便在服务恢复后仍遇到「未知玩家」提示，需要更新客户端并重启才能恢复正常体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that Riot uses a self-signed certificate, which theoretically allows for a longer validity period. However, the longer the certificate's validity, the higher the risk of private key leakage, so the industry generally does not recommend using ultra-long-period certificates.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，拳头使用的是自签名证书，理论上可签发更长有效期，但证书有效期越长，私钥泄露风险越高，因此行业普遍不建议采用超长周期证书。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the CA/Browser Forum has decided to shorten the maximum certificate validity period to 47 days starting in 2028. Apple previously supported shortening certificate cycles, which means that service disruptions due to renewal oversights may occur more frequently in the future.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，CA/浏览器联盟已决定自 2028 年起将证书最长有效期缩短至 47 天，苹果此前也支持缩短证书周期，这意味着未来类似因续签疏漏导致的服务中断事件可能更频繁出现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this incident, a Riot employee only realized the certificate had expired after seeing player feedback on Reddit and urgently coordinated with the technical team to resolve it. Servers reconnected after several hours of downtime, but the incident once again exposed the fragility of certificate management processes for large online services.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次事件中，一名拳头员工是在 Reddit 上看到玩家反馈后才意识到证书已过期，并紧急协调技术团队处理。服务器在中断数小时后恢复连接，但事件再次暴露出大型在线服务在证书管理流程上的脆弱性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>微软 CEO 呼吁淡化「AI 垃圾内容」争议，「Microslop」外号却登上热搜</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微软-CEO-呼吁淡化「AI-垃圾内容」争议，「Microslop」外号却登上热搜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/090c2a19-3be9-4867-867d-216b83a82d9f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella recently sparked ongoing public debate due to a blog post about this year's AI development trends.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微软 CEO 萨提亚・纳德拉（Satya Nadella）近日因一篇关于今年人工智能发展趋势的博文，引发持续的舆论争议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Nadella stated in his personal blog that he hopes the industry and public will no longer dwell on AI-generated &quot;AI slop&quot; and called for moving beyond the binary debate of &quot;low-quality content versus high-end experiences.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            纳德拉在个人博客中表示，希望行业与公众不再纠结于人工智能生成的「AI 垃圾（slop）」，并呼吁跳出「低质内容与高端体验」的二元争论。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that for AI to gain social acceptance, it must move from &quot;gimmick&quot; back to &quot;substance&quot; and create perceptible real value globally.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，AI 若想获得社会认可，必须从「噱头」回到「实质」，并在全球范围内创造可被感知的实际价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Slop&quot; refers to low-quality digital content generated in bulk by AI. Merriam-Webster's Dictionary named the term a top word for 2025, believing it reflects public irony regarding AI quality issues.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            所谓「slop」，指由 AI 批量生成的低质量数字内容。美国韦氏词典将该词评为 2025 年度热词，认为其反映了公众对 AI 质量问题的讽刺态度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, Nadella's statement did not quell the controversy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            然而，纳德拉的表态并未平息争议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Conversely, as Microsoft extensively embeds AI features like Copilot into its systems and applications, user complaints about degraded experience and affected performance have accumulated. On social media platforms, many users have jokingly referred to Microsoft as &quot;Microslop,&quot; with extensive discussions appearing on X, Instagram, and Facebook.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相反，由于微软在系统与应用中大规模嵌入 Copilot 等 AI 功能，用户对体验下降、性能受影响等问题的抱怨不断累积。社交平台上，大量用户将微软戏称为「Microslop」，在 X、Instagram、Facebook 均出现大量讨论。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Many users also complained about Microsoft forcibly adding AI features at the Windows system level and in basic tools like Notepad, even jokingly renaming the Microsoft suite to &quot;Sloppice,&quot; &quot;SlopDrive,&quot; etc., to express dissatisfaction with AI's excessive intrusion into daily use.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            还有不少用户吐槽微软在 Windows 系统层面和记事本等基础工具中强行加入 AI 功能，甚至调侃将微软全家桶改名为「Sloppice」「SlopDrive」等，以表达对 AI 过度介入日常使用的不满。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Microsoft itself admitted that Copilot's performance in some products was subpar. Last December, Nadella sent a strongly worded email to the team, stating that Copilot's integration with Outlook and Gmail was &quot;basically not working,&quot; and assigned some business operations to a new commercial CEO to accelerate improvements.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，微软自身也承认 Copilot 在部分产品中的表现不佳。去年 12 月，纳德拉曾向团队发出措辞严厉的邮件，指出 Copilot 与 Outlook、Gmail 的整合「基本上不奏效」，并将部分业务交由新任商业 CEO 负责，以加速改进。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At a broader industry level, AI quality and safety issues are also receiving attention. Recently, xAI's Grok was investigated for generating explicit content involving minors, while OpenAI faces legal pressure due to a lawsuit alleging it induced extreme events. These incidents further exacerbate public concerns about AI risks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在更广泛的行业层面，AI 质量与安全问题同样受到关注。就在最近，xAI 的 Grok 因生成未成年人露骨内容遭调查，OpenAI 则因一起涉嫌诱发极端事件的诉讼而面临法律压力。这些事件进一步加剧了公众对 AI 风险的担忧。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>三星 Family Hub 冰箱上新：支持语音开关门</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">三星-Family-Hub-冰箱上新：支持语音开关门</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/15219f4a-2ba2-4d09-99dd-affbfff599d8.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, Samsung announced yesterday at CES that it is adding a new voice-controlled door opening and closing feature to its Family Hub series smart refrigerators, further enhancing ease of use and accessibility in smart home scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，三星昨天在 CES 上宣布为其 Family Hub 系列智能冰箱加入全新的语音控制开关门功能，进一步强化智能家居场景下的易用性与可及性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Samsung stated that users will be able to directly issue commands such as &quot;close fridge door&quot; or &quot;open door&quot; via the built-in Bixby voice assistant, and the refrigerator door will automatically open or close, with an opening angle exceeding 90 degrees.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            三星表示，用户未来可通过内置的 Bixby 语音助手直接发出「关冰箱门」或「打开门」等指令，冰箱门将自动开启或关闭，且开门角度可超过 90 度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to voice, users can also lightly touch the refrigerator door with their palm or the back of their hand to trigger the opening and closing action, suitable for scenarios where hands are occupied during cooking, and also improving user-friendliness for those with mobility impairments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除语音外，用户也可通过手掌或手背轻触冰箱门来触发开合动作，适用于烹饪时双手不便操作的场景，同时也提升了对行动不便用户的友好度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Beyond voice control, Samsung has also introduced the Gemini model to the Family Hub series to upgrade the refrigerator's AI visual food recognition capabilities. The official statement claims the new system can &quot;instantly identify an unlimited amount of fresh and processed foods,&quot; aiming to help users plan meals more efficiently and reduce food waste.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在语音控制之外，三星还为 Family Hub 系列引入 Gemini 模型，用于升级冰箱的 AI 视觉食材识别能力。官方称，新系统可「即时识别无限量的新鲜与加工食品」，旨在帮助用户更高效地进行膳食规划并减少食物浪费。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 数据标注公司 CEO：AI 训练未来数十年仍离不开人类</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-数据标注公司-CEO：AI-训练未来数十年仍离不开人类</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6cf99d25-e18c-4829-8323-0142150cb15d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Matt Fitzpatrick, CEO of data labeling company Invisible Technologies, recently stated on the podcast &quot;20VC&quot; that a core misconception surrounding generative AI training is gradually being corrected:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，日前，数据标注公司 Invisible Technologies CEO Matt Fitzpatrick 在播客节目「20VC」中表示，围绕生成式 AI 训练的一个核心误解正在被逐渐纠正：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The role of humans in data production and feedback will not be replaced by synthetic data for decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Fitzpatrick pointed out that a long-standing view in the industry is that as synthetic data capabilities improve, AI models will become independent of human feedback within two to three years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Fitzpatrick 指出，行业内长期流传着一种观点，即随着合成数据能力提升，AI 模型将在两三年内摆脱对人类反馈的依赖。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, he believes that from a fundamental principle perspective, this judgment is not valid. The reason is that the real world contains a large number of diverse and contextually complex tasks, and AI's understanding at the levels of language, culture, and professional knowledge still requires human calibration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但他认为，从基本原理来看，这一判断并不成立。原因在于，现实世界中存在大量类型各异、语境复杂的任务，AI 在语言、文化与专业知识层面的理解仍需依赖人类校准。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He cited the legal industry as an example, pointing out that this field contains a large amount of non-public information that models cannot directly access, requiring manual processing and annotation. Furthermore, the training of generative AI still requires humans to filter, sort, and correct model outputs to ensure quality and safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他以法律行业为例指出，该领域拥有大量非公开信息，模型无法直接获取，必须依赖人工处理与标注。此外，生成式 AI 的训练仍需要人类对模型输出进行筛选、排序与纠正，以确保质量与安全性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Invisible Technologies completed $100 million in financing last September, valuing the company at $2 billion. The company competes with data labeling firms like Scale AI and Surge AI, providing high-quality training data to tech giants.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Invisible Technologies 去年 9 月完成 1 亿美元融资，估值达 20 亿美元。公司与 Scale AI、Surge AI 等数据标注企业竞争，为科技巨头提供高质量训练数据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As model capabilities improve, the industry is shifting from relying on generalist annotators to recruiting professionals in fields such as mathematics and science to meet the demand for higher-precision data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着模型能力提升，行业也从依赖通用型标注员转向招募数学、科学等领域的专业人才，以满足更高精度的数据需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CEOs of several peer companies have also expressed similar views. Mercor CEO Brendan Foody stated last September that data quality remains the core of the business, and this relies on &quot;excellent talent who are treated well.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多家同行公司 CEO 也表达了类似观点。Mercor CEO Brendan Foody 去年 9 月表示，数据质量仍是业务核心，而这依赖于「被很好对待的优秀人才」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Handshake CEO Garrett Lord pointed out that as models absorb almost all publicly available corpus from the internet, the industry's requirements for annotators are shifting from &quot;generalists&quot; to &quot;experts.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Handshake CEO Garrett Lord 则指出，随着模型吸收了互联网几乎全部公开语料，行业对标注者的要求正从「通才」转向「专家」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2699 元起，荣耀 Power2 正式发布，内置 10080mAh 电池</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2699-元起，荣耀-Power2-正式发布，内置-10080mAh-电池</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c39b6d80-f702-4756-ba97-a3374d5a765e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Honor held its first new product launch event of the year yesterday, officially unveiling the new Honor Power2 phone. It features upgrades in battery life, communication, performance, and reliability, positioned as a lightweight flagship model for outdoor scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            荣耀于昨天举行今年首场新品发布会，正式推出荣耀 Power2 新机，在续航、通信、性能与可靠性方面均升级，定位为面向户外场景的轻旗舰机型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a 10080mAh battery, supporting 80W super fast charging and 27W reverse fast charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First to feature the Dimensity 8500 Elite chip, with a 25% increase in GPU performance;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in ice-sealed liquid cooling system, with a total heat dissipation area exceeding 40000mm²;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a 6.79-inch 1.5K screen, peak brightness of 8000nits, supporting 3840Hz high-frequency PWM;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;50-megapixel OIS main camera, 5-megapixel ultra-wide-angle, 16-megapixel front camera;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features Hongyan Six-Wing antenna and self-developed RF enhancement chip C1+, supporting 25 antennas and 100% frame antenna coverage;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body thickness of 7.98mm, featuring a four-corner mortise and tenon stress-relief frame structure, supporting IP68 + IP69 + IP69K protection ratings;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available in three color options: &quot;Sunrise Orange,&quot; &quot;Snowfield White,&quot; and &quot;Phantom Night Black.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Regarding pricing, the 12GB+256GB model is priced at 2699 yuan, and the 12GB+512GB model is priced at 2999 yuan. Pre-orders for the new product have begun, and it will officially go on sale on January 9th at 10:08 AM.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             售价方面，12GB+256GB 售价 2699 元、12GB+512GB 售价 2999 元。新品已开启预售，将于 1 月 9 日 10:08 正式开售。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to phones, Honor also released the Honor Tablet 10 Pro and Honor Tablet X10 Pro. The former features a 144Hz Oasis Eye Protection Soft Light Screen and the Dimensity 8350 Extreme Edition chip, and a Year of the Horse New Year gift box set is also launched, including the new Honor Magic-Pencil 4s stylus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除手机外，荣耀同步发布荣耀平板 10 Pro 与荣耀平板 X10 Pro。前者搭载 144Hz 绿洲护眼柔光屏与天玑 8350 至尊版芯片，并推出马年新春礼盒套装，包含全新荣耀 Magic-Pencil 4s 手写笔。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Honor Tablet 10 Pro standard edition is priced at 2499 yuan, and the soft light edition is priced at 2699 yuan; the gift box edition maintains the same price and includes a stylus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            荣耀平板 10 Pro 标准版售价 2499 元，柔光版售价 2699 元；礼盒版售价保持一致并附赠手写笔。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Honor Tablet X10 Pro offers three configurations: 8GB+128GB, 8GB+256GB, and a soft light version, with prices ranging from 1499 yuan to 1899 yuan, all available for sale on January 9th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            荣耀平板 X10 Pro 提供 8GB+128GB、8GB+256GB 与柔光版三种配置，售价区间为 1499 元至 1899 元，均将于 1 月 9 日开售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>卢伟冰：REDMI Turbo 5 Max 是「2.5K 档最佳选择」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">卢伟冰：REDMI-Turbo-5-Max-是「2.5K-档最佳选择」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/17013008-4f8d-4ec9-89e5-2620be7c08df.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, REDMI phones released a new teaser poster for the upcoming &quot;Turbo 5 Max&quot; model. Lu Weibing, Partner and President of Xiaomi Group, stated, &quot;I am confident that this is the best choice in the 2.5K price segment this year,&quot; emphasizing that the phone will offer a &quot;Max&quot; level experience in terms of performance, battery life, and texture.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，REDMI 手机释出即将发布的新机「Turbo 5 Max」的全新预热海报。小米集团合伙人、总裁卢伟冰表示「我有信心，这就是 2.5K 价格档今年最好的选择」，强调该机在性能、续航与质感上均将提供「Max」级体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Related configuration leaks are summarized as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相关配置爆料整理如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First to feature the Dimensity 9 series processor;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 1.5K flat screen, complemented by 3D ultrasonic fingerprint, metal frame, and glass back cover;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 100W fast charging and symmetrical dual speakers, but the motor is uniformly an X-axis solution;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to feature Xiaomi Jinshajiang battery, with a capacity that will be the largest in Xiaomi's history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>字节跳动否认「豆包 AI 眼镜即将出货」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">字节跳动否认「豆包-AI-眼镜即将出货」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Rumors about the shipment of ByteDance's &quot;Doubao AI Glasses&quot; sparked widespread attention yesterday, but ByteDance has explicitly denied the related news.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            围绕字节跳动旗下「豆包 AI 眼镜」的出货传闻昨天引发广泛关注，但字节方面已明确否认相关消息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to LanJing News, ByteDance's &quot;Doubao AI Glasses&quot; have entered the final stage before shipment. The product was conceptualized less than a year ago, jointly developed by ByteDance and Longcheer Technology, with R&amp;amp;D based at Longcheer's Huizhou factory and mass production handled by Longcheer's Nanchang factory.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据蓝鲸新闻报道 ，字节跳动旗下「豆包 AI 眼镜」已进入出货前的最后阶段，产品立项不足一年，由字节跳动与龙旗科技联合研发，研发落地于龙旗惠州工厂，量产由龙旗南昌工厂负责。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             However, in response to market enthusiasm, a Doubao spokesperson told the media: the aforementioned rumors are &quot;untrue,&quot; and currently there are &quot;no clear sales plans.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             不过，面对市场热度，豆包相关负责人向媒体回应称：上述传闻「不实」，目前「没有明确销售计划」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Despite official denials, previous intensive leaks from the supply chain continue to keep this product under high scrutiny.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管官方否认，但供应链端此前的密集爆料仍使这款产品保持高度关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Relevant information indicates that the rumored core functions of Doubao AI Glasses will revolve around ByteDance's large model capabilities, offering various versions with or without cameras, and with or without displays; the screenless version was reportedly planned for release in the first quarter of this year, while the display-equipped version is expected to debut in the fourth quarter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相关信息显示，传闻中的豆包 AI 眼镜核心功能将围绕字节的大模型能力展开，提供是否带拍照、是否带显示等多种版本选择；无屏版本据称原计划在今年第一季度推出，带显示版本则预计在第四季度亮相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In recent years, ByteDance has continuously increased its investment in &quot;AI + hardware&quot; initiatives, including acquiring VR brand PICO, investing in smart glasses company Liweike, and launching the AI smart earphone Ola Friend.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            字节跳动近年来持续加码「AI + 硬件」布局，包括收购 VR 品牌 PICO、投资智能眼镜公司李未可，以及推出 AI 智能体耳机 Ola Friend。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Its Doubao large model has been integrated into devices from multiple terminal manufacturers, with daily Tokens call volume exceeding 50 trillion in December last year. Against the backdrop of slowing growth in mobile internet, smart glasses are considered a crucial entry point for next-generation human-computer interaction, and the market remains highly attentive to ByteDance's moves in this area.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其豆包大模型已接入多家终端厂商设备，日均 Tokens 调用量在去年 12 月突破 50 万亿。在移动互联网增长趋缓的背景下，智能眼镜被视为下一代人机交互的重要入口，市场对字节在该领域的动作保持高度关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>高通发布骁龙 X2 Plus：AI 算力 80 TOPS，主攻中高端 Windows PC</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">高通发布骁龙-X2-Plus：AI-算力-80-TOPS，主攻中高端-Windows-PC</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a0aedb11-09c5-423b-972f-2edbac2cd87a.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Today, at CES, Qualcomm officially unveiled the new Snapdragon X2 Plus processor, targeting the mid-to-high-end Windows laptop market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天，在 CES 上，高通正式发布面向中高端 Windows 笔记本市场的全新处理器骁龙 X2 Plus。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Qualcomm stated that the Snapdragon X2 Plus, serving as a complementary product to last year's flagship X2 Elite and X2 Elite Extreme, offers both 6-core and 10-core versions, both utilizing the third-generation Oryon CPU architecture and built on a 3nm process.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高通表示，骁龙 X2 Plus 作为去年旗舰级 X2 Elite 与 X2 Elite Extreme 之后的补位产品，提供 6 核与 10 核两种版本，均采用第三代 Oryon CPU 架构，并基于 3nm 工艺打造。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Official data shows that the 10-core version improves single-core performance by 35% and multi-core performance by 17% in Geekbench 6 compared to the previous generation X Plus; the 6-core version also sees a 10% increase in multi-core performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方数据显示，10 核版本在 Geekbench 6 单核性能相比上一代 X Plus 提升 35%，多核提升 17%；6 核版本多核性能也提升 10%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In reference design tests conducted at CES, the 10-core version scored 3323 in single-core and 15084 in multi-core, outperforming Intel Core Ultra 7 256V and AMD Ryzen AI 7 350.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 CES 现场的参考设计测试中，10 核版本跑出单核 3323 分、多核 15084 分，领先英特尔 Core Ultra 7 256V 与 AMD Ryzen AI 7 350。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of graphics performance, the 10-core version shows a 29% improvement in the 3DMark Steel Nomad Light test, while the 6-core version improves by 39%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            图形性能方面，10 核版本在 3DMark Steel Nomad Light 测试中提升 29%，6 核版本提升 39%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            AI capability is a key focus of this upgrade. The Snapdragon X2 Plus integrates a new generation Hexagon NPU, delivering AI computing power of 80 TOPS, a 78% increase over the previous generation, far exceeding the 40 TOPS baseline requirement for Copilot+ PCs. It also features an Adreno X2 series GPU, supporting hardware ray tracing and variable rate shading.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            AI 能力是此次升级重点。骁龙 X2 Plus 集成新一代 Hexagon NPU，AI 算力达 80 TOPS，较上一代提升 78%，远超 Copilot+ PC 的 40 TOPS 基线要求。同时搭载 Adreno X2 系列 GPU，支持硬件光追与可变速率着色。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Qualcomm emphasizes that the X2 Plus boasts a 43% improvement in power efficiency, enabling multi-day battery life, and supports features such as Wi-Fi 7, optional 5G, industrial-grade secure island, and intelligent power management.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高通强调，X2 Plus 在能效方面提升 43%，可实现多日续航，并支持 Wi-Fi 7、可选 5G、工业级安全岛与智能电源管理等功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Qualcomm stated that laptops equipped with the Snapdragon X2 Plus will be available in the first half of this year, with OEMs like Lenovo, HP, and ASUS set to announce related products during CES.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高通表示，搭载骁龙 X2 Plus 的笔记本将在今年上半年上市，联想、惠普、华硕等 OEM 将在 CES 期间发布相关产品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>宏碁发布新款 Swift 16 AI：全球最大触觉触控板亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">宏碁发布新款-Swift-16-AI：全球最大触觉触控板亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/09cd9039-ff75-4201-80d9-757259fc35a5.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Android Authority, Acer today unveiled several new consumer laptops at CES 2026, comprehensively upgrading its Swift and Aspire series with a focus on enhancing processor performance, AI capabilities, connectivity specifications, and chassis design.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Android Authority 报道，宏碁今天在 CES 2026 上发布多款面向消费者的笔记本新品，对 Swift 与 Aspire 系列进行全面升级，重点围绕处理器性能、AI 能力、连接规格与机身设计进行强化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;h3-p-pair&quot; data-pair-id=&quot;pair-17&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.3rem; margin-bottom: 1.2rem; font-family: PingFangSC-Regular,'Helvetica Neue',Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; font-size: .875rem; color: #121212; letter-spacing: .01875rem; text-align: justify;&quot;&gt;
           Swift 16 AI
          &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optionally features up to Intel Core Ultra X9 388H processor, integrating Intel Arc B390 graphics unit;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a pressure touchpad claimed to be &quot;the world's largest,&quot; measuring 175.5mm × 109.7mm, and supporting MPP 2.5 stylus input;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen can be configured up to a 16-inch 120Hz 3K OLED touchscreen panel;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 5.4, and offers ports such as dual Thunderbolt 4, USB Type-A, HDMI 2.1, and a microSD card slot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to launch in the US market in Q1 this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Swift Edge 14 AI and Swift Edge 16 AI
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Swift Edge 14 AI 与 Swift Edge 16 AI
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a new generation Intel Core Ultra processor, with options up to Ultra 9 386H;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body material has been upgraded from magnesium-aluminum alloy to stainless steel-magnesium alloy, reducing the weight of the 14-inch model to 900g, while the 16-inch model remains at 1.25kg;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both products support Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 6.0, and include a programmable shortcut key called &quot;Acer My Key,&quot; which can quickly launch applications, websites, or Windows 11's AI features;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to be released in Q2 this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Swift Go 14 AI and Swift Go 16 AI
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Swift Go 14 AI 与 Swift Go 16 AI
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to Intel Core Ultra X9 388H processor, equipped with Intel Arc B390 graphics unit;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports Wi-Fi 7, Bluetooth 6.0, and Acer My Key;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expected to be launched in the US in Q2 this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Aspire 14 AI and Aspire 16 AI are upgraded to the highest Intel Core Ultra 9 386H processor and include the Acer My Key shortcut. The Aspire 16 AI is expected to launch in Q2 this year, while the Aspire 14 AI will be released in Q3 this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Aspire 14 AI 与 Aspire 16 AI 则升级至最高 Intel Core Ultra 9 386H 处理器，并加入 Acer My Key 快捷键。Aspire 16 AI 预计今年 Q2 上市，Aspire 14 AI 则将在今年 Q3 推出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>戴尔重启 XPS 系列，推出更薄新机并强化 AI 性能</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">戴尔重启-XPS-系列，推出更薄新机并强化-AI-性能</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/78c801c4-4a8d-483d-b360-14b58a840598.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Bloomberg, Dell announced at CES 2026 the relaunch of its high-end laptop brand XPS, which was discontinued last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据彭博社报道，戴尔在 CES 2026 上宣布重启去年停更的高端笔电品牌 XPS。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dell COO Jeff Clarke stated that the company's PC business &quot;deviated somewhat&quot; in the past year and admitted that it &quot;did not listen to user feedback&quot; on brand strategy, thus deciding to restore the XPS brand system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            戴尔 COO Jeff Clarke 表示，公司 PC 业务在过去一年「有些偏航」，并坦言在品牌策略上「没有听取用户意见」，因此决定恢复 XPS 品牌体系。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Clarke began directly overseeing the PC business last summer. He pointed out that tariff pressures, AI implementation falling short of expectations, and &quot;one of the slowest CPU iterations of his career&quot; collectively led to Dell's underperformance in the past year. He apologized to users and industry professionals, stating: &quot;You were right about the brand issues.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Clarke 去年夏天开始直接负责 PC 业务。他指出，关税压力、AI 落地未达预期，以及「职业生涯中最缓慢的 CPU 迭代之一」共同导致戴尔过去一年的表现不如预期。他向用户和行业人士致歉称：「你们在品牌问题上是对的。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dell stated that partial configurations for the two new models, XPS 14 and XPS 16, will be available starting this Tuesday, and the XPS 13 will also return later this year. In the initial versions, the XPS 14 starts at $2050 (approximately 14320 RMB), and the XPS 16 starts at $2200 (approximately 15370 RMB). More configurations under $2000 (approximately 14,000 RMB) will be released in February this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            戴尔表示，两款新机型 XPS 14 与 XPS 16 将从本周二起提供部分配置，XPS 13 也将在今年稍晚回归。初期版本中，XPS 14 起售价为 2050 美元（约 14320 元人民币），XPS 16 起售价为 2200 美元（约 15370 元），更多低于 2000 美元（约 1.4 万元）的配置将于今年 2 月推出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new XPS series continues the features of a metal body, thin and light design, and narrow bezels, positioning itself in direct competition with Apple's MacBook Air 13-inch and 15-inch models. Both models have a thickness of 14.6 mm, making them Dell's thinnest laptops to date; in terms of weight, the 14-inch is approximately 1.36 kg, and the 16-inch is approximately 1.63 kg.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新款 XPS 系列延续金属机身、轻薄设计与窄边框特征，定位与苹果 MacBook Air 13 英寸与 15 英寸机型直接竞争。两款机型厚度均为 14.6 mm，为戴尔迄今最薄的笔电；重量方面，14 英寸约 1.36 kg，16 英寸约 1.63 kg。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of internal configuration, the new XPS adopts Intel's latest chips, focusing on improving AI computing performance. Dell has also redesigned the cooling system, making the fans larger, thinner, quieter, and more energy-efficient.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            内部配置方面，新款 XPS 采用英特尔最新芯片，重点提升 AI 运算性能。戴尔同时重新设计散热系统，使风扇更大、更薄、更安静且更节能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Officially, with an LCD screen configuration, the battery life can reach 27 hours; if an OLED screen is chosen, the battery life will decrease.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方称，在搭载 LCD 屏幕的配置下，续航可达 27 小时；若选择 OLED 屏幕，续航将有所下降。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The upcoming XPS 13, making its return, first debuted at CES in 2012. The new version will continue the design language of the current XPS series and further reduce its thickness to under 13 mm.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次即将回归的 XPS 13 最早于 2012 年 CES 首次亮相，新版本将延续本次 XPS 系列的设计语言，并进一步缩减厚度至 13 mm 以下。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>真我 Neo 8「赛博紫」配色曝光</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">真我-Neo-8「赛博紫」配色曝光</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/39da0244-622f-4883-a6ad-b92933e49fa3.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, realme officially released a new teaser poster for its new phone, the realme Neo 8, revealing its main color &quot;Cyber Purple&quot; for the first time. The device features a metal frame and transparent glass design, continuing the previous &quot;Awakening Halo&quot; system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，真我手机官方发布新机真我 Neo 8 的全新预热海报，首曝主打配色「赛博紫」，机身采用金属中框与透明玻璃设计，并延续此前的「觉醒光环」系统。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to blogger @DigitalChatStation and previously exposed 3C certification information, the realme Neo 8's parameters are summarized as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据博主 @数码闲聊站 和此前曝光的 3C 认证信息，真我 Neo 8 参数汇总如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with the fifth-generation Snapdragon 8 chip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a &quot;Samsung flagship large flat screen&quot; with support for 165Hz ultra-high refresh rate;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with an 8000mAh single-cell large battery;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 3D ultrasonic fingerprint recognition and IP68 dust and water resistance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一加 Turbo 6 系列将搭载 9000mAh 大电池</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">一加-Turbo-6-系列将搭载-9000mAh-大电池</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/26be8a49-6e63-4b65-98e4-7fbe3f89bc46.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OnePlus announced yesterday that the OnePlus Turbo 6 series will feature a large 9000mAh battery and adopt a new X25 spherical silicon-carbon anode material, focusing on higher energy density and longer cycle life. The new phone will be released on January 8th at 7 PM.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一加手机昨天宣布，一加 Turbo 6 系列将配备 9000mAh 大电池，并采用全新的 X25 球形硅碳负极材料，主打更高能量密度与更长循环寿命，新机将于 1 月 8 日晚 7 点发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official statement claims that the battery can still be used normally in a -20℃ low-temperature environment and boasts five years of durable battery health performance, while also featuring a self-developed battery algorithm to enhance overall battery life and safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方称该电池在 -20℃ 低温环境下仍可正常使用，并宣称具备五年耐用电池健康表现，同时搭载自研电池算法以提升整体续航与安全性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OnePlus had previously confirmed that the Turbo 6 series will come in three color options: Chasing Silver, Wilderness Green, and Lone Black. Among them, Chasing Silver uses 3D holographic engraving technology, where the pattern flows with light and shadow.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一加此前已确认，Turbo 6 系列外观配色包括追光银、旷野绿与独行黑三款，其中追光银采用 3D 全息雕刻工艺，图案会随光影流动。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of configuration, the OnePlus Turbo 6 will be equipped with the fourth-generation Snapdragon 8s Fengchi Edition processor, support 80W wired charging, and come with &quot;Fengchi Game Kernel&quot; out of the box.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            配置方面，一加 Turbo 6 将搭载第四代骁龙 8s 风驰版处理器，支持 80W 有线充电，出厂支持「风驰游戏内核」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>零一万物发布万智 2.5，多智能体进入企业规模化上岗阶段</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">零一万物发布万智-2.5，多智能体进入企业规模化上岗阶段</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/483e9057-cebe-44f7-bff3-d4a9ab2bc1f4.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, 01.AI officially launched Wanzhi 2.5 enterprise-grade multi-agent, emphasizing that AI is moving from &quot;tool intelligence&quot; to &quot;organizational intelligence.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，零一万物正式推出万智 2.5 企业级多智能体，强调 AI 正从「工具智能」迈向「组织智能」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            01.AI stated that Multi-Agent systems are reshaping enterprise organizational structures. Compared to the traditional model where a single Agent performs tasks, multi-agents can perform division of labor, collaboration, verification, and optimization under goal-oriented guidance, achieving a leap from &quot;getting things done&quot; to &quot;achieving good results.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            零一万物表示，多智能体（Multi-Agent）正在重塑企业组织结构。相比传统由单一 Agent 执行任务的模式，多智能体可在目标导向下进行分工、协作、校验与优化，实现从「做完事情」到「做好结果」的跃迁。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the &quot;Alternative Marketing Department&quot; scenario, users only need to input a single Prompt, and the &quot;Marketing Director Agent&quot; will automatically break down tasks and coordinate sub-agents such as visual designers, content managers, and media specialists to collaboratively complete the entire marketing process;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在「平替市场部」场景中，用户仅需输入一个 Prompt，「市场总监 Agent」便会自动拆解任务并调度视觉设计、内容经理、媒介专家等子智能体协同完成整套营销流程；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the &quot;Alternative HR&quot; scenario, multi-agents can handle unstructured tasks such as job posting, resume screening, and interview assistance, accurately capturing hiring intentions and performing multi-dimensional matching.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在「平替 HR」场景中，多智能体可处理职位发布、简历筛选、面试辅助等非结构化任务，精准捕捉用人意图并进行全维度匹配。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            An IDC report points out that the $650 billion enterprise application software market is being reshaped by AI agents. It is estimated that by 2031, the penetration rate of agents in customer service, sales, and marketing applications will approach 100%. IDC also predicts that China's enterprise-grade agent market size will exceed $27 billion by 2028.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            IDC 报告指出，价值 6500 亿美元的企业级应用软件市场正被 AI 智能体重塑，预计到 2031 年，客服、销售与营销类应用的智能体渗透率将接近 100%。IDC 同时预测，中国企业级智能体市场规模将在 2028 年达到 270 亿美元以上。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Based on its experience collaborating with leading clients in industries such as energy, finance, and manufacturing, 01.AI proposes six major trend judgments for Chinese enterprise agents:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            基于与能源、金融、制造等行业头部客户的合作经验，零一万物提出中国企业智能体的六大趋势性判断：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agents evolve from &quot;one person, one tool&quot; to &quot;one person, one team,&quot; and enterprise capabilities will be encapsulated, reused, and combined in a modular fashion;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-agents need to possess the three TAB elements: Teamwork (Team), Business Auto-pilot (Auto-pilot), and Business Restructuring (Business);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China will become the &quot;super engine&quot; for the global implementation of multi-agent systems, relying on a complete industrial chain, open-source ecosystem, and complex business scenarios;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;top-down project&quot; will become a key path for enterprises to gain AI dividends, and FDEs (Forward-deployed Engineers) will play an important role in the implementation process;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligent agents will feed back into enterprise digital infrastructure, forming a &quot;data flywheel&quot; through automatic labeling, data cleaning, and behavioral feedback, promoting the autonomous evolution of the enterprise knowledge system;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2026 will be the first year for the large-scale deployment of enterprise multi-agent systems, and &quot;Agent Operations Specialist&quot; will become an emerging position in enterprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Kai-Fu Lee, founder and CEO of 01.AI, stated that AI transformation must be driven by a &quot;top-down project,&quot; and enterprises need to start from top-level strategy to deeply embed intelligent agents into core business processes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            零一万物创始人及 CEO 李开复表示，AI 转型必须由「一把手工程」推动，企业需要从顶层战略出发，将智能体深度嵌入核心业务链路。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhao Binqiang, Vice President of Technology and Product Center at 01.AI, pointed out that the core value of multi-agent systems lies in driving enterprises from &quot;talent dependence&quot; to &quot;capability softwareization,&quot; transforming the implicit knowledge of top talent into reusable digital assets by solidifying decision-making logic.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            零一万物技术与产品中心副总裁赵斌强指出，多智能体的核心价值在于推动企业从「人才依赖」走向「能力软件化」，通过沉淀决策逻辑，将顶尖人才的隐性知识转化为可复用的数字资产。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this release, 01.AI simultaneously launched the Wanzhi Platform version 2.5, featuring enterprise-grade multi-agent systems as one of its core applications. The platform adopts a &quot;code-first, model-driven&quot; architecture, ensuring the stability of multi-agent systems in real production environments through the MCP protocol and security sandbox.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在此次发布中，零一万物同步推出万智平台 2.5 版本，将企业级多智能体作为核心应用之一。平台采用「代码先行、模型驱动」架构，通过 MCP 协议与安全沙箱确保多智能体在真实生产环境中的稳定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9999 元起，TCL 发布 Q10M 系列电视新品：SQD‑Mini LED 技术全面下放</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">9999-元起，TCL-发布-Q10M-系列电视新品：SQD‑Mini-LED-技术全面下放</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e3293a9d-54d3-4793-ad0b-66f7a3387496.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, TCL officially released its new SQD‑Mini LED TV Q10M series with the theme &quot;True Peak, True Popularity,&quot; highlighting the &quot;picture quality iron triangle&quot; (high contrast + high peak brightness + high color gamut), including two models: Q10M Pro and Q10M.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，TCL 以「真巅峰 真普及」为主题正式发布 SQD‑Mini LED 电视新品 Q10M 系列，主打「画质铁三角」（高对比度 + 高峰值亮度 + 高色域），包括 Q10M Pro 与 Q10M 两款机型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Q10M Pro:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Q10M Pro：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with full SQD‑Mini LED technology;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;100% BT.2020 global high color gamut, ΔE&amp;lt;0.9;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XDR brilliant brightness up to 8500 nits;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 98-inch, 85-inch, 75-inch, and 65-inch versions are equipped with 8052, 5832, 4608, and 3528 local dimming zones, respectively;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adopts a &quot;Borderless Extreme View&quot; design, achieving nearly 100% full-screen display;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with B&amp;amp;O professional audio and Lingkong System 3.0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing, the retail prices for the Q10M Pro 98-inch, 85-inch, 75-inch, and 65-inch versions are 31999 yuan, 21999 yuan, 16999 yuan, and 11999 yuan, respectively. Pre-orders are now open, with official sales starting on January 15.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，Q10M Pro 98 吋、85 吋、75 吋、65 吋四个版本零售价分别为 31999 元、21999 元、16999 元、11999 元，目前已开启预售，1 月 15 日正式开售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Q10M:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Q10M：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with SQD‑Mini LED technology;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features Super Quantum Dot and Super Butterfly Wing Huayao Screen;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covers 100% BT.2020 global high color gamut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing, the retail prices for the Q10M 98-inch, 85-inch, 75-inch, and 65-inch models are 24999 yuan, 15999 yuan, 12999 yuan, and 9999 yuan respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，Q10M 98 吋、85 吋、75 吋、65 吋零售价分别为 24999 元、15999 元、12999 元、9999 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>179 美元，Plaud 发布更易用的 AI 录音笔 NotePin S</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">179-美元，Plaud-发布更易用的-AI-录音笔-NotePin-S</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b14fce15-341e-46b8-ae02-3df963d6637a.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, Plaud updated its portable AI recording device NotePin series at CES 2026, launching the new NotePin S and simultaneously releasing the Plaud Desktop application for Mac and PC, providing a unified recording and transcription experience for both online and offline meetings.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，Plaud 在 CES 2026 上更新了其便携式 AI 录音设备 NotePin 系列，推出全新的 NotePin S，并同步上线适用于 Mac 与 PC 的 Plaud Desktop 应用，为线上线下会议提供统一的录音与转写体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The appearance of the Plaud NotePin S is largely consistent with the original NotePin released last year, still featuring a small, wearable design similar to a smart bracelet, and comes with accessories such as a lanyard, wristband, clip, and magnetic pin in the package.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Plaud NotePin S 的外观与去年发布的初代 NotePin 基本一致，依旧采用类似智能手环的小型可穿戴设计，并随包装附带挂绳、腕带、夹子与磁吸别针等配件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new model offers three colors: black, purple, and silver. Its volume, battery life, and support for Apple Find My remain consistent with the previous generation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新款提供黑色、紫色与银色三种配色，体积、电池续航与对苹果 Find My 的支持均与前代保持一致。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The core change in this upgrade is the addition of physical buttons. The original NotePin relied on long-pressing the device for haptic feedback operations, but some users reported that it was prone to accidental touches or failed to start recording successfully in fast-paced scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次升级的核心变化在于加入了物理按键。初代 NotePin 依赖长按机身进行触觉反馈式操作，但部分用户反馈在快速场景中容易误触或未成功启动录音。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The NotePin S starts recording by long-pressing the button and adds key markers with a short press, making operations clearer and reducing the risk of missed recordings. Plaud states that the core competitiveness of AI recording devices lies in 'ease of use,' and physical buttons can reduce operational ambiguity and improve reliability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            NotePin S 通过长按按键启动录音、短按添加重点标记，使操作更明确，降低漏录风险。Plaud 表示，AI 录音设备的核心竞争力在于「易用性」，物理按键能减少操作歧义，提高可靠性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the new Plaud Desktop application can automatically detect online meetings such as Zoom, Meet, and Teams in the background, and record system audio and microphone input.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，全新的 Plaud Desktop 应用可在后台自动检测 Zoom、Meet、Teams 等线上会议，并录制系统音频与麦克风输入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Users can choose automatic recording or manual triggering, and there's no need for a bot account to join the meeting. All recordings and notes will synchronize with Plaud hardware devices, forming a unified meeting audio library.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            用户可选择自动录制或手动触发，且无需让机器人账号加入会议。所有录音与笔记会与 Plaud 硬件设备同步，形成统一的会议音频资料库。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The NotePin S is now available for $179 (approximately 1250 yuan), which is $20 more than the original model, which will be gradually discontinued. Plaud Desktop is now free for all Note and NotePin users.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            NotePin S 现已上市，售价 179 美元（约 1250 元人民币），比初代贵 20 美元，原型号将逐步停产。Plaud Desktop 已向所有 Note 与 NotePin 用户免费开放。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>格力表态：不涨价、不跟进「铝代铜」方案</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">格力表态：不涨价、不跟进「铝代铜」方案</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1162573a-0d1d-4638-8a72-cb0a5a53f9d2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Gree's official WeChat account 'Gree Wenchuan' issued a statement saying that the company recently received inquiries from multiple parties regarding some enterprises raising air conditioner prices and promoting the 'aluminum-for-copper' solution. Gree stated that it will actively respond to this year's national home appliance subsidy policy, continue to benefit consumers, and promised that Gree household air conditioner prices will remain stable.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，格力官微「格力文传」发布说明称，近期公司收到多方关于部分企业上调空调价格及推进「铝代铜」方案的询问。格力表示，将积极响应今年家电国家补贴政策，继续让利消费者，并承诺格力家用空调价格保持稳定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding material usage, Gree emphasized that to meet the ten-year free warranty service standard for household air conditioners, the company will not currently adopt the 'aluminum-for-copper' solution.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在材料使用方面，格力强调，为满足家用空调十年免费包修服务标准，公司目前不会采用「铝代铜」方案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Gree pointed out that although aluminum is cheaper, it still has gaps compared to copper in key indicators such as melting point, thermal conductivity, resistivity, corrosion resistance, and long-term reliability. Therefore, it will not be rashly used before meeting Gree's quality and technical standards.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            格力指出，尽管铝材成本更低，但在熔点、热传导、电阻率、耐腐蚀性及长期可靠性等关键指标上仍与铜存在差距，因此在未达到格力质量与技术标准前，不会贸然使用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Gree also stated that if future related research fully meets quality requirements and is officially applied, the company will clearly mark it to ensure consumers' right to know and right to choose.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            格力同时表示，若未来相关研究完全满足质量要求并正式应用，公司将进行明确标注，以保障消费者的知情权与选择权。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            From an industry background perspective, affected by the continuous rise in copper prices since last year, some air conditioning companies have already announced price adjustments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从行业背景来看，受去年以来铜价持续上涨影响，已有空调企业宣布调价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Midea Group announced in December last year that, effective December 16, the ex-factory prices of some products would be increased by 5%, citing factors such as a 22% increase in copper prices throughout the year and a 40%-60% increase in refrigerant prices. Against the backdrop of increasing cost pressure, 'aluminum-for-copper' has become a hot topic in the industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            美博集团去年 12 月发布通知称，自 12 月 16 日起部分产品提货价上调 5%，理由包括铜价全年上涨 22%、制冷剂价格上涨 40%—60% 等因素。在成本压力加剧的背景下，「铝代铜」成为行业热议方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Gree has previously stated publicly multiple times that it will only adopt relevant solutions when aluminum fully meets the technical conditions of copper. Dong Mingzhu said at the end of last year: 'Can aluminum replace it? Yes, it can. But Gree will absolutely not use it until there is 100% certainty.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            格力方面此前多次公开表态，只有在铝材完全达到铜材的技术条件后才会采用相关方案。董明珠在去年底曾表示：「铝能不能代？可以代。但在没有百分之百把握之前，格力绝对不会使用。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曾因「10 元打包袋」上热搜的饭店仍在「宰客」，市场监管部门：调查中</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曾因「10-元打包袋」上热搜的饭店仍在「宰客」，市场监管部门：调查中</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/43f3f74e-26bb-4f1d-9f1b-0352530e5ea3.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from National Business Daily, recently, Lao Penglai Restaurant in Penglai District, Yantai, Shandong, has once again drawn attention due to alleged price fraud and food safety issues.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据每日经济新闻报道，近日，山东烟台蓬莱区的老蓬莱酒楼再次因涉嫌价格欺诈与食品安全问题引发关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Multiple consumers claimed that when they dined at the restaurant during last year's National Day Golden Week, they encountered problems such as inconsistent dish prices, suspected spoiled ingredients, and expired beverages. For example, crabs were quoted at 58 yuan per jin (0.5 kg) when ordering, but were charged at 58 yuan per crab when settling the bill, and two crabs of different sizes were also uniformly priced.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多名消费者称，他们在去年十一黄金周期间到该店就餐时，遇到菜品价格前后不一致、食材疑似变质、饮料过期等问题。其中，螃蟹在点餐时被告知为 58 元一斤，但结账时却按 58 元一只计算，两只大小不同的螃蟹也被统一定价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After consumers pointed out the error, the restaurant only waived a 10 yuan difference. Furthermore, after the crabs were steamed, they had black liquid, an unusual smell, and mushy meat, making them inedible.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            消费者指出错误后，店家仅抹掉 10 元差价。此外，螃蟹蒸熟后出现黑汤、异味，肉质发面，无法食用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to the crabs, consumers also reported discrepancies between the paper menu and the wall-mounted menu prices. For example, the merchant introduced 'Fish Pot Pancakes' at 88 yuan per jin, but it was ultimately charged at 128 yuan per serving, and was not weighed in front of the customer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除螃蟹外，消费者还反映，店内纸质菜单与墙贴菜单价格不符。例如，商家介绍「鱼锅饼子」价格为 88 元一斤，但最终按 128 元一份收费，且未当面过秤。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Consumers also discovered that the &quot;miscellaneous fish&quot; ingredients used for promotion were actually frozen mackerel sold at 10 yuan for 3 jin, which the merchant later admitted.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            宣传所用「杂鱼」原料也被消费者发现实际为市场价 10 元 3 斤的冷冻鲅鱼，商家随后承认。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Beverage issues also sparked controversy. Consumers claimed that the production date of the beverages provided by the store showed they had expired half a year ago in April last year, but the store denied the beverages were from within the store, stating they were brought by customers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            饮料问题同样引发争议。消费者称，店家提供的饮料生产日期显示已于去年 4 月过期半年，但店方否认饮料来自店内，并称是顾客自带。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             In response, the Penglai Tourism Resort Management Committee stated that it has noted the relevant complaints, and the local market supervision department is conducting investigations and collecting evidence. If the situation is confirmed, it will be handled according to laws and regulations.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             对此，蓬莱旅游度假区管理委员会表示，已关注到相关投诉，当地市场监管部门正开展调查取证，如情况属实，将依法依规处理。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this is not the first time the store has attracted public attention due to pricing issues. As early as September 2024, Lao Penglai Restaurant made headlines for issues such as &quot;10 yuan for a plastic bag&quot; and &quot;charging for complimentary mackerel dumplings.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，该店并非首次因价格问题引发舆论关注。早在 2024 年 9 月，老蓬莱酒楼因「打包塑料袋 10 元一个」「赠送鲅鱼饺子收费」等问题登上热搜。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At that time, the Penglai District Market Supervision Bureau's investigation found that the store had behaviors such as failing to clearly mark prices and not fulfilling service or price commitments, and a case had been filed for handling.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            彼时，蓬莱区市场监管局调查发现，该店存在未明码标价、不履行服务或价格承诺等行为，并已立案处理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>从「绕地球」到亏损扩大，香飘飘冲泡业务持续下滑</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">从「绕地球」到亏损扩大，香飘飘冲泡业务持续下滑</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/440b7bb6-6a82-446e-8cb6-8ad77058b032.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 36Kr Finance, Xiangpiaopiao's performance continued to be under pressure in the first three quarters of this year, with the decline in its main instant milk tea business accelerating. The company is hoping for multi-pronged breakthroughs in new products, ready-to-drink business, and channel innovation, but whether it can achieve a performance turnaround in the fourth quarter of this year remains uncertain.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 36 氪财经报道，香飘飘在今年前三季度的业绩继续承压，主营冲泡奶茶业务的下滑趋势进一步加速，公司寄望于新品、即饮业务与渠道创新的多线突破，能否在今年第四季度实现业绩反转仍存在不确定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the first three quarters of last year, Xiangpiaopiao achieved a total operating income of 1.684 billion yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 13.12%; the net profit attributable to shareholders of listed companies was a loss of 89.2072 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 603.07%, turning from profit to loss, with the scale of loss reaching a new high in recent years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            香飘飘在去年前三季度实现营业总收入 16.84 亿元，同比下降 13.12%；归属于上市公司股东的净利润亏损 8920.72 万元，同比下滑 603.07%，由盈转亏，亏损规模创近年新高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In 2008, the company became a national brand with the slogan &quot;selling over 300 million cups a year, enough to circle the Earth if lined up.&quot; However, with the rapid expansion of freshly made tea beverages in various markets, the advantages of its instant products in terms of health, convenience, and cost-effectiveness have continuously weakened.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司在 2008 年凭借「一年卖出 3 亿多杯，杯子连起来可以绕地球一圈」的广告语成为国民品牌，但随着现制茶饮在各级市场快速扩张，其冲泡产品在健康性、便捷性与性价比上的优势不断削弱。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the fiercely competitive takeaway market, freshly made tea beverage brands further squeezed the survival space of instant milk tea through subsidies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在价格竞争激烈的外卖市场中，现制茶饮品牌通过补贴进一步压缩冲泡奶茶的生存空间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Platforms like Meituan and JD.com have offered subsidized prices for &quot;2 yuan milk tea,&quot; while a cup of original instant milk tea at Xiangpiaopiao's Tmall flagship store sells for 4 yuan after coupons, and Mixue Bingcheng's medium pearl milk tea is 6 yuan. Sales of the instant business have continuously declined since 2020, dropping to 32.7854 million standard cases in 2024, a decrease of about one and a half &quot;Earth-circling&quot; sales compared to the 2019 peak.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            美团、京东等平台曾出现「2 元奶茶」的补贴价，而香飘飘天猫旗舰店一杯原味冲泡奶茶券后售价为 4 元，蜜雪冰城中杯珍珠奶茶则为 6 元。冲泡业务销量自 2020 年起持续下滑，2024 年降至 3278.54 万标箱，较 2019 年巅峰减少约一圈半「绕地球」的销量。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the third quarter of this year, Xiangpiaopiao's revenue decreased by 14.5% year-on-year to 649 million yuan, and its net profit attributable to the parent company was 8.18 million yuan, a year-on-year decrease of 82.7%, with instant business revenue decreasing by 26% year-on-year. The company explained that part of the decline in the instant business was due to delayed stocking for the peak season, but inventory levels have returned to a healthy state.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年第三季度，香飘飘营收同比下降 14.5% 至 6.49 亿元，归母净利润 818 万元，同比下降 82.7%，其中冲泡业务收入同比减少 26%。公司解释称，冲泡业务下滑部分源于旺季备货时间延后，但库存水平已回归良性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, inventory and inventory turnover days continued to climb. In the first three quarters of last year, the company's inventory reached 184 million yuan, a slight increase of 7.6% year-on-year. To achieve year-on-year growth in net profit attributable to the parent company this year, Xiangpiaopiao needs to achieve at least 324 million yuan in net profit in the fourth quarter, indicating significant pressure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，存货及周转天数持续攀升。去年前三季度公司存货达 1.84 亿元，同比微增 7.6%。若要实现今年归母净利润同比增长，香飘飘需在第四季度实现至少 3.24 亿元净利，压力显著。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In contrast, the ready-to-drink business has become one of the few growth points. The ready-to-drink product line, centered on Meco fruit tea, has grown for three consecutive years since 2022. In the first three quarters of last year, its revenue reached 833 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 3.92%, and its proportion exceeded that of the instant business for the first time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比之下，即饮业务成为少有的增长点。以 Meco 果汁茶为核心的即饮产品线自 2022 年起连续三年增长，去年前三季度营收达 8.33 亿元，同比增长 3.92%，占比首次超过冲泡业务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company also plans to build a ready-to-drink beverage production base in Thailand to reduce production costs and expand into overseas markets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司也计划在泰国建设即饮饮料生产基地，以降低产能成本并拓展海外市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the channel side, Xiangpiaopiao opened its first batch of offline stores in Hangzhou last year, positioned as experience spaces to collect consumer feedback and provide references for future product development. In addition, the company added &quot;production and sales of health food&quot; to its business scope, but emphasized that its strategic focus remains unchanged, and no related products are currently on the market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在渠道端，香飘飘于去年在杭州开出首批线下门店，定位为体验空间，用于收集消费者反馈，为未来产品研发提供参考。此外，公司新增「保健食品生产与销售」经营范围，但强调战略重心未变，目前暂无相关产品上市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>彭于晏主演《爆水管》定档 1 月 23 日</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">彭于晏主演《爆水管》定档-1-月-23-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f3a2a552-608c-456f-a6dd-2c4591d66653.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The crime comedy &quot;Bursting Pipes&quot; released its first &quot;Peak Crime&quot; trailer yesterday, and the film will be released on January 23.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            犯罪喜剧《爆水管》昨日发布首支「顶疯作案」版预告，影片将于 1 月 23 日上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film revolves around an unexpected confrontation between a Southeast Asian police squad and a tomb-raiding family in Heping Town. The trailer's numerous exaggerated scenes and character interactions have garnered attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片围绕东南亚警察团与盗墓贼家族在和平镇意外交锋展开，预告中呈现的大量夸张桥段与角色互动引发关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The trailer shows that Yu Dahai, the Southeast Asian police officer played by Eddie Peng, is forced to lead his team to &quot;create cases&quot; because &quot;public order is too good, leading to job insecurity,&quot; thus turning the police force into an &quot;automatic case-making machine&quot; overnight.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            预告显示，彭于晏饰演的东南亚警察于大海因「治安太好导致工作不保」，被迫带队「自造案件」，从而让警队一夜之间变成「全自动造案机」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Luo Siji, played by Allen, leads his ancestral tomb-raiding family to &quot;expand overseas business&quot; but unexpectedly gets involved in an ancient tomb treasure case triggered by a burst water pipe at the police station. The two sides &quot;meet in a frenzy&quot; in Heping Town, with everything from street running slogans to Northeastern dialect banter becoming the main source of humor in the trailer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，由艾伦饰演的罗四季则带着祖传盗墓家族「开拓海外业务」，却意外卷入警局水管爆裂引发的古墓宝藏案。两方人马在和平镇「癫疯相见」，从街头跑步口号到东北话互怼，成为预告中的主要笑点来源。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《新狂蟒之灾》开启预售</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《新狂蟒之灾》开启预售</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/229ab9d7-fad5-4a3f-b566-008e138ff865.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;New Anaconda&quot; has now opened for pre-sale and will hit national cinemas this Friday. Produced by Columbia Pictures and starring Paul Rudd and Jack Black, the film combines parody comedy with action and horror elements, making it a highly anticipated work for this year's opening season.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《新狂蟒之灾》现已开启预售，将在本周五登陆全国院线。影片由美国哥伦比亚影片公司出品，保罗·路德与杰克·布莱克主演，以恶搞喜剧风格结合动作、惊悚元素，成为今年开年档期的关注作品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film continues the core setting of giant python pursuit from the series, while also introducing a 'pig teammate' wild boar cub with limited screen time but a strong presence.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片延续系列中巨蟒追击的核心设定，同时加入一只戏份不多但存在感极强的「猪队友」野猪仔。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The character appears as a 'pendant' in the clip, escaping alongside the character played by Jack Black, creating a strong contrast effect, and was praised by audiences for 'redefining the pig teammate'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该角色在片段中以「挂件」形式出现，与杰克 · 布莱克饰演的角色共同逃生，形成强烈反差效果，被观众评价为「重新定义猪队友」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After its overseas release, the film received positive feedback from some audiences. Its North American opening weekend box office performance surpassed Hugh Jackman's 'The Song of the Blues', with a cumulative global box office of 59 million USD.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片在海外上映后获得部分观众的积极反馈，北美首周票房表现超过休 · 杰克曼主演的《蓝调之歌》，全球累计票房达到 5900 万美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《时空奇旅》公布中文配音阵容，1 月 17 日上映</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《时空奇旅》公布中文配音阵容，1-月-17-日上映</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260106_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3a12efbf-4770-4c4b-97df-148b0f5f4bbd.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The French animated film 'The Time Travellers' announced its Chinese voice cast yesterday and will be released nationwide on January 17th this year. This French animated film is produced by Oscar-winning actress Natalie Portman and directed by Hugo Bienvenu. It has won awards at multiple international film festivals and was nominated for a Golden Globe for Best Animated Feature Film.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            法国动画电影《时空奇旅》昨日公布中文配音阵容，将于今年 1 月 17 日在全国上映。这部法国动画电影由奥斯卡影后娜塔莉·波特曼担任制片人、导演于戈·比安弗尼执导，曾在多个国际电影节获得奖项，并入围金球奖最佳动画长片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of Alice, a girl, and Arco, a boy, living in different time and space, who miraculously meet through a rainbow cloak from the future world and embark on a time-traveling adventure together. The Chinese voice acting is handled by Gao Shuqiao (Xiaojiuwo) and Chen Yitong (Duoduo), who play Alice and Arco respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述生活在不同时空的少女艾丽斯与少年阿尔科，通过未来世界的虹光披风奇妙相遇，并共同踏上一段跨越时空的冒险旅程。此次中文配音由高舒乔（小酒窝）与陈奕橦（朵朵）担纲，两人分别饰演艾丽斯与阿尔科。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film will officially hit cinemas nationwide on January 17th this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片将于今年 1 月 17 日正式登陆全国院线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
