<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>小米 17 Pro 系列外观公布：大尺寸副屏亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小米-17-Pro-系列外观公布：大尺寸副屏亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/957f6767-d70c-4fd0-a2a7-28a0c09f3c37.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Xiaomi released a warm-up video on Weibo, revealing the back design of the Xiaomi 17 series. The footage showed that the Xiaomi 17 Pro's rear camera area features a secondary screen that can display time, wallpapers, and other content, consistent with the avatar briefly changed by Xiaomi's Weibo account previously.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小米在微博发布预热视频，公布了小米 17 系列的背部外观设计，画面显示小米 17 Pro 背面相机区域设计有一块副屏，可以显示时间、壁纸等内容，外观与先前小米微博账号短暂更换的头像一致。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official statement indicates that both the Xiaomi 17 Pro and Xiaomi 17 Pro Max will feature this &quot;Mystic Rear Screen,&quot; offering &quot;more excitement on one more side.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方表示，小米 17 Pro 与小米 17 Pro Max 均将搭载这块「妙享背屏」、「多一面更精彩」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing, President of Xiaomi Group, previously announced that the Xiaomi 17 series will officially debut this month, a month earlier than its predecessor, calling it &quot;the most significant leap&quot; in the history of Xiaomi's digital series. This series skips the &quot;Xiaomi 16 series&quot; naming, directly launching the Xiaomi 17 series, and will globally debut the fifth-generation Snapdragon 8 Ultimate Edition mobile platform.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米集团总裁卢伟冰此前宣布，小米 17 系列将于本月正式亮相，比上代提前一个月发布，并称这是小米数字系列史上「最重大的一次跃迁」。该系列跳过「小米 16 系列」命名，直接推出小米 17 系列，将全球首发第五代骁龙 8 至尊版移动平台。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing emphasized that Xiaomi's high-end strategy has been pursued for five years, consistently benchmarking against iPhone, shifting from &quot;parameter leadership&quot; to &quot;experience priority,&quot; achieving deep integration of software and hardware.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            卢伟冰强调，小米高端化战略已坚持五年，始终对标 iPhone，从「参数领先」转向「体验优先」，实现软硬件深度融合。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lei Jun, Chairman and CEO of Xiaomi Group, also stated that the Xiaomi 17 series boasts a cross-generational upgrade in product power, will &quot;fully benchmark against iPhone,&quot; and confront it head-on. With the official unveiling of design details, market discussion about this new generation of products has further intensified.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米集团董事长兼 CEO 雷军也表示，小米 17 系列产品力跨代升级，将「全面对标 iPhone」，正面迎战。随着外观细节的正式公布，市场对这代新品的讨论度亦进一步提高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to recent news from blogger &quot;Digital Chat Station,&quot; the Xiaomi 17 Pro will be equipped with a 50-megapixel Leica ultra-large sensor triple rear camera setup, with a main camera aperture of f1.67; the telephoto lens will be 115mm (equivalent to 5x optical zoom) with an aperture of f3.0; and the ultra-wide-angle lens will be 17mm.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据博主「数码闲聊站」日前消息，小米 17 Pro 将配备 5000 万像素徕卡超大底后置三摄，主摄光圈为 f1.67；长焦为 115mm（等效 5 倍光学变焦），光圈 f3.0；超广角为 17mm。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that the official warm-up content details show that the Xiaomi 17 Pro model in the video has a minimum aperture of f2.6.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，官方放出的预热内容细节显示，视频中的小米 17 Pro 机型最小光圈为 f2.6。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, yesterday, the Xiaomi Community officially launched the &quot;Xiaomi Tech Gala&quot; event recruitment, inviting 850 &quot;Mi Fans&quot; to participate, with registration closing on September 22.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，昨日小米社区正式开启「小米科技盛会」活动招募，将邀请 850 名「米粉」参与，报名时间 9 月 22 日截止。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Verge：液态玻璃的界面统一是「难以忍受的」</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">The-Verge：液态玻璃的界面统一是「难以忍受的」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/95d680e9-b1b6-4263-84be-892e6df6da84.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            David Pierce, editor-in-chief of The Verge, recently wrote an article providing an in-depth experience and evaluation of Apple's new &quot;Liquid Glass&quot; design system introduced across platforms such as iOS 26, macOS Tahoe 26, watchOS 26, and Vision Pro.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            The Verge 总编辑 David Pierce 近日撰文，对苹果在 iOS 26、macOS Tahoe 26、watchOS 26 及 Vision Pro 等平台引入的全新「Liquid Glass」设计系统进行了深入体验与评价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the introduction, &quot;Liquid Glass&quot; brings a unified three-dimensional interface visual effect to almost all Apple devices, with buttons and menus floating above the content, capable of changing color and refracting light with the environment, simulating a real glass texture. On immersive devices like Vision Pro, this design is considered highly compatible; on Mac, due to fewer system interface elements, the impact is relatively limited.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，「Liquid Glass」为几乎所有苹果设备带来统一的立体界面视觉效果，按钮与菜单悬浮于内容之上，并可随环境变色、折射光线，模拟真实玻璃质感。在 Vision Pro 等沉浸式设备上，这一设计被认为契合度较高；在 Mac 上，由于系统界面元素较少，影响也相对有限。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, Pierce pointed out that the design performs poorly on high-frequency interaction devices like iPhone and Apple Watch, where frequent color changes and size variations of interface elements cause visual interference and difficulty in information recognition. He mentioned that when browsing colorful web pages in Safari, the search bar is almost illegible; in watchOS 26, the time display easily blends with the watch face background, affecting readability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            然而，Pierce 指出，该设计在 iPhone 和 Apple Watch 等高频交互设备上表现不佳，界面元素频繁变色、尺寸变化，反而造成视觉干扰与信息辨识困难。他提到，在 Safari 浏览彩色网页时，搜索栏几乎难以看清；在 watchOS 26 中，时间显示容易与表盘背景融合，影响可读性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The article believes that &quot;Liquid Glass&quot; reflects Apple's current trend of promoting multi-platform interface unification, but this &quot;one-size-fits-all&quot; design philosophy ignores the usage scenarios and interaction needs of different devices. Pierce concluded that this system might be suitable for a future world where AR/VR is widespread, but in the current reality of multiple screens coexisting, the sense of unity it brings is more like &quot;unbearable convergence.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文章认为，「Liquid Glass」体现了苹果当前推动多平台界面统一的趋势，但这种「一刀切」的设计理念忽视了不同设备的使用场景与交互需求。Pierce 总结称，这套系统或许适用于未来 AR / VR 普及的世界，但在当下多屏并存的现实中，其带来的统一感更像是「难以忍受的趋同」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 最新报告：揭秘 ChatGPT 最火用途</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-最新报告：揭秘-ChatGPT-最火用途</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 15, OpenAI released a detailed survey of ChatGPT usage, covering multi-dimensional data including gender, age, region, and purpose.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 于 9 月 15 日公布了 ChatGPT 详细使用情况调查，涵盖性别、年龄、地域及用途等多维度数据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report shows that as of June 2025, ChatGPT's weekly active users have exceeded 700 million, equivalent to 10% of the global adult population, and the user base continues to grow across all genders and countries.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报告显示，截至 2025 年 6 月，ChatGPT 每周活跃用户已突破 7 亿，相当于全球成年人口的 10%，且用户规模在各性别与国家中持续增长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Notably, the proportion of female users surpassed that of males for the first time in June this year, marking a significant narrowing of the gender gap. In terms of age distribution, the younger demographic aged 18 to 25 contributed approximately 46% of message volume, becoming the most active user group.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得关注的是，女性用户比例在今年 6 月首次超过男性，标志着性别差距显著缩小。年龄分布方面，18 至 25 岁的年轻群体贡献了约 46% 的消息量，成为最活跃用户群。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regional data indicates that in low-to-middle-income countries with a per capita GDP of $10,000 to $40,000, the growth rate of ChatGPT's penetration is four times that of high-income countries, demonstrating its rapid infiltration into emerging markets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            地域数据表明，在人均 GDP 1 万至 4 万美元的低中收入国家，ChatGPT 普及率增长速度是高收入国家的 4 倍，显示其在新兴市场的快速渗透。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding usage topics, &quot;practical guidance,&quot; &quot;information retrieval,&quot; and &quot;writing&quot; ranked in the top three, accounting for a combined 78%. Among these, writing was the primary use for work-related tasks, at 40%; while 73% of conversations were unrelated to work, a significant increase from 53% a year ago.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在使用话题上，「实用指导」、「信息查询」与「写作」位列前三，合计占比达 78%。其中，写作是工作相关任务的首要用途，占比 40%；而 73% 的对话与工作无关，相较一年前的 53% 有明显提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, the research team categorized user intentions into three types: &quot;questioning,&quot; &quot;executing,&quot; and &quot;expressing.&quot; The results showed that 49% of interactions involved asking for information or advice, 40% involved requesting specific outcomes, and 11% were for communication without a specific purpose. In work scenarios, the &quot;executing&quot; category rose to 56%, but &quot;questioning&quot; interactions still had the highest satisfaction.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，研究团队还将用户意图分为「提问」、「执行」与「表达」三类，结果显示 49% 的互动为提问获取信息或建议，40% 为要求具体成果，11% 为无特定目的的交流。在工作场景中，执行类占比升至 56%，但满意度最高的仍是提问类互动。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>郭明錤：iPhone 17 系列首周末预购表现优于去年</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">郭明錤：iPhone-17-系列首周末预购表现优于去年</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7c56f56d-becd-4c53-9e8d-2cb49aa02fef.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Tianfeng International Securities analyst Ming-Chi Kuo posted on X that the overall pre-order demand for the iPhone 17 series in its first weekend was better than last year's iPhone 16 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，天风国际证券分析师郭明錤在 X 发文表示，iPhone 17 系列首周末预购需求整体优于去年的 iPhone 16 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Kuo pointed out that in terms of the total Q3 production volume for the Pro Max, Pro, and standard versions, the iPhone 17 increased by approximately 25% year-over-year compared to the iPhone 16, but the shipping time only extended by about one week, indicating stronger overall pre-order demand for these three models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            郭明錤指出，以 Pro Max、Pro 与标准版的第三季度总生产量来看，iPhone 17 较 iPhone 16 同比增加约 25% ，但出货时间仅延长约一周，显示这三款机型的总预购需求更强。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Kuo mentioned that the iPhone Air is available immediately upon launch, and while its pre-order demand appears lower than the iPhone 16 Plus during the same period last year (which had a shipping time of about 2 weeks), it's important to consider that the iPhone Air's production volume in Q3 2025 is approximately 3 times higher (about 200% year-over-year) than the iPhone 16 Plus in Q3 2024, and Apple previously had no product with a similar &quot;Air&quot; positioning. Therefore, it is recommended to observe its market performance after it has been on sale for some time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，郭明錤提到 iPhone Air 开卖即有现货，表面上预购需求低于去年同期的 iPhone 16 Plus（当时出货时间约 2 周），但需考虑 iPhone Air 在 2025 年第三季度的生产量较 iPhone 16 Plus 在 2024 年同期高约 3 倍（约 200% 同比），且苹果此前并无类似 Air 定位的产品，因此建议在开卖一段时间后再观察其市场表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among all models, the Pro Max continues to have the strongest demand. The iPhone 17 Pro Max's production volume in Q3 2025 increased by approximately 60% compared to the 16 Pro Max in the same period last year, but the shipping time is similar.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在各机型中，需求最强的依旧是 Pro Max。iPhone 17 Pro Max 在 2025 年第三季度的生产量较去年同期的 16 Pro Max 增加约 60%，但出货时间相似。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Kuo believes that the pre-order performance of the iPhone 17 series will benefit Apple's Q3 2025 financial report, but its positive impact on supply chain stock prices is limited. Investors are currently more focused on the contributions of significantly innovative products to the supply chain starting from 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            郭明錤认为，iPhone 17 系列的预购表现有利于苹果 2025 年第三季度财报，但对供应链股价的提振作用有限，投资人当前更关注 2026 年起的大幅创新产品对供应链的贡献。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>「车顶维权」车主胜诉，特斯拉被判提供行车数据</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">「车顶维权」车主胜诉，特斯拉被判提供行车数据</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Red Star News, the 4-year rights protection case of the &quot;car roof protest&quot; owner has seen new developments. The Beijing Daxing District People's Court ruled in the first instance, ordering Tesla Automobile Sales Service (Beijing) Co., Ltd. to provide Ms. Zhang, the car owner, with complete driving data for 30 minutes before the accident, recognizing that operators should guarantee consumers' right to know.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据红星新闻报道，「车顶维权」车主历时 4 年的维权案件迎来新进展。北京市大兴区人民法院一审判决，责令特斯拉汽车销售服务（北京）有限公司向车主张女士提供事故发生前 30 分钟的完整行车数据，认定经营者应保障消费者的知情权。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The case's origin dates back to February 2021, when Ms. Zhang's father was involved in a rear-end collision while driving a Tesla. Traffic police determined he was fully responsible, but the family insisted the accident was due to &quot;brake failure.&quot; In April of the same year, Ms. Zhang protested on the roof of a Tesla at the Shanghai Auto Show, drawing widespread attention, and was subsequently detained by police for 5 days.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            案件起因可追溯至 2021 年 2 月，张女士父亲驾驶特斯拉发生追尾事故，交警认定其负全责，但家属坚持认为事故源于「刹车失灵」。同年 4 月，张女士在上海车展站上特斯拉车顶维权，引发广泛关注，并因此被警方行政拘留 5 日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In October 2021, Tesla (Shanghai) Co., Ltd. sued Ms. Zhang for defamation, seeking 5 million yuan in damages. In July 2025, the Shanghai No. 2 Intermediate People's Court upheld the original judgment in its final ruling, ordering Ms. Zhang to pay 170,000 yuan in compensation and issue a public apology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2021 年 10 月，特斯拉（上海）有限公司以侵犯名誉权为由起诉张女士，索赔 500 万元。2025 年 7 月，上海市二中院终审判决维持原判，判令张女士赔偿 17 万元并公开道歉。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ms. Zhang stated that after obtaining the complete data, she would apply for judicial appraisal to inspect the vehicle's braking system based on the data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            张女士表示，待拿到完整数据后，将申请司法鉴定，以数据为依据对车辆刹车系统进行检测。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nothing 获 2 亿美元融资，明年发布 AI 设备</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Nothing-获-2-亿美元融资，明年发布-AI-设备</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d6434cb2-a6d9-403b-881d-d69ed4dabef3.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            iFanr learned that smart device company Nothing today announced the completion of a $200 million Series C funding round in the UK, led by Tiger Global, with existing investors Google Ventures, EQT, and others participating; Qualcomm Ventures and Indian billionaire Nikhil Kamath joined for the first time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            爱范儿获悉，智能设备企业 Nothing 今天在英国宣布完成 2 亿美元 C 轮融资，老虎环球领投，现有投资方谷歌风投、EQT 等跟投；高通创投和印度富豪 Nikhil Kamath 首次加入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that Nothing has currently shipped millions of devices (including smartphones and headphones, etc.), achieving cumulative historical sales exceeding $1 billion in 25 years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据了解，Nothing 目前已经出货数百万台设备（包括智能手机和耳机等产品），25 年实现历史累计销售额突破 10 亿美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that the &quot;AI device&quot; vision Nothing has had since its inception has been updated again: founder Carl Pei revealed that an &quot;AI-native device,&quot; a device independent of smartphones, will be launched next year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，Nothing 从创立之初就画的 AI 设备大饼，这次又更新了：创始人裴宇透露，将在明年推出「AI 原生设备」(AI-native device)，一种独立于手机的设备。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Nothing's AI device will be available when users need it, driven by intelligence, transforming understanding into action. It also supports cross-modal context capture and generates interactive interfaces on demand, changing with user goals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，Nothing 的 AI 设备将能够在用户需要时随时可用，并由智能驱动，将理解转化为行动。其还支持跨模态捕捉上下文，并按需生成交互界面，随用户目标而变化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Carl Pei stated that compared to the revolutionary progress made by AI, the smartphone experience remains stagnant, innovation is limited, and the results are unsatisfactory, which is why the company is focusing on AI-native devices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            裴宇表示，和 AI 所取得的革命性进展相比，智能手机的体验仍然停滞不前，创新局限，效果差强人意，是公司加力 AI 原生设备的原因。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>华为与广汽丰田合作升级为全栈方案</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">华为与广汽丰田合作升级为全栈方案</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Cailian Press, citing multiple informed sources, the cooperation between Huawei's Intelligent Automotive Solution BU and GAC Toyota will be fully upgraded to a full-stack solution, with 3 new car models to be launched within the next two years. Among them, two models planned for release in 2027 will fully feature Qiankun Intelligent Driving and HarmonyOS Cockpit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据财联社援引多位知情人士信息报道，华为车 BU 与广汽丰田的合作将全面升级为全栈方案，未来两年内将有 3 款新车落地。其中，计划于 2027 年推出的两款车型将全量搭载乾崑智驾与鸿蒙座舱。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the HarmonyOS Smart Travel brand, Zunjie will launch an MPV and an SUV next year, with the MPV benchmarked against the Toyota Alphard; Xiangjie plans to launch a major S9 facelift and an MPV, and will introduce the brand's first rugged SUV later next year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在鸿蒙智行品牌方面，尊界将于明年先后推出 MPV 与 SUV，其中 MPV 对标丰田埃尔法；享界则计划推出 S9 大改款与 MPV，并将在明年晚些时候迎来品牌首款硬派 SUV。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Huawei and BAIC recently reached an agreement to further deepen cooperation on the Xiangjie brand, with 20 billion yuan to be invested over the next 3 years for product R&amp;amp;D and market expansion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，华为与北汽近日就享界品牌达成进一步深化合作协议，未来 3 年将投入 200 亿元资金，用于产品研发与市场拓展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT 个性化页面迎来更新</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ChatGPT-个性化页面迎来更新</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/74b8d05a-3c22-42e3-91ba-2d512769bd1a.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI CEO Sam Altman announced yesterday on social media that ChatGPT's personalization page has been updated, adding an integrated entry point that unifies &quot;Personal Settings,&quot; &quot;Custom Instructions,&quot; and &quot;Memory Function&quot; into a single interface, expected to be gradually rolled out to users in the coming days.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI CEO Sam Altman 昨日在社交平台发文宣布，ChatGPT 的个性化页面迎来更新，新增整合式入口，将「个性配置」「自定义指令」与「记忆功能」统一到同一界面中，预计将在未来几天内逐步向用户推送。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman stated that this redesign aims to simplify the user's personalization management experience, allowing users to more intuitively adjust the AI's interaction style and memory preferences.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Altman 表示，此次改版旨在简化用户的个性化管理体验，让用户能够更直观地调整 AI 的交互风格与记忆偏好。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some users in the comments section proposed feature suggestions, such as &quot;supporting multi-selection to delete chat records&quot; for more efficient management of conversation history; other users questioned the necessity of personalization features, believing that the model's inherent intelligent adaptation capabilities are sufficient for daily needs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            有用户在评论区提出功能建议，例如「支持多选删除聊天记录」，以便更高效地管理会话历史；也有用户对个性化功能的必要性提出质疑，认为模型本身的智能适配能力已足够满足日常需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, yesterday morning OpenAI also launched &quot;GPT-5 Codex,&quot; a code model optimized based on GPT-5, focusing on real-world software engineering scenarios. It can not only handle daily programming interactions but also independently complete complex and time-consuming engineering projects.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，昨天凌晨 OpenAI 还推出了基于 GPT-5 优化后的代码模型「GPT-5 Codex」，聚焦于真实的软件工程场景，不仅能处理日常的编程交互，还能独立完成复杂耗时的工程项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Codex, equipped with the new model, can work continuously for over 7 hours like a real programmer, constantly iterating, fixing bugs, and running tests on complex projects, ultimately delivering a complete and usable solution.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，搭载新模型的 Codex 能像真正的程序员一样，连续工作超过 7 个小时，在复杂项目上不断迭代、修 bug、跑测试，最后交付一个完整可用的解决方案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Soon after the new model went online, Altman excitedly revealed that GPT-5-Codex already accounts for nearly 40% of Codex's total traffic. He predicts that this proportion will surpass others and become the platform's main source by September 16th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新模型上线不久，Altman 就兴奋地透露，GPT-5-Codex 已经占据了 Codex 总流量的近四成。其判断在 9 月 16 日之内，这个比例就会反超，成为平台的主要来源。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI 应用用户规模达 6 亿，豆包重回月活第一</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AI-应用用户规模达-6-亿，豆包重回月活第一</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c15eb1ce-288d-41a5-ab55-518e265ef524.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, QuestMobile released the &quot;August 2025 Monthly Report on the AI Application Industry.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，QuestMobile 发布《2025 年 8 月 AI 应用行业月度报告》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report shows that the overall user base of mobile AI applications has reached 645 million, with native app users from internet and AI tech companies accounting for 277 million, in-app AI plugin users for 622 million, and mobile phone manufacturer AI assistant users for 529 million.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报告显示，移动端 AI 应用整体用户规模已达 6.45 亿，其中互联网及 AI 科技企业原生 App 用户规模为 2.77 亿，应用插件（In-App AI）用户规模为 6.22 亿，手机厂商 AI 助手用户规模为 5.29 亿。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the native app camp,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Doubao replaced DeepSeek with a month-on-month growth rate of 6.6%, reclaiming the top spot in terms of monthly active users.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            The report points out that billion-level leading applications continue the &quot;stronger get stronger&quot; trend, while mid-to-long-tail applications with fewer than 100,000 users are generally facing growth difficulties.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在原生 App 阵营中，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             豆包以 6.6% 的环比增速取代 DeepSeek，重新夺回月活跃用户规模第一的位置。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            报告指出，亿级头部应用延续「强者恒强」趋势，而 10 万以下的中长尾应用则普遍陷入增长困境。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            From the perspective of track performance, AI search engines and AI comprehensive assistants still occupy the top two positions, with user bases of 672 million and 651 million respectively; the AI information retrieval track performed remarkably, with its user base growing by 39% month-on-month in August, reaching 73.53 million, becoming the biggest dark horse of the month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从赛道表现来看，AI 搜索引擎与 AI 综合助手依旧占据前两位，用户规模分别为 6.72 亿和 6.51 亿；AI 信息检索赛道表现亮眼，8 月用户规模环比增长 39%，达到 7,353 万，成为当月最大黑马。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of mobile phone manufacturer AI assistants, OPPO, Xiaomi, and Huawei's user proportions are 70.9%, 70.4%, and 56.8% respectively. Among them,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Xiaomi's &quot;Super Xiaoai&quot; achieved an activation rate of 37.7%, mainly due to its deep synergy with smart home devices.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在手机厂商 AI 助手方面，OPPO、小米、华为的用户占比分别为 70.9%、70.4% 和 56.8%。其中，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             小米「超级小爱」活跃率达到 37.7%，主要得益于其与智能家居的深度协同。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            QuestMobile believes that future AI application competition will shift from &quot;getting users to use&quot; to &quot;getting users to use better and longer,&quot; and multi-device coverage and scenario-based services will become key to enhancing user stickiness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            QuestMobile 认为，未来 AI 应用竞争将从「让用户用」转向「让用户用得更好、更久」，多端覆盖与场景化服务将成为提升用户粘性的关键。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>奢侈品牌客户数据遭黑客窃取</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">奢侈品牌客户数据遭黑客窃取</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to BBC reports, luxury brands such as Balenciaga, Gucci, and Alexander McQueen recently suffered cyberattacks. The hacker group &quot;Shiny Hunters&quot; claimed to have stolen a large amount of customer information, including names, emails, phone numbers, addresses, and total spending, involving approximately 7.4 million email addresses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 BBC 报道，巴黎世家、Gucci 与 Alexander McQueen 等奢侈品牌近日遭遇网络攻击，黑客团体「闪亮猎人（Shiny Hunters）」声称已窃取包含姓名、邮箱、电话、地址及消费总额在内的大量客户信息，涉及约 740 万个邮箱地址。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, &quot;Shiny Hunters,&quot; the hackers behind this incident, stated on Telegram that they obtained data by infiltrating the system of luxury brand parent company Kering in April this year, and contacted the company in June to demand a ransom payment in Bitcoin. However, Kering denied negotiating with them and emphasized that it had refused to pay the ransom.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据报道，此次事件的幕后黑客「闪亮猎人」在 Telegram 表示，他们在今年 4 月通过奢侈品牌母公司 Kering 的系统入侵获取数据，并在 6 月与该公司进行过接触，要求以比特币支付赎金，但 Kering 否认曾与其谈判，并强调已拒绝支付赎金。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Kering stated that the affected data does not include bank card numbers, credit card information, or government-issued ID numbers. The company has reported to relevant data protection agencies and notified affected customers via email. Currently, Kering stated that it has completed IT system reinforcement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Kering 表示，受影响数据不包含银行卡号、信用卡信息或政府签发的身份证号码，公司已向相关数据保护机构报告，并通过邮件通知受影响客户。目前，Kering 表示已完成 IT 系统加固。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that the leaked data includes a &quot;Total Sales&quot; field, showing that some customers spent over $30,000 to $86,000 on a single brand. Security experts warn that such high spending records could make victims prime targets for secondary fraud.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，泄露数据中包含「Total Sales」字段，显示部分客户在单一品牌消费超过 3 万至 8.6 万美元。安全专家警告，这类高消费记录可能使受害者成为二次诈骗的重点目标。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            French fashion brand Dior also experienced a data breach in May this year, with mainland Chinese users successively receiving official warning SMS messages. It is understood that the accessed database may contain affected customer information including name, gender, mobile number, email, mailing address, spending level, and preferences, but does not involve bank accounts or credit card information.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            法国时尚品牌 Dior 今年 5 月也曾发生数据泄露事件，中国大陆用户陆续收到官方警示短信。据悉，被访问的数据库中，受影响客户信息可能包括姓名、性别、手机号码、邮箱、邮寄地址、消费水平与偏好等，但不涉及银行账户或信用卡信息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the 9th, Dior was issued an administrative penalty and publicly notified by the public security network security department for &quot;failing to fulfill its personal information protection obligations in accordance with the law.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 日，Dior 因「未依法履行个人信息保护义务」被公安网安部门作出行政处罚并通告。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>联发科宣布首款台积电 2nm 芯片</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">联发科宣布首款台积电-2nm-芯片</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/376d6e0c-d070-4671-af4b-26080846029c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             MediaTek announced on its official website that its first flagship SoC using TSMC's 2nm process has completed design tape-out and is expected to be officially launched by the end of 2026, possibly as the Dimensity 9600.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             联发科技 MediaTek 在官网宣布其首款采用台积电 2 纳米制程的旗舰 SoC 已完成设计流片，预计将于 2026 年底正式上市，或为天玑 9600。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, TSMC's 2nm process introduces a nanosheet transistor structure for the first time. Compared to the N3E process, logic density is increased by 1.2 times, performance is boosted by up to 18% at the same power consumption, or power consumption is reduced by approximately 36% at the same performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，台积电 2 纳米制程首次引入纳米片电晶体结构，相较 N3E 制程，逻辑密度提升 1.2 倍，在相同功耗下性能最高提升 18%，或在相同性能下功耗降低约 36%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chen Guanzhou, MediaTek's Director, President, and COO, stated: &quot;This collaboration once again demonstrates our industry-leading innovative capability to empower a wide range of devices and applications with advanced semiconductor process technology.&quot; Dr. Zhang Xiaoqiang, TSMC's Senior Vice President of Business Development, pointed out: &quot;2nm technology marks an important step into the nanosheet era, and we will continue to optimize the technology to meet diverse customer needs.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            MediaTek 董事、总经理暨营运长陈冠州表示：「此次合作再次展现我们引领业界，将先进半导体制程技术赋能于广泛设备与应用的创新能力。」台积电业务开发资深副总经理张晓强博士则指出：「2 纳米技术标志着进入纳米片时代的重要一步，我们将持续优化技术以满足客户多元需求。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, MediaTek also announced yesterday afternoon that it will hold the &quot;Chip Discovery&quot; 2025 Dimensity flagship chip new product launch conference in Shenzhen on September 22, where it is expected to release the new Dimensity flagship chip 9500.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，MediaTek 昨天下午还宣布将于 9 月 22 日在深圳召开「芯发现」2025 天玑旗舰芯片新品发布会，预计将发布全新天玑旗舰芯片 9500。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the same day,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             vivo product manager Han Boxiao also posted that the Dimensity 9500 was &quot;jointly defined and created by Blue Factory (vivo) and MediaTek over three years.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同日，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             vivo 产品经理韩伯啸还发文表示，本次天玑 9500 是「蓝厂和联发科历时三年共同定义携手打造的」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He revealed that the Dimensity 9500 directly integrates the self-developed Blueprint Imaging Chip V3+, achieving the world's first 4K 60fps cinematic portrait video on the vivo X300 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其透露，天玑 9500 直接搭载了自研蓝图影像芯片 V3+，并在 vivo X300 系列实现全球首发 4K 60fps 电影人像视频。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to blogger &quot;Digital Chat Station,&quot; the X300 series will globally debut the Dimensity 9500.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而据博主「数码闲聊站」消息，X300 系列将全球首发天玑 9500。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vivo 开发者大会定档 10 月 10 日</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">vivo-开发者大会定档-10-月-10-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/68e6226f-7000-4ac9-9edc-fbd230545656.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            vivo announced that the 2025 Developer Conference will be held on October 10 at Hall 18 of the Shenzhen World Exhibition &amp;amp; Convention Center.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            vivo 宣布 2025 开发者大会将于 10 月 10 日在深圳国际会展中心 18 号馆举行。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official schedule, this conference will first announce the &quot;AI Strategy&quot; and officially release the new OriginOS 6 system and the self-developed BlueOS 3.0 operating system. At the same time, vivo will also present plans related to &quot;security, humanity, and ecological co-construction.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据官方日程，本次大会将率先公布「AI 战略」，并正式发布全新系统 OriginOS 6 以及自研蓝河操作系统 BlueOS 3.0。与此同时，vivo 还将带来「安全、人文及生态共建」相关计划。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to system updates, the conference will also cover the following key content:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除系统更新外，大会还将涵盖以下重点内容：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New on-device multimodal large model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blue Heart Agent and AQ + Blue Heart Little V&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-developed scheduling architecture and graphics SDK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next-generation vivo intelligent in-car solution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cooperation project with Xpeng Motors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tripartite ecosystem building and excellent partner awards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this year marks vivo's 30th anniversary, and the outside world widely expects more significant news at the conference, including the further implementation of AI strategy, vivo Vision, and new breakthroughs in hardware and ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，今年恰逢 vivo 成立 30 周年，外界普遍期待大会上会有更多重磅消息，包括 AI 战略的进一步落地、vivo Vision 以及硬件与生态的全新突破。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>西部数据或将上调硬盘价格</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">西部数据或将上调硬盘价格</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to TrendForce, citing sources, following SanDisk's 10% price increase for NAND flash and Micron's one-week halt in quotations, Western Digital has notified customers that it will immediately and gradually raise prices across its entire line of HDD products. The company stated that current demand for various capacity hard drives is unprecedentedly high, and it is also increasing investment in innovation, which are important reasons for the price hike.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 TrendForce 援引知情人士消息报道，继闪迪上调 NAND 闪存价格 10% 以及美光暂停一周报价后，西部数据已通知客户将立即逐步上调全线 HDD 产品价格。该公司表示，当前各容量硬盘需求空前高涨，同时正加大创新投入，这成为提价的重要原因。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that Western Digital plans to increase its proportion of sea freight, which may extend product shipping times to 6–10 weeks, and advises customers to plan ahead when placing orders.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，西部数据计划扩大海运比例，这可能导致产品运输时间延长至 6–10 周，并建议客户在下单时提前规划。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, industry analysis indicates that the surge in demand for high-capacity storage is closely related to the rapid rise of inference-based AI services. Multiple global cloud service providers continue to break revenue records, and tech giants like Google and Oracle are accelerating the expansion of AI infrastructure to facilitate the deployment of high-performance inference applications, thereby driving a continuous increase in demand for high-capacity HDDs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据报道，业内分析指出，高容量存储需求的激增与推理型 AI 服务的快速崛起密切相关。全球多家云服务提供商持续刷新营收纪录，科技巨头如 Google、Oracle 正加速扩建 AI 基础设施，推动高性能推理应用落地，从而带动高容量 HDD 需求持续攀升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the delivery cycle for high-capacity HDDs has extended to nearly 1 year. To address this trend, storage manufacturers are actively developing Nearline SSD products, striving to reduce the price gap with HDDs from the existing 4–5 times to approximately 3 times, thereby encouraging customer adoption.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，高容量 HDD 的交付周期已延长至接近 1 年。为应对这一趋势，存储厂商正积极研发 Nearline SSD 产品，力求将与 HDD 的价格差距从现有的 4–5 倍缩小至约 3 倍，以促进客户采用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>消息称英伟达将成为台积电 1.6nm 制程的首位客户</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">消息称英伟达将成为台积电-1.6nm-制程的首位客户</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tech news website Wccftech reported that Nvidia will be the first customer for TSMC's A16 (1.6nm) process, a move the industry believes is related to AMD's aggressive expansion in the high-end AI GPU sector.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            技术新闻网站 Wccftech 报道称，英伟达将成为台积电 A16（1.6nm）制程的首位客户，业界认为这一举动与 AMD 在高端 AI GPU 领域的激进布局有关。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to industry sources, Nvidia's decision to directly adopt TSMC's latest process node breaks a two-decade-long tradition of relying on mature processes. The A16 process is expected to introduce key technologies such as Gate-All-Around FET (GAAFET) and Super Power Rail (SPR) backside power delivery, significantly improving both performance and energy efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据产业链透露，英伟达此次选择直接切入台积电最新制程节点，打破了过去二十多年依赖成熟工艺的惯例。A16 制程预计将引入 Gate-All-Around FET（GAAFET）与 Super Power Rail（SPR）背面供电等关键技术，性能与能效均有显著提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that TSMC plans to achieve mass production of the A16 process by the end of 2026, and Nvidia is expected to launch its next-generation GPUs based on this process in late 2027 or early 2028, possibly from the Rubin Ultra or Feynman series, with Feynman being more likely. Industry insiders point out that this collaboration will not only drive a leap in AI hardware performance but also further intensify the competition between Nvidia and AMD in the high-end AI market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，台积电规划在 2026 年底实现 A16 制程的量产，英伟达有望在 2027 年末或 2028 年初推出基于该工艺的下一代 GPU，可能是 Rubin Ultra 或 Feynman 系列，其中 Feynman 的可能性更高。业内人士指出，这一合作不仅将推动 AI 硬件性能的跃升，也将进一步加剧英伟达与 AMD 在高端 AI 市场的竞争。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 Altman：AI 无法替代真实的人际情感</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-Altman：AI-无法替代真实的人际情感</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8f010c53-49ae-4ecd-91bf-622afa8d6212.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In a recent in-depth interview, renowned Silicon Valley investor Vinod Khosla and OpenAI CEO Sam Altman discussed the future direction of AI, including which capabilities will be enhanced and which human values will not be replaced.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在前不久的一次深度访谈中，硅谷知名投资人 Vinod Khosla 和 OpenAI CEO Sam Altman 探讨了关于 AI 的未来走向，以及哪些能力会被强化，哪些人类价值不会被替代等内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the interview, Sam Altman stated frankly that the boundaries of AI's capabilities are constantly being pushed, with almost all types of intellectual labor, from software development to scientific research, potentially being covered by AI. However, he emphasized that emotional connections between people are irreplaceable by any technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            访谈中，Sam Altman 直言，AI 的能力边界正在被不断突破，从软件开发到科学研究，几乎所有类型的智力劳动都可能被 AI 覆盖。然而，他强调，人与人之间的情感连接是任何技术都无法取代的。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The feeling of hearing the same encouraging words from a real person versus seeing them on an AI chat interface is completely different.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同样一句鼓励的话，从一个真实的人那里听到，和从 AI 的聊天界面看到，感受是完全不一样的。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman explained that this difference is not merely about the textual content but stems from the unique warmth and details in human communication—eye contact, vocal inflections, body language, and even the long-term trust built between individuals. These subtle emotional signals form the core of human relationships, and no matter how advanced AI becomes, it can only imitate them superficially, unable to truly access this deep experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Altman 解释，这种差异不仅仅是文字内容的不同，而是源于人类交流中独有的温度与细节 —— 眼神交流、语调起伏、肢体动作、甚至是彼此之间长期建立的信任感。这些微妙的情绪信号构成了人际关系的核心，而 AI 再先进，也只能在表层模仿，无法真正触及这种深层体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also pointed out that the widespread adoption of AI will completely change the way the software industry operates. In the future, ordinary people will be able to directly generate applications that meet their needs without a programming background. This trend will impact traditional SaaS models—if existing products cannot quickly adapt to this change, their market share and commercial value could suffer significant losses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他还指出，AI 的普及将彻底改变软件行业的生产方式。未来，普通人无需编程背景，就能直接生成符合自己需求的应用程序。这一趋势将对传统 SaaS 模式构成冲击 —— 如果现有产品无法快速适应这种变化，其市场份额和商业价值都可能遭受重大损失。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When discussing the future of the industry, Altman specifically mentioned the energy issue. He believes that the continuous rise in computing power demand will make energy one of the core bottlenecks for AI development. Even if new technologies like DeepSeek achieve breakthroughs in efficiency, the future pricing of AI may still be directly linked to electricity costs, meaning that energy supply capacity will become a critical variable in global technological competition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在谈及行业未来时，Altman 特别提到能源问题。他认为，算力需求的持续攀升将使能源成为 AI 发展的核心瓶颈之一。即便新技术如 DeepSeek 在效率上取得突破，未来 AI 的定价仍可能与电力成本直接挂钩，这意味着能源供应能力将成为全球科技竞争的关键变量。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman concluded that AI will profoundly reshape the productivity landscape, driving society into an era of high automation and personalization.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             However, no matter how technology advances, genuine human emotions and interactions will remain the irreplaceable spiritual pillars of human society.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Altman 总结道，AI 将深刻重塑生产力格局，推动社会进入一个高度自动化与个性化的时代。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             但无论技术如何进步，真实的人际情感与交流，依然是人类社会不可替代的精神支柱。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30.98 万元起，享界 S9T 正式发布</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">30.98-万元起，享界-S9T-正式发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9fe2428f-6376-45ec-914c-21cceefd8f82.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, the Enjoy Boundary S9T was officially released. Let's look at the prices first:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，享界 S9T 正式发布，先看售价：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The extended-range version starts from 309,800 yuan; the pure electric version starts from 329,800 yuan; both are available in Max and Ultra versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new car continues the exterior design of the Enjoy S9, with new nebula taillights added to the rear, and offers a new obsidian package; the doors are equipped with electric doors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新车延续了享界 S9 的外观设计，并在尾部添加了全新的星云尾灯，提供全新的黑曜套件；车门配备电动门。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Enjoy S9T adopts the new Turing platform, with all models coming standard with new continuously variable damping shock absorbers + intelligent air suspension, as well as continuous construction of road condition spatial models and a six-in-one full-domain fusion architecture; the chassis can provide a maximum height of 163mm, and emergency wading depth can reach 430mm.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            享界 S9T 采用全新的途灵平台，全系标配全新连续可变阻尼减震器 + 智能空气悬架，同时配备路况空间模型连续构建、六合一全域融合架构；底盘最高可提供 163mm 的高度，应急涉水深度可达 430mm。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of range, the Enjoy S9T extended-range version uses Huawei's Snow Owl intelligent extended-range system, with a 53.4kWh battery, providing 354km CLTC pure electric range, and a comprehensive range of up to 1305km; the pure electric version is equipped with Huawei's 800V Whale battery platform, offering a maximum CLTC pure electric range of 801km.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            续航方面，享界 S9T 增程版采用华为雪鸮智能增程系统，电池为 53.4kWh，提供 354km CLTC 纯电续航，综合续航可达 1305km；纯电版则搭载华为 800V 巨鲸电池平台，提供最高 801km 的 CLTC 纯电续航。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For comfort, the Enjoy S9T is equipped with Huawei Yuezhang Excellence Series speakers, featuring a 25-unit acoustic design and a maximum power of 2080W; all models come standard with a zero-gravity first-class passenger seat.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            舒适性上，享界 S9T 车内配备华为悦彰卓越系列音箱，拥有 25 单元声学设计，最高 2080W 功效；全系标配副驾零重力头等舱。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of intelligence, the Enjoy S9T offers a combination of 4 LiDARs, 3 distributed 4D millimeter-wave radar matrices, and 2 4D millimeter-wave corner radars, supporting Huawei Qiankun Smart Driving ADS 4 and all-dimensional anti-collision 4.0.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            智能化方面，享界 S9T 提供 4 激光雷达、3 分布式 4D 毫米波雷达矩阵以及 2 4D 毫米波角雷达的组合，支持华为乾坤智驾 ADS 4、全维防碰撞 4.0。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>理想 i6 定档 9 月底发布</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">理想-i6-定档-9-月底发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/459ebde2-fad7-43c0-af6a-0c07dc06fd6a.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Auto yesterday released a series of promotional posters for the Li Auto i6.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            理想汽车昨日发布了理想 i6 的一系列宣传海报。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the Li Auto i6's exterior continues the design of the i8, featuring an integrated shark shape and a two-tone body, making it highly recognizable.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，理想 i6外观延续了 i8 的设计，拥有一体式鲨鱼形态、上下双色车身，辨识度颇高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As a 200,000-yuan class urban five-seater SUV, the Li Auto i6 has relatively restrained body dimensions, with a length of 4.95 meters, but Li Auto states that the car's interior longitudinal usable space exceeds 3.3 meters.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            作为一辆 20 万元级的城市五座 SUV，理想 i6 的车身尺寸较为克制，车长为 4.95 米，但理想表示，该车的车内纵向可用空间超过了 3.3 米。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;(Li Auto i6) achieves the spatial magic of being compact on the outside and spacious on the inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Auto also emphasized that the i6's low-drag design brings lower energy consumption and excellent range. According to MIIT information, the Li Auto i6 has a maximum range of 710km (single-motor version), with electricity consumption as low as 13.6kWh/100km.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            理想汽车还强调，i6 的低风阻造型设计带来了更低能耗和出色的续航。工信部信息显示，理想 i6 续航最高达 710km（单电机版本），百公里电耗低至 13.6kWh/100km。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the low center of gravity design also makes the i6 more agile to drive.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，低重心设计也让 i6 开起来也更加收放自如。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1199 元起，真我 15 系列正式发布</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1199-元起，真我-15-系列正式发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/fb10e032-dca9-4ffe-859d-25359f034bbc.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the evening of September 16, Realme launched its new digital series products in Shenzhen, including the Realme 15 series, which comprises three models: Realme 15 Pro, Realme 15, and Realme 15T.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 16 日晚，真我在深圳发布全新数字系列新品，包括真我 15 系列，包括真我 15 Pro、真我 15 以及真我 15T 三款机型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new products feature comprehensive upgrades in exterior design, imaging capabilities, and battery life experience. Among them, the Realme 15 Pro is equipped with the fourth-generation Snapdragon 7 performance core and UFS 3.1 flash memory, front and rear 50-megapixel ultra-clear triple cameras, and debuts AI Magic Dual Flash and AI Night Shot modes, positioned as a &quot;night photography artifact,&quot; with a starting price of 1999 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新品在外观设计、影像能力与续航体验上全面升级，其中真我 15 Pro 搭载第四代骁龙 7 性能芯与 UFS 3.1 闪存、前后 5000 万超清三摄，首发 AI 魔法双闪与 AI 夜拍模式，定位「夜拍神器」，首销价 1999 元起。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, also released were:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，一同发布的还有：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Realme 15 is equipped with a 144Hz gaming flat screen and dual independent gaming chips, a built-in 7000mAh Titan battery, and supports IP69 full-level waterproofing, with a starting price of 1699 yuan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Realme 15T features a lightweight and thin small flat-screen design, with a body thickness of 7.79mm and a weight of 181g, also equipped with a large 7000mAh battery, with a starting price of 1199 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The entire Realme 15 series supports features such as IP69 waterproofing, 360° NFC, and universal infrared remote control, and offers multiple benefits during the initial sale period, including a 200 yuan discount, one-year extended warranty, and trade-in subsidies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            真我 15 系列全系支持 IP69 防水、360° NFC、万能红外遥控等功能，并在首销期间提供立减 200 元、延保一年、以旧换新补贴等多重福利。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta 带屏智能眼镜亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Meta-带屏智能眼镜亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/16745fad-385e-4218-9eff-26a3cbc5c9ff.gif&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to UploadVR, a video of Meta's new smart glasses product, developed in collaboration with EssilorLuxottica's brand &quot;Ray-Ban,&quot; was recently leaked, featuring the &quot;Ray-Ban Display&quot; model for the first time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 UploadVR 报道，近日，Meta 与依路视旗下品牌「雷朋」（Ray-Ban）合作的新款智能眼镜产品视频曝光，其中首次出现了「Ray-Ban Display」款式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the Ray-Ban Display smart glasses launched this time are equipped with a monocular HUD and interact via an sEMG wristband. The video shows that the HUD interface is only on the right lens, primarily displaying scenarios such as Meta AI and walking navigation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，本次推出的 Ray-Ban Display 智能眼镜配备单目 HUD，并通过 sEMG 手环进行交互操作。从视频显示，HUD 界面仅在右眼镜片，主要显示 Meta AI、步行导航等场景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, these smart glasses also come with a matching control wristband, allowing users to input text by sliding their fingers on a tabletop to quickly reply to messages.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时该款智能眼镜还拥有配套的操控手环，支持用户在桌面上通过手指滑动输入文字，以快速回复消息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the product will be unveiled alongside the existing Ray-Ban Meta series, Oakley Meta HSTN, and the rumored Oakley Meta Sphaera. Unlike the previously exposed Orion prototype, the 'Ray-Ban Display' is not a complete AR device, but rather a lighter HUD smart glasses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，该产品将与现有的 Ray-Ban Meta 系列、Oakley Meta HSTN 以及传闻中的 Oakley Meta Sphaera 一同亮相。与此前曝光的 Orion 原型不同，「Ray-Ban Display」并非完整 AR 设备，而是定位更轻量的 HUD 智能眼镜。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the price, Bloomberg reporter Mark Gurman previously revealed that the product's starting price is approximately $800 USD (about 5,690.88 RMB). The weight is expected to be 70 grams, slightly heavier than the 50 grams of regular Ray-Ban Meta glasses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            价格方面，彭博社记者 Mark Gurman 曾透露该产品起售价约为 800 美元（约合 5,690.88 人民币）。重量预计为 70 克，相比普通 Ray-Ban Meta 眼镜的 50 克略重。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that last year, reports claimed that EssilorLuxottica Group had refused to cooperate due to issues with temple thickness, but this year Meta has invested 3 billion euros in the company, acquiring a 3% stake, and intends to further increase its stake to 5%. Industry analysis suggests that this investment may have facilitated renewed cooperation between the two parties on branding and products.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，去年有报道称 EssilorLuxottica（依视路陆逊梯卡）集团曾因镜腿厚度问题而拒绝合作，但今年 Meta 已向该公司投资 30 亿欧元，持股 3%，并有意进一步增持至 5%。业内分析认为，这一投资可能促成了双方在品牌与产品上的重新合作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Meta Connect 2025 will be held this week, with the keynote speech scheduled to begin at 8 AM Beijing time on September 18th, when the product is expected to be officially released.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，Meta Connect 2025 将于本周举行，主旨演讲定于北京时间 9 月 18 日上午 8 点开始，届时该产品有望正式发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>腾讯混元 3D 模型 3.0 亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">腾讯混元-3D-模型-3.0-亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Tencent Hunyuan officially released version 3.0 of its 3D model, claiming 'real-person figurine modeling freedom'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，腾讯混元正式发布旗下 3D 模型 3.0 版本，号称「真人手办建模自由」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official introduction, Hunyuan 3D 3.0 pioneers the 3D-DiT hierarchical sculpting model, breaking through the bottleneck of traditional technology's difficulty in balancing overall structure, regularity, and local details. It addresses the two major generation challenges of overall structure and local details, achieving ultra-high-definition 3D geometry generation with sharp edges and clear details, maintaining industry SOTA results.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方介绍，混元 3D 3.0 首创 3D-DiT 分级雕刻模型，突破传统技术难以兼顾整体结构、规整度与局部细节的瓶颈，解决整体结构与局部细节两大生成难点，实现边缘锐利、细节清晰的超高清 3D 几何生成，效果保持业界 SOTA。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to previous models, Hunyuan 3D 3.0 has undergone specialized optimization for character generation, significantly improving modeling accuracy, achieving delicate facial reconstruction, making facial features clearer and more three-dimensional, enriching details, and making character postures more natural and fluid.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相较于前代模型，混元 3D 3.0 针对人物生成进行专项优化，显著提升建模精度，实现精细的面部重塑，使五官轮廓更加清晰立体，细节更加丰富，人物体态更自然流畅。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of complex geometric structure generation, Hunyuan 3D 3.0 adopts a hierarchical generation strategy, first building the underlying structure and then gradually refining details. Combined with enhanced data processing technology, it significantly improves the understanding and reconstruction capabilities for invisible areas.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在复杂几何结构生成方面，混元 3D 3.0 采用分级生成策略，先构建底层结构，再逐步精雕细节，结合增强的数据处理技术，大幅提升对不可见区域的理解与还原能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding texture generation, Hunyuan 3D 3.0 further optimizes texture adherence and geometric alignment accuracy, ensuring that texture details faithfully reflect the design intent, achieving more precise texture mapping and fitting, and resulting in a more realistic and delicate surface texture.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在纹理生成方面，混元 3D 3.0 进一步优化纹理遵循度和几何对齐精度，确保纹理细节忠实于设计意图，实现更精准的纹理映射与贴合，表面质感更加真实细腻。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Hunyuan 3D 3.0 has been integrated into the Hunyuan 3D AI creation engine, made freely available to users, and simultaneously launched on Tencent Cloud API.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，混元 3D 3.0 已集成于混元 3D AI 创作引擎，面向用户免费开放，并同步上线腾讯云 API。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, the Hunyuan 3D Omni model, which supports multi-condition control, will soon be open-sourced, further promoting innovative applications of 3D generation technology in academic research and industrial scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，支持多条件控制的混元 3D Omni 模型也即将开源，进一步推动 3D 生成技术在学术研究与工业场景的创新应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>刘强东开直播现炒热菜</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">刘强东开直播现炒热菜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 16th, Liu Qiangdong, founder and chairman of JD.com, appeared in the 'JD Wine Tasting' live stream and relaunched the 'User Meet-and-Greet,' where he cooked the famous Suqian dish 'Yellow Dog Pork Head Meat' on site.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 16 日，京东集团创始人、董事局主席刘强东现身「京东品酒会」直播间，并重启「用户见面会」，现场烹制宿迁名菜「黄狗猪头肉」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Cailian Press, Liu Qiangdong stated in the live stream that he was very nervous during his first live broadcast, 'as nervous as Mr. Jia Guolong cooking for the first time, as nervous as Luo Yonghao giving a talk show for the first time.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据财联社报道，刘强东在直播间表示自己第一次直播很紧张，「像贾国龙先生第一次炒菜一样紧张，像罗永浩第一次说脱口秀一样紧张。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding cooking, Liu Qiangdong said that whenever he is home, he basically cooks for his family every day.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在做菜方面，刘强东表示只要回家，基本上天天都会给家人做饭。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Blue Whale News, Liu Qiangdong also communicated with the media at the meeting, stating that he had invited Wang Xing to a gathering today, but Wang Xing said he was 'at war' with Cheng Wei outside, and 'Puzhong said he wouldn't dare go if the boss didn't go'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另据蓝鲸新闻，刘强东在会上还与媒体交流表示，今天约王兴聚会，王兴说与程维在外面「战争」，而「莆中说老板不去我也不敢去」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Liu Qiangdong also stated that private enterprises should be simple, compete when necessary, and entrepreneurs should not become enemies. There's no need to turn normal business competition into personal grudges.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            刘强东还表示，民营企业要简单，该竞争就竞争，企业家不应该变成仇人，不要把正常的商业竞争变成个人恩怨，没有必要。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;I respect Brother Xing very much, and I admire Puzhong, but I hope enterprises can be more open, simpler, and purer, and think less about too many things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>喜茶官宣喜柿多多回归</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">喜茶官宣喜柿多多回归</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9668a420-8e1f-4b22-af2b-af232aa27c84.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            HEYTEA announced the third-year return of its autumn limited drink 'Joyful Persimmon Abundance,' with the original recipe back online. It also collaborated with artist Yi Hui to launch a themed visual, showcasing the natural process of persimmons from growth to ripeness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            喜茶 HEYTEA 宣布旗下秋季限定饮品「喜柿多多」迎来第三年回归，原配方再度上线，并携手画师易辉推出主题视觉，呈现柿子从生长到成熟的自然过程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the introduction, the persimmons used this time are from Yongding, Fujian, with a 500-year cultivation history and have received national geographical indication certification. Compared to ordinary persimmons, Yongding Red Persimmons are not astringent, require no spitting of seeds, have a soft and glutinous texture, and can be 'pulled into strands.' The new product is paired with fragrance-free Luyan tea soup and crispy boba, aiming to bring a dual experience of elegant tea aroma and lingering persimmon fragrance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，本次所用柿子产自福建永定，拥有 500 年培育历史，已获国家地理标志认证。与普通柿子相比，永定红柿无涩感、无需吐籽，口感软糯且可「拉丝」。新品搭配无香精绿妍茶汤与脂脆波波，旨在带来清雅茶香与绵延柿香的双重体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the event, consumers can purchase the 'Joyful Persimmon Refrigerator Magnet Combo' at stores nationwide and participate in the 'Inspiration Special Exhibition' held at Shanghai Super Brand Mall from September 16th to September 28th. In addition to the beverage experience, limited merchandise will also be available on site.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            活动期间，消费者可在全国门店购买「喜柿 · 冰箱贴套餐」，并参与 9 月 16 日至 9 月 28 日在上海正大广场举办的「灵感特展」，现场除饮品体验外，还可获取限量周边。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>自由职业平台裁员 30%</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">自由职业平台裁员-30%</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the Wall Street Journal, Israeli multinational online freelancing service platform Fiverr recently announced it would cut approximately 250 jobs, accounting for about 30% of the company's total workforce. Officials stated that this move is part of the company's &quot;resizing and refocusing&quot; strategy, aimed at creating a leaner, more efficient AI-first organizational structure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据华尔街日报，近日，以色列跨国在线自由职业服务平台 Fiverr 宣布将裁减约 250 个岗位，占公司总员工数的约 30%。官方表示，此举是公司「精简与聚焦（resizing and refocusing）」战略的一部分，旨在打造更精干、更高效的 AI 优先型组织架构。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Fiverr stated that some of the saved costs will be reinvested in business development, while the rest will be used to improve adjusted earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization (EBITDA). The company expects to achieve a long-term adjusted EBITDA margin of 25% in 2026, one year ahead of schedule.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Fiverr 称，部分节省下的成本将重新投入业务发展，其余将用于提升调整后的息税折旧摊销前利润（EBITDA）。公司预计将在 2026 年实现 25% 的长期调整后 EBITDA 利润率，比原计划提前一年。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding its financial report, Fiverr reiterated its Q3 and full-year 2025 financial guidance. Previously, the company's revenue grew by 15% year-over-year in Q2, reaching $108.6 million. Officials noted that &quot;demand for AI-related services is growing rapidly, especially in areas such as AI agents, workflow automation, and 'vibe coding'.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财报方面，Fiverr 重申了 2025 财年第三季度及全年业绩指引。此前二季度公司营收同比增长 15%，达到 1.086 亿美元。官方指出，「AI 相关服务需求正快速增长，尤其是在 AI 智能体、工作流自动化以及『vibe coding』等领域」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Affected by the news, Fiverr's stock price fell 5.6% on the day, closing at $22.52, with a cumulative decline of approximately 29% year-to-date. The company was founded in 2010 and listed on the New York Stock Exchange in 2019.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            受消息影响，Fiverr 股价当日下跌 5.6%，报 22.52 美元，今年以来累计跌幅约 29%。该公司成立于 2010 年，并于 2019 年在纽约证券交易所上市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>纯牛奶生产新规：禁用复原乳</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">纯牛奶生产新规：禁用复原乳</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Guangzhou Daily, the No. 1 amendment to the &quot;National Food Safety Standard for Sterilized Milk,&quot; jointly issued by the National Health Commission and the State Administration for Market Regulation, officially came into effect on September 16.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据广州日报报道，9 月 16 日起，国家卫生健康委、市场监管总局联合发布的《食品安全国家标准 灭菌乳》第 1 号修改单正式施行。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new regulation clarifies that sterilized milk can only be produced using raw milk as an ingredient, and reconstituted milk is not allowed; dairy products produced using reconstituted milk must not be labeled as &quot;pure cow (or goat) milk&quot; or &quot;pure cow (or goat) dairy product,&quot; and will be managed as formulated milk.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新规明确，生产灭菌乳只能以生乳为原料，不得使用复原乳；使用复原乳生产的乳品不得标注「纯牛（羊）奶」或「纯牛（羊）乳」，将作为调制乳管理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reporters visited several supermarkets in Chengdu and found that the ingredient lists of room-temperature pure milk, skim milk, and other products on the shelves only stated &quot;raw milk,&quot; with no mention of &quot;reconstituted milk.&quot; According to interviews, most consumers were unaware of the new regulation and focused more on brands than ingredient lists when purchasing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            记者在成都市区多家商超走访发现，货架上的常温纯牛奶、脱脂牛奶等产品配料表均仅标注「生牛乳」，未见「复原乳」字样。据采访，多数消费者对新规并不知情，选购时更关注品牌而非配料表。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reconstituted milk is a liquid obtained by mixing dried dairy products with water in proportion, commonly known as &quot;milk powder rehydrated with water.&quot; Experts pointed out in the report that reconstituted milk undergoes multiple heat treatments, making some heat-sensitive nutrients such as immunoglobulins, active enzymes, and lactoferrin susceptible to damage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            复原乳是将干燥乳制品与水按比例混匀获得的乳液，俗称「奶粉加水还原」。有专家在报道中指出，复原乳经过多次热加工，部分热敏感营养成分如免疫球蛋白、活性酶、乳铁蛋白等易被破坏。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《汉斯·季默与朋友们：沙漠之钻音乐会》预售开启</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《汉斯·季默与朋友们：沙漠之钻音乐会》预售开启</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/417f0714-5d8d-42f9-adc4-874697f8c43b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The documentary film &quot;Hans Zimmer and Friends: The Desert Diamond Concert&quot; officially opened for pre-sale today and will be released in cinemas nationwide on September 20.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            纪录片电影《汉斯·季默与朋友们：沙漠之钻音乐会》今日正式开启预售，将于 9 月 20 日在全国院线上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film, 158 minutes long, fully captures Hans Zimmer's concert in Dubai. Audiences can not only experience the stunning melodies of classic scores like &quot;Pirates of the Caribbean&quot; and &quot;Inception&quot; with immersive surround sound in theaters but also gain a deeper understanding of the &quot;master composer's&quot; creative philosophy and sources of inspiration through behind-the-scenes footage and interviews.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片全长 158 分钟，完整收录了汉斯·季默在迪拜的音乐会现场。观众不仅能在影院环绕音效下沉浸式体验《加勒比海盗》《盗梦空间》等经典配乐的震撼旋律，还能通过幕后花絮与对谈，深入了解这位「配乐大师」的创作理念与灵感来源。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Notably, the film also showcases interesting anecdotes about Hans Zimmer's collaboration with director Christopher Nolan. Nolan revealed that whenever they discussed the score, Zimmer would constantly come up with new ideas, often forcing him to &quot;call a halt.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，影片还展现了汉斯 · 季默与导演克里斯托弗 · 诺兰的合作趣事。诺兰透露，每次讨论配乐时，季默总能抛出源源不断的新点子，甚至常常让他不得不「叫停」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This film is imported by China Film Group Corporation, and translated and distributed by China Film Co., Ltd. Officials stated that audiences will receive a unique &quot;two-fold surprise with one movie ticket&quot; experience through the big screen and top-tier sound.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本片由中国电影集团公司进口、中国电影产业集团股份有限公司译制并发行。官方表示，观众将通过大银幕与顶级音效，获得「一张电影票，两重惊喜」的独特体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>动画电影《三国的星空第一部》曝制作特辑</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">动画电影《三国的星空第一部》曝制作特辑</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c5bf0dab-cae6-41cf-a58d-02eb25b14f4d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The animated film &quot;The Starry Sky of the Three Kingdoms Part One&quot; released its production special today. The film is written and supervised by Yi Zhongtian, directed by Yu Meng and Yuan Yuan, with Yi Haibei as the general producer, and will be released nationwide on October 1, 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            动画电影《三国的星空第一部》今日发布制作特辑。影片由易中天编剧、监制，于孟、袁原执导，易海贝担任总制片人，将于 2025 年 10 月 1 日全国上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, the creative team, with &quot;authenticity&quot; as its core concept, conducted on-site visits to the Han-Wei Luoyang ancient city ruins, referenced materials from over 100 museums, and drew upon a large number of unearthed artifacts, striving for meticulousness and realism in details. For example, the Han dynasty warhorses in the film are depicted without stirrups, and street fruit stalls only sell pears, both consistent with historical research.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，主创团队以「真」为核心理念，实地走访汉魏洛阳故城遗址，参考超过 100 家博物馆资料，并借鉴大量出土文物，力求在细节上做到考究与真实。例如，影片中汉代战马未设马镫，街头水果摊仅售梨子，均符合史实考证。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The special also features a scene of Cao Cao and Yuan Shao engaging in &quot;diplomatic negotiations,&quot; with dishes including fish sashimi (kuai) and roasted meat (mo zhi), echoing the historical origin of the idiom &quot;kuai zhi ren kou&quot; (popular and widely praised). Furthermore, the &quot;Pottery Storyteller Figurine,&quot; one of the 41 artifacts returned by the United States in March 2025, will also appear in the film, performing alongside the &quot;Eastern Han Drumming Storyteller Figurine&quot; from the National Museum's collection, symbolizing the cultural return of lost artifacts.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            特辑还展示了曹操与袁绍「折冲尊俎」的戏份，菜品包括鱼脍、貊炙，呼应「脍炙人口」一词的历史渊源。此外，2025 年 3 月由美国归还的 41 件文物之一「陶说唱俑」也将在影片中亮相，与国博馆藏的「东汉击鼓说唱俑」同台演绎，象征流失文物的文化回归。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film constructs a grand vision of the Eastern Han Luoyang city: young Emperor Liu Xie moving through a sea of peonies, elephants from the Western Regions presenting tribute, and envoys from myriad nations gathering before Deyang Hall, showcasing a prosperous era comparable to the Roman Empire as &quot;Eastern and Western Twin Powers.&quot; The creative team stated that they hope to enable modern audiences to trace back to the origins, experience the millennium-old Han charm, and foster cultural confidence through the visuals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片构建了盛大的东汉洛阳城景象：小皇帝刘协穿梭于牡丹花海，西域大象入贡，德阳殿前万国来朝，展现出与罗马帝国并称「东西双雄」的盛世风貌。主创团队表示，希望通过影像让新时代观众追本溯源，感受千年汉韵与文化自信。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>惊悚片《女佣》发布角色海报</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 03:31:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">惊悚片《女佣》发布角色海报</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.17_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b7f0a46a-792a-4df3-856c-284bf8fc6b88.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the psychological thriller &quot;The Maid&quot; released multiple character posters, and the film will be released in North America on December 19.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，心理惊悚片《女佣》发布多张角色海报，影片将于 12 月 19 日北美上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is adapted from Freida McFadden's bestselling novel of the same name, telling the story of struggling Millie who, after becoming the maid for the wealthy, upper-class couple Nina and Andrew, feels relieved and starts a new life, but soon discovers that this family's secrets are far more dangerous than her own.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片改编自弗雷达·麦克法登的同名畅销小说，讲述了苦苦奋斗的米莉在成为尼娜和安德鲁这对上流社会的富豪夫妇的女佣后，她如释重负，开始了新的生活，但她很快发现，这个家庭的秘密远比她自己的更危险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is directed by Paul Feig and stars Sydney Sweeney, Amanda Seyfried, and others.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片由保罗·费格执导，西德妮·斯威尼、阿曼达·塞弗里德等主演。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifanr.com/tags/%e6%97%a9%e6%8a%a5&quot;&gt;
            早报
           &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
