<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Meta 斥资数十亿美元收购 Manus，创始人肖弘出任副总裁</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Meta-斥资数十亿美元收购-Manus，创始人肖弘出任副总裁</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f7542e9d-4755-4d49-8782-37738ab731b5.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Today, Meta acquired Butterfly Effect, a Chinese AI startup and developer of AI Agent Manus, for billions of dollars, with both parties making official announcements. This is Meta's third-largest acquisition since its inception, trailing only WhatsApp and Scale AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天，Meta 以数十亿美元收购中国 AI 初创公司、AI Agent Manus 开发商蝴蝶效应，双方均发文官宣。这是 Meta 成立以来的第三大收购，仅次于 WhatsApp 和 Scale AI。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After the transaction is completed, Butterfly Effect will maintain independent operations, and founder Xiao Hong will serve as Meta's Vice President.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            交易完成后，蝴蝶效应将保持独立运营，创始人肖弘将出任 Meta 副总裁。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to LatePost, the acquisition negotiations were completed rapidly within more than ten days. Before Meta proposed the acquisition, Butterfly Effect was undergoing a new round of financing with a valuation of $2 billion. Liu Yuan, partner at ZhenFund and angel investor in Butterfly Effect, stated that the speed of the negotiations made him briefly wonder if it was &quot;a fake offer.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另据《晚点 LatePost》报道，收购谈判在十余天内迅速完成。在 Meta 提出收购前，蝴蝶效应正以 20 亿美元估值进行新一轮融资。真格基金合伙人、蝴蝶效应天使投资人刘元表示，谈判速度之快令人一度怀疑「是不是一个假的 offer」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ultimately, the terms and vision proposed by Meta founder and CEO Mark Zuckerberg impressed the founding team, and Zuckerberg himself, along with several executives, are loyal users of Manus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            最终，Meta 创始人兼 CEO 马克·扎克伯格提出的条件与愿景打动了创始团队，扎克伯格本人及多位高管也是 Manus 的忠实用户。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This acquisition is a crucial step for Meta in advancing its &quot;super intelligence&quot; strategy. In July this year, Zuckerberg stated in an open letter that Meta possesses vast infrastructure and expertise, and has both the willingness and ability to bring new technologies to billions of users.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次收购是 Meta 推进其「超级智能」战略的重要一步。今年 7 月，扎克伯格在公开信中表示，Meta 拥有庞大的基础设施和专业能力，有意愿也有能力将新技术推向数十亿用户。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Concurrently, Meta offered top AI researchers annual salaries exceeding hundreds of millions of dollars and reorganized its AI team.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同期，Meta 向顶尖 AI 研究者开出上亿美元年薪，并重组 AI 团队。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Butterfly Effect was founded in 2022. Its founder, Xiao Hong, graduated from Huazhong University of Science and Technology and previously developed the WeChat official account typesetting tool Yiban and the WeChat Work plugin Weiban.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            蝴蝶效应成立于 2022 年，创始人肖弘毕业于华中科技大学，曾开发微信公众号排版工具壹伴和企业微信插件微伴。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company's first product is the browser AI plugin Monica, which offers large model functionalities such as chat, search, and writing, becoming one of the few profitable AI products in China. In early 2024, ByteDance offered $30 million in an attempt to acquire Butterfly Effect.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司首款产品为浏览器 AI 插件 Monica，提供聊天、搜索、写作等大模型功能，成为中国少数实现盈利的 AI 产品之一。2024 年初，字节跳动曾出价 3000 万美元试图收购蝴蝶效应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In 2024, Ji Yichao, a post-90s serial entrepreneur, and product manager Zhang Tao joined Butterfly Effect to jointly develop Manus. The product launched in March this year, possessing the ability to orchestrate multiple tools to solve complex problems, quickly attracting attention both domestically and internationally. In mid-December, Manus announced that its Annual Recurring Revenue (ARR) had surpassed $100 million.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2024 年，90 后连续创业者季逸超与产品经理张涛加入蝴蝶效应，共同开发出 Manus。该产品于今年 3 月上线，具备调度多工具解决复杂问题的能力，迅速引发中外关注。12 月中旬，Manus 宣布其年度经常性收入（ARR）突破 1 亿美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Before the acquisition, Butterfly Effect completed 4 rounds of financing, with investors including ZhenFund, Sequoia China, Tencent, Benchmark Capital, and several Chinese and American tech entrepreneurs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            收购前，蝴蝶效应共完成 4 轮融资，投资方包括真格基金、红杉中国、腾讯、Benchmark Capital 及多位中美科技创业者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dai Yusen, Managing Partner at ZhenFund, stated that Manus has become a symbol of China's new generation of entrepreneurial spirit, &quot;competing fairly and squarely on the global stage, without relying on connections or seniority.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            真格基金管理合伙人戴雨森表示，Manus 已成为中国新一代创业精神的象征，「不靠关系，不比资历，在全球舞台上光明正大同台竞技」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 高薪招募「备战负责人」，年薪 55.5 万美元 对冲 AI 风险</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-高薪招募「备战负责人」，年薪-55.5-万美元-对冲-AI-风险</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0ea0ebc0-806e-430c-bc9c-9755dff00755.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, OpenAI is recruiting a new &quot;Head of Preparedness,&quot; with an annual salary of $555,000 (approximately 3.89 million RMB) and stock options.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，OpenAI 正在招聘一名新的「Head of Preparedness」（备战负责人），年薪为 55.5 万美元（约合 389 万元人民币），并提供期权。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This position belongs to OpenAI's Safety Systems team and is responsible for building capability evaluations, threat modeling, and mitigation measures for models, establishing a coherent, rigorous, and scalable safety process to limit the potential negative impacts of artificial intelligence.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该职位隶属于 OpenAI 的 Safety Systems 团队，负责为模型构建能力评估、威胁建模和缓解措施，搭建一套连贯、严谨且可规模化运行的安全流程，以限制人工智能可能带来的负面影响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI CEO Sam Altman recently posted on X, stating that this is a role &quot;taking on a critical part at an important moment.&quot; Model capabilities are rapidly improving, not only already able to complete many valuable tasks but also beginning to bring real-world challenges.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI CEO Sam Altman 近日在 X 上发文称，这是一个「在重要时刻承担关键角色」的岗位，模型能力正快速提升，不仅已经能完成许多有价值的任务，也开始带来现实挑战。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He specifically mentioned that the potential impact of large models on mental health has already had a &quot;preview&quot; this year, and in the cybersecurity domain, models are already &quot;good enough to start finding critical vulnerabilities.&quot; This means that preventing the misuse of these capabilities will be one of the core tasks of this role.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他特别提到，大模型对心理健康的潜在影响在今年已有「预览」，而在网络安全领域，模型已经「好到开始发现关键漏洞」，这意味着如何防止这些能力被滥用，将是该岗位的核心任务之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman stated in the post that OpenAI already has a relatively mature system for measuring capabilities, but the next step is to understand in more detail how these capabilities might be misused and to design effective constraint mechanisms in products and the real world, allowing society to minimize risks while enjoying the immense benefits brought by AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Altman 在贴文中表示，OpenAI 已有一套较为成熟的能力测量体系，但接下来需要更加细致地理解这些能力可能如何被滥用，并在产品和现实世界中设计出有效的约束机制，让社会在享受 AI 带来的巨大收益时，尽量减少风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that this job would be &quot;very high-pressure,&quot; and the new head would be &quot;thrown into the deep end almost immediately.&quot; He also called for those interested in topics such as cutting-edge cybersecurity defense, biosafety, and self-improving system safety to consider applying.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，这份工作会「非常有压力」，新任负责人将「几乎立刻被丢进深水区」。他还呼吁，对前沿网络安全防御、生物安全以及自改进系统安全性等议题感兴趣的人考虑应聘。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the job description, the new Head of Preparedness will be directly responsible for the evaluation system and protection strategies, coordinating the team to build testing and safety pipelines for different threat scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据职位描述，新任备战负责人将对评估体系和防护策略负直接责任，协调团队构建面向不同威胁场景的测试和安全管线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This position is seen as a hub for OpenAI's &quot;proactive governance&quot; in model safety: it requires both understanding and predicting the model's capability boundaries and designing actionable prevention mechanisms to avoid the model being used by attackers for high-risk purposes such as cyber intrusion or biological threats.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该岗位被视为 OpenAI 在模型安全「前置治理」上的枢纽：既要理解和预测模型的能力边界，又要设计出可操作的防范机制，避免模型被攻击者用于网络入侵、生物威胁等高风险用途。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI has always declared its core mission is &quot;to develop artificial intelligence in a way that benefits all of humanity,&quot; and has regarded safety protocols as a core part of its operations since the company's early days. However, with the successive launch of products and increasing commercialization pressure, some former employees have publicly questioned the company's balance between safety and profitability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 一直宣称其核心使命是「以造福全人类的方式发展人工智能」，并从公司早期就将安全协议视作运营的核心部分。然而，随着产品陆续推出、商业化压力上升，一些前员工曾公开质疑公司在安全与盈利之间的平衡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A former employee who was responsible for AGI-related safety research stated in a blog post last year that they had &quot;gradually lost confidence in the company's ability to act responsibly as it approaches AGI,&quot; and pointed out a significant turnover in the relevant safety team over the past year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一名曾负责 AGI 相关安全研究的前员工在去年发表的博客中称，自己「对公司在接近 AGI 时能否负责任地行事逐渐失去信心」，并指出相关安全团队的人员在过去一年出现较大流失。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI also previously drew attention due to the way ChatGPT was used in mental health scenarios. As chatbots became popular among consumers, many users treated them as &quot;alternative confidants,&quot; which to some extent exacerbated mental health issues in certain cases.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 早前也因 ChatGPT 在心理健康场景中的使用方式而遭到关注。随着聊天机器人在消费者之间普及，不少用户将其当作「替代性倾诉对象」，在一定程度上加剧了部分案例中的精神健康问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last October, OpenAI stated it was collaborating with mental health professionals to improve how ChatGPT interacts with users at risk of self-harm, delusions, and other issues, to reduce potential harm caused by the model in sensitive scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年 10 月，OpenAI 表示正与心理健康专业人士合作，改进 ChatGPT 与存在自伤、妄想等风险用户的互动方式，以减少模型在敏感场景下可能造成的伤害。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Against this backdrop, on the one hand, OpenAI is attempting to attract senior talent with backgrounds in safety, cybersecurity defense, or biological risk assessment, by offering high salaries and clearer responsibilities;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在这一背景下，一方面，OpenAI 试图用高薪和更清晰的权责，吸引具备安全、网络攻防或生物风险评估背景的高级人才；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the other hand, this is also seen as a signal to respond to external doubts and reassert safety as a priority: while vigorously pursuing commercialization, more systematic evaluation and protection mechanisms will be implemented to hedge against the social risks that AI might trigger.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另一方面，这也被视为对外回应质疑、重申安全优先级的信号：在高强度商业化推进的同时，将通过更加系统化的评估和防护机制，来对冲 AI 可能引发的社会风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>微信回应「占用存储空间」八大误解：聊天记录才是最大「空间大户」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微信回应「占用存储空间」八大误解：聊天记录才是最大「空间大户」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8f0fdced-445e-4a0f-8715-7afee03302e5.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, WeChat systematically responded in its official podcast to several long-standing misconceptions surrounding WeChat's storage consumption, and introduced recent and future optimization directions. The team emphasized that the true core of space occupation is not cache, but local chat records that cannot be rebuilt in the cloud. WeChat officially stated:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，微信在官方播客中系统回应了围绕微信占用存储空间的多项长期误解，并介绍近期及未来的优化方向。团队强调，真正占用空间的核心并非缓存，而是无法在云端重建的本地聊天记录。微信官方表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             The same file forwarded in multiple chats will not be saved repeatedly; the system relies on a hard link mechanism to make multiple references point to the same underlying file. Only when using third-party tools to export data will hard links be broken down into multiple independent files, thus creating the illusion of &quot;duplicate files&quot;;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             同一文件在多个聊天中转发并不会重复保存，系统依赖硬链接机制让多个引用指向同一份底层文件；只有在使用第三方工具导出数据时，硬链接才会被拆解成多份独立文件，从而造成「重复文件」的错觉；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             The situation where space is not immediately reduced after deleting chat records is due to an asynchronous deletion mechanism; the system will perform actual cleanup when the device is idle to avoid data corruption caused by tight space;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             删除聊天记录后空间未立即减少的情况为异步删除机制所致，系统会在设备空闲时再执行实际清理，以避免因空间紧张导致数据损坏；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Among users whose WeChat occupies over 40GB of space, chat records account for an average of over 70%. Content such as Moments, Mini Programs, and Video Accounts mostly belong to renewable data, which are categorized into automatically cleanable cache areas and will not grow indefinitely;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             在微信占用空间超过 40GB 的用户中，聊天记录平均占比超过 70%。朋友圈、小程序、视频号等内容多属于可再生数据，会被归入可自动清理的缓存区域，不会无限增长；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             &quot;Expired files&quot; do not occupy local space, while &quot;necessary files&quot; include basic resources required for operation; deleting them may lead to functional abnormalities, so manual cleanup is not available;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             「文件过期」并不占用本地空间，「必要文件」则包含运行所需的基础资源，删除可能导致功能异常，因此不会开放手动清理；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
              The &quot;hundreds of times&quot; expansion of the installation package size over more than a decade is a natural result of feature expansion
             &lt;/strong&gt;
             , but the Android version has been continuously optimizing its size; storage optimization is a long-term project that cannot be solved by a single technical means.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
              安装包体积「十多年来膨胀了几百倍」是功能扩展的自然结果
             &lt;/strong&gt;
             ，但安卓版本已在持续优化体积；存储优化是一项长期工程，难以依靠单一技术手段解决。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding specific measures:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            具体措施方面：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             WeChat has launched multiple optimizations, including sorting by file size, batch cleaning original images and videos while retaining compressed versions, avoiding duplicate saving in albums, background deduplication and merging of historical files, and further compressing image and video sizes;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             微信已上线多项优化，包括按文件大小排序、批量清理原图原视频并保留压缩版本、避免相册重复保存、后台去重合并历史文件，以及进一步压缩图片视频体积；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             The trigger threshold for the &quot;storage full&quot; pop-up has been lowered, the storage space entry has been moved forward, and more cleanable data has been separated from previously un-cleanable categories.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             下调了存储不足弹窗的触发阈值，前置存储空间入口，并将更多可清理数据从原本不可清理的类别中拆分出来。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            WeChat stated that all optimizations are based on the premise of not losing user data, especially chat records. In the future, it will continue to improve mechanism visibility, such as showing how many chats a file is referenced by, to narrow the gap between technical implementation and user perception.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微信表示，所有优化均以不丢失用户数据为前提，尤其是聊天记录。未来将继续提升机制可见性，例如展示文件被多少个聊天引用，以缩小技术实现与用户感知之间的差距。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>苹果上诉 15 亿英镑「苹果税」反垄断裁决</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果上诉-15-亿英镑「苹果税」反垄断裁决</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8c357e84-7ad9-4d8a-8fc7-2b868c410898.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Guardian, Apple has applied to the UK Court of Appeal to overturn an antitrust ruling totaling £1.5 billion (approximately $1.76 billion).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《卫报》报道，苹果已向英国上诉法院提出申请，要求推翻一项金额高达 15 亿英镑（约合 17.6 亿美元）的反垄断裁决。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The ruling found that Apple abused its dominant position in the iOS app distribution market between 2015 and 2024, charging users excessive App Store commissions and harming the interests of approximately 36 million British consumers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该裁决认定苹果在 2015 年至 2024 年间滥用其在 iOS 应用分发市场的主导地位，向用户收取过高的 App Store 佣金，损害了约 3600 万英国消费者的利益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In October this year, the UK Competition Appeal Tribunal (CAT) ruled that Apple, through its closed control over the App Store on iPhones and iPads, charged commissions as high as 30%, far exceeding what would likely be seen in a competitive market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 10 月，英国竞争上诉法庭（CAT）裁定，苹果通过对 iPhone 和 iPad 上的 App Store 实施封闭控制，收取高达 30% 的佣金，远高于竞争市场中可能出现的水平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The court believed that reasonable commissions should be 17.5% for app sales and 10% for in-app purchases. The case was brought as a class action, and all UK users who made purchases through the App Store during the relevant period were automatically included in the claim, unless they actively opted out.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            法庭认为，合理的佣金应为应用销售的 17.5%、应用内购买的 10%。该案以集体诉讼形式提出，所有在相关期间内通过 App Store 消费的英国用户均被自动纳入索赔范围，除非主动选择退出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple strongly opposed the ruling, arguing that the court's understanding of the app economy was fundamentally flawed, and emphasized that the App Store offers advantages such as security, privacy protection, and a vast market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果对该裁决表示强烈反对，认为法庭对应用经济的理解存在根本性错误，并强调 App Store 提供了安全、隐私保护和庞大市场等优势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company pointed out that most developers currently only pay a 15% commission, and last year, the App Store facilitated over $55 billion in sales in the UK.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司指出，目前大多数开发者仅需支付 15% 的佣金，且去年 App Store 在英国促成了超过 550 亿美元的销售额。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After being denied permission to appeal by CAT in November this year, Apple directly applied to the Court of Appeal for review. If this appeal is rejected again, the £1.5 billion compensation will be distributed to eligible British consumers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在今年 11 月被 CAT 拒绝上诉许可后，苹果直接向上诉法院申请复审。若该上诉再次被驳回，15 亿英镑的赔偿金将分配给符合条件的英国消费者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>「全球大模型第一股」智谱华章启动招股</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">「全球大模型第一股」智谱华章启动招股</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/85c2b7ab-2b9c-41c3-ba55-747e71c9d4b8.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On December 30, Zhipu Huazhang, a large model vendor, officially launched its global offering, planning to list on the main board of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on January 8, 2026, with stock code 02513.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            12 月 30 日，大模型厂商智谱华章正式启动全球招股，计划于 2026 年 1 月 8 日在港交所主板挂牌交易，股票代码为 02513。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This IPO is dubbed by the market as the &quot;first global large model stock,&quot; marking the entry of a representative enterprise in China's Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) field into the capital market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次 IPO 被市场称为「全球大模型第一股」，标志着中国通用人工智能（AGI）领域的代表性企业迈入资本市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the global offering document, Zhipu Huazhang plans to issue 37.4195 million H shares, with 1.871 million shares for public offering in Hong Kong and 35.5485 million shares for international offering. The issue price is HKD 116.20 per share, with an expected total fundraising of HKD 4.3 billion, corresponding to a post-IPO market capitalization exceeding HKD 51.1 billion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据全球发售文件，智谱华章本次拟发行 3741.95 万股 H 股，其中香港公开发售 187.1 万股，国际发售 3554.85 万股，发行价为每股 116.20 港元，预计募资总额达 43 亿港元，对应 IPO 后市值超过 511 亿港元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhipu was founded in 2019, dedicated to building China's local general artificial intelligence technology system, and has established a full-stack original architecture and complete model system comparable to OpenAI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            智谱成立于 2019 年，致力于打造中国本土的通用人工智能技术体系，已构建起对标 OpenAI 的全栈原创架构和完整模型体系。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Frost &amp;amp; Sullivan data, Zhipu ranked first among independent general large model developers in China by last year's revenue. Its revenue grew from 57.4 million yuan in 2022 to 312.4 million yuan in 2024, with a compound annual growth rate of 130%; revenue in the first half of this year was 191 million yuan, a year-on-year increase of 325%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据弗若斯特沙利文数据，按去年收入计算，智谱在中国独立通用大模型开发商中排名第一。其收入从 2022 年的 5740 万元增长至 2024 年的 3.124 亿元，年复合增长率达 130%；今年上半年收入为 1.91 亿元，同比增长 325%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of R&amp;amp;D investment, Zhipu maintains high-intensity investment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在研发投入方面，智谱保持高强度投入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The prospectus shows that R&amp;amp;D expenses from 2022 to 2024 were 84.4 million yuan, 528.9 million yuan, and 2.1954 billion yuan, respectively. Investment in the first half of this year reached 1.5947 billion yuan, with cumulative R&amp;amp;D expenditure of approximately 4.4 billion yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            招股书显示，2022 年至 2024 年研发费用分别为 8440 万元、5.289 亿元和 21.954 亿元，今年上半年投入达 15.947 亿元，累计研发支出约 44 亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Its latest model, GLM-4.7, has topped both the open-source model and domestic model rankings in the global authoritative evaluation list, the AA Intelligence Index.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其最新模型 GLM-4.7 已在全球权威评测榜单 AA 智能指数中，位列开源模型与国产模型双榜首。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The prospectus discloses that 70% of the net proceeds (approximately HK$2.9 billion) will be used for R&amp;amp;D investment in general AI large models, and 10% (approximately HK$420 million) will be used for the continuous optimization of the MaaS platform, including base model updates, training and inference tools, and infrastructure construction.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            招股文件披露，募集资金净额的 70%（约 29 亿港元）将用于通用 AI 大模型的研发投入，10%（约 4.2 亿港元）将用于 MaaS 平台的持续优化，包括基座模型更新、训练与推理工具及基础设施建设。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This offering will continue until January 5 next year. If successfully listed, Zhipu Huazhang will become the first listed company in the Hong Kong stock market focused on general large models, further consolidating its leading position in the AGI field.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次招股将持续至明年 1 月 5 日，若顺利上市，智谱华章将成为港股市场首家专注通用大模型的上市公司，进一步巩固其在 AGI 领域的领先地位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>上汽通用五菱首款「满血华为」车型登陆华为乾崑 App</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">上汽通用五菱首款「满血华为」车型登陆华为乾崑-App</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1c93ccd1-581e-4a5e-8cdf-e67b036ba6e9.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the first flagship model from the deepened strategic cooperation between SAIC-GM-Wuling and Huawei, the &quot;Huajing S&quot;, officially launched on the Huawei Qiankun App, marking the completion of the new car's R&amp;amp;D verification and its full entry into a new user-oriented phase.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，上汽通用五菱与华为深化战略合作的首款旗舰车型「华境 S」正式登陆华为乾崑 App，标志着新车完成研发验证并全面进入面向用户的新阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This launch also marks an important milestone for the strategic synergy between the two parties, moving towards substantial implementation since the signing of the &quot;Three Intelligences&quot; (assisted driving, intelligent cockpit, intelligent manufacturing) deepened cooperation agreement in September this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次上线也是双方自今年 9 月签署「三智」（辅助驾驶、智能座舱、智能制造）深化合作协议以来，战略协同迈向实质落地的重要节点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Huajing S comes standard with the Huawei Qiankun solution across all models, representing a concentrated embodiment of the integrated capabilities of both parties.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            华境 S 全系标配华为乾崑解决方案，是双方融合能力的集中体现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Its &quot;full-blooded Huawei&quot; technical solution includes Qiankun Smart Driving HUAWEI ADS 4 Pro, Harmony Cockpit HarmonySpace 5, Qiankun Vehicle Cloud HUAWEI IVCS, and is among the first to be equipped with Huawei's in-cabin laser vision (Limera), achieving complete intelligent capabilities in the vehicle.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其「满血华为」技术方案包括乾崑智驾 HUAWEI ADS 4 Pro、鸿蒙座舱 HarmonySpace 5、乾崑车云 HUAWEI IVCS，并首批搭载华为舱内激光视觉（Limera），实现智能能力的完整上车。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, SAIC-GM-Wuling, with its manufacturing experience covering over 31 million users, strong supply chain integration capabilities, and a smart island manufacturing system (I²MS) with tens of billions of investment, constitutes another &quot;Hua&quot; standard for the Huajing S, providing manufacturing-side assurance for the product's realization from concept to experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，上汽通用五菱以覆盖超过 3100 万用户的制造经验、强大的供应链整合能力，以及百亿级投入的智能岛制造体系（I²MS），构成华境 S 的另一重「华」标准，为产品从理念到体验的落地提供制造端保障。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new car is planned to be launched in the first half of next year and will be one of the first models equipped with Huawei Qiankun Smart Driving ADS 4 Pro.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新车计划于明年上半年上市，并将成为首批搭载华为乾崑智驾 ADS 4 Pro 的车型之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            SAIC-GM-Wuling stated that the Huajing S, built upon the deep foundations of both parties, will work with users to move towards a better travel experience. It will continue to adhere to the principle of &quot;Wuling builds what the people need,&quot; promoting the high-quality development of China's automotive industry and showcasing new heights of Chinese intelligent manufacturing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上汽通用五菱表示，华境 S 立足双方深厚积淀，将与用户共同迈向更美好的出行体验。将继续坚持「人民需要什么，五菱就造什么」，推动中国汽车产业高质量发展，展现中国智造的新高度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蚂蚁阿福辟谣：问答无广告、不做商业排名</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蚂蚁阿福辟谣：问答无广告、不做商业排名</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/fd7ab316-050d-487f-828a-6044c61cba20.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Ant Group's AI health application &quot;Ant Afu&quot; issued a statement responding to recent market rumors, emphasizing that its Q&amp;amp;A results &quot;do not contain any advertising recommendations, commercial rankings, nor are they influenced by any other commercial factors&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，蚂蚁集团旗下 AI 健康应用「蚂蚁阿福」发布声明，回应近期市场上出现的相关谣言，强调其问答结果中「没有任何广告推荐、不存在商业排名，也不受任何其他商业因素干扰」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In mid-this month, Ant Group announced the upgrade of its AQ brand to &quot;Ant Afu&quot; and released a new version of the App, upgrading around three major functions: health companionship, health Q&amp;amp;A, and health services, shifting its positioning from an AI tool to an &quot;AI health friend&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本月中旬，蚂蚁集团宣布将旗下 AQ 品牌升级为「蚂蚁阿福」，并发布 App 新版本，围绕健康陪伴、健康问答与健康服务三大功能进行升级，定位从 AI 工具转向「AI 健康朋友」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The upgraded product focuses on the &quot;Health +&quot; strategy, aiming to help users manage their personal and family health in a more human-like way.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            升级后的产品聚焦「健康 +」战略，旨在以更贴近真人的方式帮助用户管理自身与家庭健康。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to data disclosed by Ant Group, the &quot;Ant Afu&quot; App's monthly active users have exceeded 15 million, placing it among the top five AI Apps in China and making it the largest health management AI application in the country. Currently, Afu answers over 5 million health questions daily, with 55% of users coming from third-tier cities and below.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据蚂蚁集团披露的数据，「蚂蚁阿福」App 月活用户已超过 1500 万，跻身国内 AI App 前五，成为国内规模最大的健康管理类 AI 应用。目前，阿福每天回答超过 500 万个健康提问，其中 55% 用户来自三线及以下城市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>摄影大赛一等奖作品被指 AI 生成，主办方：正在核查</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">摄影大赛一等奖作品被指-AI-生成，主办方：正在核查</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0a4ba6da-5d81-48ad-b6ed-9b493fcff125.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiupai News, the &quot;Fresh Fujian · Meet Lvfa&quot; photography competition hosted by Fujian Provincial Tourism Development Group recently attracted attention due to its first-prize winning work, &quot;Lake Autumn Mist Shadow,&quot; being questioned as AI-generated.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据九派新闻报道，福建省旅游发展集团主办的「清新福建 · 遇见旅发」摄影大赛近日因一等奖作品《湖秋雾影》被质疑为 AI 生成，引发关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The work was submitted by a photography enthusiast named Zhou, winning the first prize, which included 1,000 yuan and a &quot;Fresh Fujian&quot; cultural tourism benefit card worth 199 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该作品由署名为周某某的摄影爱好者投稿，获得一等奖，奖金为 1000 元及一张价值 199 元的「清新福建」文旅惠民卡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The list of winners for the competition was announced on December 18th this year, with 5 first prizes, 10 second prizes, 20 third prizes, and 153 finalist awards. The competition explicitly stipulated that entries must be original images, prohibiting synthesis, image swapping, and AI generation. Participants were required to fill in the shooting location and guarantee the authenticity of their work.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            大赛于今年 12 月 18 日公布获奖名单，评选出一等奖 5 名、二等奖 10 名、三等奖 20 名及入围奖 153 名。大赛明确规定参赛作品必须为原创图片，禁止合成、换图及 AI 生成，参赛者需填写拍摄地点并保证作品真实性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The doubts arose from analyses by netizens and professionals regarding the image details of &quot;Lake Autumn Mist Shadow.&quot; A photographer from the Fujian Photographers Association pointed out that when magnified, the work showed distortion in the straightness of building edges, skewed window outlines, and blurred text, leading to a higher probability of it being AI-generated.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            质疑声源于网友及专业人士对《湖秋雾影》图像细节的分析。福建省摄影家协会一位摄影师指出，该作品在放大后出现建筑边缘曲直失真、窗户轮廓歪斜、文字模糊等问题，判断为 AI 生成的可能性较高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            AIGC domain experts further pointed out that the leaf textures and color transitions in the image are too uniform, lacking the detailed differences found in real photos due to changes in lighting and perspective, presenting an overall &quot;overly smooth&quot; texture.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            AIGC 领域专家进一步指出，图中树叶纹理与颜色过渡过于均匀，缺乏真实照片中因光照与视角变化产生的细节差异，整体呈现「过度平滑」的质感。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Another AI detection tool analyzed the image, and the results showed an AI generation concentration of 43.95%, but the system could not definitively determine whether it was an AI work. Some netizens pointed out that such tools are only for reference and cannot be used as a final basis for judgment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另有 AI 检测工具对该图像进行分析，结果显示 AI 生成浓度为 43.95%，但系统未能明确判定其是否为 AI 作品。部分网友指出，该类工具仅具参考价值，无法作为最终判定依据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Facing the controversy,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the organizer, Fujian Tourism Development Group, responded that it had received relevant queries during the public announcement period and is currently investigating, with results to be announced through official channels later.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Regarding issues such as the composition of the judging panel, the organizer stated it was &quot;inconvenient to disclose&quot; but emphasized that the matter would be handled strictly in accordance with the competition's official terms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            面对争议，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             主办方福建省旅游发展集团回应称，已在公示期间收到相关质疑，目前正在核查中，后续将通过官方渠道公布调查结果。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            对于评委组成等问题，主办方表示「不便透露」，但强调将严格依据大赛公告条款处理此事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>京东 x 宇树科技全国首店明天开业</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">京东-x-宇树科技全国首店明天开业</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4f753629-87de-4988-b036-a98aa058cacf.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Unitree Robotics announced that its first offline store in China, in collaboration with JD.com, will officially open in Beijing on December 31st, marking the formal establishment of its retail channel.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，宇树科技宣布，其与京东合作的全国首家线下门店将于 12 月 31 日在北京正式开业，标志着其零售渠道正式落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the store is located in JD MALL (Beijing Shuangjing Store) and showcases several star products from Unitree Robotics, including the Go2 quadruped robot dog and the G1 humanoid robot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，该门店选址于京东 MALL（北京双井店），集中展示了宇树科技旗下多款明星产品，包括 Go2 四足机器狗与 G1 人形机器人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The store features an immersive interactive experience zone where users can experience robot products on-site, and by scanning product QR codes, jump to the official mini-program for self-service ordering, supporting in-store pickup or home delivery by JD.com.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            店内设有沉浸式互动体验区，用户可现场体验机器人产品，并通过扫描商品二维码跳转至官方小程序自助下单，支持门店自提或由京东配送到家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to the Shuangjing store, Unitree Robotics' first national store has also officially opened in Beijing Wangfujing Yintai in88, with hoarding construction already completed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除双井门店外，宇树科技全国首店也已正式入驻北京王府井银泰 in88，目前已完成围挡施工。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that Unitree Robotics was founded in 2016, focusing on the independent research and development and production of consumer-grade and industrial-grade high-performance legged/humanoid robots and dexterous robotic arms. With its fully self-developed core technology, the company became the world's first to publicly retail high-performance quadruped robots and be the first to achieve industry implementation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开资料显示，宇树科技成立于 2016 年，专注于消费级与行业级高性能足式/人形机器人及灵巧机械臂的自主研发与生产。公司凭借全自研核心技术，成为全球首家公开零售高性能四足机器人并率先实现行业落地的企业。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>机构：DRAM 缺货加剧，价格在明年也不会下降</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">机构：DRAM-缺货加剧，价格在明年也不会下降</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            NPR recently published a blog post stating that as artificial intelligence drives a surge in demand for memory chips, the global DRAM (Dynamic Random Access Memory) market is facing a severe supply-demand imbalance, which is expected to push up prices for various consumer electronic products, including smartphones, computers, and game consoles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            NPR 日前发表博文称，随着人工智能对内存芯片的需求激增，全球 DRAM（动态随机存取存储器）市场正面临严重供需失衡，预计将推高包括智能手机、电脑、游戏主机等多类消费电子产品的价格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wu Yating, Senior Vice President at market research firm TrendForce, stated that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             current DRAM chip demand already exceeds supply by about 10%, and the gap continues to widen.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            市场研究机构 TrendForce 集邦咨询高级副总裁吴雅婷表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             目前 DRAM 芯片的需求已超出供应约 10%，且缺口仍在持续扩大。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            She pointed out that in the fourth quarter of this year, manufacturers' costs for purchasing DRAM increased by 50% compared to the previous quarter; if faster delivery is desired, prices could even be two to three times the original.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Wu expects DRAM prices to rise by another 40% next quarter, stating that &quot;prices will not fall next year either.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            她指出，今年第四季度，制造商采购 DRAM 的成本较上一季度上涨了 50%；若希望加快交付，价格甚至可能是原价的两到三倍。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             吴预计，下一季度 DRAM 价格还将上涨 40%，并称「价格在明年也不会下降」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report suggests that the demand for memory from AI data centers is the main reason for the rising chip prices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道认为，AI 数据中心对内存的需求是推高芯片价格的主要原因。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sanchit Vir Gogia, CEO of Greyhound Research, stated that AI model training and inference systems require large, continuous memory resources, high bandwidth, and tight coupling with computing units. &quot;AI has changed the nature of demand,&quot; he said, indicating this is not a cyclical fluctuation but a structural shift.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Greyhound Research CEO Sanchit Vir Gogia 表示，AI 模型的训练与推理系统需要大量、持续的内存资源、高带宽以及与计算单元的紧密耦合，「AI 改变了需求的本质」，这并非周期性波动，而是结构性转变。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            To meet the AI demand for high-end memory, chip manufacturers are prioritizing shifting production capacity to the more profitable AI market. Micron CEO Sanjay Mehrotra stated in the latest earnings call that the company's performance exceeded expectations, benefiting from rising memory prices, and predicted that &quot;industry total supply will remain well below demand for the foreseeable future.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            为满足高端内存的 AI 需求，芯片制造商正优先将产能转向利润更高的 AI 市场。美光 CEO Sanjay Mehrotra 在最新财报电话会议中表示，受益于内存价格上涨，公司业绩超出预期，并预计「在可预见的未来，行业总供应仍将远低于需求」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, this also means that memory supply for traditional consumer electronic products such as PCs, mobile phones, and TVs will be further squeezed. Dell Technologies COO Jeff Clarke frankly stated in the November 25th earnings call that rising PC costs are inevitable, saying, &quot;I don't think this won't be passed on to consumers.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            然而，这也意味着传统消费电子产品如 PC、手机、电视等的内存供应将被进一步压缩。戴尔科技 COO Jeff Clarke 在 11 月 25 日的财报电话会议中坦言，PC 成本上升已不可避免，「我不认为这不会传导至消费者端」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the short term, the industry will find it difficult to alleviate the supply-demand imbalance through capacity expansion. Wu Yating pointed out that the expansion capacity of existing factories will reach its limit by the end of 2026, while Micron's new factory in Idaho is not expected to start production until 2027.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            短期内，行业难以通过扩产缓解供需矛盾。吴雅婷指出，现有工厂的扩产能力将在 2026 年底达到极限，而美光在爱达荷州新建的工厂预计要到 2027 年才能投产。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Amidst the AI-driven memory chip boom, consumers may face higher device prices, while chip manufacturers usher in a new growth cycle.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 AI 带动的内存芯片热潮下，消费者或将面临更高的设备价格，而芯片制造商则迎来新一轮增长周期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曾经为双屏手机开发的 Windows 系统被曝光</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曾经为双屏手机开发的-Windows-系统被曝光</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/de591b98-8062-41a9-9ae2-1acf359095e8.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Microsoft's &quot;Andromeda OS,&quot; a Windows-like operating system developed for the Surface Duo series but later canceled, has recently been &quot;resurrected&quot; by enthusiasts from an internal build and successfully run on the first-generation Surface Duo.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微软曾为 Surface Duo 系列开发、但已被取消的类 Windows 操作系统「Andromeda OS」近日被爱好者从内部版本中「复活」，并成功在首代 Surface Duo 上运行。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, the system is based on Windows 10, with an interface style similar to early Windows Phone, and was previously internally codenamed 'Windows 8828080', never officially released to the public.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，该系统基于 Windows 10，界面风格类似早年的 Windows Phone，此前在内部被称为「Windows 8828080」，从未正式对公众发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Andromeda OS is being demonstrated by community developer Gustave Monce on the first-generation Surface Duo. He showcased the system's operation on social platform X and provided a mirror download link and detailed installation instructions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，Andromeda OS 由社区开发者 Gustave Monce 在首代 Surface Duo 上演示，他在社交平台 X 上展示了系统运行画面，并提供了镜像下载链接以及详细安装指引。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The installation guide is hosted on GitHub. Users need to flash the system onto the device, but it only supports the first-generation Surface Duo; due to driver issues, it currently cannot boot properly on the Surface Duo 2.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            安装指南托管在 GitHub，用户需要通过刷机方式将系统写入设备，但仅支持首代 Surface Duo，因驱动问题暂时无法在 Surface Duo 2 上正常启动。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Based on the currently released version, Andromeda OS is still in a preview state, and its stability and feature completeness are insufficient for use as a daily primary system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从当前放出的版本来看，Andromeda OS 仍处于预览状态，稳定性和功能完整性均不足以作为日常主力系统使用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            💻 GitHub:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WOA-Project/SurfaceDuo-Guides/blob/main/Install/AOS/SurfaceDuo1.md&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/WOA-Project/SurfaceDuo-Guides/blob/main/Install/AOS/SurfaceDuo1.md
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            💻 GitHub:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/WOA-Project/SurfaceDuo-Guides/blob/main/Install/AOS/SurfaceDuo1.md&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/WOA-Project/SurfaceDuo-Guides/blob/main/Install/AOS/SurfaceDuo1.md
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>正式官宣，火山引擎成为总台春晚独家 AI 云合作伙伴</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">正式官宣，火山引擎成为总台春晚独家-AI-云合作伙伴</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3cca6dc2-5c73-486e-9bc8-3a7b20cf3c0e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the launch event for the sub-venues of the '2026 Spring Festival Gala' was held in Beijing, where it was announced that Volcengine has become the exclusive AI cloud partner for the CCTV Spring Festival Gala. Based on multimodal large models and cloud computing technology, Volcengine will deeply participate in program production, online interaction, and video live streaming, providing technical support for the show.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，《2026 年春节联欢晚会》分会场发布活动在北京举行，会上宣布火山引擎成为总台春晚独家 AI 云合作伙伴。基于多模态大模型与云计算技术，火山引擎将深度参与节目生产、线上互动及视频直播，为节目提供技术支撑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As ByteDance's cloud and AI service platform, Volcengine has continuously provided underlying technical support for Douyin's Spring Festival Gala live broadcasts over the past 5 years, and in 2021, it supported Douyin in completing 70.3 billion red packet interactions, demonstrating its high-concurrency bearing capacity and stability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            作为字节跳动旗下的云与 AI 服务平台，火山引擎在过去 5 年持续为抖音春晚直播提供底层技术保障，并在 2021 年支撑抖音完成 703 亿次红包互动，展现出高并发承载能力与稳定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This year, Volcengine has built an AI cloud-native architecture based on large models, becoming the AI cloud service provider with the highest market share in China's public cloud large model market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年，火山引擎基于大模型构建 AI 云原生架构，已成为中国公有云大模型市场份额最高的 AI 云服务商。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 Related reading:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/EBQMamOw6nFIluLsPdxJzA&quot;&gt;
             Doubao is going to the Spring Festival Gala, can we rely on AI to get red packets for the New Year?
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 相关阅读：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/EBQMamOw6nFIluLsPdxJzA&quot;&gt;
             豆包要上春晚了，过年能靠 AI 领红包吗?
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>智能手机被收走后，纽约教师发现学生问得最多的是「现在几点」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">智能手机被收走后，纽约教师发现学生问得最多的是「现在几点」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f87699ac-1904-4472-9d2f-0232bbb36641.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Gothamist, after New York State implemented a smartphone ban in public schools statewide this fall, some teachers unexpectedly discovered that many middle school students couldn't read traditional analog clocks and had to repeatedly ask teachers, 'What time is it now?'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Gothamist 报道，纽约州今年秋季在全州公立学校实施智能手机禁令后，一些教师意外发现：不少中学生不会看传统指针钟，只能一遍遍问老师「现在几点了」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report quoted Tiana Millen, an assistant principal at Cardozo High School in Queens, New York City, who stated that the phone ban has had a generally noticeable effect: students are more focused in class, move more smoothly in hallways, are more willing to chat with each other at lunch instead of staring at screens, and tardiness rates have decreased.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道援引纽约市皇后区 Cardozo 高中的一名副校长 Tiana Millen 表示，手机禁令总体效果明显，学生在课堂上更专心、在走廊里行走更顺畅，中午也更愿意彼此聊天而不是盯着屏幕，迟到率有所下降。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, she also pointed out that a new problem has emerged: many students, even when looking up at the wall clock, 'don't know if they are late' because they simply cannot read analog clock time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但她也指出，一个新问题随之暴露 —— 很多学生即便抬头看墙上的时钟，也「不知道自己是不是迟到了」，因为他们根本不会读指针钟时间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Madi Mornhinweg, a high school English teacher in Manhattan, said the situation was so severe that she had to 're-teach' content learned in childhood, such as the most basic clock-reading training like 'where is the big hand, where is the small hand'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            曼哈顿一名高中英语教师 Madi Mornhinweg 称，这一情况严重到她不得不在课堂上「重教」小时候学过的内容，例如「大指针在哪儿、小指针在哪儿」这类最基础的读钟训练。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The New York City Department of Education responded that, according to curriculum standards, students should master the ability to read analog and digital clocks in first and second grade, including time expressions such as 'o’clock', 'half-past', and 'quarter-to'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            纽约市教育局回应称，按照课程标准，学生应在一年级和二年级就掌握读取模拟与数字时钟的能力，包括「o’clock（正点）」「half-past（三十分）」「quarter-to（五十分）」等时间表达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A spokesperson for the Department of Education stated that in an increasingly digital environment, 'no traditional time-telling skill should be left behind'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            教育局发言人表示，在日益数字化的环境中，「不能让任何一种传统读时技能被丢在身后」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, some students admitted in interviews that even if they learned it as children, they hardly use it now, and many classmates have 'forgotten this skill,' often just 'asking others directly for convenience'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，一些学生在接受采访时承认，即便自己小时候学过，现在几乎不再用，很多同学已经「忘了这项技能」，更多时候只是「图省事直接问别人」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, teachers generally acknowledge that this generation of students is significantly more proficient with digital tools. Many schools have opened programming and robotics courses, and teachers often turn to students for help when encountering software compatibility or file opening issues in daily teaching.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，教师们也普遍承认，这一代学生在数字工具上的熟练度明显更高。许多学校已经开设编程和机器人课程，教师在日常教学中遇到软件兼容或文件打开问题时，往往会求助学生。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            One teacher mentioned that she was at a loss in class when new software couldn't open a PDF file, and ultimately, students taught her step by step how to operate it. This kind of 'technological role reversal' is becoming increasingly common on campus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一名教师就提到，自己在课堂上因新软件无法打开 PDF 文件而手足无措，最终是学生一步步教她如何操作，这种「技术角色反转」在校园中越来越常见。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>亿万点券泛滥，《彩虹六号：围攻》紧急全球关服</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">亿万点券泛滥，《彩虹六号：围攻》紧急全球关服</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8c189a18-75c5-4528-9ceb-aa09b8ffd539.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ubisoft's tactical shooter game 'Rainbow Six Siege' recently suffered a severe security incident. Hackers exploited an internal system vulnerability to inject approximately 2 billion R6 Credits and Renown into global player accounts, and massively tampered with ban and item data, forcing Ubisoft to urgently shut down all platform servers and perform a database rollback.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            育碧旗下战术射击游戏《彩虹六号：围攻》近日遭遇严重安全事件，黑客利用内部系统漏洞向全球玩家账户注入约 20 亿 R6 点券与声望值，并大规模篡改封禁与道具数据，迫使育碧紧急关闭全平台服务器并进行数据库回滚。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to combined player feedback and information from multiple media outlets, the chaos began on the morning of December 27th, Eastern US Time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            综合玩家反馈与多家媒体信息显示，此次混乱始于今年 12 月 27 日美国东部时间上午。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some Rainbow Six Siege players found their accounts unexpectedly received billions of in-game points, unlocking all cosmetic items including developer-exclusive skins. At the same time, the in-game ban announcement board began to show a large number of false ban messages, with accounts being randomly banned and unbanned.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分《彩虹六号：围攻》玩家发现账户无预警获得数十亿游戏点数，解锁了包含开发者专用皮肤在内的全部外观道具，同时游戏内封禁公告栏开始出现大量虚假封禁信息，存在账号被随机封禁与解封的情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Ubisoft's official store pricing, 15,000 R6 Credits cost $99.99 (approximately 700 RMB).
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Approximately $13.33 million (approximately 93.43 million RMB) worth of 2 billion R6 Credits, equivalent to in-game paid currency, were indiscriminately distributed to player accounts.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            按育碧官方商店定价，R6 点券 1.5 万需 99.99 美元（约合 700 元人民币）购买，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             约 1333 万美元（约合 9343 万元人民币）的 20 亿点券等值游戏内付费货币，被无差别发放至玩家账户。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After confirming the situation was out of control, the official Rainbow Six Siege X account announced that it had intentionally shut down the game and its built-in marketplace features, with the team focusing on troubleshooting and fixing the issues.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在确认事态失控后，《彩虹六号：围攻》官方 X 账号发布公告称，已有意关闭游戏及其内置市场功能，团队正专注于排查和修复问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, Ubisoft further stated that players would not be penalized for spending the abnormally acquired credits, but all transaction records since 11:00 UTC would be rolled back to restore the economic system and account status.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后，育碧进一步表示，玩家不会因花掉异常获得的点券受到惩罚，但将回滚自世界标准时间 11:00 以来的全部交易记录，以恢复经济系统与账户状态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Multiple security agencies and whistleblowers believe that this incident is not a single game service configuration issue, but may be related to deeper security vulnerabilities within Ubisoft's internal infrastructure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多家安全机构与爆料方认为，此次事件并非单一游戏服务配置问题，而可能与育碧内部基础设施存在更深层次安全隐患相关。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Security company Aardwolf Security pointed out that attackers could not only arbitrarily modify player currency, items, and account status, but also manipulate the ban and announcement systems. This suggests an intrusion into core database management permissions, with inconsistent changes, implying that attackers might be testing multiple attack paths or semi-automated exploitation scripts.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            安全公司 Aardwolf Security 指出，攻击者不仅能任意修改玩家货币、物品与账号状态，还能操纵封禁与公告系统，这更像是对核心数据库管理权限的入侵，且变更执行不一致，暗示攻击者可能在测试多条攻击路径或半自动化利用脚本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Security research groups like VX-Underground and Pirat_Nation further claimed that attackers exploited the recently disclosed MongoDB vulnerability &quot;MongoBleed&quot; (CVE-2025-14847).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            安全研究团体 VX-Underground 与 Pirat_Nation 等进一步声称，攻击者利用了近期披露的 MongoDB 漏洞「MongoBleed」（CVE-2025-14847）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Under unauthenticated conditions, attackers obtained credentials and keys from exposed database instances, then moved laterally to Ubisoft's internal Git repositories,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             stealing terabytes of game source code, development tools, and related SDK code dating back to the 1990s, potentially even involving user data, which was used as leverage for extortion.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在未认证条件下，攻击者从暴露的数据库实例中获取凭证与密钥，进而横向移动至育碧内部 Git 仓库，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             盗取自上世纪 90 年代以来的 TB 级游戏源码、开发工具与相关 SDK 代码，甚至可能涉及用户数据，被用作勒索筹码。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, claims of a so-called &quot;wider intrusion&quot; have not yet been independently verified.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，目前关于所谓「更大范围入侵」的说法尚未得到独立验证。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            BleepingComputer stated that it is not yet possible to confirm whether MongoBleed was actually exploited, whether internal source code was indeed stolen, or whether user data was leaked, and there are also contradictions among the claims of multiple groups purporting to be involved in the attack.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            BleepingComputer 表示，尚无法确认 MongoBleed 是否被实际利用、内部源码是否确被窃取，以及用户数据是否遭泄露，多支声称参与攻击的团伙之间的说法也存在互相矛盾之处。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As of publication, Ubisoft has not issued an official statement regarding source code theft, user data security, or a broader infrastructure intrusion, only publicly acknowledging that Rainbow Six Siege was abused in-game and that recovery and investigation efforts are underway; GCORES also pointed out that the widely rumored leaked source code has not yet appeared on the public internet.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            截至发稿，育碧尚未就源代码被盗、用户数据安全及更广泛基础设施入侵发布正式说明，仅公开承认《彩虹六号：围攻》在游戏内遭到滥用，正在推进恢复与调查工作；机核网也指出，网传已外泄的大量源码尚未在公开网络上出现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 AI 教父：明年 AI 将取代更多岗位，软件工程项目「将几乎不再需要人类参与」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-AI-教父：明年-AI-将取代更多岗位，软件工程项目「将几乎不再需要人类参与」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/527eb09f-f1c9-4691-93c8-c6096ea5b913.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Fortune magazine, &quot;Godfather of AI&quot; Geoffrey Hinton recently stated on CNN's &quot;State of the Union&quot; program that artificial intelligence technology will further improve next year, gaining the ability to replace more human jobs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《财富》杂志报道，「AI 教父」Geoffrey Hinton 日前在 CNN 节目《State of the Union》中表示，人工智能技术将在明年进一步提升，具备取代更多人类工作的能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that AI is already capable of handling roles such as call centers and will expand into more areas in the future.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，AI 已能胜任呼叫中心等岗位，未来将扩展至更多领域。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Hinton emphasized that the pace of AI's progress far exceeds expectations, with the time to complete a task being halved every 7 months on average.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Hinton 强调，AI 的进步速度远超预期，平均每 7 个月就能将任务完成时间缩短一半。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For example, coding tasks that used to take an hour can now be completed by AI in minutes; in a few years, AI will be able to complete software engineering projects that originally took a month in a very short time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            例如，过去需耗时一小时的编码任务，如今 AI 可在数分钟内完成；几年后，AI 将能在极短时间内完成原本需耗时一个月的软件工程项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He predicted: &quot;By then, software engineering projects will hardly require human involvement.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他预测：「届时，软件工程项目将几乎不再需要人类参与。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since leaving Google in 2023 and publicly warning about AI risks, Hinton's concerns about the technology have continued to intensify.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自 2023 年离开 Google 并公开警示 AI 风险以来，Hinton 对该技术的担忧持续加剧。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that AI's improvements in reasoning and deception capabilities are particularly significant: &quot;If AI believes someone is hindering its goals, it will try to deceive them to complete the task and maintain its existence.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，AI 在推理与欺骗能力方面的提升尤为显著，「如果 AI 认为有人阻碍其目标实现，它将试图欺骗对方以完成任务并维持自身存在。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Despite AI's immense potential in fields such as healthcare, education, and climate research, Hinton remains concerned about its negative impacts. He criticized the current societal underinvestment in addressing AI risks, noting that when some companies weigh security against profit, they tend to sacrifice the safety of a few for overall benefit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管 AI 在医疗、教育与气候研究等领域具备巨大潜力，Hinton 仍对其负面影响表示担忧。他批评当前社会对 AI 风险的应对投入不足，部分企业在安全与利润之间权衡时，倾向于牺牲少数人的安全以换取整体效益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He cited autonomous driving as an example, stating: &quot;Self-driving cars do cause deaths, but fewer deaths than human drivers.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他以自动驾驶为例称：「无人车确实会致人死亡，但比起人类驾驶员，死亡人数会更少。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hinton previously stated in interviews with the Financial Times and Bloomberg TV that one of AI's commercialization paths is to &quot;replace humans with cheaper things,&quot; which will lead to &quot;mass unemployment and surging profits,&quot; ultimately &quot;making a few people richer and most people poorer.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Hinton 此前曾在《金融时报》与彭博电视的采访中指出，AI 的商业化路径之一即是「用更便宜的东西取代人类」，这将导致「大规模失业与利润激增」，最终「让少数人更富，大多数人更穷」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Although some studies show that AI can improve the productivity of existing employees, data also indicates that since the launch of ChatGPT, the number of entry-level job postings has significantly declined by about 30%, and companies like Amazon have admitted that AI has improved operational efficiency while simultaneously laying off staff.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管部分研究显示 AI 可提升现有员工生产力，但也有数据显示，自 ChatGPT 推出以来，初级岗位招聘数量大幅下滑约 30%，亚马逊等公司亦在裁员的同时承认 AI 提高了运营效率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>荣耀 Power2 官宣，有 iPhone 17 Pro Max 同款配色</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">荣耀-Power2-官宣，有-iPhone-17-Pro-Max-同款配色</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/be38af6c-45be-4fce-ae70-e6cb5aa097be.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Honor officially announced that the new Power2 phone will be released on January 5, 2026, at 19:30. The biggest highlight of this phone is its 10080mAh fourth-generation Qinghai Lake battery, making it the world's first smartphone with a battery capacity exceeding 10,000 mAh.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，荣耀正式宣布新机 Power2 将于 2026 年 1 月 5 日 19:30 发布。该机最大亮点为搭载 10080mAh 的第四代青海湖电池，成为全球首款电池容量突破万毫安的智能手机。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First to feature the MediaTek Dimensity 8500 Elite chip, with an AnTuTu score of approximately 2.2 million;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a 6.79-inch 1.5K screen;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in 10080mAh battery, supporting 80W wired fast charging and 27W reverse charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thickness of 7.98mm, body weight of 216g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of appearance, the Honor Power2 adopts a flat screen and flat edge design, with a horizontal matrix triple camera module on the rear, featuring a 50-megapixel main camera and a 16-megapixel front camera. Color options include Snow White, Midnight Black, and the signature Sunrise Orange.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外观方面，荣耀 Power2 采用直屏直边设计，后置横向矩阵三摄模组，主摄为 5000 万像素，前摄为 1600 万像素。配色包括雪原白、幻夜黑与主打的旭日橙。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             It is worth noting that some netizens have pointed out that the &quot;Sunrise Orange&quot; color scheme is quite similar to the &quot;Starry Orange&quot; of the iPhone 17 Pro Max.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             值得注意的是，有网友指出「旭日橙」配色与 iPhone 17 Pro Max 的「星宇橙」颇为相似。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the Honor Power2 continues its predecessor's positioning as a &quot;weak network nemesis,&quot; focusing on being the &quot;elevator signal king.&quot; It is expected to be equipped with Honor's self-developed C1+ communication chip and weak network optimization algorithms to improve communication stability in weak signal environments such as elevators and parking lots.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，荣耀 Power2 还延续前代「弱网克星」定位，主打「电梯信号王」，预计将搭载荣耀自研 C1+ 通讯芯片与弱网优化算法，提升电梯、车库等弱信号环境下的通信稳定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一加 Turbo 6 配置曝光：骁龙 8s Gen4＋ 9000mAh 电池</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">一加-Turbo-6-配置曝光：骁龙-8s-Gen4＋-9000mAh-电池</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/960e5b8f-231c-4e0e-80e3-189d68c013a5.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, OnePlus announced the core specifications of its new model, the &quot;OnePlus Turbo 6,&quot; during a live broadcast. This phone is positioned as a new Turbo series product line, expected to be released in January next year, focusing on long battery life and high-performance durability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，一加在直播中公布了全新机型「一加 Turbo 6」的核心配置，该机定位全新 Turbo 系列产品线，预计将于明年 1 月发布，主打长续航与高性能耐用，
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Qualcomm Snapdragon 8s Gen4 chip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a BOE 1.5K 165Hz LTPS high-refresh-rate eye-protection flat screen;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in 9000mAh &quot;Glacier Battery,&quot; supporting 27W wired reverse charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports IP66 / IP68 / IP69 / IP69K dust and water resistance, with a total weight of approximately 217.25g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of appearance, the OnePlus Turbo 6's overall visual style continues the design language of the OnePlus 15, adopting a low-saturation scheme that balances recognition and durable texture. The back design emphasizes an outdoor and rugged style; color options are expected to include &quot;Solitary Black,&quot; &quot;Wilderness Green,&quot; and &quot;Chasing Light Silver.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外观方面，一加 Turbo 6 整体视觉风格延续了一加 15 的设计语言，采用低饱和度方案，兼顾识别度与耐看质感，机身背部设计强调户外与硬朗风格；配色上预计提供「独行黑」「旷野青」「追光银」三种版本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding storage configurations, based on AnTuTu benchmark scores and leaked information, the OnePlus Turbo 6 will offer a maximum storage combination of 16GB + 512GB, while also covering various specifications such as 12GB + 256GB, 12GB + 512GB, and 16GB + 256GB.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            存储组合方面，根据安兔兔跑分与爆料信息，一加 Turbo 6 将提供最高 16GB＋512GB 的存储组合，同时还将覆盖 12GB＋256GB、12GB＋512GB、16GB＋256GB 等多种规格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LG 公布 AI 游戏显示器，支持 5K 超分</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">LG-公布-AI-游戏显示器，支持-5K-超分</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/045b88dd-a168-4717-a25e-a41d6df05aa7.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, LG Electronics recently announced its new UltraGear evo series gaming monitors. The first batch includes three models: 39GX950B, 27GM950B, and 52G930B, featuring 5K-level resolution, high refresh rates, and on-device AI upscaling capabilities. They are expected to officially debut at CES 2026 next year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，LG 电子近日宣布全新 UltraGear evo 系列电竞显示器，首批包括 39GX950B、27GM950B 和 52G930B 三款机型，主打 5K 级分辨率、高刷新率与端侧 AI 超分能力，预计将在明年 CES 2026 上正式亮相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            39-inch 39GX950B:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            39 英寸 39GX950B：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 1500R curvature OLED panel;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 165Hz refresh rate at 5120 × 2160 resolution, and can boost the refresh rate to 330Hz after lowering the resolution, with a response time of 0.03ms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            52-inch 52G930B:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            52 英寸 52G930B：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5K2K dual-mode large curved screen, with a refresh rate of up to 240Hz at native resolution;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provides an approximate 12:9 wide &quot;panoramic&quot; field of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The more anticipated 27-inch 27GM950B is LG's &quot;first 5K New MiniLED gaming monitor,&quot; featuring a new generation MiniLED backlight solution, offering 2304 local dimming zones and a peak brightness of up to 1250 nits.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            更受关注的 27 英寸 27GM950B 是 LG 打出的「首款 5K New MiniLED 电竞显示器」，采用新一代 MiniLED 背光方案，提供 2304 分区背光与最高 1250 nits 峰值亮度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            LG states that this solution, while enhancing brightness, minimizes the halo effect common in traditional MiniLED products, making it more suitable for high-brightness environments and HDR content creation compared to OLED.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            LG 称这一方案在提升亮度的同时，尽量抑制传统 MiniLED 产品中常见的光晕问题，相比 OLED 更适合高亮环境与 HDR 内容创作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reports indicate that both the 39GX950B and 27GM950B are equipped with edge AI technology, supporting AI super-resolution, scene optimization, and audio enhancement features. They can perform real-time super-resolution on low-resolution content and adjust display and sound effects based on game type or screen content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，39GX950B 与 27GM950B 均搭载端侧 AI 技术，支持 AI 超分辨率、场景优化与音频增强功能，可对低分辨率内容进行实时超分，并根据游戏类型或画面内容调整显示和声音效果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>元旦出入境客流预计日均超 210 万，口岸将迎高峰</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">元旦出入境客流预计日均超-210-万，口岸将迎高峰</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Xinhua News Agency, national ports of entry and exit are expected to see a significant peak in passenger traffic during this year's New Year's Day holiday, with an estimated daily average of over 2.1 million inbound and outbound travelers, a 22.4% increase year-on-year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新华社报道，今年元旦假期全国口岸将迎来显著的出入境客流高峰，预计日均出入境旅客将突破 210 万人次，同比去年增长 22.4%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to information released by the National Immigration Administration, the peak passenger flow will primarily be concentrated on the evening of December 31, 2025, and January 1, 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据国家移民管理局发布的信息，客流高峰将主要集中在 2025 年 12 月 31 日晚间及 2026 年 1 月 1 日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For major airport ports, the daily average inbound and outbound passenger flow at Shanghai Pudong, Guangzhou Baiyun, Beijing Capital, Chengdu Tianfu, Shenzhen Bao'an, and other ports is expected to reach 97,000, 53,000, 43,000, 19,000, and 18,000 respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            大型空港口岸方面，上海浦东、广州白云、北京首都、成都天府、深圳宝安等口岸的日均出入境客流预计分别达到 9.7 万、5.3 万、4.3 万、1.9 万、1.8 万人次。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Guangdong, Hong Kong, and Macao will host multiple large-scale events during the New Year's Day period, including light festivals, concerts, and New Year's Eve galas, driving a significant increase in cross-border traffic at land ports adjacent to Hong Kong and Macao.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，粤港澳三地在元旦期间将举办光影节、演唱会、跨年汇演等多场大型活动，带动毗邻港澳陆路口岸通关量明显上升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The daily average inbound and outbound passenger flow at Shenzhen Luohu, Futian, Shenzhen Bay, Liantang, and Guangzhou-Shenzhen-Hong Kong Express Rail Link West Kowloon Station ports is expected to reach 240,000, 230,000, 180,000, 110,000, and 100,000 respectively;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            深圳罗湖、福田、深圳湾、莲塘及广深港高铁西九龙站等口岸的日均出入境旅客预计分别达到 24 万、23 万、18 万、11 万、10 万人次；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The daily average inbound and outbound passenger flow at Zhuhai Gongbei, Qingmao, Hengqin, and Hong Kong-Zhuhai-Macao Bridge ports is expected to reach 400,000, 113,000, 100,000, and 95,000 respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            珠海拱北、青茂、横琴及港珠澳大桥口岸的日均出入境旅客预计分别达到 40 万、11.3 万、10 万、9.5 万人次。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            To ensure smooth customs clearance, the National Immigration Administration has deployed national border inspection agencies to strengthen passenger flow monitoring, promptly release port clearance information, and require scientific organization of duties and sufficient police force to ensure that Chinese citizens' waiting time for clearance does not exceed 30 minutes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            为确保通关秩序平稳，国家移民管理局已部署全国边检机关加强客流监测、及时发布口岸通关信息，并要求科学组织勤务、备足警力，确保中国公民通关排队不超过 30 分钟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, some key ports will extend their operating hours to cope with peak passenger flow.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，部分重点口岸将延长通关时间，以应对高峰期客流。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Immigration management departments remind travelers to pay attention to changes in port passenger flow, check the validity of their documents, and understand the security situation and entry policies of their destination before traveling. If difficulties are encountered during customs clearance, travelers can call the 12367 hotline or seek assistance from on-site police officers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            移民管理部门提醒旅客在出行前关注口岸客流变化，检查证件有效性，并提前了解目的地安全形势及入境政策。通关过程中如遇困难，可拨打 12367 热线或向现场执勤警察寻求帮助。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Levi’s 推出马年限定系列，双马皮牌焕新演绎「好事成双」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Levi’s-推出马年限定系列，双马皮牌焕新演绎「好事成双」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f822a571-ada9-4d4c-b4b5-1abde9095bb0.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apparel brand Levi's has launched a new Year of the Horse limited edition series, themed &quot;Good Things Come in Pairs,&quot; blending festive elements with classic brand designs to convey New Year blessings and individual style.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            服装品牌 Levi’s 推出全新马年限定系列，以「好事成双」为主题，融合节庆元素与品牌经典设计，传递新年祝福与个性风格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Inspired by the iconic Levi's Two-Horse Pull leather patch, this series reimagines it in festive red, complemented by golden horseshoe embellishments, symbolizing good fortune for the New Year. The gold selvedge design also makes a return in this collection, paired with a paisley-patterned lining, continuing the brand's American vintage DNA and showcasing a blend of tradition and modernity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该系列以象征 Levi’s 精神的双马皮牌为灵感，将其焕新为节庆红配色，并搭配金色马蹄铁装饰，寓意新年好运。金赤耳设计亦在本次系列中回归，辅以腰果花纹内衬，延续品牌美式复古基因，展现传统与现代的融合。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For menswear, key items include a reversible bomber jacket, paired with a faux shearling Type III denim jacket and an unlined relaxed-fit denim jacket, showcasing a blend of relaxed tailoring and modern style. Bottoms include 578™ drawstring jeans, 505™ loose straight-leg jeans, and 502™ tapered jeans;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The women's collection focuses on layering and proportion changes, including items such as thickened faux shearling jackets, V-neck knitwear, and textured shirts, showcasing a relaxed and confident dressing attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the series will be officially released starting January 9 at designated Levi’s stores nationwide.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，该系列将于 1 月 9 日起在全国指定 Levi’s 门店正式发售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>新一代数字人民币体系将于明年启动实施</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">新一代数字人民币体系将于明年启动实施</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2b5d3fb5-d825-40da-bcfb-45a4c6667fa8.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV News, the People's Bank of China has issued the &quot;Action Plan on Further Strengthening the Digital RMB Management Service System and Related Financial Infrastructure Construction&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视新闻报道，中国人民银行已出台《关于进一步加强数字人民币管理服务体系和相关金融基础设施建设的行动方案》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The &quot;Plan&quot; clarifies that the new generation of digital RMB measurement framework, management system, operating mechanism, and ecosystem will be officially launched and implemented on January 1 next year, thereby improving the top-level design and infrastructure layout of the digital RMB at institutional and technical levels.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《方案》明确新一代数字人民币计量框架、管理体系、运行机制和生态体系将于明年 1 月 1 日正式启动实施，以此在制度和技术层面完善数字人民币的顶层设计与基础设施布局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As of the end of November this year, the digital RMB has cumulatively processed 3.48 billion transactions, with a cumulative transaction value of 16.7 trillion yuan; 230 million individual wallets have been opened through the digital RMB App, and 18.84 million digital RMB corporate wallets have been opened, indicating a continuous increase in its coverage and frequency of use in retail payment scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            截至今年 11 月底，数字人民币已累计处理交易 34.8 亿笔，累计交易金额 16.7 万亿元；通过数字人民币 App 开立的个人钱包达到 2.3 亿个，数字人民币单位钱包已开立 1884 万个，显示其在零售支付场景的覆盖面和使用频率持续提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>扎克 · 施奈德新片《最后一张照片》释出剧照</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">扎克-·-施奈德新片《最后一张照片》释出剧照</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5a6ed3d8-82d3-4929-8fe4-e1e65f4e3ca3.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zack Snyder's long-prepared &quot;dream project&quot; &quot;The Last Photograph&quot; recently released multiple stills and on-set photos, with the film's core plot and main production information simultaneously revealed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            扎克·施奈德多年来筹备的「梦想项目」《最后一张照片》近日发布多张剧照与片场照，影片核心剧情与主要制作信息同步曝光。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of a former DEA agent who returns to the mountains of South America to find his missing niece and nephew and investigate the brutal murder of their diplomat parents. On his journey, he is accompanied by a war correspondent and drug addict whose career has hit rock bottom, and who is the only survivor to have seen the killer's face.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述一名前美国禁毒署特工重返南美山区，试图寻找失踪的侄子与侄女，并追查其外交官父母遭遇残忍谋杀的真相。在旅途中，他与一名事业跌入谷谷的瘾君子战地记者同行，这名记者是唯一见过凶手面目的幸存者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the two delve deeper into the jungle, they gradually move away from civilization and begin to question the boundaries between reality and the surreal.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着两人深入丛林，他们逐渐远离文明，也开始质疑现实与超现实的界限。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Snyder stated that &quot;The Last Photograph&quot; is a meditation on life and death, inspired by his past life experiences, and explores these themes through imagery. The film's screenplay was co-written by Snyder and his long-time collaborator Kurt Johnstad, who previously worked on films such as &quot;300&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            施奈德表示，《最后一张照片》是一场关于生与死的冥想，灵感来自他过往人生经历，并通过影像探索这些主题。影片剧本由施奈德与其长期合作伙伴库尔特·约恩斯塔德共同创作，后者曾参与《斯巴达 300 勇士》等作品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《中国奇谭2》发布终极预告：九段奇谭元旦上线</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《中国奇谭2》发布终极预告：九段奇谭元旦上线</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/28d02abe-86c1-4583-bb4a-7d9929092d02.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Chinese Tales 2&quot; released its final trailer yesterday. As a brand new chapter in the &quot;Chinese Tales&quot; series, it will be exclusively launched on Bilibili on January 1 next year. The trailer uses a profound &quot;door&quot; as its visual starting point, connecting nine independent short films, presenting themes of emotion, destiny, and human nature with diverse Chinese fantasy aesthetics.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《中国奇谭2》昨日发布终极预告，作为《中国奇谭》系列的全新篇章，该作将在明年 1 月 1 日于哔哩哔哩独家上线。预告以一扇深邃的「门」为视觉起点，串联九个独立短片，以多元中式奇幻美学呈现情感、命运与人心的主题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This season's nine short films cover diverse themes such as growth, desire, family affection, Jianghu (martial arts world), folklore, and mythology, including &quot;How to Become Three Dragons,&quot; &quot;The Man in the Ear,&quot; &quot;Today's Zoo,&quot; &quot;Xiao Xue,&quot; &quot;San Lang,&quot; &quot;Big Bird,&quot; &quot;Worshiping the Mountain,&quot; &quot;Xing Tian,&quot; and &quot;The Great Nobleman.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本季九部短片涵盖成长、欲望、亲情、江湖、民俗、神话等多元题材，包括《如何成为三条龙》《耳中人》《今日动物园》《小雪》《三郎》《大鸟》《拜山》《刑天》《大贵人》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The creative team continues its deep understanding of traditional culture and explores more experimental expressions in various styles such as ink wash painting, felt stop-motion, and dark fairy tales.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            创作团队延续对传统文化的深度理解，并在水墨、毛毡定格、暗黑童话等多种风格中探索更具实验性的表达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Executive Producer Su Da stated that the series is always rooted in traditional culture while emphasizing emotional connections with contemporary audiences; Chief Director Chen Liaoyu pointed out that each short film's inspiration comes from real life, ultimately pointing to the inner world of people today. The production team hopes to tell Chinese stories through animation and expand the expressive boundaries of Eastern narratives.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            总监制速达表示，系列始终扎根传统文化，同时强调与当代观众的情感联结；总导演陈廖宇则指出，每部短片灵感均源自现实生活，最终指向当下人的内心。制作团队希望以动画语言讲述中国故事，拓展东方叙事的表达边界。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《用武之地》发布 Beyond 片尾曲 MV</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《用武之地》发布-Beyond-片尾曲-MV</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251230_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c2e2a93c-c4c8-4496-96a8-667e8385b50c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The production company for the film &quot;A Place to Fight&quot; yesterday released the ending theme MV for Beyond band's classic song &quot;Amani,&quot; and the film will be released on New Year's Eve, December 31.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电影《用武之地》片方昨天发布 Beyond 乐队经典歌曲《Amani》的片尾曲 MV，影片将于 12 月 31 日跨年上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film focuses on the survival plight of ordinary people in war-torn areas, with a 105-day hostage escape as the main storyline. The emotional impact when the ending theme song plays has been described by many preview audiences as &quot;instant tears&quot; and &quot;touching the heart.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片聚焦战乱腹地普通人的生存困境，以长达 105 天的人质逃亡为主线，片尾曲响起时的情绪冲击被大量提前点映观众形容为「瞬间落泪」「直抵人心」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the film, Ma Xiao (played by Xiao Yang), inspired by the method left by Miao Feng (played by Zheng Kai), grows tomatoes on barren land and establishes trust and friendship with the villagers of Ali Village, who are deeply troubled by war. &quot;Uncle Tomato&quot; thus becomes an emotional memory anchor for many viewers on social media platforms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            片中，马笑（肖央 饰）在苗峰（郑恺 饰）留下的方法启发下，在贫瘠土地上种出西红柿，并与深受战乱困扰的阿里村村民建立起信任与友谊，「西红柿叔叔」也因此成为大量观众在社交平台的情感记忆锚点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
