<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>独家｜iPhone 17 支持 AVS 充电协议</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">独家｜iPhone-17-支持-AVS-充电协议</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/83c5d56f-d67a-4746-8906-e14bbf62660e.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the September 10th launch event, an inconspicuous protocol abbreviation appeared on the &quot;40W Dynamic Power Adapter (up to 60W)&quot; that quietly debuted with the iPhone 17 series: AVS (Adjustable Voltage Supply).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 9 月 10 日的发布会上，随着 iPhone 17 系列一同悄然登场的「40W 动态电源适配器(最高 60W)」上，出现了一个不起眼的协议缩写：AVS (Adjustable Voltage Supply，可调电压电源)。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            We found that the AVS supported by the iPhone 17 series and the new charger is more precisely SPR AVS (Standard Power Range Adjustable Voltage Supply). It is understood that SPR AVS is a new protocol that has just been implemented in the USB PD 3.2 standard proposed at the end of 2024.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据我们发现，本次 iPhone 17 系列及新充电器支持的 AVS，更确切的说是 SPR AVS (Standard Power Range Adjustable Voltage Supply，标准电源范围可调电压电源)。据悉，SPR AVS 是一个新协议，在 24 年底提出的 USB PD 3.2 标准中才刚刚落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For a long time, Apple devices, including the iPhone 16, have relied on a &quot;fixed voltage charging + secondary step-down inside the device&quot; fast charging scheme. The PPS fast charging chosen by subsequent Android manufacturers allows for more precise voltage and current regulation between the charger and the phone, thereby reducing the step-down work inside the phone.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            长久以来，包括 iPhone 16 在内的苹果设备，其快充方案都依赖于「固定电压充电 + 机内二次降压」的模式。而后续 Android 阵营的厂商们所选择的 PPS 快充，允许充电器和手机之间进行更精细的电压、电流调节，从而减少手机内部的降压工作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             However, Apple's choice of the new SPR AVS protocol actually stems from dissatisfaction with the mainstream fast charging protocol PPS, including two major &quot;fatal flaws&quot;:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             但苹果选择了 SPR AVS 这个新协议，背后其实是对主流快充协议 PPS 的不满，包括两大「硬伤」：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The so-called 20mV voltage step is practically impossible to achieve: line loss, the charger's own voltage ripple, and other factors can cause deviations exceeding this 20mV specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &quot;maximum power&quot; concept of PPS leads to simultaneous activation of maximum current and maximum voltage limits, with the actual result being that the nominal maximum power is simply not achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that AVS first originated in the PD 3.1 EPR (Extended Power Range) specification designed for high-power devices such as laptops, capable of providing an ultra-high power of up to 48V 5A = 240W. Apple's own MacBook Pro 16-inch was the first mainstream commercial product to feature AVS.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据了解，AVS 其最早诞生于为笔记本电脑等高功率设备设计的 PD 3.1 EPR (Extended Power Range 扩展功率范围) 规范中，可以最大提供 48V 5A = 240W 的超大功率。苹果自家的 MacBook Pro 16 英寸便是 AVS 的第一个主流商业化产品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The SPR AVS supported by iPhone 17 is the USB-IF association officially bringing this advanced voltage regulation technology down to the Standard Power Range (below 100W) in the latest PD 3.2 specification.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而 iPhone 17 所支持的 SPR AVS，则是 USB-IF 协会在最新的 PD 3.2 规范中，正式将这一先进的调压技术下放到 100W 以下的标准功率范围（Standard Power Range）内。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             The technology is too complex, so for users, what AVS can achieve after implementation is:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             技术太复杂，那么对用户来说，AVS 实装后能做到：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cooler fast charging: Because the voltage transformation work is handled by the charger during charging, body heat generation is reduced, the charging power curve is smoother, and high power can be maintained for longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batteries are more durable: Long-term high temperatures and voltage shocks can cause batteries to age faster, while SPR AVS is more friendly to low-voltage, high-current precise power supply, reducing unnecessary losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No licensing fees: It is an open protocol, requiring no licensing fees, meaning no protocol costs are passed on to consumers, further reducing product prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             precisely because this SPR AVS is a standard extension, it also allows SDC (Software-Defined Charger) products, represented by the Sugar Factory's small power bank, to immediately support the new protocol by upgrading their existing devices.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             正因为本次 SPR AVS 是标准的扩展，也让制糖工厂小电拼为代表的 SDC（Software-Defined Charger 软件定义的充电器）产品，可以第一时间通过协议升级的方法，让现有设备「摇身一变」支持新协议。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the Sugar Factory AI Power Bank will open internal testing for its AVS function on September 15th.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             制糖工厂 AI 小电拼将在 9 月 15 日开放 AVS 功能内测。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/50d9f21b-8ffa-495a-95be-b42c827e4811.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>电信、移动回应 iPhone Air 仅支持 eSIM：很快就来</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">电信、移动回应-iPhone-Air-仅支持-eSIM：很快就来</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/cbc7dc7e-291e-4b91-a372-72cbdc8d44a1.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Apple officially launched the iPhone Air, and the Chinese domestic version was not absent, set to go on sale on September 19th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，苹果正式推出了 iPhone Air，同时国行版也并未缺席，将于 9 月 19 日迎来发售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this iPhone Air Chinese domestic version is also an eSIM-only phone, and currently China Unicom is responsible for the eSIM-related services for this model. Many consumers have posted, asking when China Mobile and China Telecom will launch mobile eSIM services.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，本次 iPhone Air 国行同样是一台仅有 eSIM 的手机，并且目前由中国联通负责该机型的 eSIM 相关业务。不少消费者都纷纷发文表示，中国移动和中国电信何时才能上线手机 eSIM 服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the above situation, both China Mobile and China Telecom have responded:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于上述情况，中国移动和中国电信均进行了回应：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China Mobile: Blogger &quot;Wu Xiaojie WJie&quot; posted yesterday, stating that Mobile's eSIM for phones &quot;is not working! It's falling behind again.&quot; Subsequently, China Mobile's official Weibo commented in the comments section, saying: China Mobile already supports eSIM mobile services, and the opening of services will be announced separately later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China Telecom: According to Shanghai Securities News, China Telecom responded that its eSIM mobile phone business is fully prepared, and it is expected that after obtaining formal approval for commercial trials from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology in the near future, it will soon open eSIM mobile phone service handling, including for iPhone 17, to users. Please stay tuned for the specific opening time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Apple's official website, eSIM is an industry-standard digital SIM card built into the iPhone, eliminating the need for a physical SIM card. With eSIM, users have more flexibility, simplicity, and stronger security, with seamless connectivity, especially useful when traveling globally.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据苹果官网显示，eSIM 是一种符合业界标准的数字 SIM 卡，内置于 iPhone 中，让用户不再需要实体 SIM 卡。有了 eSIM，用户使用更灵活、更简便、安全性更强，连网丝滑顺畅，全球旅行时尤其好用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>工信部等部门联合整治汽车行业网络乱象</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">工信部等部门联合整治汽车行业网络乱象</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to MIIT Micro-Report, to implement the deployment requirements of the State Council's executive meeting on effectively regulating the competitive order of the new energy vehicle industry, six departments including the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, the Central Social Work Department, the Cyberspace Administration of China, the National Development and Reform Commission, the Ministry of Public Security, and the State Administration for Market Regulation recently jointly issued the &quot;Notice on Carrying out Special Rectification Actions for Network Chaos in the Automotive Industry,&quot; deciding to carry out a 3-month special rectification action for network chaos in the automotive industry nationwide.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据工信微报消息，为落实国务院常务会议关于切实规范新能源汽车产业竞争秩序部署要求，工业和信息化部、中央社会工作部、中央网信办、国家发展改革委、公安部、市场监管总局等六部门近日联合印发《关于开展汽车行业网络乱象专项整治行动的通知》，决定在全国范围内开展为期 3 个月的汽车行业网络乱象专项整治行动。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This special rectification action will focus on rectifying network chaos such as illegal profiteering, exaggerated and false propaganda, and malicious defamation and attacks, improving the quality and efficiency of handling network chaos involving automotive enterprises, urging enterprises to standardize marketing and promotional behaviors, creating a good public opinion environment, and safeguarding the high-quality development of the automotive industry. Key issues to be rectified mainly include:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次专项整治行动将集中整治非法牟利、夸大和虚假宣传、恶意诋毁攻击等网络乱象，提升涉汽车企业网络乱象处置质效，督促企业规范营销宣传行为，营造良好舆论环境，护航汽车产业高质量发展。重点整治问题主要包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Illegal Profiteering:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             非法牟利：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By creating fake images and videos, fabricating stories, hyping and spreading negative topics related to car companies, maliciously interpreting fluctuations in car sales, and attacking car companies' operational development strategies, etc., to gain online traffic and commercial benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing their discourse power and influence, under the guise of &quot;news supervision,&quot; &quot;public opinion supervision,&quot; &quot;popular science,&quot; etc., to obtain commercial benefits through false or non-standard evaluations that combine business and testing, or testing for business, and even extorting &quot;protection fees&quot; from car companies. By publishing false or untrue information or negative information about enterprises, or setting the tone in comment sections, at important junctures such as new car product launches and car company financing, to coerce enterprises into business cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utilizing technologies such as motherboard machines and generative AI to create new types of &quot;internet trolls,&quot; producing false content, generating fake popularity and trends, evading platform monitoring, and seeking illegal profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Exaggerated and False Propaganda:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             夸大和虚假宣传：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making false or misleading claims about the performance, functions, quality, sales status, etc., of automobiles and power batteries, deceiving and misleading consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Car companies manipulating agencies or review accounts to conduct false or non-standard evaluations. Citing and fabricating false data, selectively disclosing sales data, and creating various lists such as sales rankings under false pretenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using industry events such as exhibitions and forums, as well as online marketing and promotional activities, to create and hype topics, causing negative impacts on the industry and society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Malicious Slander and Attack:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             恶意诋毁攻击：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of curbing and suppressing competitors, slandering and attacking automotive companies or products, tarnishing corporate or product reputation, and making malicious complaints against companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizing and manipulating online trolls, &quot;black public relations,&quot; &quot;black mouths,&quot; and &quot;fan circle&quot; followers to jointly publish false and negative information involving automotive companies and entrepreneurs, inciting netizens' emotions, engaging in &quot;flame wars,&quot; and maliciously slandering competitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automotive company executives using their influence to &quot;drag down&quot; and provoke online disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The &quot;Notice&quot; emphasizes guiding automotive companies to report clues about online chaos such as online trolls, &quot;black public relations,&quot; &quot;black mouths,&quot; and &quot;fan circle&quot; followers in the automotive industry to website platforms, the Central Cyberspace Administration of China's Illegal and Undesirable Information Reporting Center, and provincial cyberspace administrations in the companies' localities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《通知》强调，引导汽车企业向网站平台、中央网信办违法和不良信息举报中心、企业属地省级网信办举报反映汽车行业网络水军、「黑公关」「黑嘴」及「饭圈」粉丝等网络乱象问题线索。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The &quot;Notice&quot; also requires that departments such as industry and information technology, social work, cyberspace administration, development and reform, public security, and market supervision in various regions strengthen organizational leadership and coordinated linkage; network platform enterprises should conduct in-depth self-inspection and self-correction, and strengthen the identification and control of online trolls and &quot;black mouths&quot; that use generative AI technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《通知》还要求，各地工业和信息化、社会工作、网信、发展改革、公安、市场监管等部门要加强组织领导和协调联动；网络平台企业要深入开展自查自纠，加强对采用生成式人工智能技术等的网络水军、「黑嘴」的甄别管控。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>各大手机厂商高管评价 iPhone 17</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">各大手机厂商高管评价-iPhone-17</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the iPhone 17 series and iPhone Air were officially released. Subsequently, executives from major mobile phone manufacturers posted comments on the new devices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，iPhone 17 系列、iPhone Air 正式发布。随后，各大手机厂商的高管纷纷发文评价了本次新机。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing, President of Xiaomi Group, believes that &quot;this is definitely the year with the biggest changes for iPhone.&quot; He pointed out:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米集团总裁卢伟冰认为，「这绝对是iPhone变化最大的一年」。其指出：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The iPhone 17 standard version is indeed very strong, pushing the limits; the iPhone Air is very stunning and may reactivate the ultra-thin phone market; the new design of the iPhone 17 Pro series is controversial, but its recognition is maximized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing also emphasized that 2025 will be a big year for changes in phone form factors. He also stated that he would purchase one for trial. And he asked netizens, &quot;What do you all think of this change in lineup (replacing Plus with Air)?&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            卢伟冰还强调，2025 年将会是手机形态变化的大年。其还表示，自己将会购买一部进行试用。并询问网友，「大家如何看待这次的变阵（用 Air 取代了 Plus）？」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Jie, President of OnePlus China, stated,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;Welcome Apple to the full 'high refresh rate era.' High refresh rate is indeed 'hard to go back once used,' and it is one of the most important improvements in mobile phone experience over the past decade.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            At the same time, Li Jie also revealed that OnePlus will once again lead the industry, taking the lead in entering the new &quot;ultra-high refresh rate era.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一加中国区总裁李杰则表示
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「欢迎苹果来到全面『高刷时代』，高刷确实『旦用难回』，是过去十年手机体验最重要的提升之一。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            同时李杰还透露，一加将再次引领行业，率先进入全新的「超高刷时代」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chen Xi, Design Director of OPPO ColorOS, commented on the iPhone Air:
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;Very suitable for dual-wielding.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            He believes that the lightweight and thin characteristics of the Air model make dual-wielding easier, and the functional trade-offs made for lightness (such as battery life) are suitable for supplementing with dual-wielding. In addition, Chen Xi also stated that the eSIM migration cost is slightly higher, so it is also suitable for dual-wielding.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而 OPPO ColorOS 设计总监陈希对 iPhone Air 进行了评价：
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「非常适合双持。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            其认为 Air 机型的轻薄特质让双持更轻松，同时为轻薄所做的功能取舍（如续航），适合双持补充。另外，陈希还表示，eSIM 迁移成本略高，因此也适合双持使用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Not only did executives from mobile phone manufacturers comment on the new iPhone, but OpenAI CEO Sam Altman also stated yesterday,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;This is the first time in a long time that I genuinely want to upgrade my iPhone! It looks cool.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不仅手机厂商的高管们发文评价本次新 iPhone，OpenAI CEO Sam Altman 也在昨日表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「这是我很久以来，第一次真正想要升级 iPhone！看起来很酷。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Later, a netizen commented below, &quot;Let Apple replace Siri with ChatGPT voice,&quot; to which Altman replied,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;Honestly, I support it, sounds like a good idea.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Altman also specifically responded in the comments section that it was the iPhone Air that made him feel &quot;cool.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            后续有网友在底下评论称「让苹果用 ChatGPT 语音替换 Siri」，Altman 回复表示
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「说实话，我支持，听起来是个好主意。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            并且 Altman 也在评论区具体回应了是 iPhone Air 令他感觉「很酷」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f5b17e32-4617-432e-8f78-fcbcdb4afdb1.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to our observations on JD.com, the pre-order volume for the iPhone 17 series (including Air models) has exceeded 2 million, with the iPhone 17 standard version having the highest pre-order volume, followed by the iPhone 17 Pro Max.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据我们观察京东发现，目前 iPhone 17 系列（含 Air 机型）预约量已超过 200 万，其中 iPhone 17 标准版预约量最高，iPhone 17 Pro Max 次之。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>华为开源新 7B 模型，快慢思考自由切换</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">华为开源新-7B-模型，快慢思考自由切换</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Huawei open-sourced the latest achievement of the Pangu model — &quot;openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，华为开源了盘古模型最新成果 ——「openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1 is an efficient large language model trained from scratch based on Ascend NPU, with 7B parameters and approximately 25T tokens trained,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             featuring fast and slow thinking fusion and adaptive switching capabilities.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1 是基于昇腾 NPU 从零训练的高效大语言模型，参数量为 7B，训练了约 25T tokens，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             具备快慢思考融合与自适应切换能力。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official evaluation results show that V1.1's adaptive mode can achieve a slow thinking level close to V1.1 in multiple tasks (such as CMMLU, MATH-500, AIME24/25, etc.).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从官方公布的测评结果显示，V1.1 的自适应模式能够在多项任务（如 CMMLU、MATH-500、AIME24/25 等）中，拥有接近 V1.1 的慢思考水平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to accuracy, the development team also statistically analyzed the model's output length on some datasets. Through a data quality-driven learning strategy, adaptive fast and slow thinking can, with minimal impact on accuracy:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除精度外，开发团队还在部分数据集上统计了模型的输出长度，通过数据质量驱动的学习策略，自适应快慢思考可以在基本不影响精度地的提下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Effectively automatically switch part of the output to fast thinking on simple tasks, significantly shortening the average output thought chain length;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In difficult tasks, by maintaining slow thinking ability, the accuracy is on par with pure slow thinking models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1 is available on GitCode.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前 openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1 已上架 GitCode。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            GitCode:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.gitcode.com/ascend-tribe/openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1&quot;&gt;
             https://ai.gitcode.com/ascend-tribe/openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GitCode：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://ai.gitcode.com/ascend-tribe/openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1&quot;&gt;
             https://ai.gitcode.com/ascend-tribe/openPangu-Embedded-7B-V1.1
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>英伟达上线新 GPU，专为百万 token 推理而生</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">英伟达上线新-GPU，专为百万-token-推理而生</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/92d62ef7-3fb2-4b04-9454-de3329d7ef82.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Nvidia announced the launch of a new generation GPU named Rubin CPX, designed specifically for large-scale context processing. Officially, Rubin CPX can run software programming and video generation with millions of tokens at unprecedented efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，英伟达宣布推出一款名为 Rubin CPX 的新一代 GPU，其专为大规模上下文处理而设计。官方表示，Rubin CPX 能够以前所未有的效率跑百万级 tokens 的软件编程和视频生成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, Rubin CPX will be used in conjunction with Nvidia Vera CPU and Rubin GPU, forming the new NVIDIA Vera Rubin NVL144 CPX platform.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，Rubin CPX 将与英伟达 Vera CPU、Rubin GPU 搭配使用，并组合成全新的 NVIDIA Vera Rubin NVL144 CPX 平台。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This integrated NVIDIA MGX system can provide 8 exaflops of AI computing power in a single rack, achieving 7.5 times the AI performance of GB300 NVL72; it also comes with 100TB of high-speed memory and 1.7 PB/s of memory bandwidth.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该集成式 NVIDIA MGX 系统在单机架可提供 8 exaflops 的 AI 算力，达到 GB300 NVL72 的 7.5 倍 AI 性能；同时还配备 100TB 高速内存和 1.7 PB/s 的内存带宽。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang stated that the Vera Rubin platform will mark another leap forward in the frontier of AI computing — not only introducing the next-generation Rubin GPU but also bringing a new class of CPX processors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英伟达 CEO 黄仁勋表示，Vera Rubin 平台将标志着 AI 计算前沿的又一次飞跃 —— 不仅引入了下一代 Rubin GPU，还带来了一类全新的 CPX 处理器。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Just as RTX graphics cards revolutionized graphics and physical AI, Rubin CPX is the first CUDA GPU designed specifically for large-scale contextual AI, enabling models to reason within millions of tokens of knowledge at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Rubin CPX is expected to be available by the end of 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，Rubin CPX 预计将于 2026 年底上市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>爱诗科技完成 6000 万美元融资，阿里巴巴领投</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">爱诗科技完成-6000-万美元融资，阿里巴巴领投</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 10,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             AI video generation company PixVerse announced the completion of over $60 million in Series B financing
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 10 日，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             AI 视频生成企业爱诗科技宣布完成超过 6000 万美元 B 轮融资
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             this round of financing for PixVerse was led by Alibaba
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , with follow-on investments from Dalong Capital, Shenzhen Capital Group, Beijing AI Industry Investment Fund, Hunan Electric Power, Giant Network, and Antler, among others.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             爱诗科技本次融资由阿里巴巴领投
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，达晨财智、深创投、北京市人工智能产业投资基金、湖南电广、巨人网络和 Antler 等投资方跟投。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            PixVerse introduced that its global user base has now exceeded 100 million, its self-developed video generation large model PixVerse V5 ranks first on Artificial Analysis's image-to-video list, and its product PixVerse (Paiwo AI) was selected as the 25th in a16z's &quot;Global Top 50 Generative AI Consumer Mobile Applications&quot; list.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            爱诗科技介绍，目前公司全球用户规模突破 1 亿，自研视频生成大模型 PixVerse V5 位居 Artificial Analysis 图生视频榜首，产品 PixVerse（拍我 AI）入选 a16z「全球 Top 50 生成式 AI 消费移动应用」榜单第 25 位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding this financing round, Wang Changhu, founder and CEO of PixVerse, stated:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于此次融资，爱诗科技创始人兼 CEO 王长虎表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The birth of video generation technology is not accidental; it is the inevitable outcome of the long-term evolution of content and interaction methods, and it is ushering in a new era. On this journey, we are deeply honored to receive recognition and support from top global internet companies, leading domestic investment institutions, premier content industry partners, and internationally renowned investment institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>戴尔回应裁员：持续优化运营管理</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">戴尔回应裁员：持续优化运营管理</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 9, in response to recent market rumors about layoffs at Dell China, Dell responded via Jiemian News:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 9 日，针对近日市场上关于戴尔中国裁员的传闻，戴尔通过界面新闻回应称：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;We are continuously evaluating our business development to maintain a competitive advantage globally. Through the reorganization of market, sales, and other business processes, along with a series of other initiatives, we are continuously optimizing our operational management and ensuring that we can create value for our customers and provide the best innovation and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, Dell has successively implemented a series of cost-reduction and efficiency-improvement measures globally in the past two years, including personnel reductions. This response is consistent with its statements in other markets, confirming the consistency of its global strategy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据报道，戴尔近两年在全球范围内陆续采取了系列降本增效的措施，其中包括缩减人员。此回应与其在他国市场的表态相同，印证了其全球策略的一致性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to previous news from The Paper, there are rumors that Dell recently initiated a layoff plan targeting some employees in China. According to two informed sources who received notifications, Dell will hold one-on-one talks with affected employees this week, with their last working day set for October 10. They added that employees can apply for internal transfers to any vacant positions within the company before their departure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而据此前澎湃新闻消息，有传闻称，戴尔近期针对部分在华员工启动裁员计划。据两位收到通知的知情人士透露，戴尔本周将与受影响员工进行一对一谈话，其最后工作日定为 10 月 10 日。他们补充道，员工在离职前可申请转岗公司内部任何空缺岗位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Insiders said the layoffs primarily involve Dell's EMC storage division and Client Solutions Group (CSG) located in Shanghai and Xiamen, a coastal city in southeastern Fujian. One of them revealed that this is the third round of layoffs in recent months, with the departure dates for the previous two rounds being August 15 and September 12, respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士称，此次裁员主要涉及戴尔位于上海和福建东南部沿海城市厦门的 EMC 存储部门及客户端解决方案集团（CSG）。其中一人透露，这是近几个月来的第三轮裁员，此前两轮的离职日期分别为 8 月 15 日和 9 月 12 日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that, according to the latest market data from research firm Counterpoint Research, mainland China's PC market (excluding tablets) shipments reached 10.2 million units in Q2 2025, with Lenovo, Huawei, Asus, HP, and others ranking among the top five, while Dell's data is no longer listed separately.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，据数据机构 Counterpoint Research 的最新市场数据显示，2025 年第二季大陆 PC 市场（不含平板电脑）出货量达 1020 万台，联想、华为、华硕、惠普等位列前五，而戴尔的数据则不再单独列出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>消息称奔驰计划未来三年推 40+ 款新车</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">消息称奔驰计划未来三年推-40+-款新车</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d866c0f9-9925-463c-b97e-3781803d0d3b.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Carscoops, Mercedes-Benz officially released its new all-electric GLC model, marking what the company describes as &quot;the largest new car wave in its history&quot; about to begin.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Carscoops 报道，梅赛德斯-奔驰正式发布了旗下全新纯电 GLC 车型，而这也标志着该公司所描述的「其历史上最大规模」的一次新车潮即将开始。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Mercedes-Benz plans to launch over 40 new models within the next three years
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , and is committed to significantly reducing production costs. At the same time, Mercedes-Benz is making a controversial shift – moving from a pure luxury focus to pursuing higher sales and more affordable models, aiming to strengthen the company's financial position.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据报道，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             奔驰计划在未来三年内将推出超过 40 款新车
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，并且致力于显著降低生产成本。与此同时，奔驰正在做出一个有争议的转变 —— 从纯粹的豪华焦点转向追求更高销量、更经济实惠的车型，旨在加强公司财务状况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            To cope with the influx of new vehicles, Mercedes-Benz has invested over 2 billion euros (approximately 16.68 billion RMB) in its European assembly plants.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            为了应对一系列新车来袭，奔驰已投资超 20 亿欧元（约合人民币 166.8 亿元）用于其欧洲装配厂。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the launch event of the new electric GLC, Mercedes-Benz CEO Ola Källenius stated: &quot;With the introduction of the new electric GLC, the largest product launch in our company's history continues to gain momentum.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在全新电动 GLC 的发布活动上，梅赛德斯-奔驰 CEO Ola Källenius（康林松）表示：「随着全新电动 GLC 的推出，我们公司历史上最大规模的产品发布正持续获得动力。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Mercedes-Benz also stated that it will reduce production costs by 10% between 2024 and 2027. In addition to leveraging digitalization to help achieve this goal, it will also use artificial intelligence, increase the use of renewable energy, and drive improvements in production and logistics efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            奔驰还表示，将在 2024 年至 2027 年间将生产成本降低 10%。除了利用数字化帮助实现这一目标外，其还将使用人工智能和增加可再生能源的使用，并推动生产和物流效率的提高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>支付宝发布 AI 就业助手「晓叶」</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">支付宝发布-AI-就业助手「晓叶」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/47d63d3a-861a-4ac9-ad6e-de724064360c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 10, Alipay's digital employment team officially launched its AI employment assistant, &quot;Xiaoye.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 10 日，支付宝数字就业团队正式发布 AI 就业助手「晓叶」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official introduction, Xiaoye leverages large AI models and digital human technology to further enhance the experience of corporate recruitment and job seekers, aiming to create a new model of efficient, intelligent, and trustworthy employment services in the AI era.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方介绍，晓叶依托人工智能大模型与数字人技术，进一步提升企业招聘与求职者找工的体验，旨在打造 AI 时代高效、智能、可信赖的就业服务新模式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the newly launched AI employment assistant &quot;Xiaoye&quot; will enhance services at both ends of the employment market through 4 core capabilities, including job matching, online interviews, career planning, and training recommendations:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，此次发布的 AI 就业助手「晓叶」将通过 4 大核心能力，包括撮合匹配岗位、在线面试、职业规划和培训推荐，提升就业市场两端的服务：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI Matching: Can achieve &quot;jobs finding people&quot;; intelligent interaction with the AI assistant can deeply understand job seekers' needs, recommend relevant positions more accurately, and solve the pain point of job seekers struggling to search through a vast number of positions. Currently, 12 million jobs on Alipay's employment channel have integrated the AI matching function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI Online Interview: Allows for direct access to the interview stage without waiting; after applying for a recommended position through &quot;Xiaoye,&quot; job seekers can go directly to an AI online interview room without waiting or traveling, making interviews no longer limited by location and time, and further improving job search efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI can also be used for career planning, providing actionable advice based on job seekers' personal characteristics, past experience, skills/certificates, and personal intentions, assisting with short, medium, and long-term career development planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of vocational training, AI can also identify the gap between job seekers' current abilities and target positions, accurately recommend high-quality, carefully selected courses, and address the pain points of &quot;supply-demand mismatch&quot; and &quot;learning-application disconnect&quot; in traditional vocational training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, ecological partners such as Qingtuan Community, Haina AI, Jianzhimao, Yupao Zhipin, Linggonglong Jianzhi, Qingnian Community Workplace, Jiyouyuan Rijie, Taoxiansheng, Gongzizai, and Shankejie have partnered with AI employment assistant &quot;Xiaoye.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，青团社、海纳 AI、兼职猫、鱼泡直聘、灵工龙兼职、青年社职场、吉有缘日结、淘鲜生、工自在、闪客日结等生态伙伴已经与 AI 就业助手「晓叶」达成合作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 Transformer 作者：我们可能走错了 AI 发展的路</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-Transformer-作者：我们可能走错了-AI-发展的路</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/44ef328a-4949-4345-8181-a01bdf84fb3a.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Ashish Vaswani, the first author of the paper &quot;Attention is All You Need&quot; (which proposed the Transformer architecture), was interviewed by Bloomberg and offered a profound reflection: the current AI development model, dominated by a few tech giants, might be stifling genuine technological breakthroughs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，论文《Attention is All You Need》（提出了 Transformer 架构）的第一作者 Ashish Vaswani 接受了彭博社专访，并提出了深刻反思：当前由少数科技巨头主导的 AI 发展模式，可能正在扼杀真正的技术突破。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Vaswani believes that the enormous commercial interests in the AI field have led a few companies like Google and OpenAI to invest huge sums in incremental improvements to existing Transformer models, rather than exploring new paths that could lead to revolutionary breakthroughs. The essence of this &quot;arms race&quot; is commercial competition, not pure scientific exploration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Vaswani 认为，AI 领域巨大的商业利益，导致 Google、OpenAI 等少数公司将巨额资金投入到对现有 Transformer 模型的渐进式改良上，而非探索全新的、可能带来革命性突破的路径。这种「军备竞赛」的本质是商业竞争，而非纯粹的科学探索。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The industry once widely believed in &quot;Scaling Laws&quot; – that is, the more data and computing power invested, the stronger the model would become. However, after the highly anticipated release of GPT-5, its &quot;incremental&quot; improvements were seen by many experts as a sign of diminishing returns for this law.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            业界曾普遍信奉「规模定律」（Scaling Laws）—— 即投入更多数据和算力，模型就会变得更强。然而，备受期待的 GPT-5 发布后，其「挤牙膏式」的提升被许多专家视为该定律回报递减的信号。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, Vaswani believes it is too early to conclude that AI progress has stalled. But he also stated that discussions following the GPT-5 release reinforced his concerns about the way AI is being developed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但 Vaswani 认为，现在下结论说 AI 的进步已经停滞还为时过早。但他也表示，GPT-5 发布后的讨论加强了他对人工智能开发方式的担忧。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, he believes there is genuine science to pursue in applying AI in fields such as education and healthcare, stating,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;We cannot let closed-off AI development prevent us from exploring these new frontiers.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，他认为在教育和医疗保健等领域应用人工智能确实有真正的科学可以追求，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「我们不能让封闭式的 AI 开发阻止我们探索这些新的前沿领域。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>尼康正式发布紧凑型电影摄影机「ZR」</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">尼康正式发布紧凑型电影摄影机「ZR」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ed791012-911a-4d61-9859-c5813faa987a.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Nikon officially released its new compact cinema camera, the &quot;ZR,&quot;
            &lt;strong&gt;
             which is its first mass-produced model since acquiring professional cinema camera company RED, and is considered a significant milestone for Nikon in the video field.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，尼康正式发布紧凑型电影摄影机新品「ZR」，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             这是其收购专业电影机公司 RED 后推出的首款量产机型，被视为尼康在视频领域的重要里程碑。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The main parameters of the camera are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该机的主要参数如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New &quot;R3D NE RAW&quot; internal recording format, supporting up to 6K/60p, 12-bit recording.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in &quot;Cinematic video&quot; preset for direct output of RED-style footage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 4-inch 1000-nit DCI-P3 LCD display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced 32-bit float audio technology, combined with OZO Audio's multiple pickup modes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Building on this, the ZR also supports various high dynamic range formats such as RED R3D NE, N-RAW, and Apple ProRes RAW HQ, meeting the needs of different creators.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在此基础上，ZR 还支持 RED R3D NE、N-RAW 以及 Apple ProRes RAW HQ 等多种高动态范围格式，满足不同创作者的需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding focusing, the camera body is equipped with Nikon's deep learning AI autofocus, which can intelligently recognize 9 types of objects, including people and vehicles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对焦方面，机身搭载尼康深度学习 AI 自动对焦，可智能识别人物、车辆等 9 类对象。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of other features, this new product offers slow-motion presets, supporting 4K/119.88p or FHD/239.76p. The lightweight magnesium alloy body adopts a fanless design, balancing durability and quietness, while the Z-mount provides high expandability, adapting to a wide range of lenses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其他功能方面，本次新品提供慢动作预设，支持 4K/119.88p 或 FHD/239.76p。轻量化镁合金机身采用无风扇设计，兼顾耐用与静音，Z 卡口带来高度扩展性，适配丰富的镜头群。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing, the
            &lt;strong&gt;
             ZR body-only is priced at 13,999 yuan, and the 24-70mm F4 kit is priced at 17,999 yuan.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             ZR 裸机定价 13,999 元，搭配 24-70mm F4 套机售价 17,999 元。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vivo X300 Pro 跑分公布，破 400 万</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">vivo-X300-Pro-跑分公布，破-400-万</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6965d66a-6b60-438f-a5c7-019433ff0bde.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, vivo product manager Han Boxiao and vivo official sources announced that the joint laboratory of vivo and Arm showcased its latest achievements at the Arm Unlocked 2025 AI Technology Summit:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，vivo 产品经理韩伯啸及 vivo 官方发文称，vivo 与 Arm 的联合实验室携新成果在 Arm Unlocked 2025 AI 技术峰会上，展示了其最新成果：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delving into the micro-architecture level, achieving stronger performance and better energy efficiency;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pioneering the implementation of SME2 innovative features to create a more efficient on-device AI experience;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that SME2 is a set of high-level CPU instruction sets in the Armv9 architecture, which is an upgrade based on SME and can support real-time inference tasks such as image processing, natural language processing, and speech generation on mobile devices under an AI heterogeneous computing framework.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，SME2 是 Armv9 架构中的一组高阶 CPU 指令集，其基于 SME 升级、能够在 AI 异质运算框架下，支持影像处理、自然语言处理、语音生成等在行动端的即时推理任务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Han Boxiao also announced the AnTuTu benchmark score for the vivo X300 Pro Satellite Communication Edition: 4,011,932 points, with a peak temperature of 35.6℃ (specific test environment unknown).
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             韩伯啸还公布了 vivo X300 Pro 卫星通信版的安兔兔跑分情况：4011932 分，并且显示峰值温度为 35.6℃（未知具体测试环境）。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPPO 将首发小红书 4K 超清实况图</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OPPO-将首发小红书-4K-超清实况图</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/16a0dd9a-1936-4489-8d46-2fcf0724e8e3.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 10, OPPO and Xiaohongshu announced the joint establishment of an &quot;Imaging Innovation Joint Lab,&quot; dedicated to providing users and creators with a better image quality experience throughout the entire imaging chain, from shooting to sharing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 10 日，OPPO 与小红书宣布共同成立「影像创新联合实验室」，致力于让用户和创作者在影像的拍摄至分享完整链路中，获得更好的影像画质体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that both parties will conduct joint technical research based on Xiaohongshu's &quot;Original Image Direct Output&quot; technology brand, focusing on core scenarios in the mobile imaging era, and co-build imaging capabilities in areas such as direct output of 4K ultra-clear live photos, static images, HDR effects, and Dolby Vision videos.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，双方将基于小红书「原画直出」技术品牌，围绕移动影像时代核心场景开展联合技术攻关，在直出 4K 超清实况照片、静态图像、HDR 效果及杜比视界视频等方面展开影像能力共建。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that the relevant technical cooperation results
            &lt;strong&gt;
             will first be implemented in OPPO's next-generation flagship Find X9 series products
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , enabling a full-link operation of &quot;shooting-viewing-sharing&quot; and achieving 4K ultra-clear live photos with &quot;OPPO direct output, Xiaohongshu direct publishing.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，相关技术合作成果，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             将率先在 OPPO 下一代旗舰 Find X9 系列产品中落地
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，打通「拍摄-观看-分享」全链路操作，实现 4K 超清实况照片「OPPO 直出，小红书直发」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, both parties will continue to explore and output imaging standards, jointly creating industry benchmark cases:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，双方将持续探讨并输出影像标准，共同打造行业标杆案例：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of user insights, both parties will not only deeply discuss imaging development trends and changes in user needs but also participate in each other's user research and exchange activities quarterly;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, information exchange based on Xiaohongshu platform's imaging user behavior trends and OPPO's demographic characteristics will provide input for both parties' next technical planning strategies and directions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the level of imaging capability co-construction, both parties aim to achieve a full-link lossless imaging experience, assisting users in obtaining a better experience throughout the entire imaging chain from shooting to sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>鸿蒙版《原神》上线</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">鸿蒙版《原神》上线</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1d0d9f0d-5763-4385-88c6-20fb2dec1612.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the HarmonyOS version of &quot;Genshin Impact&quot; was officially launched, supporting HarmonyOS 5 and above systems on HarmonyOS phones/tablets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，鸿蒙版《原神》正式上线，支持 HarmonyOS 5 及已上系统的鸿蒙手机/平板。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the HarmonyOS version also launched with the &quot;Song of the Empty Moon: Part One&quot; update, opening up the new area Nordkalen. According to our actual tests, players can choose between two download options: &quot;Full Resources&quot; (estimated download size 39.34GB) and &quot;Basic Resources&quot; (estimated download size 26.88GB).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，本次鸿蒙版同样上线的为空月之歌「月之一」版本，新区域挪德卡莱开放。据我们实际测试发现，玩家可以选择「完整资源」（预估下载量为 39.34GB）和「基础资源」（预估下载量为 26.88GB）两种方案下载。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The HarmonyOS version of &quot;Genshin Impact&quot; uses the Sky Island server (official server), and game progress is interoperable with &quot;Genshin Impact&quot; Sky Island servers on other platforms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            鸿蒙版《原神》为天空岛服务器（官方服务器），与其他平台的《原神》天空岛服务器游戏进度互通。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to official information, the configuration requirements for the HarmonyOS version of &quot;Genshin Impact&quot; are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据了解，官方给出的鸿蒙版《原神》配置要求如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Supported configuration: Kirin 8000 and above; 6GB RAM and above; HarmonyOS 5 or higher; 45GB of available space required.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             支持配置：麒麟 8000 及以上；6GB 内存及以上；HarmonyOS 5 或更高版本；需预留 45GB 可用空间。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Recommended configuration: Kirin 9010S and above; 8GB RAM and above; HarmonyOS 5.1 or higher; 60GB of available space required.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             推荐配置：麒麟 9010S 及以上；8GB 内存及以上；HarmonyOS 5.1 或更高版本；需预留 60GB 可用空间。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>高德地图上线「扫街榜」</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">高德地图上线「扫街榜」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/04cd74f2-ebda-4d2d-8ec1-debbb6066b59.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Amap officially launched the world's first life service ranking list based on real navigation, travel behavior, and integrated AI technology – the Amap Street Scan List, establishing a new offline service credit system.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             高德地图正式推出了全球首个基于真实导航、出行行为，融合 AI 技术打造而成的生活服务榜单——高德扫街榜，构建全新的线下服务信用体系。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to official introduction, unlike common food and entertainment lists on the market, the Amap Street Scan List incorporates user action indicators, combining real navigation-to-store behavior with evaluation feedback, avoiding the problem of conventional lists being easily manipulated or inflated. Therefore, the Amap Street Scan List has become a product that is very difficult to game.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方介绍，不同于市面上常见的美食玩乐榜单，高德扫街榜纳入了用户的行动指标，将真实的导航到店行为与评价反馈结合起来，避免了常规榜单容易被刷分、注水的问题。因此高德扫街榜成为一个很难被刷榜的产品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Li Gang, product manager of Amap Street Scan List, &quot;Only when users actually go, or even repeatedly visit a store, is it the most genuine positive review for a merchant, a true vote with their feet.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据高德扫街榜产品经理李刚介绍，「只有用户去了，甚至反复到店，才是对商家最真实的好评，是真正的用脚投票。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the comprehensive score of merchants on the Street Scan List incorporates real behaviors such as navigation, search, store visits, and collections. On this basis, it verifies the authenticity, professionalism, timeliness, and content quality of comments, and then calculates a score driven by an AI model, which serves as the ranking basis for the Street Scan List.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，扫街榜的商家综合评分，纳入了导航、搜索、到店、收藏等真实行为，在此基础上检验评论的真实性、专业度、时效性、内容质量等维度，再通过 AI 模型驱动计算得出分数，成为扫街榜的排名依据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the Amap Street Scan List covers over 1.6 million offline service merchants in more than 300 cities nationwide, including over 870,000 restaurants, 230,000 hotels, and nearly 50,000 scenic spots.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，高德扫街榜已经覆盖了全国超 300 个城市的 160 万个线下服务商家，包括超 87 万家餐厅、23 万家酒店以及近 5 万个景区等。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that yesterday was the 26th anniversary of Alibaba's establishment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，昨日为阿里巴巴成立 26 周年的日子。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>美团官宣大众点评「重启」品质外卖</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">美团官宣大众点评「重启」品质外卖</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d52fb467-88af-4cc6-aab3-af3ab07b7b52.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Meituan announced that Dianping will officially &quot;restart&quot; its quality takeout service.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，美团宣布大众点评将正式「重启」品质外卖服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to official introduction, the &quot;restarted&quot; quality takeout service by Dianping will utilize a self-developed B-side large model, combined with massive real review data to analyze user needs, further filter out non-authentic review data, and provide reliable decisions to users through &quot;AI + real high scores.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据官方介绍，本次大众点评「重启」的品质外卖服务将通过 B 端自研大模型，结合海量真实评价数据分析用户需求，进一步剔除非真实点评数据，以「AI + 真实高分」为用户提供可靠决策。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After this upgrade and restart, Dianping's quality takeout will fully cover various high-quality restaurants, including those on the Must-Eat List, Black Pearl, and high-star hotels. The first batch has already gathered over a million high-scoring dine-in restaurants, leveraging massive user real in-store reviews to deliver quality dine-in restaurant takeout to everyone.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次升级重启后，大众点评品质外卖将全面覆盖必吃榜、黑珍珠以及高星酒店等各类优质餐厅。首批已集合超百万家高分堂食店，依托海量用户真实到店评价，将优质堂食餐厅的外卖送到大家身边。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meituan stated that in the future, it will continue to invite more new restaurants to join based on genuine customer ratings and actual merchant operations, enabling all high-scoring dine-in restaurants nationwide to provide comprehensive services for both in-store and home delivery.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            美团方面表示，未来其将根据顾客真实评分、商家真实运营情况不断邀请更多新餐厅加入，让全国所有高分堂食餐厅，都能为用户提供到店、到家的全面服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Meituan also revealed that its C-side AI intelligent agent service will be released within a week and is currently in the &quot;building-wide testing&quot; phase.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             另据美团透露，其 C 端 AI 智能体服务也将于一周内发布，目前正在「封楼测试」阶段。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>泰国电影《不亲密朋友》中国内地定档</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">泰国电影《不亲密朋友》中国内地定档</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9b5db75e-cd23-472d-882d-913a3e35c121.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the Thai film &quot;Not Friends&quot; has been scheduled for release in mainland China on October 18th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，泰国电影《不亲密朋友》中国内地定档 10 月 18 日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of transfer student Pei and campus celebrity Joe who accidentally become deskmates. As they gradually become friends, Joe unexpectedly dies in a car accident. To commemorate Joe, Pei decides to invite all students to jointly shoot a short film. As the plan progresses, everyone discovers that Pei's motive for shooting the short film is not simple.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述转学生佩伊与校园风云人物乔偶然成为了同桌，在两人逐渐成为好友的过程中，乔却意外车祸离世。为了纪念乔，佩伊决定邀请全校同学共同拍摄一部短片。随着计划进行，众人发现佩伊拍摄短片的动机并不简单。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is produced by GDH559, the production company behind &quot;Bad Genius&quot; and &quot;How to Make Millions Before Grandma Dies,&quot; written and directed by Atta Hemwadee, and stars Anthony Buisseret and Pisitpon Ekpongpisit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片由《天才枪手》《姥姥的外孙》制作公司 GDH559 出品，阿塔·汉瓦迪编剧/导演，安东尼·布塞尔特、平西朋·艾格朋皮西主演。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>恐怖片《好狗狗》释出新海报</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">恐怖片《好狗狗》释出新海报</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f1c90976-18bf-42e1-ad31-0aadb7ce5b43.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sina Movies, the horror film &quot;Good Boy&quot; released a new poster: a hand in the dark reaches for the dog.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪电影消息，恐怖片《好狗狗》释出新海报：黑暗中的手伸向狗狗。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is described as a &quot;heartbreaking horror film,&quot; telling the story from a dog's perspective. A man named Todd moves into a new country home and is haunted by an evil spirit, while his loyal dog Indy wants to protect its beloved owner, seeing the terrifying presence approaching in the dark.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片描述为一部「让人心碎的恐怖片」，故事从汪星人的视角讲述，男子 Todd 搬进乡下新家，被邪恶灵魂缠上了，而他忠诚的狗狗 Indy 想要保护最爱的主人，它能看到在黑暗中逼近的可怕存在。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is directed by Ben Leonberg, starring Larry Fessenden, Shane Jensen, and others. It is reported that the movie trailer garnered over 1 million views on YouTube in four days. Distributor IFC originally scheduled the film for a limited release in North American theaters on October 3 this year, but has now announced a wide release on the same day.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片由本·莱昂伯格导演，拉瑞·凡斯登、Shane Jensen 等出演。据悉，电影预告片在 YouTube 四天观看量超过 100 万，发行方 IFC 本安排该片于今年 10 月 3 日在北美有限影院上映，现宣布改为同天大规模公映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《惊天魔盗团 3》发布新剧照</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 03:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《惊天魔盗团-3》发布新剧照</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.11_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9170117b-38b9-4d44-89ed-43a85b81ee60.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the movie &quot;Now You See Me 3&quot; released new stills, featuring both new and old cast members.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近期，电影《惊天魔盗团 3》发布新剧照，新老阵容齐聚。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of how mysterious tarot cards bring together eight magicians from two generations of the Eye of Horus to battle a global criminal network behind the Blood Diamond family.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片讲述了神秘塔罗牌牵动两代魔盗团八位魔术师首次联手，对战血色钻石家族背后的全球级犯罪网络的故事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is produced by Lionsgate, directed by Ruben Fleischer, written by Michael Lesslie and Seth Grahame-Smith, and stars Ariana Greenblatt, Justice Smith, and others. It is set to be released in North America on November 14, 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片由狮门影业出品，鲁本·弗雷斯彻执导，迈克尔·莱斯利、赛斯·格雷厄姆-史密斯编剧，阿丽亚娜·格林布拉特、贾斯蒂斯·史密斯等主演，将于 2025 年 11 月 14 日北美上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifanr.com/tags/%e6%97%a9%e6%8a%a5&quot;&gt;
            早报
           &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
