<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>雷军：小米 17 系列全面对标 iPhone（卢伟冰：小米 17「全方位大升级」）（对标苹果 小米将跳过 16 推出 17）（小米官博头像偷跑新品）</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">雷军：小米-17-系列全面对标-iPhone（卢伟冰：小米-17「全方位大升级」）（对标苹果-小米将跳过-16-推出-17）（小米官博头像偷跑新品）</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            (Headline: Xiaomi 17 new phone appearance exposed, Lei Jun says it fully benchmarks iPhone
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            （标：小米 17 新机外观曝光，雷军称全面对标 iPhone
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;mmwAGhz&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7cc44820.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637852&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1346px) 100vw, 1346px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7cc44820.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7cc44820.png 1346w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7cc44820-360x282.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7cc44820-768x603.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7cc44820-1024x803.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Lu Weibing, President of Xiaomi Group, announced that the all-new Xiaomi 17 series will officially debut this month, a month earlier than its predecessor, calling it &quot;the most significant leap&quot; in the history of Xiaomi's digital series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，小米集团总裁卢伟冰宣布，全新小米 17 系列将于本月正式亮相，比上代提前一个月发布，并称这是小米数字系列史上「最重大的一次跃迁」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this new Xiaomi flagship did not adopt the sequential naming of &quot;Xiaomi 16 Series&quot; but instead uses the Xiaomi 17 Series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，本次小米新旗舰并未采用「小米 16 系列」这一顺序命名，而是采用小米 17 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Lu Weibing, the Xiaomi 17 series is a transformative work from Xiaomi's five-year high-end strategy, ushering in a critical formation change and achieving cross-generational upgrades in overall product power. The series includes three models: Xiaomi 17, Xiaomi 17 Pro, and Xiaomi 17 Pro Max, all of which will globally debut the fifth-generation Snapdragon 8 Ultimate Edition mobile platform. Among them:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据卢伟冰介绍，小米 17 系列是小米高端化战略五年来的蜕变之作，迎来关键变阵，全系产品力实现跨代升级。该系列包括三款机型：小米 17、小米 17 Pro 和小米 17 Pro Max，均将全球首发第五代骁龙 8 至尊版移动平台。其中：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi 17 is positioned as &quot;the strongest standard flagship in history,&quot; with comprehensive upgrades and &quot;more features without a price increase&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi 17 Pro focuses on being a compact technology imaging flagship;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Xiaomi 17 Pro Max is dubbed &quot;Xiaomi's most powerful peak technology imaging flagship in history.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing stated that in the five years since launching its high-end strategy, Xiaomi has firmly benchmarked against the iPhone, achieving significant progress under the philosophy of &quot;no shortcomings in high-end, prioritizing experience over leading parameters, and deep integration of software and hardware.&quot; The Xiaomi 17 series not only features major breakthroughs in underlying technology but will also bring a new experience to break the &quot;sense of boredom&quot; in the current mobile phone market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            卢伟冰表示，在开启高端化战略的五年来，小米坚定对标 iPhone，并在「高端无短板、从参数领先到体验优先，软硬件深度融合」的理念下取得显著进展。此次小米 17 系列不仅在底层技术上有重大突破，还将带来全新体验，以打破当前手机市场的「无聊感」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, Lei Jun, Chairman and CEO of Xiaomi Group, reposted the Weibo post and stated:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后，小米集团董事长兼 CEO 雷军更是转发微博并表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The Xiaomi 17 series features a cross-generational upgrade in product power, fully benchmarking against the iPhone, and directly confronting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday afternoon, Xiaomi Mobile's official Weibo account unexpectedly changed to a &quot;new avatar,&quot; prominently displaying a never-before-seen Xiaomi phone, suspected to be the &quot;Xiaomi 17 Pro Max&quot; that Xiaomi is about to release.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天下午，小米手机官方微博还意外地换上了一个「新头像」，其中赫然显示一台从未见过的小米手机，疑似是小米即将要发布的「小米 17 Pro Max」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As seen in the image, this Xiaomi phone adopts a brand-new camera Deco design. In addition to two massive lenses, the module itself has become a complete display screen.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从图中可以看到，这部小米手机采用了全新的相机 Deco 设计，除了两颗硕大的镜头之外，模组本身变成了一个完整的显示屏。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Xiaomi Mobile's official Weibo account has &quot;recalled&quot; this avatar, and the avatar image has also been removed from the Weibo album.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，小米手机官方微博已经「撤回」了这个头像，微博相册当中也去掉了这张头像图片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>西贝发道歉信，罗永浩再怒怼</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">西贝发道歉信，罗永浩再怒怼</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;cRLFugy&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7daa0a58.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637853&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1268px) 100vw, 1268px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7daa0a58.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7daa0a58.png 1268w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7daa0a58-360x191.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7daa0a58-768x408.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7daa0a58-1024x544.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Xibei Catering Group, whose &quot;pre-made dishes&quot; controversy continues to ferment, once again issued an apology letter in response to public concerns, promising to complete adjustments to various dish processing methods before October 1.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，因「预制菜」争议持续发酵的西贝餐饮集团，再次发布致歉信回应公众关切，并承诺将在 10 月 1 日前完成多项菜品加工方式的调整。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the apology letter, Xibei admitted that &quot;there is a significant difference between production processes and customer expectations,&quot; failing to meet demands and expectations. They apologized to customers, emphasizing that they will &quot;adjust central kitchen pre-processing techniques to on-site store processing as much as possible,&quot; and introduced nine specific rectification measures, including:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            致歉信中，西贝承认「生产工艺与顾客的期望有较大差异」，未能满足需求与期待，向顾客致歉，强调将「尽可能把中央厨房前置加工工艺调整到门店现场加工」，并出台了九条具体整改措施，包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil and ingredient upgrade: All dishes will switch to non-GMO soybean oil, and children's meal cod strips will be replaced with freshly cut and fried/roasted yellow croaker at the store;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children's meals prepared on-site: Beef stew rice with beef sauce and beef patties will all be freshly stir-fried and made at the store;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freshly processed meat dishes: Lamb skewers, pork ribs with sauerkraut, crispy roujiamo braised meat, and hand-shredded spicy chicken will all be changed to raw meat skewered, grilled, braised, or boiled on-site at the store;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freshly brewed porridges: Oat millet porridge will be changed to freshly brewed millet porridge at the store, with fresh pumpkin slices added for brewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the announcement, the adjustments cover a variety of dishes including children's meals, lamb skewers, pork ribs with sauerkraut, crispy roujiamo, hand-shredded spicy chicken, and oat millet porridge, all of which will be changed to be freshly made, stir-fried, grilled, or braised at the store.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据公告，调整范围涵盖儿童餐、烤羊肉串、猪排烩酸菜、酥皮肉夹馍、手撕椒麻鸡、燕麦小米粥等多款菜品，均将改为门店现做、现炒、现烤或现卤。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the shelf life issue of concern to the public, Xibei stated that it is communicating with upstream suppliers to &quot;shorten the shelf life as much as possible while ensuring food safety and inventory turnover.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于外界关注的保质期问题，西贝表示正与上游供应商沟通，「在保证食品安全和库存周转的前提下，尽量缩短保质期」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The letter also quoted Xibei founder Jia Guolong's previous statement: &quot;The cooks revolve around the diners; whatever you say is good, that's what we'll do. Customers 'abuse' me a thousand times, but I treat them like first love.&quot; It also stated that Xibei will &quot;thoroughly learn from Pang Donglai&quot; to create transparent operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            信中还引用了西贝创始人贾国龙此前的发言：「做饭的围着吃饭的转，你说咋好就咋办。顾客『虐』我千百遍，我待顾客如初恋。」并称将「彻彻底底向胖东来学习」，打造透明化运营。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Intriguingly, two versions of this apology letter appeared during its release. The only difference was that the character &quot;虐&quot; (abuse) in &quot;顾客虐我千百遍&quot; (customers abuse me a thousand times) was enclosed in quotation marks in the second version. Some analysts believe this subtle adjustment was intended to reduce controversy, but it instead drew public attention to the wording itself.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            耐人寻味的是，此次致歉信在发布过程中出现了两个版本，唯一的区别是「顾客虐我千百遍」中的「虐」字在第二版中被加上了引号。有分析认为，这一细节调整意在降低争议，但反而让舆论焦点集中到该用词本身。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Considering the background of previous events, this apology letter is Xibei's renewed public statement of rectification after its public confrontation with Luo Yonghao over &quot;pre-made dishes.&quot; Previously, Xibei had denied that the dishes in question were pre-made and opened its kitchen for tours, but also admitted that some dishes were used overnight.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            结合此前事件背景，此次致歉信是西贝在与罗永浩的「预制菜」舆论交锋后，再次作出的公开整改表态。此前，西贝曾否认涉事菜品属于预制菜，并开放后厨参观，但也承认部分菜品存在隔夜使用情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response to this, Luo Yonghao continued to express doubts on social media, believing there was a gap between Xibei's previous promises and actual practices. He criticized the rectification timeline, certain ingredient processing methods, and related compliance issues, even implying that Xibei might be involved in tax evasion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对这一回应，罗永浩在社交平台上继续表达质疑，认为西贝此前的承诺与实际做法存在差距，并对整改时间安排、部分食材处理方式及相关合规问题提出批评，甚至暗示西贝可能存在偷税漏税的情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;AzfGgkS&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7e1f2b5e.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637854&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1264px) 100vw, 1264px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7e1f2b5e.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7e1f2b5e.png 1264w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7e1f2b5e-360x252.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7e1f2b5e-768x538.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7e1f2b5e-1024x718.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, Pang Donglai founder Yu Donglai recently posted, stating, &quot;Regarding Xibei, I have good intentions, and I affirm that Xibei is excellent in many aspects! I hope people will rationally understand and help businesses improve and move towards betterment, rather than inadvertently destroying a company! Because building a good company is incredibly difficult!&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，胖东来创始人于东来日前发文称，「关于西贝我是好意，也肯定西贝在很多方面还是很优秀的！希望人们理性理解帮助企业改善问题走向美好、而不是不经意间的毁掉一个企业！因为做好一个企业太不容易！」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yu Donglai also stated that he believes Xibei will quickly address people's concerns about certain food safety issues. He added, &quot;Every enterprise has many problems! But the mainstream of society is more about mutual accusations. I hope people will be filled with more goodwill in the future!&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            于东来还表示自己相信西贝会尽快完善人们对部分食品安全的担忧，其还称「任何一个企业都存在很多的问题！但社会的主流更多的是相互的指责，望人们未来都充满更多的善念！」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, Luo Yonghao reposted the relevant content and stated, &quot;I hope you (Yu Donglai), before clarifying the truth, will not be misled by bad friends, stir up this muddy water, and tarnish your reputation.&quot; Luo Yonghao stated that, with the fermentation of the event over several days, it is clear that the person who wants to destroy Xibei is Mr. Jia (Jia Guolong) himself.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后罗永浩转发相关内容并表示「希望您（于东来）弄清真相之前，千万不要被损友误导，搅这个浑水，连累了您的名声。」罗永浩表示，几日事件的发酵，可以看出来，想要毁掉西贝的人就是贾总（贾国龙）本人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also published a lengthy article stating that although Xibei's official apology letter was issued, it did not apologize to him personally, nor did Jia Guolong himself apologize for previously slandering him as a &quot;cyber mafia.&quot; Luo Yonghao said that, according to his past character, he would insist on demanding a fair explanation, but after turning fifty, he has witnessed too many middle-aged people doing reckless things due to &quot;saving face.&quot; This time, to prevent Jia Guolong's stubbornness from harming the company and its employees' livelihoods, he decided to abandon some of his original plans:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他同时发布长文表示，虽然西贝官方发了致歉信，但并未向他个人道歉，贾国龙本人也未就此前污蔑其为“网络黑社会”一事道歉。罗永浩称，按过去性格会坚持讨要公正说法，但五十岁后目睹过太多中年人因“面子”做出不顾后果的事，这次为了避免让贾国龙的固执伤及企业和员工生计，决定放弃部分原计划：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drop the defamation lawsuit against Jia Guolong (unless the other party makes similar remarks again);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abandon the previous plan to &quot;reward&quot; Jia Guolong with 100,000 yuan in cash as a satire (unless the other party makes absurd remarks again);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue to fulfill the commitment to help consumers initiate class action lawsuits against Xibei. Those in need can contact him via email [email protected] , and he will arrange for lawyers to provide legal aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Luo Yonghao reiterated that he does not oppose pre-made dishes and has even sold them in e-commerce live streams, but catering enterprises must ensure consumers' right to know and not use pre-made dishes to impersonate freshly prepared dishes. He finally stated that the draft &quot;National Standard for Food Safety of Pre-made Dishes&quot; led by the National Health Commission has passed expert review and is expected to be implemented as soon as possible.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            罗永浩再次强调，自己并不反对预制菜，甚至在电商直播中销售过，但餐饮企业必须保障消费者知情权，不能用预制菜冒充现做菜肴。他最后表示，国家卫健委主导的《预制菜食品安全国家标准》草案已通过专家审查，期待尽快实施。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>中汽协会就供应链账期问题发表倡议（多车企回复中汽协会账期倡议）</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">中汽协会就供应链账期问题发表倡议（多车企回复中汽协会账期倡议）</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday morning, the China Association of Automobile Manufacturers (CAAM) released the &quot;Initiative on Standardizing Supplier Payment for Automobile OEMs&quot; in Beijing, aiming to promote the implementation of the &quot;Regulations on Ensuring Payment to Small and Medium-sized Enterprises,&quot; support key automakers in fulfilling their supplier payment term commitments with high quality, and build a collaborative win-win development ecosystem for &quot;OEMs - Parts Suppliers.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天上午，中国汽车工业协会在北京发布《汽车整车企业供应商账款支付规范倡议》，旨在推动落实《保障中小企业款项支付条例》，支持重点车企高质量践行供应商账期承诺，构建「整车 — 零部件」协作共赢发展生态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The initiative puts forward specific requirements around four key links:
            &lt;strong&gt;
             order confirmation, delivery and acceptance, payment and settlement, and contract term
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            :
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该倡议围绕
            &lt;strong&gt;
             订单确认、交付与验收、支付与结算、合同期限
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            四个关键环节提出具体要求：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Order Confirmation: Both supply and demand parties clarify order date, specifications, quantity, and delivery requirements through purchase orders and delivery notices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delivery and Acceptance: Automakers should complete acceptance within principle of no more than 3 working days after receiving goods and issue an acceptance form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Payment and Settlement: Encourage payment using cash or bank acceptance bills ; small and medium-sized enterprises are advocated to use cash or bank acceptance bills entirely; if the supply unit price is not fixed, an advance payment of no less than 80% of the contract unit price or 50% of the development fixed unit price should be made, with subsequent adjustments for overpayment or underpayment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contract Term: Advocate for establishing long-term stable cooperative relationships, with each contract valid for no less than 1 year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CAAM stated that this move is to address issues such as &quot;price compression and extended payment cycles&quot; caused by intensified competition in the automotive market, protect the legitimate rights and interests of suppliers, especially small and medium-sized enterprises, and calls on OEMs to incorporate this initiative into their contracts and genuinely fulfill their payment term commitments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中汽协会表示，此举是为应对汽车市场竞争加剧导致的「压价、延长付款周期」等问题，维护供应商特别是中小企业的合法权益，并呼吁整车企业将该倡议纳入合约，切实履行账期承诺。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Following the release of the initiative, automakers such as Nio, Great Wall, Xiaomi, Leapmotor, Xpeng, Geely, BAIC, JAC, and FAW have responded, successively issuing statements expressing their active implementation of the &quot;Initiative,&quot; committing to complete payment within 60 days, and promoting the construction of a collaborative win-win industrial ecosystem for &quot;OEMs-Parts Suppliers.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在该倡议发表后，蔚来、长城、小米、零跑、小鹏、吉利、北汽、江汽、一汽等车企纷纷响应，陆续发布声明表示将积极落实《倡议》，承诺在 60 天内完成账款支付，推动构建「整车—零部件」协作共赢的产业生态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to relevant information released by the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, as of yesterday afternoon, 17 automakers, including Dongfeng, SAIC, Chery, Seres, Li Auto, Changan, GAC, and BYD, which had previously expressed their positions, have made statements. The pattern of upstream and downstream collaboration in the industry to promote high-quality development is accelerating.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据工信部发布的相关信息，截止昨日下午，包含此前已表态的东风、上汽、奇瑞、赛力斯、理想、长安、广汽、比亚迪在内，已有 17 家车企作出表态，行业上下游协同推动高质量发展的格局正在加速形成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>苹果推送 iOS 26 正式版</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果推送-iOS-26-正式版</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;gxYOJkA&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7eddd12e.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637855&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2172px) 100vw, 2172px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7eddd12e.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7eddd12e.png 2172w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7eddd12e-360x192.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7eddd12e-768x410.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b7eddd12e-1024x547.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Early this morning, Apple pushed the official versions of operating systems such as iOS 26 and iPadOS 26.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天凌晨，苹果推送 iOS 26、iPadOS 26 等操作系统的正式版。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For this OS 26 system family, from iPhone to Mac, from iPad to Vision Pro, Apple has unified the interface language and interaction logic across its entire product line.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次 OS 26 系统家族，从 iPhone 到 Mac，从 iPad 到 Vision Pro，苹果统一了全家桶的界面语言和交互逻辑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of design, Apple named this UI design &quot;Solarium,&quot; which includes new design elements such as &quot;Liquid Glass.&quot; This glass material can reflect and refract the surrounding environment, and the overall visual style leans towards visionOS, extensively using glass material to handle hierarchical differentiation tasks within the interface.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            设计方面，苹果给本次的 UI 设计取名为「Solarium（阳光房）」，包含了「液态玻璃（Liquid Glass）」等全新设计元素。这种玻璃材质可以反射和折射周围环境，整体视觉风格向 visionOS 靠拢，大量使用玻璃材质来承担界面中的层级分化任务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For iOS 26, the lock screen has been upgraded with gravity-sensing spatial wallpaper effects; interfaces for Camera, Photos, Safari browser, etc., have been extremely simplified; CarPlay's visual language has been synchronously updated. It is understood that iOS 26 also added a battery management feature called &quot;Adaptive Power,&quot; which is enabled by default on the iPhone 17 series and iPhone Air.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            iOS 26 方面，锁屏升级了基于重力感应的空间壁纸效果；相机、相册、Safari 浏览器等界面极致简化；CarPlay 同步更新视觉语言。据了解，iOS 26 还新增了一项名为「自适应电源」的电池管理功能，而该功能在 iPhone 17 系列以及 iPhone Air 上默认开启。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Apple's official documentation, this feature can learn user habits through on-device intelligent algorithms and automatically adjust power consumption as needed. It is worth noting that this feature requires about 7 days for background learning and calibration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据苹果官方文档介绍，该功能能够通过设备端的智能算法学习用户的使用习惯，并根据需要来进行自动调节功耗。值得一提的是，该功能需要耗费约 7 天时间进行后台学习校准。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://ifanr.feishu.cn/space/api/box/stream/download/asynccode/?code=YmY2MThmMGE2MzE2ZjE0MjM1YmVhZGFmMGY4MGE3ZDdfWU01eGdqd2hYMkJCaHB5RFBldTNpNUk0czQ5bEl4MGFfVG9rZW46SHB1cmJxV1hpb2FMTHl4eXk2eWN3RFlLbmVkXzE3NTc5ODM0Mzg6MTc1Nzk4NzAzOF9WNA&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On iPadOS 26, there is a new window management system that supports free scaling, dragging, tiling, etc., providing a desktop-level multitasking experience; a new menu bar is introduced, supporting pull-down operations and search functions, and developers can also customize their own menus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            iPadOS 26 上，拥有全新窗口管理系统，支持自由缩放、拖拽、平铺、等，提供桌面级别的多任务体验；引入全新菜单栏，支持下拉操作与搜索功能，开发者还可以定制自己的菜单。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 9to5Mac, Apple has updated its new technical support page, emphasizing the importance of iPhone system updates and their potential impact on devices in the documentation; it also explains to users why iPhones might experience short-term impacts on battery life and performance after updating to iOS 26.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另据 9to5Mac 报道，苹果目前已更新了新的技术支持页面，并在文档中强调了 iPhone 系统更新的重要性以及对设备的潜在影响； 其还向用户解释，为何在更新 iOS 26 系统之后，iPhone 可能会在短期内遇到续航和性能方面的影响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding battery life and performance changes, Apple explained that this is because the system needs to complete data and file indexing in the background, prepare for search functions, and also download new resources and update applications. These tasks will additionally occupy hardware resources.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对续航、性能变化问题，苹果则解释表示，这是因为系统需要在后台完成数据和文件的索引，为搜索功能做准备，同时还会下载新资源和更新应用，这些任务会额外占用硬件资源。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Apple also pointed out that new features in iOS 26 may enhance user experience, but some features may continuously consume more processing performance and battery.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，苹果还指出 iOS 26 中的新功能可能能够提升用户体验，但部分功能可能会持续消耗更多处理性能以及电池损耗。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>市监局对英伟达展开反垄断调查</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">市监局对英伟达展开反垄断调查</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday afternoon, the State Administration for Market Regulation recently announced that, following a preliminary investigation, NVIDIA Corporation violated the &quot;Anti-Monopoly Law of the People's Republic of China&quot; and the restrictive conditions previously attached to its acquisition of Mellanox Technologies Ltd. Based on the above circumstances, the regulatory authorities have decided to conduct a further investigation into NVIDIA in accordance with the law.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天下午，国家市场监管总局近日发布公告称，经初步调查，英伟达公司违反《中华人民共和国反垄断法》及此前针对其收购迈络思科技有限公司股权案所附加的限制性条件。基于上述情况，监管部门已依法决定对英伟达实施进一步调查。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The announcement pointed out that this investigation will focus on NVIDIA's compliance in fulfilling the attached conditions, with a key review of its conduct in market competition order, technological cooperation, and supply chain fairness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公告指出，此次调查将围绕英伟达在履行附加条件过程中的合规性展开，重点审查其在市场竞争秩序、技术合作及供应链公平性等方面的行为。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that NVIDIA holds over 90% of the global market share in GPU accelerators, while Mellanox has nearly 70% in InfiniBand network interconnect devices. After deep integration, the two have formed a highly closed ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，英伟达在 GPU 加速器市场的全球份额高达 90% 以上，而迈络思在 InfiniBand 网络互联设备领域的占有率接近 70%，二者深度整合后形成了高度封闭的生态体系。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>中美就妥善解决 TikTok 问题达成基本框架共识</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">中美就妥善解决-TikTok-问题达成基本框架共识</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;SJFPIbU&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8008765f.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637856&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 3240px) 100vw, 3240px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8008765f.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8008765f.jpeg 3240w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8008765f-360x240.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8008765f-768x512.jpeg 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8008765f-1024x683.jpeg 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV News, last night, Li Chenggang, China's International Trade Negotiator and Vice Minister of Commerce, stated in Madrid, Spain, that China and the United States have reached a basic framework consensus on properly resolving the TikTok issue through cooperation, reducing investment barriers, and promoting economic and trade cooperation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视新闻报道，昨晚，中国商务部国际贸易谈判代表兼副部长李成钢在西班牙马德里表示，中美双方就以合作方式妥善解决 TikTok 问题、减少投资障碍、促进经贸合作等，达成了基本框架共识。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Chenggang introduced that from September 14th to 15th, Chinese and US economic and trade teams held talks in Madrid. Based on mutual respect and equal consultation, the two sides conducted candid, in-depth, and constructive communication on economic and trade issues including TikTok.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            李成钢介绍，9 月 14 日至 15 日，中美经贸团队在马德里举行会谈，双方在相互尊重、平等协商的基础上，就 TikTok 等经贸议题进行了坦诚、深入、建设性的沟通。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the TikTok issue, Li Chenggang emphasized that China opposes the politicization, instrumentalization, and weaponization of technology and economic and trade issues, firmly safeguards national interests and the legitimate rights and interests of Chinese enterprises, and conducts technology export approvals in accordance with laws and regulations. The Chinese government respects corporate will and supports equal commercial negotiations based on market principles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对 TikTok 问题，李成钢强调，中国反对将科技和经贸问题政治化、工具化、武器化，坚决维护国家利益和中资企业合法权益，并依法依规开展技术出口审批。中国政府尊重企业意愿，支持在市场原则基础上开展平等商业谈判。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Jingtao, Deputy Director of the Cyberspace Administration of China, revealed that both sides have reached a consensus on resolving the TikTok issue through methods such as entrusted operation of US user data and content security services, and authorization of algorithm and intellectual property usage rights. The Chinese side will review and approve relevant technology exports and authorizations in accordance with the law.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国国家互联网信息办公室副主任王京涛透露，双方已就通过美国用户数据与内容安全业务委托运营、算法及知识产权使用权授权等方式解决 TikTok 问题达成共识。中方将依法审批相关技术出口与授权事宜。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Chenggang pointed out that the achievements of the China-US economic and trade talks were hard-won, and the US should not demand that China accommodate its concerns while continuously suppressing Chinese enterprises. China urges the US to lift restrictive measures as soon as possible, meet China halfway, and promote the stable, healthy, and sustainable development of bilateral economic and trade relations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            李成钢指出，中美经贸会谈成果来之不易，美方不应一边要求中方照顾其关切，一边持续打压中国企业。中方敦促美方尽快取消限制措施，与中方相向而行，推动双边经贸关系稳定、健康、可持续发展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>第五代骁龙 8 至尊版公布</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">第五代骁龙-8-至尊版公布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;pHtsaCx&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8064a5a0.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637857&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8064a5a0.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8064a5a0.png 1080w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8064a5a0-360x240.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8064a5a0-768x512.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8064a5a0-1024x683.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Qualcomm announced on its official WeChat public account &quot;Qualcomm China&quot; that its flagship mobile platform family will welcome a new member – the 5th generation Snapdragon 8 Extreme Edition, which will be officially released at the upcoming 2025 Snapdragon Summit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，高通在其官方微信公众号「高通中国」发布推文，宣布其旗舰移动平台家族将迎来全新成员 —— 第五代骁龙 8 至尊版，并将在即将到来的 2025 骁龙峰会上正式发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official statement indicates that the 5th generation Snapdragon 8 Extreme Edition continues the single-digit generational naming system, representing the fifth-generation product of the Snapdragon 8 series flagship platform, aiming to strengthen its industry-leading position and simplify consumers' understanding of the product roadmap.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方表示，第五代骁龙 8 至尊版延续了单数字代际命名体系，代表骁龙 8 系旗舰平台的第五代产品，旨在强化其行业领先地位并简化消费者对产品路线图的理解。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The &quot;Extreme Edition&quot; naming is exclusive to our most industry-leading products, platforms that continuously push boundaries in terms of features, experience, and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, last year's Snapdragon 8 Extreme Edition first introduced the self-developed Qualcomm Oryon CPU architecture, bringing significant performance and power efficiency improvements. This year's new generation product will further optimize on this basis, continuing to define new standards for flagship performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，去年推出的骁龙 8 至尊版首次引入自研 Qualcomm Oryon CPU 架构，带来了显著的性能与能效提升。今年的新一代产品将在此基础上进一步优化，继续定义旗舰性能新标准。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Qualcomm also revealed that other mobile platforms released in the future will adopt the same &quot;fifth-generation&quot; generational naming to maintain product line consistency and facilitate clearer understanding of positioning and upgrade scope for consumers and OEM manufacturers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高通还透露，未来发布的其他移动平台也将采用相同的「第五代」代际命名，以保持产品线的一致性，方便消费者与 OEM 厂商更清晰地理解定位与升级幅度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>大疆官宣将于 17 日召开发布会</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">大疆官宣将于-17-日召开发布会</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;aiLpBEj&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b80f3d592.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637858&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 902px) 100vw, 902px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b80f3d592.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b80f3d592.png 902w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b80f3d592-360x600.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b80f3d592-768x1280.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b80f3d592-615x1024.png 615w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            DJI announced last night through official channels that it will hold a new product launch event on September 17th at 20:00, with the theme &quot;Small but Confident,&quot; possibly officially launching the DJI Mini 5 Pro drone.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            大疆昨晚通过官方渠道宣布，将于 9 月 17 日 20:00 举办新品发布会，主题为「小有底气」，或将正式推出 DJI Mini 5 Pro 无人机。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p id=&quot;SCOAvtG&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8180ba2f.gif&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637859&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 426px) 100vw, 426px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8180ba2f.gif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8180ba2f.gif 426w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8180ba2f-360x203.gif 360w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to previously leaked information and official teaser posters, the DJI Mini 5 Pro will weigh less than 250 grams, feature a 1-inch CMOS sensor, support lossless vertical shooting and 225° gimbal rotation, record 4K 120fps video, and offer a 48mm telephoto mode (expected to be achieved via digital zoom). The dynamic range is increased to
            &lt;strong&gt;
             14 stops
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , supporting 10-bit D-Log M and HLG color modes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据此前曝光信息及官方预热海报，DJI Mini 5 Pro 机身重量将低于 250 克，配备 1 英寸 CMOS 传感器，支持无损竖拍与 225° 云台旋转，可拍摄 4K 120 帧视频，并提供 48mm 长焦模式（预计通过数码变焦实现）。动态范围提升至
            &lt;strong&gt;
             14 档
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，支持 10-bit D-Log M 与 HLG 色彩模式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The drone also features a LiDAR laser sensor, supporting &quot;night-level omnidirectional active obstacle avoidance,&quot; capable of tracking objects at up to 15 meters/second, suitable for intelligent follow-shot in various scenarios like running and cycling. In terms of battery life, the standard battery allows for 36 minutes of flight, while the long-endurance battery can reach 52 minutes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该机还搭载 LiDAR 激光传感器，支持「夜景级全向主动避障」，最高可 15 米 / 秒追踪物体，适用于跑步、骑行等多场景智能跟拍。续航方面，标准电池可飞行 36 分钟，长续航电池可达 52 分钟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the first DJI drone to support OcuSync 4 Plus image transmission technology, its image transmission range can reach 20 kilometers in the US (FCC) environment, providing more stable signal assurance for beyond-visual-line-of-sight aerial photography.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            作为首款支持 OcuSync 4 Plus 图传技术的大疆无人机，其在美国（FCC）环境下图传距离可达 20 公里，为超视距航拍提供更稳定的信号保障。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to leaked product pages, the DJI Mini 5 Pro will offer three bundle versions:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据泄露的商品页面，DJI Mini 5 Pro 将提供三种套装版本：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard Edition (RC-N3 Remote Controller) : Priced at 819 Euros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fly More Combo (RC-N3 Remote Controller) : Priced at 1029 Euros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fly More Combo (DJI RC2 Remote Controller) : Priced at 1159 Euros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of appearance, the new drone continues the lightweight design, weighing less than 250 grams and equipped with a C0 label, meaning it can enjoy more relaxed flight restrictions in the EU market. Functionally, the DJI Mini 5 Pro will support OcuSync 4.0 image transmission technology and be compatible with the DJI RC2 remote controller, with significant improvements expected in signal stability and transmission distance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外观方面，新机延续轻量化设计，重量低于 250 克，并配备 C0 标签，意味着在欧盟市场可享受更宽松的飞行限制。功能上，DJI Mini 5 Pro 将支持 OcuSync 4.0 图传技术，并兼容 DJI RC2 遥控器，预计在信号稳定性与传输距离上有显著提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, earlier packaging and actual machine leaks show that this drone will be equipped with a 1-inch sensor and LiDAR, possessing stronger obstacle avoidance capabilities and imaging performance. Users in India have already unboxed and completed their first test flight, further confirming the appearance and some functional details.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，早前的包装与实机泄露显示，该机将搭载 1 英寸传感器与 LiDAR 激光雷达，具备更强的避障能力与影像表现。印度地区已有用户抢先开箱并完成首次试飞，进一步印证了外观与部分功能细节。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>星链出现短暂服务中断</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">星链出现短暂服务中断</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;bHbSuEP&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b81cc11a2.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637860&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2126px) 100vw, 2126px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b81cc11a2.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b81cc11a2.png 2126w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b81cc11a2-360x264.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b81cc11a2-768x564.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b81cc11a2-1024x752.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reuters reported that according to data from the outage tracking platform Downdetector, Elon Musk's satellite internet service Starlink has returned to normal in most areas after a brief outage on Monday.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            路透社报道，据故障追踪平台 Downdetector 数据显示，埃隆·马斯克旗下的卫星互联网服务星链（Starlink）在本周一出现短暂中断后，已于大部分地区恢复正常。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Data shows that connection issues reported by US users dropped to below 1,000 people at 1:15 AM ET (1:15 PM Beijing time on September 15), a significant decrease from the peak of over 43,000 people.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            数据显示，美国用户报告的连接问题在美东时间凌晨 1 点 15 分（北京时间 9 月 15 日 13 点 15 分）已降至 1,000 人以下，较高峰期的逾 43,000 人大幅回落。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starlink's official website initially posted a notice stating: &quot;Starlink is currently experiencing a service outage, and our team is investigating,&quot; but did not disclose the specific reason. The notice was subsequently removed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星链官网在故障初期曾发布提示称：「星链当前正经历服务中断，我们的团队正在调查」，但并未透露具体原因，该提示随后被移除。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starlink is operated by SpaceX, founded by Elon Musk, providing internet access services to users worldwide through a constellation of low-Earth orbit satellites, especially widely used in remote and conflict-affected areas. SpaceX has not yet provided further comment on this incident.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星链由 Elon Musk 创立的 SpaceX 运营，通过低轨道卫星星座为全球用户提供互联网接入服务，尤其在偏远和战乱地区被广泛使用。SpaceX 暂未就此次事件作出进一步回应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>宇树科技发布开源世界模型-动作架构</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">宇树科技发布开源世界模型-动作架构</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;gLhBcaN&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b830525ac.gif&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637861&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b830525ac.gif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b830525ac.gif 800w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b830525ac-360x284.gif 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b830525ac-768x606.gif 768w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Unitree Robotics officially launched the open-source World Model-Action (WMA) architecture across multiple robot body types —
            &lt;strong&gt;
             UnifoLM-WMA-0
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            . This architecture aims to provide a unified technical foundation for general robot learning, with its core being a world model capable of understanding the physical laws of robot-environment interaction.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            宇树科技正式推出跨多类机器人本体的开源世界模型-动作（WMA）架构 ——
            &lt;strong&gt;
             UnifoLM-WMA-0
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。该架构旨在为通用机器人学习提供统一的技术基础，核心在于一个能够理解机器人与环境交互物理规律的世界模型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This world model has two core functions:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该世界模型具备两大核心功能：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simulation Engine: Operates as an interactive simulator, generating synthetic data for robot learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy Enhancement: Can interface with action heads, optimizing decision-making performance by predicting future interactions with the physical world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The model receives image and text instructions, generating future action videos corresponding to the text instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official introduction, UnifoLM-WMA-0 supports two operating modes:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方介绍，UnifoLM-WMA-0 支持两种运行模式：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision Mode: Provides predictive information on robot-environment physical interactions, assisting in strategy generation of actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simulation Mode: Generates high-fidelity environmental feedback based on robot actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of training, the team completed model training based on 5 Unitree Robotics open-source datasets. Test results show that the model can achieve interactively controllable generation based on &quot;current images&quot; and a certain number of &quot;robot future actions,&quot; and possesses the ability for continuous interactive generation for long-range tasks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在训练方面，团队基于 5 个宇树科技开源数据集完成模型训练，测试结果显示，该模型可根据「当前图像」及一定数量的「机器人未来动作」实现交互可控生成，并具备长程任务的持续交互生成能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 推出新编程模型</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-推出新编程模型</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;WiqNwIL&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8448b4d9.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637862&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8448b4d9.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8448b4d9.png 3840w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8448b4d9-360x203.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8448b4d9-768x432.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8448b4d9-1024x576.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI announced the launch of the newly upgraded GPT‑5‑Codex, a version specifically optimized for software engineering based on GPT‑5, aimed at enhancing real-time collaboration and the ability to independently complete complex tasks. Officially, this version shows significant improvements in scenarios such as code review, feature development, and large-scale refactoring, &quot;capable of working continuously and independently for over 7 hours in tests.&quot; Here are the main highlights of this upgrade:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 宣布推出全新升级的 GPT‑5‑Codex，这是在 GPT‑5 基础上专为软件工程优化的版本，旨在提升实时协作与独立完成复杂任务的能力。官方表示，该版本在代码审查、功能开发、大规模重构等场景中表现显著提升，「在测试中可连续独立工作超过 7 小时」。以下是本次升级的主要亮点：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comprehensive Tool Upgrade: Codex CLI has been completely redesigned, IDE plugins support mainstream environments like VS Code, and deep integration with GitHub allows seamless switching between cloud and local environments;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enhanced code review capabilities: Automatically detect critical vulnerabilities in PRs, reduce invalid comments, and directly propose and implement modification suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, GPT‑5‑Codex has become the default model for Codex cloud tasks and code reviews, and developers can also use it locally via the Codex CLI or IDE plugin. Compared to the general version of GPT‑5, the new version's accuracy in code refactoring tasks has increased from 33.9% to 51.3%, and the proportion of high-impact review comments has also risen from 39.4% to 52.4%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，GPT‑5‑Codex 已成为 Codex 云端任务与代码审查的默认模型，开发者也可通过 Codex CLI 或 IDE 插件在本地使用。与通用版 GPT‑5 相比，新版本在代码重构任务的准确率从 33.9% 提升至 51.3%，高影响力审查评论比例也从 39.4% 提升至 52.4%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the Codex CLI and IDE plugin have been simultaneously upgraded to support directly attaching design materials such as screenshots and wireframes in the terminal, and can automatically set up a running environment and execute dependency installations in the cloud. The official statement claims that through optimizations like caching containers, the median completion time for cloud tasks has been reduced by 90%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，Codex CLI 与 IDE 插件同步升级，支持在终端直接附加截图、线框图等设计资料，并可在云端自动搭建运行环境、执行依赖安装。官方称，通过缓存容器等优化，云端任务完成时间中位数缩短了 90%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Codex has been integrated into ChatGPT Plus, Pro, Business, Edu, and Enterprise plans. Enterprise users can purchase additional quotas as needed, and an API access version will be launched soon.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，Codex 已整合至 ChatGPT Plus、Pro、Business、Edu 与 Enterprise 计划中，企业用户可按需购买额外额度，API 接入版本也将很快上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grok 推出旗下「最快」模型</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Grok-推出旗下「最快」模型</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;lvTTQDD&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b85198e74.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637863&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b85198e74.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b85198e74.jpeg 2000w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b85198e74-360x186.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b85198e74-768x397.jpeg 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b85198e74-1024x529.jpeg 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Elon Musk's xAI company officially released its new model &quot;Grok 4 Fast,&quot; emphasizing an extremely fast response experience. It is currently only available to subscribers. Users can enable this feature in the model selector on the Grok web interface, by turning on the new &quot;Early Access Beta&quot; switch in &quot;Subscription Settings.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，Elon Musk 创立的 xAI 公司正式发布全新模型「Grok 4 Fast」，主打极速响应体验。目前仅限订阅用户可用。用户可在 Grok 网页端的模型选择器中启用该功能，需在「订阅设置」中打开新增的「早期访问测试版」开关方可使用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that &quot;Grok 4 Fast&quot; excels in speed, with user feedback indicating its response speed can be up to 10 times faster than the standard Grok 4. This model undergoes specialized optimization to reduce processing time for complex tasks; for example, when generating robot SVG images, it prioritizes simplified output forms to ensure speed over complexity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，「Grok 4 Fast」在速度方面表现突出，用户反馈其响应速度最高可达标准版 Grok 4 的 10 倍。该模型通过专项优化，减少复杂任务的处理时间，例如在生成机器人 SVG 图像时，会优先采用简化输出形式，以确保速度优先于复杂度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This design is highly appealing to users seeking immediate results, significantly boosting work and creative efficiency. However, in creative or tasks requiring fine-grained processing, &quot;Grok 4 Fast&quot; will make trade-offs in content depth and detail in exchange for faster responses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这一设计对于追求即时结果的用户极具吸引力，可显著提升工作与创作效率。不过，在创意类或需要精细处理的任务中，「Grok 4 Fast」会在内容深度与细节上有所取舍，以换取更快的响应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that &quot;Grok 4 Fast&quot; is not making its debut; it was previously internally tested on the Arena platform under the codename &quot;Sonoma.&quot; Currently, the model is still in the &quot;early access&quot; phase, with potential plans to open it to free users in the future, and it might even replace the older Grok 3 version. Additionally, xAI has added a &quot;Changelog&quot; section to the Grok web interface and plans to adapt &quot;Grok 4 Fast&quot; for mobile applications.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，「Grok 4 Fast」并非首次亮相，早前曾以「Sonoma」为代号在 Arena 平台进行内测。当前，该模型仍处于「早期访问」阶段，未来有望向免费用户开放，甚至可能取代老版本 Grok 3。此外，xAI 还在 Grok 网页端新增了「更新日志」板块，并计划让「Grok 4 Fast」适配移动端应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, xAI has recently undergone significant personnel restructuring. According to Business Insider, the company abruptly laid off at least 500 data annotators responsible for providing training data for Grok last Friday.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，xAI 近期也在人员结构上进行重大调整。据 Business Insider 报道，公司于上周五突然解雇了至少 500 名负责为 Grok 提供训练数据的数据标注员。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Internal emails indicate this is part of a strategic shift for the company, moving from reliance on general AI trainers to a large-scale expansion of its specialized AI mentor team (with plans to expand tenfold). xAI states that this move aims to accelerate investment in specialized training resources to better support the development of next-generation models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            内部邮件显示，这是公司从依赖通用型 AI 训练员转向大规模扩充专业 AI 导师团队（计划扩充 10 倍）的一部分战略转型。xAI 表示，此举旨在加速专业化训练资源的投入，以更好地支持新一代模型的发展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《滚石》母公司就 AI 概览起诉 Google</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《滚石》母公司就-AI-概览起诉-Google</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, Penske Media Corporation (PMC), the parent company of American magazines Rolling Stone and The Hollywood Reporter, has officially filed a lawsuit against Google, alleging that its AI Overviews feature severely impacts website traffic and advertising revenue.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，美国杂志《滚石》与《好莱坞报道》的母公司 Penske Media Corporation（PMC）已正式对 Google 提起诉讼，指控其 AI 概览（AI Overviews）功能严重冲击网站流量与广告收入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            PMC stated that Google's AI summaries displayed at the top of search results give users &quot;almost no reason to click on the original news link,&quot; directly leading to a year-over-year decline of over 1/3 in affiliate link revenue this year. The company claims this behavior is &quot; illegally exploiting the labor of journalists.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            PMC 表示，Google 在搜索结果顶部展示的 AI 摘要，让用户「几乎没有理由点击原始新闻链接」，直接导致今年联盟链接收入同比下滑超过 1/3。该公司称，这种行为是在「非法利用记者的劳动成果」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is noteworthy that PMC is the first major U.S. media company to sue Google over AI Overviews, but it is not the first case. In February this year, online education company Chegg and several independent European publishers also filed similar lawsuits. News/media alliances have even called this feature &quot;the definition of theft&quot; and called for intervention from the U.S. Department of Justice.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，PMC 是首家就 AI 概览起诉 Google 的美国大型媒体公司，但并非首例。今年 2 月，在线教育公司 Chegg 以及欧洲多家独立出版商也曾发起类似诉讼。新闻/媒体联盟更是将该功能称为「盗窃的定义」，并呼吁美国司法部介入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Google spokesperson José Castañeda responded by stating, &quot;With AI Overviews, search functionality is more user-friendly, and usage has significantly increased.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Google 发言人何塞 · 卡斯塔涅达（José Castañeda）则回应称，「通过 AI 概览，搜索功能更加好用，使用率也大大提升」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, with Google previously admitting that &quot;the open internet is rapidly declining&quot; and facing multiple antitrust lawsuits, its defense in this case may become more challenging.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，随着 Google 先前承认「开放互联网正在迅速衰退」并面临多起反垄断诉讼，其在此案中的辩护难度或将加大。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>上汽 MG 悬赏 500 万征集黑公关线索</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">上汽-MG-悬赏-500-万征集黑公关线索</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;JPOupKn&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b857ce395.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637864&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1260px) 100vw, 1260px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b857ce395.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b857ce395.png 1260w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b857ce395-360x238.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b857ce395-768x507.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b857ce395-1024x676.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            SAIC MG announced yesterday that it will publicly solicit clues and evidence regarding alleged malicious rumor-mongering, insults, defamation, and commercial disparagement against the company and its brand, with rewards of up to 5 million RMB.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上汽 MG 昨天宣布，将面向社会公开征集涉嫌针对企业及品牌实施恶意造谣、侮辱、诽谤及商业诋毁等行为的线索与证据，最高奖励可达人民币 500 万元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            SAIC MG stated in the article that this move aims to implement the deployment requirements of the State Council's executive meeting regarding regulating the competitive order of the new energy vehicle industry, respond to the Cyberspace Administration of China's &quot;Qinglang&quot; special action, and maintain a fair competitive market environment and the legitimate rights and interests of users.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上汽 MG 在文中称，此举旨在落实国务院常务会议关于规范新能源汽车产业竞争秩序的部署要求，并响应中央网信办清朗专项行动，维护公平竞争的市场环境与用户合法权益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The scope of this solicitation includes, but is not limited to:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次征集范围包括但不限于：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information regarding self-media accounts, marketing accounts, and MCN agencies suspected of fabricating and spreading false information;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evidence such as chat records, audio/video materials, email correspondence, contract documents, and fund transfer vouchers suspected of malicious defamation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            SAIC MG stated that for any clues and evidence provided that are verified as true by the legal department, legally sourced, and adopted or recognized by judicial authorities, rewards ranging from 10,000 to 5,000,000 yuan will be given based on the importance of the clue, the value of the case, and its role, and it promises to strictly keep the informant's information confidential.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上汽 MG 表示，凡所提供的线索与证据经法务部门核查属实、来源合法，并被司法机关采纳或认定的，将根据线索重要程度、案件价值及作用，给予 1 万元至 500 万元不等的奖励，并承诺严格保密举报人信息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Lei Jun, Chairman and CEO of Xiaomi Group, had previously posted on Weibo regarding &quot;black PR&quot; related topics, stating that &quot;Xiaomi's legal department has collected evidence from hundreds of accounts and initiated dozens of lawsuits this year.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，此前小米集团董事长、CEO 雷军也曾在微博针对「黑公关」相关话题发文，表示「小米法务部今年已取证数百个账号，发起诉讼数十起」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小牛电动创始人或入局新能源特种车赛道</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小牛电动创始人或入局新能源特种车赛道</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reliable sources cited by Blue Whale Technology, Li Yinan, founder of Niu Technologies, former CEO, and founder of NIUTRON, established Changzhou Niujin Technology Co., Ltd. in 2024, officially entering the new energy special vehicle sector.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据蓝鲸科技援引可靠信源报道，小牛电动创始人、前 CEO 及自游家创始人李一男已于 2024 年创立常州扭劲科技有限公司，正式入局新能源特种车赛道。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Information shows that Changzhou Niujin Technology is associated with Jiangsu Niujin Technology Co., Ltd., which focuses on the R&amp;amp;D, production, and sales of new energy special vehicles. Its three models, GT and NVMM, have already rolled off the production line in Jintan Hua Luogeng High-tech Zone.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            资料显示，常州扭劲科技与江苏扭劲科技有限公司存在关联，后者专注于新能源特种车的研发、生产与销售，旗下 GT、NVMM 三款车型已在金坛华罗庚高新区下线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Li Yinan joined Huawei in 1993 and quickly rose to vice president, leading core product R&amp;amp;D and contributing to the company's rise. In 2000, he founded Harbor Networks, which was later acquired by Huawei, and he returned. After leaving Huawei in 2008, he served as Baidu CTO, among other positions. In 2015, he founded Niu Technologies. In 2016, he was sentenced for insider trading, and he resigned after being released from prison in 2017.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，李一男曾于 1993 年加入华为并迅速晋升至副总裁，主持核心产品研发助力公司崛起。2000 年创办港湾网络，后被华为收购并回归。2008 年离开华为后，历任百度 CTO 等职。2015 年创办小牛电动，2016 年因内幕交易获刑，2017 年出狱后辞任。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In 2021, he started another venture, founding Niu Innovation Energy Technology Co., Ltd., and launched the new energy vehicle brand &quot;NIUTRON&quot; (Chinese name &quot;Ziyoujia&quot;). However, in 2023, due to partner debt issues, the models were not delivered, and the official APP was discontinued.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2021 年，他再次创业，创立牛创新能源科技有限公司，推出新能源汽车品牌「NIUTRON」（中文名「自游家」），但 2023 年因合作方债务问题导致车型未交付且官方 APP 停服。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 OpenAI 董事长：「AI 泡沫」是良性循环</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-OpenAI-董事长：「AI-泡沫」是良性循环</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, Bret Taylor, OpenAI Chairman and Sierra CEO, recently stated at an event in San Francisco that the current &quot;AI bubble&quot; bears striking similarities to the internet boom of the late last century.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，OpenAI 董事长兼 Sierra CEO 布雷特・泰勒（Bret Taylor）近日在旧金山的一场活动中直言，当前的「AI 泡沫」与上世纪末的互联网繁荣有着惊人的相似之处。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He believes that this bubble is not entirely negative; instead, it could become a &quot;virtuous cycle&quot; driving technological and economic development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他认为，这种泡沫并非全然负面，反而可能成为推动技术与经济发展的「良性循环」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Taylor pointed out that while the dot-com bubble saw failures like Pets.com and Webvan, it also fostered long-term winners such as Amazon and Google.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            泰勒指出，互联网泡沫时期虽然出现了 Pets.com、Webvan 等失败案例，但也孕育了亚马逊、Google 等长期赢家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that modern AI technologies, such as large language models, have demonstrated disruptive potential in areas like software engineering and customer service, capable of transforming scarce highly skilled resources into more widespread productivity, thereby unleashing immense economic value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，大型语言模型等现代 AI 技术已在软件工程、客户服务等领域展现出颠覆性潜力，能够将稀缺的高技能资源转化为更普及的生产力，从而释放巨大的经济价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;I believe we are both in a bubble and witnessing a technological revolution that will reshape the global economy. These two things can be true simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Taylor also cautioned that the investment enthusiasm in the AI industry inevitably comes with risks, and some companies and capital will face losses, but infrastructure and technological achievements, like the fiber optic networks of the internet era, will ultimately be utilized by later winners.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            泰勒同时提醒，AI 行业的投资热情必然伴随风险，部分企业和资本将面临损失，但基础设施和技术成果会像互联网时代的光纤网络一样，最终被后来的赢家所利用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPPO Find X9 Pro 将配备 2 亿长焦</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OPPO-Find-X9-Pro-将配备-2-亿长焦</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;zXPyIHy&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b864ee573.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637865&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b864ee573.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b864ee573.jpeg 1080w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b864ee573-360x480.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b864ee573-768x1024.jpeg 768w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Pete Lau, Senior Vice President and Chief Product Officer of OPPO, posted on social media to preview the upcoming Find X9 series, attaching a 200-megapixel sample photo taken directly with the Find X9 Pro, inviting users to zoom in and view the details.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，OPPO 高级副总裁、首席产品官刘作虎在社交平台发文预热即将发布的 Find X9 系列，并附上了用 Find X9 Pro 直出的 2 亿像素样张，邀请用户放大查看细节。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Pete Lau defined the Find X9 series as a complete &quot;image quality revolution.&quot; He stated that an increase in pixel count is not the only key to the imaging experience; &quot;what truly moves us has never been pixels, but image quality.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            刘作虎将 Find X9 系列定义为一次彻底的「画质革命」。他表示，像素数量的提升并非影像体验的唯一关键，「真正触动你我的，从来都不是像素，而是画质」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of color, the Find X9 series is the first to fully adopt the upgraded Ultra-level Danxia lens, aiming to truly restore the blue of the sky, the softness of skin, and the warmth of the sunset. Pete Lau stated that this generation of products is a masterpiece of cooperation with Hasselblad, and some colleagues even nicknamed it &quot;Hasselblad Image Quality King.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在色彩方面，Find X9 系列首次全系普及升级版 Ultra 级丹霞镜头，旨在真实还原天空的蓝、肌肤的柔与夕阳的暖。刘作虎称，这一代产品是与哈苏合作的集大成之作，内部甚至有同事为其起了昵称 ——「哈苏画质王」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new phone will also upgrade Master Mode and reborn XPAN Mode, and launch a Hasselblad professional photography kit, emphasizing the imaging philosophy of &quot;great for portraits,&quot; allowing users to &quot;travel without carrying a camera.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新机还将升级大师模式、重生 XPAN 模式，并推出哈苏专业摄影套装，强调「拍人好」的影像理念，让用户「出游不用再背相机」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, according to Zhou Yibao, product manager for the OPPO Find series, the OPPO Find X9 Pro will feature the full-spec LYT-828 main camera and simultaneously introduce the industry's first &quot;Instant Triple Exposure&quot; technology capable of continuous operation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另据 OPPO Find 系列产品负责人周意保消息，OPPO Find X9 Pro 将搭载满血版 LYT-828 主摄，并同步推出行业首个可实现连续运作的「瞬时三曝光」技术。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhou Yibao explained that this &quot;Instant Triple Exposure&quot; technology not only inherits the high real-time performance unique to DCG-HDR technology but also achieves extreme dynamic range performance through the fusion of long and short frames. This means that the full-link HDR experience, from preview and live display to final imaging, has been significantly improved, and the ability for shadowless capture has also entered a new stage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            周意保介绍，这套「瞬时三曝光」技术，不仅延续了 DCG-HDR 技术特有的高实时性，更通过长短帧融合，实现了极致的动态范围表现。意味着从预览、实况显示到最终成像，全链路 HDR 体验都获得显著提升，无影抓拍的能力也迈进新阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the release date, the OPPO Find X9 series will be unveiled in October.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            发布日期方面，OPPO Find X9 系列将在 10 月亮相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the same day, Chen Xi, Design Director of ColorOS, also announced several user feedback issues for ColorOS 16:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同日，ColorOS 设计总监陈希还公布了 ColorOS 16 的多项用户反馈问题：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White bar immersion: We have been trying our best to promote third-party adaptation, and currently, immersive adaptation has been implemented on some pages such as Weibo full-screen preview interface, Douyin settings page, and Douyin nearby group buying page;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduced OPPO Serif font, and made the unified font adaptation more comprehensive;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Push Notifications: Collaborated with multiple third-party apps to optimize issues such as &quot;weak reminders, delays, and loss,&quot; and developed a new &quot;smart detection&quot; feature — if an application is found to be unable to receive messages due to certain issues, the system will automatically &quot;wake it up.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2999 元起，魅族 22 正式发布</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2999-元起，魅族-22-正式发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;mlfxuYP&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b86b5d7d9.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637866&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 690px) 100vw, 690px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b86b5d7d9.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b86b5d7d9.png 690w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b86b5d7d9-360x480.png 360w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday afternoon, Meizu held a flagship new product and Flyme AIOS ecosystem launch event in Zhuhai, introducing the all-new Meizu 22 series smartphones.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天下午，魅族在珠海召开旗舰新品暨 Flyme AIOS 生态发布会，推出了全新魅族 22 系列手机。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the main selling points, the new phone is equipped with the fourth-generation Snapdragon 8s processor, offering various storage combinations and color options, including white, pink, and black. It weighs 190 grams, is 8.15mm thick, features a 1.2mm four-equal-bezel design and a 2.5D micro-arc flat screen, and is equipped with an independent AI button that can launch 20+ quick functions with one click.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            主要卖点方面，新机搭载第四代骁龙 8s 处理器，提供多种存储组合及配色选择，包括白、粉、黑三色，重量 190 克，厚度 8.15mm，采用 1.2mm 四等边设计与 2.5D 微弧直屏，配备独立 AI 按键，可一键启动 20+ 快捷功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of display, the Meizu 22 features a 6.3-inch 1.5K resolution flat screen, with the white version sporting a four-equal-bezel &quot;monologue&quot; frame. It supports 1 – 120Hz adaptive refresh rate, AOD all-day off-screen display, a global peak brightness of 1800 nits, local peak brightness of 6000 nits, covers 100% DCI-P3 color gamut, and includes &quot;Ruran Eye Protection Technology.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            屏幕方面，魅族 22 配备 6.3 英寸 1.5K 分辨率直屏，白色版搭载四等边「独白」边框，支持 1 – 120Hz 自适应刷新率、AOD 全天候熄屏显示，全局激发亮度 1800 尼特、局部峰值亮度 6000 尼特，覆盖 100% DCI-P3 色域，并内置「如然护眼技术」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The imaging system consists of four 50-megapixel lenses, including an OV50H wide-angle main camera, a SONY IMX882 3x periscope telephoto lens, an OV50D ultra-wide-angle lens, and an OV50D front-facing selfie camera. It supports OIS optical image stabilization, telephoto macro, wide-angle macro, and back-lit HDR selfies, among other features.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影像系统由四颗 5000 万像素镜头组成，包括 OV50H 广角主摄、SONY IMX882 3 倍潜望长焦、OV50D 超广角及 OV50D 前置自拍镜头，支持 OIS 光学防抖、长焦微距、广角微距及逆光 HDR 自拍等功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of battery life and heat dissipation, the new phone features a built-in 5500 mAh battery, supports 80W wired and 66W wireless fast charging, and is equipped with a 4500mm² VC liquid cooling system. The system runs Flyme AIOS 2, supporting features like AI drawing, AI filters, one-click passerby removal, and includes built-in Flyme Auto 2 car-machine interconnection.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            续航与散热方面，新机内置 5500 毫安时电池，支持 80W 有线与 66W 无线快充，配备 4500mm² VC 液冷系统。系统运行 Flyme AIOS 2，支持 AI 妙绘、AI 滤镜、一键路人消除等功能，并内置 Flyme Auto 2 车机互联。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the Meizu 22 features IP66 + IP68 dust and water resistance certification, mEngine super-sensing X-axis linear motor, and other configurations.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             It should be noted that USB 3.2, DP 1.2 Alt output, and
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             UWB
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             features are only available on the top-tier 16 + 1TB configuration.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，魅族 22 具备 IP66 + IP68 防尘防水认证、mEngine 超感 X 轴线性马达等配置。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             需要注意的是，USB 3.2、DP 1.2 Alt 输出和
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             UWB
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             特性仅在 16 + 1TB 的顶配上提供。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of pricing, the Meizu 22 starts at
            &lt;strong&gt;
             2999 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            for the 12GB+256GB configuration; a &quot;Return to Port - China Flagship Limited Edition&quot; is also available, featuring a customized UI, back cover design, and fleet-themed accessories, priced at
            &lt;strong&gt;
             4199 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，魅族 22 起售价为
            &lt;strong&gt;
             2999 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，配置为 12GB+256GB 起；另外还提供 归航・中华旗舰限定版，拥有定制 UI、背盖设计及舰队主题配件，售价
            &lt;strong&gt;
             4199 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            New products such as the Meizu AI shooting glasses StarVSnap (priced at 1999 yuan) and PANDAER tech-fashion items were also released at this launch event.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次发布会上还发布了魅族 AI 拍摄眼镜 StarVSnap（售价 1999 元）和 PANDAER 科技潮品等新品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth mentioning that Meizu officially stated after the new phone went on sale: it sold out within 5 minutes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，魅族官方在新机开售后表示：5 分钟陆续售罄。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vivo X300 Pro 将采用三焦段变焦闪光灯</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">vivo-X300-Pro-将采用三焦段变焦闪光灯</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Vivo product manager Han Boxiao revealed yesterday on Weibo that the vivo X300 Pro will undergo a major upgrade in its imaging system, featuring a &quot;triple-focal-length zoom flash&quot; for the first time, covering the three classic focal lengths of 24mm, 50mm, and 85mm.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            vivo 产品经理韩伯啸昨日在微博透露，vivo X300 Pro 将在影像系统上迎来重大升级，首次配备「三焦段变焦闪光灯」，覆盖 24mm、50mm 和 85mm 三大经典焦段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, the 85mm focal length brightness is increased by 60% compared to its predecessor, and it pioneers &quot;bokeh fusion technology&quot; to achieve uniform fill light for the 50mm focal length, claiming to keep night portraits clear and natural across different focal lengths.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，85mm 焦段亮度相比前代提升 60%，并首创「光斑融合技术」，实现 50mm 焦段的均匀补光，宣称能让夜景人像在不同焦段下都能保持清晰自然。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, vivo previously debuted the &quot;zoom flash&quot; and &quot;flash portrait&quot; features on the X200 Ultra, which, combined with its self-developed BluePrint imaging chip VS1 and algorithms, achieved DSLR-comparable night portrait effects, becoming one of the most popular features after users purchased the device.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，vivo 此前在 X200 Ultra 上首发「变焦闪光灯」与「闪光人像」功能，结合自研蓝图影像芯片 VS1 及算法，实现了媲美单反的夜景人像效果，成为用户购机后最受欢迎的功能之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This upgrade to the X300 Pro extends this technology to three focal lengths and simultaneously brings it to all models in the X300 series. The standard X300 version will also feature a dual-focal-length zoom flash.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次 X300 Pro 的升级，将这一技术扩展至三焦段，并同步下放至 X300 系列全系机型，X300 标准版也将搭载双焦段变焦闪光灯。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Han Boxiao stated that the X300 series continues the Pro-level design philosophy, with hardware and software &quot;fully optimized,&quot; aiming to bring users a more professional night flash portrait experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            韩伯啸表示，X300 系列延续 Pro 级设计思路，硬件与软件「全面拉满」，旨在为用户带来更专业的夜景闪光人像体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TCL 发布全球首款 SQD-Mini LED 电视</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">TCL-发布全球首款-SQD-Mini-LED-电视</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;cCFUnhy&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87a33ffd.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637867&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 792px) 100vw, 792px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87a33ffd.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87a33ffd.jpeg 792w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87a33ffd-360x126.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87a33ffd-768x270.jpeg 768w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 15, TCL officially launched the X11L, the world's first flagship TV equipped with SQD-Mini LED technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 15 日，TCL 正式推出全球首款搭载 SQD-Mini LED 技术的旗舰电视 X11L。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that TCL's newly launched SQD-Mini LED technology breaks the decade-long bottleneck of RGB-Mini LED in color gamut, achieving 100% BT.2020 global high color gamut, and comprehensively surpasses OLED and traditional Mini LED in brightness, light control, lifespan, and picture quality performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，TCL 本次推出的 SQD-Mini LED 技术打破了 RGB-Mini LED 在色域上的十年瓶颈，实现了 100% BT.2020 全局高色域，在亮度、控光、寿命和画质表现上全面超越 OLED 与传统 Mini LED。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official introduction, SQD-Mini LED is based on two core technologies: &quot;Super Butterfly Wing Huayao Screen&quot; and &quot;Super Quantum Dot.&quot; It can maintain stable high color gamut performance in any picture and effectively avoid color crosstalk issues. Compared to RGB-Mini LED, a single light-emitting chip can emit white light, providing more dimming zones and higher brightness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方介绍，SQD-Mini LED 基于「超级蝶翼华曜屏」与「超级量子点」两大核心技术，能够在任何画面下保持稳定的高色域表现，并有效避免串色问题。相比 RGB-Mini LED，单颗发光芯片即可发出白光，带来更多分区与更高亮度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The main highlights of the X11L, which uses this technology, include:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而打在该技术的 X11L 主要亮点包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Super Quantum Dot and Super Butterfly Wing Huayao Screen, a 20000+ full-scene local dimming system, with a peak brightness of up to 10000 nits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a thickness of only about 2 cm, its minimalist appearance blends with Chris Lefteri's design aesthetics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep collaboration with Bang &amp;amp; Olufsen to create a cinematic original sound experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New generation TSR AI light and color co-control chip + Fuxi AI large model, intelligent control experience further upgraded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of appearance, the TCL X11L was created with the participation of CMF design master Chris Lefteri, emphasizing the concept of &quot;humanized technology,&quot; supporting both stand-mounted and seamless wall-mounted installations, balancing artistic appeal with practicality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外观方面，TCL X11L 由 CMF 设计大师 Chris Lefteri 参与打造，强调「人性化科技」理念，支持座装与无缝贴墙挂装，兼顾艺术感与实用性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing, the TCL X11L is available in three versions: 98-inch, 85-inch, and 75-inch, with retail prices of 59999 yuan, 34999 yuan, and 19999 yuan, respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，TCL X11L 提供 98 吋、85 吋与 75 吋三种版本，零售价分别为 59999 元、34999 元和 19999 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小鹏 X9 增程版将在 10 月亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小鹏-X9-增程版将在-10-月亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;spbTtyH&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87f260d0.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637868&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 690px) 100vw, 690px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87f260d0.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87f260d0.jpeg 690w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87f260d0-360x640.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b87f260d0-576x1024.jpeg 576w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He Xiaopeng, CEO and Chairman of Xpeng Motors, revealed yesterday on social media that its Xpeng X9 Super Range-Extended version, the world's longest-range new energy seven-seater SUV, will be officially released next month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小鹏汽车 CEO、董事长何小鹏昨日在社交平台透露，旗下全球续航最长新能源大七座 SUV —— 小鹏 X9 超级增程版，将在下个月正式发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, the vehicle has an R&amp;amp;D cycle of 800 days, involved over 1000 test cars, traversed 330 cities in 20 countries, accumulated over 20 million kilometers in test mileage, and underwent various complex environmental tests including extreme cold, high temperatures, and plateaus, all to ensure that every kilometer of its range is verifiable.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，该车型研发周期长达 800 天，投入超 1000 台测试车，跨越 20 国 330 城，累计测试里程超过 2000 万公里，经历极寒、高温、高原等多种复杂环境考验，旨在确保每一公里续航都经得起验证。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He Xiaopeng stated that he hopes the long-range performance of the Xpeng X9 Super Range-Extended version will allow &quot;the warmth of home to extend further down the road.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            何小鹏表示，希望小鹏 X9 超级增程的长续航表现，能让「家的温暖延续到更远的路上」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that in the new product announcement of the 398th batch of &quot;Road Motor Vehicle Manufacturers and Products Announcement&quot; released by the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology on August 8, the Xpeng X9 Range-Extended MPV also appeared, with the product name &quot;Plug-in Range-Extended Hybrid Multi-Purpose Passenger Vehicle.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，8 月 8 日工信部发布的第 398 批《道路机动车辆生产企业及产品公告》新产品公示中，小鹏 X9 增程版 MPV 也现身其中，产品名称为「插电式增程混合动力多用途乘用车」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Declaration information shows that the vehicle is 5316mm long, 1988mm wide, 1785mm high, with a wheelbase of 3160mm; it is equipped with CATL's lithium iron phosphate battery, a drive motor with a rated power of 110kW and a peak power of 210kW, and an engine with a maximum net power of 110kW.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            申报信息显示，该车长 5316mm、宽 1988mm、高 1785mm，轴距为 3160mm；搭载中创新航的磷酸铁锂蓄电池，驱动电机额定功率 110kW、峰值功率 210kW，发动机最大净功率同为 110kW。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32.99 万元起，26 款岚图梦想家正式上市</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">32.99-万元起，26-款岚图梦想家正式上市</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;wQVwGCV&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8919cd5c.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637869&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1016px) 100vw, 1016px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8919cd5c.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8919cd5c.jpeg 1016w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8919cd5c-360x203.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8919cd5c-768x432.jpeg 768w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            News on September 15: The 2026 Voyah Dreamer officially launched in Shanghai, introducing two major series, &quot;Kunpeng&quot; and &quot;Qiankun,&quot; with five configurations, and offering both PHEV and EV power modes, with official guide prices ranging from 329,900 to 439,900 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 15 日消息，2026 款岚图梦想家在上海正式上市，推出「鲲鹏」与「乾崑」两大系列、五款配置，并提供 PHEV 与 EV 两种动力模式，官方指导价为 32.99 万-43.99 万元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the new car features an 800V high-voltage architecture, 5C super-charging technology, and a 62.5 kWh large battery, achieving a CLTC pure electric range of 350km, with a 20%-80% charge taking only 12 minutes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，新车搭载 800V 高压架构、5C 超充技术与 62.5 度大电池，CLTC 纯电续航达 350km，20%-80% 充电仅需 12 分钟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The 2026 Voyah Dreamer is not only the world's first MPV equipped with Huawei ADS 4 and HarmonyOS Cockpit 5, but also supports features such as intelligent rear-wheel steering and an AI zero-gravity massage cabin, achieving industry-leading standards in both active and passive safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2026 款岚图梦想家不仅作为全球首款配备华为 ADS 4 与鸿蒙座舱 5 的 MPV，还支持智能后轮转向、AI 零重力按摩舱等配置，并在主动与被动安全方面均达到行业领先水准。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Voyah stated that the 2026 Dreamer will reshape the high-end MPV market landscape with its cross-category technological strength and generational value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            岚图方面表示，2026 款梦想家将以跨品类技术实力与断代价值，重塑高端 MPV 市场格局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>美的回应「用工超时、欠薪」：信息不实</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">美的回应「用工超时、欠薪」：信息不实</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, a netizen recently posted on social media, claiming that their father experienced &quot;working 14 hours a day&quot; and &quot;being owed wages after resignation&quot; while working at a Midea factory, which has attracted widespread attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，近期有网友在社交平台发帖称，其父亲在美的工厂工作期间遭遇「一天工作 14 小时」及「离职后被欠薪」情况，引发广泛关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response to the above situation, Midea stated through reports that the company has completed a comprehensive investigation, and the employment information reported by the poster is untrue. According to Midea:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对上述情况，美的方面通过报道回应称，公司已完成全面核查，发帖人反映的用工信息不属实。据美的消息：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From September 8 to September 11, Mr. Zhang worked as a frontline operator at Hefei Hualing Co., Ltd., with normal work hours and no overtime until 9 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 12, Mr. Zhang voluntarily resigned without any abnormalities. When the company issued wages, multiple transfer failures occurred due to an abnormal bank account. The wages were settled in person on September 13, and there was no intentional wage arrears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Midea stated that the post severely damaged the company's reputation and that they had reported it to the police. During the police investigation, the poster's daughter admitted that statements such as &quot;overtime&quot; and &quot;wage arrears&quot; were inconsistent with the facts, and she had deleted the post and apologized to the factory representative.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            美的方面称，该帖严重损害公司声誉，已报警处理。警方调查中，发帖人之女承认「加班」及「欠薪」等言论与事实不符，已删除帖子并向工厂代表道歉。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PUMA × ROSÉ 联名系列亮相上海外滩</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">PUMA-×-ROSÉ-联名系列亮相上海外滩</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;jhsIVNz&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8998c379.jpeg&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637870&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 2000px) 100vw, 2000px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8998c379.jpeg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8998c379.jpeg 2000w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8998c379-360x180.jpeg 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8998c379-768x384.jpeg 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8998c379-1024x512.jpeg 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, PUMA teamed up with popular Korean star ROSÉ to launch their first complete collaborative collection, opening a limited-time space on the Bund in Shanghai, attracting a large number of fans to visit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，PUMA 携手韩国人气女星 ROSÉ 推出首个完整联名系列，并在上海外滩开设限时空间吸引大批粉丝打卡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the collection includes multiple apparel and footwear items. Among them, the Speedcat OG Premium and Speedcat Ballet shoe models were deeply involved in the design by ROSÉ, incorporating strap details into classic silhouettes, giving the items a &quot;rebellious yet well-behaved&quot; aesthetic. Consumers can freely adjust the strap methods to achieve personalized styling.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，该系列包含多款服饰与鞋履，其中 Speedcat OG Premium 与 Speedcat Ballet 两款鞋型由 ROSÉ 深度参与设计，在经典轮廓中融入绑带细节，赋予单品「乖巧中的叛逆」气质。消费者可自由调整绑带方式，实现个性化造型表达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This time, PUMA not only launched an exclusive &quot;ROSIE&quot; logo but also released accompanying merchandise such as custom shoe boxes, ambassador photocards, and exclusive badges, further strengthening the collaborative identity. After its release, the collection quickly went viral on social media, with &quot;ROSÉ's Aesthetic&quot; becoming a hot topic, driving a new wave of retro sports fashion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            PUMA 此次不仅推出专属「ROSIE」标识，还配套发售定制鞋盒、代言人小卡及专属徽章等周边，进一步强化联名身份。系列发售后迅速在社交媒体刷屏，「ROSÉ 式美学」成为热议话题，带动新一轮复古运动时尚风潮。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to PUMA's Q2 FY2025 financial report, global revenue for the quarter reached 1.942 billion euros after currency adjustments, with direct-to-consumer business growing by 9.2% year-on-year and footwear business growing by 5.1% year-on-year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 PUMA 2025 财年第二季度财报显示，经货币调整后本季度全球营收达 19.42 亿欧元，直营业务同比增长 9.2%，鞋类业务同比增长 5.1%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蒙牛官宣贾玲为品牌代言人</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蒙牛官宣贾玲为品牌代言人</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;bHQXyTC&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8a8144a6.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637871&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1920px) 100vw, 1920px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8a8144a6.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8a8144a6.png 1920w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8a8144a6-360x203.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8a8144a6-768x432.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8a8144a6-1024x576.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Mengniu officially announced actress Jia Ling as its brand ambassador and simultaneously launched the theme short film &quot;Yaoqiang Hao&quot; (Strong-willed).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，蒙牛正式宣布演员贾玲成为品牌代言人，并同步推出主题短片「要强号」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Set against a fast-paced dance track, the short film connects and presents stories of struggle from different eras, showcasing the consistent &quot;strong-willed&quot; spirit of the Chinese people.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            短片以快节奏舞曲为背景，将不同时代的奋斗故事串联呈现，展现了中国人一以贯之的「要强」精神。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the film, Jia Ling, with her authentic and optimistic image, interprets a persistent attitude towards career and life, echoing the brand's long-standing commitment to product quality. Mengniu stated that it will continue to accompany thousands of families with high-quality nutritional products, witnessing and supporting the strong-willed journey of every generation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片中，贾玲以其真实、乐观的形象诠释了对事业与生活的坚持态度，呼应了品牌长期以来对产品品质的坚守。蒙牛方面表示，将继续以高品质营养产品陪伴万千家庭，见证并支持每一代人的要强之路。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2025 艾美奖落幕</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-艾美奖落幕</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;TdXJqkO&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8b1d07a9.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637872&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 900px) 100vw, 900px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8b1d07a9.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8b1d07a9.png 900w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8b1d07a9-360x240.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8b1d07a9-768x512.png 768w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the evening of September 14, the 77th Primetime Emmy Awards concluded at the Peacock Theater in Los Angeles, witnessing highlight moments from many popular series and genuine emotional expressions from actors. This year's awards ceremony not only saw the birth of multiple major award winners but also left behind many unforgettable speeches and stage moments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 14 日晚，第 77 届黄金时段艾美奖在洛杉矶 Peacock 剧院落幕，现场见证了多部热门剧集的高光时刻与演员的真情流露。本届颁奖礼不仅诞生了多项重量级奖项得主，也留下了不少令人难忘的发言与舞台瞬间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At this year's awards ceremony, &quot;Adolescence&quot; and &quot;The Studio&quot; became the focus of attention. The former swept 6 major awards, including Best Limited/Anthology Series, Best Director, and multiple acting awards; the latter, led by Seth Rogen, won 4 comedy awards. Here is a quick overview of this year's Emmy winners:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本届颁奖礼中，《青春迷惘》与《片场风云》成为全场焦点，前者狂揽 6 项大奖，包括最佳限定剧/诗选剧、最佳导演与多项表演奖；后者则由塞斯·罗根领衔斩获 4 项喜剧类大奖。以下是本次艾美奖得主速览：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Outstanding Comedy Series: &quot;The Studio,&quot; starring Seth Rogen, who also won &quot;Outstanding Lead Actor in a Comedy Series&quot;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             最佳喜剧类剧集： 《The Studio》，主演 Seth Rogen 同时获「喜剧类最佳男主角」
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Outstanding Drama Series: &quot;The Pitt,&quot; starring Noah Wyle, who also won &quot;Outstanding Lead Actor in a Drama Series&quot;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             最佳剧情类剧集： 《The Pitt》，主演 Noah Wyle 同时获「剧情类最佳男主角」
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Outstanding Lead Actress in a Drama Series: Britt Lower (&quot;Severance&quot;)
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             剧情类最佳女主角： Britt Lower（《Severance》）
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Outstanding Lead Actress in a Comedy Series: Jean Smart (&quot;Hacks&quot;)
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             喜剧类最佳女主角： Jean Smart（《Hacks》）
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Outstanding Limited or Anthology Series: Netflix's &quot;Adolescence,&quot; which also swept the category for Outstanding Lead Actor (Stephen Graham), Outstanding Supporting Actress (Erin Doherty), and Outstanding Supporting Actor (Owen Cooper)
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             最佳限定/选集类剧集： Netflix《Adolescence》，并包揽该类别最佳男主角（Stephen Graham）、最佳女配角（Erin Doherty）、最佳男配角（Owen Cooper）
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Outstanding Talk Series: &quot;The Late Show with Stephen Colbert&quot;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             最佳脱口秀节目： 《The Late Show with Stephen Colbert》
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The ceremony also had its share of highlights: Scarlett Johansson and her boyfriend appeared on the red carpet, two on-screen mother-daughter duos from &quot;Gilmore Girls&quot; and &quot;Wednesday&quot; shared the stage, the cast of &quot;Law &amp;amp; Order&quot; reunited, and Ted Danson and Mary Steenburgen received the Bob Hope Humanitarian Award.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            典礼现场亦不乏亮点：斯嘉丽·约翰逊与男友亮相红毯，《吉尔莫女孩》《星期三》两对荧幕母女档同台，《法律与秩序》剧组重聚，泰德·丹森与玛丽·斯汀伯根获鲍勃·霍普人道主义奖。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>喜剧电影《浪浪人生》发布新预告</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">喜剧电影《浪浪人生》发布新预告</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;CcnKlTP&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8d37a45a.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637874&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1080px) 100vw, 1080px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8d37a45a.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8d37a45a.png 1080w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8d37a45a-360x575.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8d37a45a-768x1226.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8d37a45a-641x1024.png 641w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the comedy film &quot;Wanderer's Life&quot; released a new trailer titled &quot;This Home is on Fire.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，喜剧电影《浪浪人生》发布新版「这个家燃起来了」预告片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of Huang Rongfa, once the &quot;big brother&quot; who dominated the small town, now soft-spoken and weak-legged, entering a difficult mode of life. However, he and his family are not swept away by the waves of fate; facing adversity, the family can only &quot;go wild&quot; and confront life head-on to turn the tide.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片讲述曾经叱咤小镇的「大哥」黄荣发如今嘴硬腿软，开启人生困难模式，但他和家人都没有被命运的风浪裹挟；逆境当前，一家唯有兴「疯」作浪跟生活贴脸硬刚，才能逆风翻盘的故事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is executive produced by Han Han, directed by Ma Lin, and stars Huang Bo, Fan Chengcheng, Yin Tao, Chang Yuan, Li Jiaqi, Liu Xuehua, Sun Yizhou, and Fu Hang. It will be released nationwide on October 1.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片由韩寒监制，马林执导，黄渤、范丞丞、殷桃、常远、李嘉琦、刘雪华、孙艺洲、付航主演，将于 10 月 1 日全国上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>律政剧《万法公平》公布新预告</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:32:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">律政剧《万法公平》公布新预告</guid>
      <description>&lt;p id=&quot;mtAaFHs&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8da4fb08.png&quot; rel=&quot;lightbox[1637837]&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-1637875&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 3840px) 100vw, 3840px&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8da4fb08.png&quot; srcset=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8da4fb08.png 3840w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8da4fb08-360x203.png 360w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8da4fb08-768x432.png 768w, https://s3.ifanr.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/img_68c8b8da4fb08-1024x576.png 1024w&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The legal drama series &quot;All's Fair,&quot; created by Ryan Murphy, released a new 30-second trailer today. The series focuses on a law firm founded by a group of &quot;sharp-tongued&quot; women and the various cases they take on. The trailer features impactful lines – &quot;He hurt you, be angry, seek revenge.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            由瑞恩·墨菲打造的律政题材剧集《万法公平》今日释出全新 30 秒预告片。该剧聚焦一家由一群「尖刻」女性创办的律师事务所，以及她们接手的各类案件，预告中出现了颇具冲击力的台词 ——「他伤害了你，去愤怒，去复仇」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The cast includes Kim Kardashian, Naomi Watts, Niecy Nash, Tiana Taylor, Sarah Paulson, Glenn Close, Sofia Boutella, and more, making for a star-studded lineup. The series will premiere on Hulu in November this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            演员阵容方面，金 · 卡戴珊、娜奥米 · 沃茨、南希 · 纳什、缇雅娜 · 泰勒、莎拉 · 保罗森、格伦 · 克洛斯、索菲亚 · 布伊等悉数亮相，星光熠熠。该剧将于今年 11 月在 Hulu 平台上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
