<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 18 Pro 预测渲染曝光：单挖孔屏幕</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">iPhone-18-Pro-预测渲染曝光：单挖孔屏幕</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/33e06684-c620-4946-aeb6-01a294f8445e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the well-known tech leak website FrontPageTech (fpt.) released a predictive rendering video of the iPhone 18 Pro,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             showing that the new device may feature under-display Face ID and a punch-hole moved to the upper left corner
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , with significant changes also coming to its imaging system and internal configuration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，知名科技爆料网站 FrontPageTech（fpt.）发布了 iPhone 18 Pro 的预测渲染视频，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             显示新机或将搭载屏下 Face ID、挖孔移到左上角
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，且在影像系统及内部配置上迎来显著变化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            fpt. believes that despite changes in hardware structure, Apple will still retain the &quot;Dynamic Island&quot; interaction, but due to adjustments in under-display components, its display area will become smaller, and its form will also be adjusted, retaining only pure software interaction functions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            fpt. 认为，尽管硬件结构发生改变，苹果仍将保留「灵动岛」交互，但由于屏下组件的调整，其显示区域将变得更小，形态也会有所调整，仅保留纯粹的软件交互功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The imaging system will be at the core of this upgrade. Reports indicate that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the iPhone 18 Pro is expected to feature variable aperture technology.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            This technology can increase light intake in low-light conditions and contract the aperture in bright environments or when shooting close-up objects, adapting to more shooting scenarios and needs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影像系统将是此次升级的核心。报道称，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             iPhone 18 Pro 有望搭载可变光圈技术。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            该技术可在低光环境下增加进光量，并在明亮环境或拍摄近物时收缩光圈，适应更多拍摄场景和需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, sources also point out that this technology was previously tested on the iPhone 17 Pro but was not mass-produced, and it's not ruled out that this feature might be exclusive to the iPhone 18 Pro Max model.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，消息源也指出，该技术此前曾在 iPhone 17 Pro 上进行过测试，但最终未量产，且不排除该功能仅限于 iPhone 18 Pro Max 机型独占的可能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding core hardware specifications, the iPhone 18 Pro will be equipped with the A20 Pro chip, built on a 2nm process, further enhancing energy efficiency and performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            核心硬件规格上，iPhone 18 Pro 将搭载基于 2nm 工艺打造的 A20 Pro 芯片，能效与性能将进一步提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Apple will enable its self-developed C2 chip to replace Qualcomm's baseband. In terms of connectivity, Apple is committed to achieving satellite 5G network support, aiming to allow devices to transmit network data via satellite without completely relying on ground base stations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，苹果将启用自研的 C2 芯片取代高通基带。连接性方面，苹果正致力于实现卫星 5G 网络支持，旨在让设备不完全依赖地面基站，也能通过卫星进行联网数据传输。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, fpt. also mentioned that Apple might change the mechanical structure of &quot;camera control&quot; to pressure-sensitive triggering to reduce manufacturing and maintenance costs. In terms of color, Apple is testing three new colors: Burgundy Red, Brown, and Purple.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，fpt. 还提到苹果或将「相机控制」的机械结构改为压感触发，以降低制造与维修成本。配色方面，苹果正在测试勃艮第红、棕色及紫色三种新配色。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             As for the foldable iPhone making its debut at the same event, fpt. claims its price is extremely high, even comparable to &quot;a used Honda car.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             至于同台登场的折叠屏 iPhone，fpt. 称其售价极为高昂，价格甚至堪比「一辆二手本田」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>追觅 CEO 公开回应「做出百万亿公司」：是未来</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">追觅-CEO-公开回应「做出百万亿公司」：是未来</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4c730d8e-902e-443d-a41f-6b877770a675.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Yu Hao, CEO of Dreame Technology, posted on Weibo, responding to previous remarks on WeChat Moments about a &quot;trillion-dollar company ecosystem.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，追觅科技 CEO 俞浩在微博发文，针对此前朋友圈「百万亿美金的公司生态」言论进行了回应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             He emphasized that the relevant goal is not to be achieved within one year, but rather a long-term vision spanning twenty years.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             他强调，相关目标并非一年内实现，而是一个二十年的长期愿景。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that every approximately 20 years, the highest market capitalization company in human society increases by an order of magnitude, so in the future, there will inevitably be companies with a market capitalization of hundreds of trillions of dollars, &quot;if not us, then others.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，人类社会每隔约 20 年，最高市值公司都会提升一个数量级，因此未来必然会出现市值达到百万亿美元的企业，「不是我们，也会是其他人」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yu Hao said that Dreame's mission is &quot;to use technology to promote the progress of human society and civilization,&quot; and emphasized that the company has maintained this direction since its establishment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            俞浩称，追觅的使命是「用科技推动人类社会与文明的进步」，并强调公司自成立以来始终保持这一方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Yu Hao also pointed out that even if the ultimate goal is not achieved, the process itself will bring positive impacts.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             俞浩还指出，即使最终未能实现最高目标，过程本身也会带来积极影响。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He cited data stating that Dreame has helped over 40,000 children broaden their horizons through public welfare projects. The company currently has nearly 40,000 employees, including over 18,000 R&amp;amp;D and management personnel, and achieved tens of billions of yuan in revenue last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他列举数据称，追觅已帮助超过四万名儿童通过公益项目拓展视野，公司目前拥有近四万名员工，其中研发和管理人员超过 1.8 万人，去年实现了数百亿元收入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that Dreame has achieved technological breakthroughs when entering the high-speed motor field, with products entering major developed markets globally and market shares reaching 40% to 70% in some regions. He also stated that Dreame chose a high-end positioning, with net profits leading the industry, and the company has maintained rapid growth for six consecutive years since its establishment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，追觅在进入高速电机领域时已实现技术突破，产品进入全球主要发达市场，并在部分地区市占率达到 40%～70%。他还表示，追觅选择高端定位，净利润在行业内居首，且公司自成立以来连续六年保持高速增长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In another post yesterday, Yu Hao further revealed that Dreame not only maintains profitability in its main business but also began to lay out an ecosystem fund four years ago to support future development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在昨天的另一则发文中，俞浩进一步透露，追觅不仅保持主业盈利，还在四年前开始布局生态链基金，以支持未来发展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Whatever we do, we will plan long-term, plan early, much further and deeper than everyone imagines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that Dreame obtained its fund license during the capital winter and achieved first place in both fundraising quantity and scale last year. He emphasized that Dreame's ecosystem fund and company profitability form a dual support, which will provide assurance for future synergistic development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，追觅在资本寒冬时期获得基金牌照，并在去年实现募资数量和规模双料第一。他强调，追觅生态基金与公司盈利形成双重支撑，将为未来协同发展提供保障。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阿维塔回应「15 车连撞」事故：辅助驾驶未激活，系驾驶员超速所致</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">阿维塔回应「15-车连撞」事故：辅助驾驶未激活，系驾驶员超速所致</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/cc388110-152f-408d-9698-72419f34a639.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Avatr officially responded to the widely publicized incident of &quot;an Avatr 07 hitting 15 cars in Nanning, Guangxi.&quot; Avatr emphasized that local traffic police have completed the on-site investigation and issued an accident report,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             clearly stating that the cause of the accident was the driver's excessive speed.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，阿维塔官方就近日引发广泛关注的「广西南宁一辆阿维塔 07 连撞 15 辆车」事件发表了回应。阿维塔强调，当地交警已完成现场调查并出具事故认定书，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             明确事故原因为驾驶员超速驾驶所致。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             The post also cited vehicle data, pointing out that before and during the accident, the vehicle was consistently in &quot;NCA_STANDBY&quot; status, meaning the assisted driving function was not activated, and airbags deployed normally after the collision.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             发文还援引车辆数据指出，事故发生前及发生时，车辆始终处于「NCA_STANDBY」状态，即辅助驾驶功能未激活，碰撞后安全气囊正常弹出。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company pointed out that the party involved in the accident confirmed never having accepted media interviews, but after the first public statement on January 13, some media outlets still published unverified false reports such as &quot;driving assistance system out of control&quot; and maliciously edited and spread them, severely damaging the brand's reputation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司指出，事故当事人确认从未接受过媒体采访，但在 1 月 13 日首次公开说明后，仍有部分媒体未经核实发布「驾驶辅助系统失控」等不实报道，并进行恶意剪辑传播，严重损害品牌声誉。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, some mainstream media have voluntarily removed related content. Avatr stated that it will take legal action against future malicious rumors and defamation and reminds car owners to comply with traffic laws and pay attention to driving safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，部分主流媒体已主动下架相关内容。阿维塔表示，将对未来可能出现的恶意造谣和抹黑行为采取法律手段，并提醒车主遵守交通法规，注意行车安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>贾国龙深夜再发声：罗永浩让西贝雪上加霜</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">贾国龙深夜再发声：罗永浩让西贝雪上加霜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the &quot;internet war of words&quot; between Xibei founder Jia Guolong and Luo Yonghao continued:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，西贝创始人贾国龙与罗永浩的「互联网骂战」持续：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jia Guolong claimed he &quot;doesn't understand public relations, can't argue sophistically,&quot; and was &quot;maliciously confused by internet celebrities&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luo Yonghao then posted again regarding the Xibei incident: &quot;I have never seen a company in my life that, without making other mistakes, could go bankrupt simply because it was slandered.&quot; He also mentioned in the article that &quot;frozen broccoli indeed costs more&quot; and emphasized that pre-made dishes are not for restaurant owners to deceive people with meal kits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, on the evening of January 16, both of their Weibo accounts were suspended. Sina Weibo CEO Wang Gaofei (@laiquzhijian) subsequently posted, citing content from the Cyberspace Administration of China's &quot;Negative List of Network Celebrity Account Behaviors&quot; regarding &quot;organizing fights and debates,&quot; implying that the suspension of both accounts was related to such rules.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但在 1 月 16 日当晚，两人的微博账号通通被禁言。新浪微博 CEO 王高飞（@来去之间）随后发文援引网信办《网络名人账号行为负面清单》中「组织约架论战」相关内容，暗示双方账号被禁言与此类规则相关。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After his account was suspended, Jia Guolong used the &quot;Xibei People's Voice&quot; account to publish a response, accusing Luo Yonghao of &quot;maliciously inciting public sentiment,&quot; stating, &quot;During the online violence instigated by Luo Yonghao last year, Xibei restaurant staff across the country were verbally abused, physically assaulted, and forced to kneel dozens of times.&quot; He also expressed willingness to go with Luo to relevant departments to verify whether there were reports to the police or cross-provincial arrests.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在账号被禁言后，贾国龙转由「西贝人心声」账号发布回应内容，指责罗永浩「恶意煽动公共情绪」，「去年罗永浩制造的网暴期间，全国西贝门店服务员被骂被打被逼下跪数十次。」并表示愿意与其共同前往相关部门核查是否存在报警或跨省抓捕等情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1f74bc4d-0339-49e4-af4d-3faca88f6c4c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the evening of the 17th, Jia Guolong posted &quot;Response Two: Prepared Dishes and Why I Spoke Out?&quot; on his WeChat Moments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 17 号晚间，贾国龙在朋友圈发布《回应二：预制菜和我为什么站出来？》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that Xibei had enjoyed 37 years of healthy development, but last year (September 2025), due to controversies surrounding prepared dishes and broccoli, customer traffic plummeted. Jia Guolong also stated that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the company's four months of efforts were in vain, and insults, abuse, and slanders continuously appeared in every corner of the internet.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其指出，西贝 37 年健康发展，但去年（2025 年）9 月因预制菜、西兰花等风波，导致客流断崖式下降。贾国龙还表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             公司拼了四个月都没用，侮辱辱骂诋毁不断出现在互联网各个角落。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jia Guolong stated that he merely replied to a friend's message on WeChat Moments, only to be hit by another &quot;public opinion&quot; tidal wave stirred up by Luo Yonghao. He said:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            贾国龙表示，自己只是在朋友圈回复了朋友的消息，就遭到了罗永浩再次掀起的「舆论」巨浪。他表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;(This) caused me and Xibei employees to suffer countless insults, adding insult to injury for an already beleaguered Xibei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also mentioned, &quot;Whoever helps Xibei gets doxxed and cyberbullied by Luo Yonghao&quot;: Yu Donglai, Yu Minhong, Hua Shan. Whoever speaks well of Xibei, whoever opposes Luo Yonghao, will be attacked by Luo Yonghao and the public relations organization of &quot;Make a Friend&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其还提起「谁帮西贝谁就被罗永浩挂出来网暴」：于东来、俞敏洪、华杉。谁说西贝好、谁反对罗永浩，谁就被罗永浩和交个朋友的公关组织攻击。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1f387739-bc42-4fa7-8415-7e1cdf718567.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a report by Southern Metropolis Daily, on January 17, Luo Yonghao posted on his WeChat Moments, responding to the &quot;spat&quot; with Xibei and Jia Guolong over prepared dishes. He confirmed that he had been suspended by the platform for 15 days,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             and stated that he would &quot;interpret the suspension as protection for me in good faith.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另据《南方都市报》报道，1 月 17 日，罗永浩在朋友圈发文回应了有关同西贝和贾国龙的预制菜「口水战」，其确认被平台禁言了 15 天，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             并表示会将禁言「善意解读成是对我的保护」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Luo Yonghao emphasized in his WeChat Moments post that he would no longer respond to this matter personally. He stated: &quot;I believe that laws and regulations related to the transparency of prepared dishes will also be introduced soon. In the future, if any rumors related to me and this matter become truly outrageous, the company will write a steady and trouble-free public relations draft to clarify them.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，罗永浩在朋友圈内容中强调，其个人不会再回应这件事。他称：「相信跟预制菜透明化相关的法律法规也会尽快出台。将来如果有跟我和这件事相关的谣言传得实在不像话，公司会写四平八稳的、不会给平台惹麻烦的公关稿予以澄清。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Jia Guolong confirmed that Xibei would close 102 stores nationwide in one go, affecting approximately 4,000 employees. The closure ratio accounts for about 30% of the total number of stores, and they are mainly concentrated in first- and second-tier cities, including 19 in Shanghai, and 10, 8, and 5 respectively in Beijing, Shenzhen, and Guangzhou.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，贾国龙确认西贝将一次性关闭全国 102 家门店，涉及约 4000 名员工，关店比例约占总门店数三成，且主要集中在一、二线城市，其中上海 19 家，北京、深圳、广州分别关闭 10、8、5 家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jia Guolong stated that all departing employees' salaries would be paid &quot;to the last penny,&quot; and stored-value cards could continue to be used at other stores or be refunded.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            贾国龙表示，所有离职员工工资将「一分钱不会差」，储值卡可在其他门店继续使用或办理退款。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, People's Daily Commentary published an article titled &quot;The Online Public Opinion Environment Cannot Become a Shortcoming for Enterprise Development,&quot; evaluating the Xibei store closure incident.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，人民日报评论发布《网络舆论环境不能成为企业发展的短板》文章，评价了西贝关店事件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The article pointed out that this is a typical event in the internet era. Online influencers temporarily swayed public opinion with &quot;sensational material,&quot; the exposed party responded strongly with &quot;pre-internet era thinking,&quot; and online platforms created and maintained hot topics with &quot;cheering and instigation&quot; to attract attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文章指出，这是互联网时代的一起典型事件。网络大 V 以「劲爆语料」一时左右网络舆论场，被爆料者以「前互联网时代思维」强硬回应，网络平台以「起哄架秧子」制造热点、保持热度来吸引眼球。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The article also emphasized that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             there are issues with the two parties involved and the platform, issues with enterprises underestimating consumer opinions and suggestions, and more importantly, issues with the current online public opinion environment.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文章还强调，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             有两个当事人、平台的问题，有企业轻视消费者意见建议的问题，更要看到当下网络舆论环境的问题。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The Xibei incident has long gone beyond a war of words. Luo Yonghao and his ilk, Jia Guolong and his ilk, Sina Weibo, and other platforms all have lessons to learn. &quot;Creating a clear and bright cyberspace&quot; is by no means an empty proposition, but a common answer sheet that all parties must constantly get right. Whoever violates this rule will ultimately face severe punishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>一公司就「涨薪 20 元」向员工致歉</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">一公司就「涨薪-20-元」向员工致歉</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a report by Cover News, a recent apology letter from Chongqing Meixin Group regarding its 2026 annual salary adjustment has attracted attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据封面新闻报道，近日，重庆美心集团一份关于 2026 年度调薪的致歉信受到关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The letter stated that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             this year the company decided to increase the monthly salary of grassroots employees by 20 yuan, and expressed apologies for the low increase, saying, &quot;We are very sorry, we apologize to everyone.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            信中称，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             今年公司决定为基层员工涨 20 元月薪，并对涨幅较低表达歉意，「非常抱歉，对不起大家」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The apology letter also stated: &quot;The company's manufacturing accounts receivable remain high, and non-manufacturing operations have not met expectations. This meager figure is the company's greatest sincerity in its difficult situation.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            致歉信还写道：「公司制造业应收账款居高不下，非制造业经营不达预期。这微薄的数字，是公司在困境中的最大心意。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report pointed out that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             in fact, this is already the company's 37th consecutive year of raising employee salaries.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             事实上这已经是该公司连续第 37 年为员工涨薪。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Employees stated through the report that when the company was founded in 1989, a rule was established that salaries must be adjusted once at the beginning of each year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            员工通过报道表示，1989 年公司成立时就立下规矩，每年年初都要调一次薪。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is revealed that in previous years, the regular increase was between 150-200 yuan, but in recent years, due to multiple factors such as fluctuations in the real estate industry and the overseas economic environment, the company's operations have faced considerable pressure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据透露，往年常规涨幅在 150-200 元之间，但近几年受房地产行业波动、海外经济环境等多重因素影响，公司经营面临较大压力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that Meixin Group is a Chongqing-based enterprise that started by producing security doors. Regarding this slight salary increase, Meixin Group staff stated that the adjustment mainly targets the company's grassroots employees.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据了解，美心集团是重庆一家以生产防盗门起家的企业。对于此次微幅涨薪，美心集团工作人员表示，调薪主要针对的是公司基层员工。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He admitted that the company had worried that 'too small an increase would make employees feel embarrassed,' but after comprehensive consideration, honest communication and respecting employees' right to know were deemed more important.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他坦言，公司曾担心「涨太少反而让员工觉得没面子」，但最后综合考量，坦诚沟通、尊重员工的知情权更为重要。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>陶哲轩点赞，GPT-5.2 Pro 再次破解公开数学难题</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">陶哲轩点赞，GPT-5.2-Pro-再次破解公开数学难题</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/81d3eb9d-2e1d-4f49-9a2c-a18c49a9760c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Neel Somani, founder of blockchain software development company Eclipse, posted on X that he used OpenAI's latest model GPT-5.2 Pro to solve another famous Erdős mathematical problem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，区块链软件开发公司 Eclipse 创始人 Neel Somani 在 X 发文称，其使用 OpenAI 最新模型 GPT-5.2 Pro 破解了另一项著名的 Erdős（埃尔德什）数学难题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Mathematician Terence Tao later confirmed that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the model almost independently completed the solution process for at least one Erdős problem, and described it as one of the 'clearest cases of AI solving open problems.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后数学家陶哲轩（Terence Tao）确认，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             该模型在至少一个 Erdős 问题上几乎独立完成了解答过程，并评价这是「AI 解决开放问题的最明确案例」之一。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI President and co-founder Greg Brockman also reposted and commented on X, calling this achievement an important sign of progress in mathematics and science.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 总裁兼联合创始人格雷格 · 布罗克曼（Greg Brockman）也在 X 上转发并评论，称这一成果是数学与科学进步的重要标志。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that although relevant proofs exist in existing literature, the solution provided by GPT-5.2 Pro is 'significantly different from previous proofs' and still holds research value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其指出，虽然已有文献中存在相关证明，但 GPT-5.2 Pro 给出的解法「与此前的证明有明显不同」，仍具有研究价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that GPT-5.2 Pro is one of OpenAI's advanced model series released last year, positioned to handle professional and complex tasks, emphasizing stronger reasoning and structured output capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，GPT-5.2 Pro 是 OpenAI 去年发布的高级模型系列之一，定位于处理专业复杂任务，强调更强的推理与结构化输出能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Official documentation shows that this series has made significant progress in scientific and mathematical tasks, capable of generating detailed arguments and exploring hypotheses and proof directions, but still requires verification by human experts.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方文档显示，该系列在科学与数学任务方面取得显著进展，能够生成详细论证并探索假设与证明方向，但仍需人类专家进行校验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Terence Tao also warned that while this achievement is groundbreaking, most open problems vary greatly in difficulty, and only a few are suitable for completion by existing tools with limited human guidance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            陶哲轩也提醒，尽管这一成果具有突破性意义，但多数开放问题难度差异巨大，仅有少量问题适合在有限人类指导下由现有工具完成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Under the related post on X, some users also pointed out in the annotations that Somani's statement had flaws, as relevant problems had already been proven in historical literature. Nevertheless, GPT-5.2 Pro's solution is still considered an exploration of 'different paths'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 X 的相关帖子底下，也有用户在附注中指出 Somani 的表述存在瑕疵，因相关问题在历史文献中已有证明，但无论如何，GPT-5.2 Pro 的解法仍被认为是「不同路径」的探索。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阿里 CEO 吴泳铭：2025 年几场「大仗」都打得漂亮</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">阿里-CEO-吴泳铭：2025-年几场「大仗」都打得漂亮</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to IT Home, Alibaba CEO Eddie Wu yesterday published a New Year's letter, in which he reviewed the business performance of the past year, stating that several 'major battles' in 2025 were fought beautifully:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 IT 之家消息，阿里巴巴 CEO 吴泳铭昨日发布新年家书，他在信中回顾了过去一年的业务表现，称 2025 年几场「大仗」都打得漂亮：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taobao Flash Sale achieved a breakthrough, and the 'eat, live, travel, play, shop' comprehensive consumer service system accelerated its formation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amap's 'Street Scan List' helped promote the sustainable development of the offline service industry;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Qianwen App's public beta downloads exceeded 10 million in its first week, marking Alibaba AI's transition from industry application to mass popularization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Eddie Wu pointed out that these achievements are not single business breakthroughs, but rather a chemical reaction generated by the synergy of the Alibaba ecosystem, proving that AI brings upgrades rather than replacements.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            吴泳铭指出，这些成果并非单一业务突破，而是阿里生态协同产生的化学反应，证明 AI 带来的是升级而非替代。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding corporate culture, Eddie Wu mentioned that in 2025, Alibaba will refresh its employee badges, using 'one year fragrant, three years mellow, five years aged, ten years fragrant' to mark different lengths of service, and will hold a special concert for employees who have been with the company for ten years on this year's 510 Alibaba Day.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对企业文化，吴泳铭提到 2025 年阿里将焕新工牌，采用「一年香、三年醇、五年陈、十年馨」标识不同司龄，并将在今年 510 阿里日为入职满十年的员工举办专场音乐会。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that 26-year-old Alibaba is still on its entrepreneurial journey, and facing the opportunities of AI reshaping the world and changes in consumption structure, it will adhere to long-termism.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，26 岁的阿里仍处于创业路上，面对 AI 重塑世界和消费结构变革的机遇，将坚持长期主义。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>马斯克向 OpenAI 和微软索赔高达 1340 亿美元，奥特曼斥其断章取义</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">马斯克向-OpenAI-和微软索赔高达-1340-亿美元，奥特曼斥其断章取义</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Bloomberg, Elon Musk is seeking $79 billion to $134 billion in damages from OpenAI and Microsoft, claiming OpenAI defrauded him by abandoning its non-profit mission. This exorbitant claim stems from expert witness and financial economist C. Paul Wazan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据彭博社报道， 埃隆·马斯克向 OpenAI 和微软索赔 790 亿至 1340 亿美元， 理由是 OpenAI 背弃非营利使命欺骗了他。而这一天价索赔源自专家证人、金融经济学家 C·保罗·瓦赞。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He believes Musk is entitled to a significant share of OpenAI's current $500 billion valuation, ** because Musk donated $38 million in seed funding when he co-founded OpenAI in 2015. If calculated this way, Musk's return on investment would reach 3500 times. **
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他认为马斯克有权从 OpenAI 目前 5000 亿美元的估值中获得相当大的份额，** 因为马斯克在 2015 年联合创立 OpenAI 时捐赠了 3800 万美元种子资金。如果按此计算， 马斯克的投资回报将达到 3500 倍。**
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Vazan's analysis, which combined Musk's initial financial contributions with his technical and business advice to the early OpenAI team, calculated OpenAI's unjust enrichment to be between $65.5 billion and $109.4 billion, and Microsoft's unjust enrichment to be between $13.3 billion and $25.1 billion, asserting the right to demand the court order both companies to return the funds.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            瓦赞的分析综合了马斯克的初始财务贡献以及他为 OpenAI 早期团队提供的技术和商业建议， 计算出 OpenAI 的不当得利为 655 亿至 1094 亿美元， 微软的不当得利为 133 亿至 251 亿美元，并主张有权要求法院责令两家公司返还。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, OpenAI views the lawsuit as part of Musk's 'ongoing harassment' rather than a legitimate economic claim. Reportedly, OpenAI sent letters to investors and business partners on Thursday, warning that Musk would make 'deliberately exaggerated, attention-grabbing claims' before the trial in April.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，OpenAI 认为这起诉讼是马斯克「持续骚扰行为」的一部分， 而非合理的经济诉求。据报道，OpenAI 周四已致信投资者和商业伙伴， 警告马斯克将在 4 月开庭审理前提出「刻意夸张、博眼球的主张」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, yesterday, Sam Altman also posted multiple tweets on social media in response:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，昨日，Sam Altman 也在社交媒体上连发多条推文回应：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Musk is slandering Greg by taking things out of context, but the truth is, Musk was pushing for a new organizational structure at the time, and Greg and Ilya spent a lot of time trying to figure out if his various demands could be met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b7bf8084-7ad7-4d8f-8433-e46ca5a1a0a7.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman pointed out that Musk claimed he wanted to raise $80 billion to build a self-sufficient Martian city, and stated that he needed and should have a majority stake. &quot;He said he needed complete control because he had suffered losses in the past without control. When we discussed succession plans, he also suddenly mentioned that he hoped his children would control AGI in the future.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            奥特曼指出，马斯克称自己想筹集 800 亿美元，用于建设一个能自给自足的火星城市，并表示他需要也应该拥有大多数股权。「他说他需要完全控制权，因为他过去吃过没有控制权的亏。当我们讨论继任计划时，他还突然提到，希望未来由他的孩子来掌控 AGI。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;I respect people's right to express what they want, and I believe it helps solve problems (or not). But Elon saying these things provides important context for Greg's attempts to figure out what he truly wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 年度经常性收入达 200 亿美元</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-年度经常性收入达-200-亿美元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ef933ebd-f544-4c7e-966b-d4efa7a25464.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, OpenAI CFO Sarah Friar published a blog post introducing the company's development over recent years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，OpenAI 首席财务官 Sarah Friar 发布博客，介绍了公司近几年的发展情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The article pointed out that OpenAI's annual recurring revenue grew 10-fold between 2023 and 2025:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文中指出，OpenAI 在 2023 年至 2025 年期间，年度经常性收入增长达 10 倍：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;It was $2 billion in 2023, reaching $20 billion in 2025 (approximately 139.4 billion RMB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sarah stated that OpenAI's weekly active users (WAU) and daily active users (DAU) continue to hit new historical highs. This revenue, in turn, funds the next wave of computing and innovation, and this cycle is continuously strengthening.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Sarah 表示，OpenAI 的每周活跃用户（WAU）和每日活跃用户（DAU）人数不断创下历史新高。而收入又为下一个计算和创新浪潮提供资金，并且这个循环正在不断强化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;As ChatGPT becomes a tool people rely on daily to get real work done, we follow a simple yet enduring principle: our business model should grow as intelligent value is delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinking Machines 联创被曝职场恋情未公开遭解雇</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Thinking-Machines-联创被曝职场恋情未公开遭解雇</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Wall Street Journal, Barrett Zoff, co-founder of AI startup Thinking Machines, was fired on Wednesday due to an undisclosed workplace romance, as well as performance and behavioral issues.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《华尔街日报》报道，AI 初创公司 Thinking Machines 联合创始人巴雷特·佐夫周三被解雇，原因是存在未公开的职场恋情以及业绩和行为问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Internal emails obtained by The Wall Street Journal show that Thinking Machines CEO Mira Murati told employees that Zoff had performance, behavioral, and trust issues since mid-2025, and the company had given him multiple opportunities. She believed Zoff began contacting competitors because he knew his prospects were unclear.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《华尔街日报》获得的内部邮件显示，Thinking Machines CEO 米拉·穆拉蒂告诉员工， 佐夫自 2025 年中期以来就存在业绩、行为和信任问题， 公司已给过他多次机会， 她认为佐夫因清楚自己前景不明才开始与竞争对手接触。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last week,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Murati announced on X that she was parting ways with Zoff, and less than an hour later, OpenAI's Head of Consumer Products, Fijay Simo, posted an announcement hiring Zoff
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , stating that they had been &quot;preparing for this for weeks,&quot; implying that OpenAI had contacted Zoff before his departure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上周，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             穆拉蒂在 X 上宣布与佐夫分道扬镳， 不到一小时后 OpenAI 应用部门 CEO 菲吉·西莫就发帖宣布聘用佐夫
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ， 并称「为此筹备了好几周」， 这意味着 OpenAI 在佐夫离职前就已接洽。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to Zoff, OpenAI also poached two other employees, Luke Metz and Sam Schoenhals. All three had previously worked at OpenAI and only founded Thinking Machines with former OpenAI CTO Murati in early 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除佐夫外，OpenAI 同时挖走了另外两名员工卢克·梅茨和萨姆·舍恩霍尔茨。三人此前都曾在 OpenAI 工作，2025 年初才跟随前 OpenAI CTO 穆拉蒂创立 Thinking Machines。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The startup, valued at $12 billion in its latest funding round, has currently only released one developer tool and is losing core talent, with co-founder Andrew Tulloch having already moved to Meta last October.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这家在最近一轮融资中估值 120 亿美元的初创公司目前仅发布了一款开发者工具， 且正在流失核心人才，而去年 10 月联合创始人安德鲁·塔洛克已跳槽至 Meta。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>特斯拉 AI 芯片最新进展：AI5 设计快完成了</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">特斯拉-AI-芯片最新进展：AI5-设计快完成了</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b828d56f-7e89-45db-bdb8-51870e1a0813.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Tesla CEO Elon Musk posted on X, stating that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Tesla's AI5 chip design is nearing completion, the AI6 chip is in early development, and future plans include AI7, AI8, and AI9, with the goal of achieving a '9-month design cycle.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，特斯拉 CEO 埃隆 · 马斯克在 X 发文表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             特斯拉 AI5 芯片设计已接近完成，AI6 芯片处于早期研发阶段，未来还将推出 AI7、AI8、AI9，目标是实现「9 个月设计周期」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Musk emphasized that these chips will become 'the highest-volume AI chips globally.' However, foreign media outlet electrek reported that Musk's statements contain certain contradictions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            马斯克强调，这些芯片将成为「全球产量最高的 AI 芯片」。但外媒 electrek 报道指出，马斯克的相关表述存在一定矛盾。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last July, Musk stated that the AI5 chip was 'design complete,' but now says it's 'nearing completion.' Industry insiders point out that after chip design is complete, it still needs to go through tape-out, sample verification, and testing before entering mass production.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年 7 月，马斯克曾表示 AI5 芯片已「设计完成」，但如今又称「接近完成」。业内人士指出，芯片设计完成后仍需经历流片、样品验证和测试等环节，才能进入量产阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Therefore, if the AI5 chip can only be mass-produced by mid-next year, the Cybercab planned for release this year might continue to use the existing AI4 chip.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            因此，若 AI5 芯片要到明年中期才能量产，计划于今年推出的 Cybercab 或将继续搭载现有的 AI4 芯片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In contrast, while Apple's A-series mobile chips maintain a yearly iteration, their planning and design are often determined years in advance. It is widely believed in the industry that Musk's optimistic estimates should be viewed with caution.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比之下，苹果 A 系列移动芯片虽然保持一年一迭代，但其规划与设计往往在数年前就已确定。业内普遍认为，马斯克的乐观估计需谨慎看待。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He previously claimed that the HW3 chip could achieve 'full self-driving,' but currently, millions of Tesla vehicles equipped with HW3 and HW4 have not yet reached unsupervised autonomous driving levels.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前他曾宣称 HW3 芯片已能实现「完全自动驾驶」，但目前数百万辆搭载 HW3、HW4 的特斯拉汽车仍未达到无人监督的自动驾驶水平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Musk added on X that Tesla's AI team is 'extremely hardcore' and predicted that future AI chip production would far exceed that of other manufacturers. He called for more engineers to join the R&amp;amp;D to push Tesla to maintain its lead in real-world AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            马斯克在 X 补充称，特斯拉 AI 团队「极其硬核」，并预测未来的 AI 芯片产量将远超其他厂商。他呼吁更多工程师加入研发，推动特斯拉在现实世界 AI 领域保持领先。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 DeepMind CEO：AGI 5-10 年内实现</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-DeepMind-CEO：AGI-5-10-年内实现</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Google DeepMind CEO Demis Hassabis was interviewed on CNBC, where he discussed with the host the importance of scaling laws and the ongoing pursuit of developing Artificial General Intelligence (AGI).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，Google DeepMind CEO Demis Hassabis 接受了 CNBC 的节目采访，与主持人共同讨论了缩放定律的重要性以及发展通用人工智能（AGI）的持续追求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Demis stated that he still believes AGI can be achieved within 5 to 10 years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Demis 表示，自己依然认为 5 到 10 年内 AGI 能得以实现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that AGI, including AI, will involve a combination of LLMs (Large Language Models) and world models, rather than one component replacing another.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其指出，包括 AI 在内的 AGI 将涉及 LLMs（大语言模型）和世界模型的组合，而不是一个组件取代另一个组件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Demis believes that AI may require better reasoning, long-term planning, and the concept of 'world models' to better understand physics and perform simulations, reflecting the work of human scientists. He also emphasized that, in addition to world models, AGI may require other types of technologies and capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Demis 认为，AI 可能需要更好的推理、长期规划和 「世界模型」 的概念，以更好地理解物理学并进行模拟，反映人类科学家的工作。其也强调，除了世界模型之外，AGI 可能还需要其他类型的技术和能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, he also stated that for AI to make progress in scientific capabilities, it needs to be able to propose new hypotheses and ideas, not just solve existing conjectures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时他也表示，为了使 AI 在科学能力方面取得进步，它需要能够提出新的假设和想法，而不仅仅是解决现有的猜测。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>全新奇瑞 QQ3 预计 2 月发布</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">全新奇瑞-QQ3-预计-2-月发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0ce5064f-1775-481f-8b68-01f316112dfb.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Chery Automobile held its 2026 Automotive AI Night and unveiled five new cars at the press conference:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，奇瑞汽车举办 2026 汽车 AI 之夜，并在发布会上公布了五款新车：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-new QQ3: Positioned as an entry-level compact car, with a 2700mm wheelbase and an electric front trunk; equipped with the 'Falcon 500' intelligent driving system built on the Horizon Journey 6 chip; features rear-engine, rear-wheel drive with multi-link independent suspension; officially launching in February;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SUV T9L: Features a long wheelbase of 2920mm, highlighting a 17.3-inch ultra-large central control screen and dual zero-gravity seats in the front. In terms of power, the upgraded Kunpeng AI Super Hybrid C-DM 6.0 keeps the car's fuel consumption at 3.9 liters when battery is low, with an all-electric range of 230 kilometers;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coupe A9: Compact in length, only 4860mm. Debuts the 'AI Boya Sound' system, featuring 23 speakers, support for mic-less K-singing, and AI tuning;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iCAR V27: Body length reaches 5055mm, with a size comparable to a mid-to-large SUV. For intelligent driving, it uses the Horizon Journey 6P chip, providing 560TOPS of computing power;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jetour G700 focuses on the digitalization of off-road performance, equipped with a Qualcomm 8255 chip and the XWD² Super All-Domain Intelligent Control System, featuring a 'one-key cross-axle mode'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that Chery stated their investment in technology has gone beyond the cars themselves.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，奇瑞表示，他们对于技术投入已经超出了汽车本身。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Chery's Mojia robots, humanoid robot 'Mornine,' and robot dog 'Argos' have achieved mass production and delivery to over 30 countries worldwide. On the streets of Wuhu, the first Chery traffic police robot has also officially started duty.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，奇瑞旗下的墨甲机器人，人形机器人「墨茵（Mornine）」和机器狗「Argos」，已经实现了向全球 30 多个国家的量产化交付。在芜湖街头，首款奇瑞交警机器人也已正式上岗。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chery's goal is to mass-produce the VLA foundational model by 2026, and mass-produce real-world AI platforms and model-driven physical world robots by 2028, completing its transformation from a traditional automaker to a technology company.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            奇瑞的目标是在 2026 年量产 VLA 基础模型，并在 2028 年量产真实世界 AI 基座和模型驱动的物理世界机器人，完成从传统车企向科技企业的转型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 Related Reading: Is QQ also joining the intelligent driving race? Chery, infused with AI, has also started making robots.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 相关阅读：QQ 也要卷智驾？染上 AI 的奇瑞，还开始做机器人了
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>荣耀总裁：Magic8 Pro Air 电池有黑科技</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">荣耀总裁：Magic8-Pro-Air-电池有黑科技</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6eaa402c-e40b-4b14-bef6-e75b020883a6.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Fang Fei, President of Honor's product line, posted an article revealing more information about the new Honor Magic8 Pro Air:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近期，荣耀产品线总裁方飞发文，透露了更多新机荣耀 Magic8 Pro Air 的信息：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fang Fei pointed out that only by making a phone both thin and powerful can it be called Pro Air, and once truly achieved, thin and light models will no longer be a compromise, but a track that the entire industry can continue to follow and invest in;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of imaging, the Honor Magic8 Pro Air is equipped with the same 50MP large-sensor main camera as the Magic8 Pro; it also features an AI zoom array flash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Honor Magic8 Pro Air will use a Qinghai Lake battery and will be equipped with black technology (according to previous leaks, the new phone will feature a 5500mAh large battery);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The middle frame uses super-strong aerospace aluminum alloy, with stronger bending resistance than the iPhone Air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the new phone will be available in four colors: orange, purple, white, and black, and will feature a flat metal middle frame. According to previous leaks, the new phone will be 6.3mm thick, weigh 158g, and be equipped with a 1/1.3-inch large-sensor main camera.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，新机将提供橙色、紫色、白色、黑色四款配色，配备直边金属中框。据此前消息透露，新机厚度为 6.3mm、重量为 158g，配备 1/1.3 英寸大底主摄。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new phone will be officially released tonight.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新机将于今晚正式发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>真我 Neo8 外围配置公布</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">真我-Neo8-外围配置公布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/41334764-eff7-468b-8730-ddab4c78916d.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Realme announced more configuration details for its new phone, the Neo8:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近期，真我公布了旗下新机 Neo8 的更多配置信息：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with 3D ultrasonic fingerprint unlock, dual-frequency GPS, Crystal Armor Glass, and ultra-linear stereo dual speakers;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 165Hz screen, using Samsung M14 luminous material, with a local peak brightness of 6500nit, and a 50% increase in screen lifespan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adopts the fifth-generation Snapdragon 8 and Sky Signal Chip S1, supporting a new geek performance panel (customizable temperature control, customizable chip frequency);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a transparent back cover design, available in purple, white, and black, and equipped with an Awakening Halo System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new phone will be released on January 22nd.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新机将于 1 月 22 日发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12306：误购车票可限时免费退</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">12306：误购车票可限时免费退</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Xinhua News Agency, it has learned from China National Railway Group Co., Ltd.:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新华社从中国国家铁路集团有限公司获悉：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Starting from January 19, the railway 12306 platform (including website, APP, etc.) will launch a limited-time free refund service for passengers who mistakenly purchase tickets. When passengers purchase train tickets for travel dates on or after February 2 through the railway 12306 platform, if a ticket is mistakenly purchased within 30 minutes of successful payment and more than 4 hours before departure, the purchaser can process the refund online by themselves without incurring a refund fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A relevant person in charge from the Passenger Transport Center of China National Railway Group introduced:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            国铁集团客运中心相关负责人介绍：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a ticket purchaser buys train tickets for domestic passenger trains or cross-border passenger trains with a departure or arrival station of Hong Kong West Kowloon for travel dates on or after February 2, using electronic payment or points payment through the railway 12306 platform, if a mistaken purchase occurs during the operation, they can process a free online refund within 30 minutes of successful payment and more than 4 hours before departure;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the ticket purchaser uses electronic payment, the ticket fare will be refunded via the original channel; if points payment is used, the points will be returned via the original channel, and the validity period of the returned points remains unchanged; the same ticket purchaser is limited to processing one mistaken purchase free refund per natural day, and this service does not apply to ticket changes, reservations, or standby ticket purchases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the railway department implements a tiered refund policy. Refunds processed within the specified free refund period do not count towards the limit of mistaken purchase free refunds. Additionally, if a passenger makes a mistaken purchase at an offline ticket window, they must raise it on the spot, and staff will promptly assist them in exchanging for a new ticket.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前铁路部门实行阶梯式退票政策，在规定免费退票时间内办理退票的，不占用误购免费退票次数。此外，如果旅客在线下售票窗口发生误购，须当场提出，工作人员会及时帮助旅客换发新票。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曝 R 星暖心回应绝症粉丝愿望：或能提前试玩《GTA6》</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝-R-星暖心回应绝症粉丝愿望：或能提前试玩《GTA6》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3d51b0c2-6ce2-48d8-823f-33f9fc5cc1d1.jpeg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to blogger &quot;GTA 6 Countdown&quot;, Rockstar Games has accepted a request from a seriously ill fan and may have allowed this fan to play &quot;GTA6&quot; early.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据博主「GTA 6 Countdown」消息，Rockstar Games 接受了一名病重粉丝的请求，并且或已让这位粉丝提前玩到《GTA6》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the information released by the blogger, Ubisoft Toronto employee Anthony Armstrong previously posted a long article on LinkedIn, stating that one of his family members has been battling cancer for many years and now has only 6-12 months left to live.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从博主公布的消息显示，育碧多伦多员工 Anthony Armstrong 曾在领英平台发布长文，称自己的一位家人多年来一直与癌症抗争，现阶段生命只剩 6-12 个月。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, he is also a huge fan of the &quot;GTA&quot; series, so he hopes this family member can experience &quot;GTA6&quot; before passing away.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但同时他也是一名《GTA》系列游戏的铁粉，因此希望这位家人能在病逝前体验上《GTA6》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Anthony Armstrong also emphasized that he fully understands the importance of confidentiality during the development phase, and therefore, signing a non-disclosure agreement (NDA) is acceptable. Subsequently, Anthony Armstrong posted that he had contacted Rockstar Games.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Anthony Armstrong 也强调，自己完全理解开发阶段保密性的重要，因此哪怕签署保密协议（NDA）也可接受。后续 Anthony Armstrong 发文称已与 R 星取得联系。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that Anthony Armstrong later deleted the tweet, and GTA 6 Countdown speculated that it might be due to signing a non-disclosure agreement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，后续 Anthony Armstrong 删除了推文，而 GTA 6 Countdown 推测可能是因签署了保密协议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>公安部网安局：「小女孩 50 元淘到名酒」视频系摆拍</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">公安部网安局：「小女孩-50-元淘到名酒」视频系摆拍</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to news from the Cyberspace Security Bureau of the Ministry of Public Security, a video titled &quot;Little Girl Finds Famous Wine for 50 Yuan&quot; recently attracted attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据公安部网安局消息，近日，一段「小女孩 50 元淘到名酒」的视频引发关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that in the video, a man asked his daughter what she bought for 50 yuan at the school's flea market. The child successively took out snacks and toys from her backpack, and finally pulled out a bottle of famous wine.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，视频中，一男子询问女儿用 50 元从学校跳蚤市场买了什么，孩子接连从书包里拿出零食、玩具，最后竟掏出一瓶名酒。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The video sparked widespread attention and discussion among netizens, with some questioning &quot;treating the school flea market as a traffic show&quot; and &quot;letting traffic hijack the innocence of children.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该视频引发大量网民关注和讨论，部分网民对「将学校跳蚤市场当做流量秀场」「让流量裹挟孩子的干净纯粹」提出质疑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Upon investigation, the aforementioned video was found to be false content. It was fabricated, staged, and published by netizen Zhou (male, 32 years old, unemployed) to gain attention and attract traffic, disseminating false information about &quot;daughter exchanging 50 yuan for famous wine at school flea market,&quot; which led to widespread circulation of the false information, attracting netizen attention, and disrupting the order of cyberspace.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            经查，上述视频为虚假内容，系网民周某（男，32 岁，无业）为博取关注、吸引流量，编造、摆拍并发布了「女儿在学校跳蚤市场用 50 元换回名酒」的不实信息，导致该虚假信息大量传播，引发网民关注，扰乱网络空间秩序。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Public security organs have lawfully imposed administrative penalties on Zhou.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             公安机关已依法对周某予以行政处罚。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 年春晚完成首次彩排</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2026-年春晚完成首次彩排</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1b14d99a-b1b7-4095-bb02-241a339b2c2c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV News, on January 17, China Media Group's &quot;2026 Spring Festival Gala&quot; successfully completed its first rehearsal.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视新闻，1 月 17 日，中央广播电视总台《2026 年春节联欢晚会》顺利完成首次彩排。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Various types of programs, innovative technology applications, stage visual design, and other elements have been integrated, with smooth transitions between all segments, and the overall effect of the gala is beginning to emerge.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            各类型节目与创新技术应用、舞美视觉设计等要素完成融合，各环节流程衔接顺畅，晚会整体效果初显。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The CCTV Year of the Horse Spring Festival Gala adheres to the main theme of &quot;Joyful and Auspicious, Full of Cheer,&quot; with &quot;Galloping Steeds, Unstoppable Momentum&quot; as its theme. Under the nourishment of culture and empowerment of technology, it presents a vibrant and thriving new era of striving.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            总台马年春晚坚持「欢乐吉祥、喜气洋洋」的主基调，以「骐骥驰骋 势不可挡」为主题，在文化滋养与科技赋能下，呈现活力满满、蒸蒸日上的新时代奋进气象。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The CCTV Year of the Horse Spring Festival Gala draws wisdom and strength from excellent traditional Chinese culture, subtly integrating the zodiac horse element, which symbolizes self-improvement and pioneering spirit, into its creation. It adheres to the integrated communication of &quot;thought + art + technology,&quot; continuously expanding the boundaries of artistic expression. In stage design, AI, AR, XR, and other technological means are flexibly used to create an immersive, three-dimensional visual effect where &quot;people are in the scenery, and the scenery moves with people&quot; between virtual and reality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            总台马年春晚从中华优秀传统文化中汲取智慧和力量，将寓意自强不息、锐意进取的生肖马元素巧妙融入创作，坚持「思想+艺术+技术」融合传播，不断拓宽艺术表达边界。舞美设计中，灵活运用 AI、AR、XR 等科技手段，在虚实之间营造出「人在景中、景随人动」的沉浸立体式视觉效果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Art installations interpreted with &quot;horse&quot; patterns and shapes form a dynamic stage space of galloping horses, rising and falling. Original songs have a brisk rhythm, singing out the spirited demeanor of a magnificent steed; opera programs, based on the traditional &quot;Tang Ma&quot; (horse-riding) routine, innovatively arrange a situational horse dance, with every move showcasing a dashing and heroic posture.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            以「马」的纹样造型演绎的艺术装置，构成万马奔腾、起伏错落的舞台空间。原创歌曲节奏明快，唱出骏马般意气风发的精神面貌；戏曲节目根据传统程式「趟马」，创新编排情景化马舞，一招一式尽显飒爽英姿。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The CCTV Year of the Horse Spring Festival Gala is an upgrade of &quot;technology + art,&quot; integrating &quot;technological intelligence&quot; into stage presentation, content creation, and more, enriching people's colorful imagination of the Spring Festival atmosphere.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            总台马年春晚是「科技+艺术」的再升级，将「科技智造」融入舞美呈现、内容创作等，丰富人们对年味的缤纷想象。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Following the smart robots performing Yangko dance becoming &quot;top-tier&quot; at the Year of the Snake Spring Festival Gala, robots will once again appear on the Spring Festival Gala stage, showcasing new advancements in China's technological progress with their tech-savvy and fresh creative sparks.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             继蛇年春晚扭秧歌的智能机器人跻身「顶流」后，机器人将再度登上春晚舞台，用科技范和新鲜感的创意火花彰显我国科技进步的新气象。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B 站公布 2025 百大 UP 主名单</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">B-站公布-2025-百大-UP-主名单</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f150d829-6d45-4e20-a8b8-bac0a8b36a79.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Bilibili officially announced its list of Top 100 UP creators for 2025. The official statement indicated that this selection continued to use the three dimensions of &quot;professionalism, influence, and innovation,&quot; serving as the platform's annual summary and showcase of its creator ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，哔哩哔哩正式公布 2025 年度百大 UP 主名单。官方表示，此次评选延续「专业性、影响力、创新性」三大维度，成为平台对创作者生态的年度总结与展示。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Creators such as Funch, Laofanqie, Muyu Shuixin, and Xiaoyao Sanren, who have been selected for eight consecutive years, continue to hold steady on the list, demonstrating long-term stable creativity and influence;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             泛式、老番茄、木鱼水心、逍遥散人等连续八年入选的创作者继续稳居榜单，显示出长期稳定的创作力与影响力；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Geekerwan, Movie TOP, Xiaochao Yuanzhang, Yingshi Jufeng, and others have also maintained their multi-year presence, highlighting their sustained popularity and professionalism in fields such as digital technology and film/television;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             极客湾 Geekerwan、电影最 TOP、小潮院长、影视飓风等也保持多年蝉联，凸显其在数码、影视等领域的持续话题度与专业性；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             This year, a total of 28 UP creators were selected for the first time, reflecting the platform's content ecosystem's continuous update and iteration;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             今年共有 28 位 UP 主首次入选，反映出平台内容生态的更新迭代；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             Compared to last year, some creators were not re-selected. For example, Daoyueshe Shiyuji, Jisu Paidang, Xing Youye, and others were on the list in 2024 but have been dropped this year.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             与去年相比，部分创作者未能继续入选。例如盗月社食遇记、极速拍档、星有野等在 2024 年仍在榜单之列，但今年已落选。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that since 2018, the selection of the Top 100 UP creators has become a key annual event for Bilibili and is gradually regarded as an important barometer for observing content consumption trends among young people.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开资料显示，自 2018 年起，百大 UP 主评选已成为哔哩哔哩的年度重点活动，并逐渐被视为观察年轻人内容消费趋势的重要风向标。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>电影《镖人》马来西亚定档大年初一</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 04:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">电影《镖人》马来西亚定档大年初一</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/1.19_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/bba95cc8-d2b9-4b6c-a8b0-8e78c773420b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The movie &quot;Blade of the Guardians: The Wind Rises in the Desert&quot; recently officially announced its release date, set to hit Malaysian cinemas on February 17th (the first day of Chinese New Year) this year, while mainland China has officially announced its release during the Spring Festival holiday.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电影《镖人：风起大漠》日前正式宣布定档，将于今年 2 月 17 日（大年初一）登陆马来西亚院线，中国大陆官宣春节档上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is directed by Yuen Woo-ping, with Wu Jing serving as both lead actor and producer. It is adapted from Xu Xianzhe's comic of the same name, &quot;Blade of the Guardians,&quot; which maintains a Douban rating of 8.4~8.9 and has appeared on Japan's NHK television three times, accumulating a large number of core fans.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片由袁和平执导，吴京担任主演兼制片人。影片改编自许先哲同名漫画《镖人》，原作在豆瓣评分维持在 8.4~8.9 分，并三度登上日本 NHK 电视台，积累了大量核心粉丝。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The story is set in the Western Regions desert, where the镖客 (blade-wielding escort) Dao Ma is tasked with escorting the mysterious Zhi Shilang to Chang'an. Along the way, they encounter an ambush by a Hu merchant family, and their fated bond gradually unfolds, intertwining loyalty and life-and-death struggles amidst the glint of blades and the yellow sand.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            故事背景设定在西域大漠，镖客刀马受命护送身份神秘的知世郎前往长安，途中遭遇胡商家族围剿，宿命羁绊逐步揭开，刀光黄沙之间交织信义与生死。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifanr.com/tags/%e6%97%a9%e6%8a%a5&quot;&gt;
            早报
           &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
