<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>快手出现大量色情直播刷屏，平台：遭黑灰产攻击，已报警</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">快手出现大量色情直播刷屏，平台：遭黑灰产攻击，已报警</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/312ccdb6-e5d2-49b4-b0a4-2efcd86ddaba.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, short video platform Kuaishou experienced a serious cybersecurity incident, with a large amount of pornographic content flooding into multiple live broadcast rooms in a short period. This included the playback of obscene films and suggestive performances. The number of viewers in some live rooms surged to over 50,000, leading to concentrated user complaints and public attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日晚间，短视频平台快手突发严重网络安全事件，大量涉黄内容在短时间内涌入多个直播间，出现播放淫秽影片、低俗擦边表演等情形，部分直播间观看人数一度飙升至 5 万+，引发用户集中投诉与舆论关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Multiple users reported that around 10 PM yesterday, on Kuaishou's live broadcast recommendation page, many normally functioning live rooms were extensively replaced with pornographic content, and the number of online viewers in some rooms quickly surpassed ten thousand.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多名用户反映，昨天 22 时左右，在快手直播推荐页面中，原本正常的直播间被大面积替换为涉黄内容，部分房间在线人数迅速突破万级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some live rooms were subsequently forced to close, with a page prompt stating 'Server busy, please try again later'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一些直播间随后被强制关闭，页面提示为「服务器繁忙，请稍后重试」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Kuaishou officially responded in the early hours of yesterday, stating that around 10 PM on the 22nd, the platform was subjected to 'black and gray industry attacks'. Emergency measures have been taken, and system repairs are underway. Kuaishou stated that the platform firmly resists illegal content, and the relevant situation has been reported to the authorities and the public security organs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            快手官方在昨天凌晨先后发布回应称，22 日 22 时左右平台遭到「黑灰产攻击」，目前已紧急处理并进行系统修复。快手表示，平台坚决抵制违规内容，相关情况已上报有关部门，并向公安机关报警。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Around 1 AM yesterday, Kuaishou again responded, confirming the attack; by 2 AM yesterday, the platform's live broadcast channels gradually resumed normal access.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            到昨天凌晨 1 时左右，快手再次回应确认遭遇攻击；至昨天凌晨 2 时，平台直播频道陆续恢复正常访问。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding user reporting channels, staff at the Haidian Branch of the Beijing Municipal Public Security Bureau confirmed that they have received reports from multiple citizens concerning Kuaishou's pornographic live broadcasts, and the police are currently gathering further information.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在用户举报渠道方面，北京市公安局海淀分局接线人员证实，已接到多名群众就快手涉黄直播问题的报案，目前警方正在进一步了解情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>意大利监管机构对苹果罚款近 1 亿欧元，因「滥用市场支配地位」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">意大利监管机构对苹果罚款近-1-亿欧元，因「滥用市场支配地位」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5d3bddc4-0a64-4a9b-9ba4-69edf59df124.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Reuters, the Italian Competition Authority (AGCM) fined Apple and two of its subsidiaries 98.6 million euros (approximately 115.53 million US dollars), finding that they &quot;abused their dominant position&quot; in the mobile application market. The core issue involves the &quot;App Tracking Transparency&quot; (ATT) privacy policy and its data consent mechanism implemented through the App Store for third-party developers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据路透社报道，意大利竞争与市场管理局（AGCM）对苹果及其两家子公司处以 9860 万欧元（约 1.1553 亿美元）罚款，认定其在移动应用市场「滥用市场支配地位」，核心问题涉及通过 App Store 对第三方开发者实施的「应用追踪透明度」（ATT）隐私政策及其数据同意机制。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The investigation conclusions announced by AGCM yesterday pointed out that Apple holds an &quot;absolute dominant position&quot; in the app distribution market on the iOS platform, and the ATT policy terms are unilaterally set by Apple and are disproportionate to its stated data protection goals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            AGCM 昨天宣布的调查结论指出，苹果在 iOS 平台的应用分发市场处于「绝对主导地位」，ATT 政策条款由苹果单方面制定，且与其宣称的数据保护目标不相称。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In practice, ATT requires third-party developers to obtain consent for specific data collection and advertising purposes through Apple's mandatory ATT prompt box, leading to a &quot;double consent&quot; process for the same purpose, thereby restricting the collection, association, and use of data, and harming the interests of developers, advertisers, and intermediary platforms that rely on advertising revenue.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在实际执行中，ATT 要求第三方开发者通过苹果强制的 ATT 提示框获取特定数据收集与广告目的的同意，导致同一目的出现「双重同意」流程，进而限制数据的收集、关联与使用，损害依赖广告收入的开发者、广告主及中介平台的利益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            AGCM stated that the case was opened for investigation in May 2023 and is being coordinated with the European Commission and other international competition regulatory bodies. Apple did not immediately respond to requests for comment on the matter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            AGCM 表示，该案自 2023 年 5 月立案调查，并与欧盟委员会及其他国际竞争监管机构协调推进。苹果未就此事立即回应置评请求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regulators believe that the relevant terms of ATT are detrimental to the interests of Apple's business partners and do not comply with privacy regulatory requirements. ATT has been applicable to third-party applications distributed through the App Store since April 2021 and is considered anti-competitive.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            监管方认为，ATT 的相关条款对苹果商业伙伴利益构成不利，且不符合隐私监管要求。ATT 自 2021 年 4 月起适用于通过 App Store 分发的第三方应用，具有限制竞争性质。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>三星明年或推「阔折叠」对标折叠屏 iPhone</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">三星明年或推「阔折叠」对标折叠屏-iPhone</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a42dd66a-1053-4f41-8e0c-0e83d969d41f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Android Authority, Samsung is developing a new &quot;wide-fold&quot; form factor model, planned for release in the autumn of 2026, to directly compete with Apple's first foldable phone, the iPhone Fold.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Android Authority 报道，三星正开发一款面向「阔折叠」形态的新机型，计划在 2026 年秋季发布，与苹果首款折叠屏手机 iPhone Fold 正面竞争。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This &quot;wide-fold&quot; model adopts a 4:3 inner screen ratio, closer to a tablet, emphasizing a more stable grip and an experience better suited for reading, browsing, and split-screen operations, and is seen as Samsung's new direction in foldable screen form factors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这款「阔折叠」采用更接近平板的 4:3 内屏比例，主打更稳定的握持与更适合阅读、浏览与分屏操作的体验，被视为三星在折叠屏形态上的新方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reportedly, Samsung's &quot;wide-fold&quot; will feature a 7.6-inch OLED inner screen and a 5.4-inch outer screen, and when unfolded, it will be
            &lt;strong&gt;
             similar to a passport
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            . It will support 25W wireless charging, one of Samsung's fastest wireless charging specifications to date, and this charging capability is expected to debut next year on the Galaxy S26 Ultra before expanding to the foldable product line.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据称，三星「阔折叠」配备 7.6 英寸 OLED 内屏与 5.4 英寸外屏，展开后
            &lt;strong&gt;
             类似一本护照
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，将支持 25W 无线充电，为三星迄今最快的无线充电规格之一，且该充电能力预计将先于明年在 Galaxy S26 Ultra 首发，再拓展到折叠产品线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Unlike the &quot;tall and narrow book-like&quot; form factor of the existing Galaxy Z Fold series, the &quot;wide-fold&quot; emphasizes balance for two-handed holding and reading efficiency. Samsung is also rumored to form a &quot;Flip + Standard Fold + Wide-Fold&quot; three-model combination within the Z series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与现有 Galaxy Z Fold 系列的「高长书式」形态不同，「阔折叠」更强调双手持握的平衡与阅读效率，三星也被传将在 Z 系列中形成「Flip + 标准 Fold + 阔折叠」的三机型组合。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Analyst Ming-Chi Kuo previously stated that the iPhone Fold's inner screen will be approximately 7.76 inches and the outer screen 5.49 inches, with an unfolded size close to but slightly smaller than the iPad mini; due to development progress, the iPhone Fold may face supply shortages before the end of 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析师郭明錤此前表示，iPhone Fold 内屏约 7.76 英寸、外屏 5.49 英寸，展开尺寸接近但略小于 iPad mini；受开发进度影响，iPhone Fold 或在 2026 年底前面临供货紧张。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waymo 无人出租车旧金山停电中集体「冻住」，马斯克：特斯拉 Robotaxi 不受影响</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Waymo-无人出租车旧金山停电中集体「冻住」，马斯克：特斯拉-Robotaxi-不受影响</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/710a0bd2-15e1-4390-917f-366b67a4f023.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Bloomberg, Alphabet's autonomous ride-hailing service Waymo was temporarily &quot;frozen&quot; at multiple points across San Francisco due to a massive power outage. Several driverless cars stopped in the middle of the road, blocking traffic. The company subsequently suspended its robotaxi operations in the San Francisco Bay Area and gradually resumed service the following evening.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据彭博社报道，日前，Alphabet 旗下自动驾驶出行服务 Waymo 因旧金山大规模停电事件一度在全市多点「冻住」，多辆无人车停在路中央阻塞交通，随后公司暂停了旧金山湾区的无人出租车运营，并在次日晚间逐步恢复服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On December 20, local time, San Francisco experienced a widespread power outage, with traffic lights at some major intersections going out. Approximately 120,000 to 130,000 Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric (PG&amp;amp;E) customers were affected. The power company stated that the incident originated from a substation fire, causing &quot;severe and widespread&quot; damage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            当地时间 12 月 20 日，旧金山发生大范围停电，部分主要路口的交通信号灯熄灭，约有 12 万至 13 万名 Pacific Gas &amp;amp; Electric（PG&amp;amp;E）用户受影响，电力公司称事故源于一座变电站起火并造成「严重且广泛」损坏。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            With the power outage, the city's public transportation Muni also experienced service disruptions. San Francisco Mayor Daniel Lurie posted on social media platform X, reminding residents not to travel unless necessary, and stated that police, firefighters, and traffic management personnel had been dispatched to affected areas to direct traffic and restore order.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着电力中断，市内公共交通 Muni 也出现服务受阻，旧金山市长 Daniel Lurie 在社交平台 X 发文提醒居民非必要不要出行，并表示已调集警察、消防员和交通管理人员前往受影响街区疏导交通和恢复秩序。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the peak of the power outage, multiple social media videos and on-site photos showed Waymo driverless cars stalled at various intersections and in the middle of lanes, with only their hazard lights on. Human drivers behind them were forced to slow down, detour, or remain stuck in traffic.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在停电高峰时段，多段社交媒体视频和现场图片显示，Waymo 无人车在多个路口和车道中间停滞不前，只开启双闪灯，后方人类司机被迫减速绕行或滞留在车流中。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A passenger recalled that the vehicle suddenly stopped at a &quot;heavily trafficked intersection&quot; where traffic lights were out and pedestrians were crossing densely, without giving a clear explanation. After waiting several minutes in the car and being unable to contact customer service, he ultimately chose to walk the rest of the way. These scenes made Waymo one of the most prominent &quot;high-profile victims&quot; of this power outage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            有乘客回忆称，车辆在信号灯熄灭、行人密集穿行的「车流密集路口」前突然停车且未给出明确解释，他在车内等待数分钟后联系不到客服，最终选择步行完成剩余路程。这些画面使 Waymo 成为此次停电事件中最引人注目的「高调受害者」之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Waymo stated that its autonomous driving system is designed to treat inoperative traffic lights as four-way stop intersections, and vehicles will remain stopped longer during the &quot;intersection status confirmation&quot; period to ensure safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Waymo 表示，其自动驾驶系统在设计上会将失效的交通信号灯视作四向停车路口，车辆会在「确认路口状态」期间停留更久，以保障安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, the scale of this power outage was rare, causing some vehicles to remain at intersections for significantly longer than usual, thereby adding more &quot;traffic friction&quot; during peak congestion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但此次停电规模罕见，导致部分车辆在路口逗留时间明显超出常态，从而在拥堵高峰叠加出更多「交通摩擦」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company emphasized that most ongoing trips were ultimately completed successfully, and systemic shutdown measures were only officially triggered after vehicles safely parked or returned to the depot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司强调，多数在运行中的行程最终仍顺利完成，车辆在安全停车或返回车库后，才正式触发系统性停运措施。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the power outage gradually eased on Sunday, PG&amp;amp;E stated that power had been restored to over 110,000 affected customers, while approximately 21,000 users remained without power, primarily concentrated in the Presidio, Richmond District, Golden Gate Park, and parts of the downtown area.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着停电在周日逐步缓解，PG&amp;amp;E 称已为超过 11 万名受影响用户恢复供电，仍有约 2.1 万用户持续断电，主要集中在 Presidio、Richmond 区、金门公园及部分市中心区域。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the same day, Waymo pushed in-app notifications to Bay Area users, announcing the &quot;proactive suspension&quot; of robotaxi services in San Francisco and at least 7 surrounding cities due to safety concerns, and stated that it is closely coordinating with municipal departments, committed to &quot;restarting operations as soon as safely possible.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Waymo 同日在应用内向湾区用户推送通知，宣布出于安全考虑「主动暂停」旧金山及周边至少 7 个城市的无人出租车服务，并表示正与市政部门密切协同，致力于「尽快在确保安全的前提下重启运营」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            By Sunday afternoon to evening, Waymo confirmed to TechCrunch and CNBC that the company had resumed driverless car operations in the San Francisco Bay Area.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            到周日下午至晚间，Waymo 向 TechCrunch 和 CNBC 确认，公司已在旧金山湾区恢复无人车运营。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A Waymo spokesperson reiterated in a statement that the power outage was a &quot;widespread event&quot; that caused city-wide traffic signal failures and public transport disruptions. The company is &quot;rapidly integrating lessons learned from this incident&quot; and emphasized its commitment to continuously improving technology to better adapt systems to similar extreme conditions, in order to &quot;earn and maintain community trust.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Waymo 发言人在声明中重申，这次停电是一次「广泛事件」，引发全市交通信号失效和公共交通中断，公司正在「快速整合本次事件的经验教训」，并强调将持续改进技术，让系统更好地适应类似极端工况，以「赢得并维持社区的信任」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2bf8daee-9d62-4295-85e1-c2124d1ecd7e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             After the incident, Tesla CEO Elon Musk posted on X, stating that &quot;Tesla's robotaxis were unaffected by the San Francisco power outage,&quot; using the opportunity to highlight his company's product performance during the outage.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             事件发生后，特斯拉 CEO 马斯克在 X 上发文称，「特斯拉的无人驾驶出租车未受旧金山停电影响」，借机突出自家产品在本次停电中的表现。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, Tesla has not yet been approved to conduct fully driverless commercial operations in California. Its ride-hailing services in the area still require vehicles equipped with &quot;FSD (supervised)&quot; and a human driver present.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，目前特斯拉在加州尚未获批开展完全无人化的商业运营，其在当地的叫车服务仍需由配备「FSD（受监督）」的车辆执行并有人类司机在场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regulatory authorities have also not issued Tesla permits for driverless testing or passenger transport without a safety driver, which stands in stark contrast to the fully driverless service Waymo provides in San Francisco.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            监管部门也未向特斯拉颁发无需安全员的无人驾驶测试或载客牌照，这与 Waymo 在旧金山提供的完全无人化服务形成鲜明对比。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Autonomous driving safety experts point out that this power outage incident exposed the vulnerability of highly automated mobility systems when dealing with infrastructure failures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自动驾驶安全专家指出，本次停电风波暴露出高自动化出行系统在应对基础设施故障时的脆弱性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CNBC cited researchers' views, pointing out that scenarios like large-scale power outages are &quot;completely foreseeable&quot; in urban operations, and autonomous driving companies should reserve more sufficient redundancy and manual fallback mechanisms in their product design and deployment strategies;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            CNBC 援引研究者观点指出，像大规模停电这种情景在城市运行中「完全可预期」，自动驾驶企业应在产品设计和部署策略中预留更充分的冗余和人工兜底机制；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, city and state regulatory agencies also need to re-examine the &quot;penetration rate ceiling&quot; of highly automated vehicles in the road network, and clarify responsibility allocation in the event of &quot;chaotic congestion,&quot; making driverless car operators accountable for traffic behavior just like human drivers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，城市与州监管机构也需要重新审视高度自动化车辆在路网中的「渗透率上限」，并在发生「混乱式拥堵」时明确责任划分，让无人车运营方像人类司机一样为交通行为负责。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阿里千问 App 发布 2025 十大 AI 提示词：「股票」登顶</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">阿里千问-App-发布-2025-十大-AI-提示词：「股票」登顶</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/511b2383-e4a5-4248-ab1b-67f3de5d3300.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Alibaba's Qianwen App released its &quot;Top 10 AI Prompt Words for 2025&quot; list, with &quot;Stocks&quot; taking the top spot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，阿里千问 App 发布「2025 十大 AI 提示词」榜单，其中「股票」位列榜首。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The complete list includes: Stocks, Bazi (Eight Characters), Emotional Counseling, WeChat Moments Copywriting, Tourist Attraction Recommendations, Double Color Ball Numbers, Insomnia, Answering This Question, Division of Divorce Property, and The Meaning of Life, showcasing AI's multiple positioning in financial management, life assistance, emotional support, and educational legal scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            完整榜单包括：股票、八字、情感咨询、朋友圈文案、景点推荐、双色球号码、失眠、解答这道题、离婚财产分割、人生的意义，呈现 AI 在理财、生活助理、情绪支持及教育法律场景的多重定位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Data released by Alibaba shows that in just 23 days since its public beta, the &quot;Qianwen App&quot; has surpassed 30 million monthly active users across all platforms, becoming one of the fastest-growing AI applications globally.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            阿里公开的数据显示，「千问 App」公测仅 23 天，全端月活跃用户数已突破 3000 万，成为全球增速最快的 AI 应用之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Qianwen has opened four capabilities to all users: AI PPT, AI Writing, AI Library, and AI Tutoring. It continuously integrates into various life scenarios such as maps, food delivery, ticket booking, office work, learning, shopping, and health, strengthening its real-world &quot;task-handling&quot; capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，千问已面向所有用户开放 AI PPT、AI 写作、AI 文库及 AI 讲题四项能力，并持续接入地图、外卖、订票、办公、学习、购物、健康等生活场景，强化其现实「办事」能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>央行推「免申即享」信用修复：2026 年起自动调整征信</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">央行推「免申即享」信用修复：2026-年起自动调整征信</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/19551f3d-920b-4e58-a7af-c194c232089f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Xinhua News Agency, the People's Bank of China yesterday released a one-time credit repair policy arrangement to support individuals with damaged credit but active repayment to efficiently rebuild their credit. The policy will be implemented on an &quot;apply-free and enjoy&quot; basis, automatically identified and uniformly processed by the credit reporting system, effective from January 1, 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新华社报道，昨天中国人民银行发布一次性信用修复政策安排，支持信用受损但积极还款的个人高效重塑信用。政策以「免申即享」方式实施，由征信系统自动识别与统一处理，自 2026 年 1 月 1 日起生效。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Overdue information meeting the following conditions will not be displayed in personal credit reports:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            满足下述条件的逾期信息，将不在个人信用报告中展示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only applies to personal credit overdue information displayed in the People's Bank of China's credit reporting system;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overdue period occurred between January 1, 2020, and December 31, 2025;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single overdue amount does not exceed 10,000 yuan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overdue debt must be fully repaid by March 31, 2026 (inclusive).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding supporting measures, the public can confirm overdue information adjustments through online and offline channels. In the first half of 2026, two additional opportunities for free offline personal credit report inquiries will be provided to verify the repair progress and results.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            配套措施方面，公众可通过线上与线下渠道确认逾期信息调整情况。2026 年上半年将额外增加 2 次线下免费查询个人信用报告机会，以便核对修复进度与结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The central bank also reminds that the policy does not charge any fees and does not require third-party agents. Any attempt to solicit money or information under this guise is a scam, and the public can report it to the central bank's branches or the public security organs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            央行同时提醒，政策不收取费用、不需第三方代理，任何借此名义索要钱财或信息的均为诈骗，公众可向央行分支机构反映或向公安机关报案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            My country's centralized and unified credit reporting system has been online since 2006 and has become an important financial infrastructure. As of the end of November, it has collected information on 1.16 billion natural persons, of whom 810 million have credit records, and the cumulative annual query volume reached 6.58 billion times.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            我国集中统一征信系统自 2006 年上线，已成为重要金融基础设施。截至 11 月末已采集 11.6 亿自然人信息，其中 8.1 亿人有信贷记录，年度累计查询量达 65.8 亿次。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This one-time credit repair balances &quot;punishment for dishonesty&quot; with &quot;targeted measures&quot;. Through automation technology and limited conditions, it provides a channel for rebuilding credit for small overdue payments not caused by subjective intent, strengthening the fairness and accessibility of the credit system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次一次性信用修复兼顾「失信必惩」与「精准施策」，通过自动化技术与限定条件的约束，为非主观故意导致的小额逾期提供重塑信用的通道，强化信用体系的公平与可得性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>吉利汽车完成极氪私有化并全资控股，后者自纽交所退市</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">吉利汽车完成极氪私有化并全资控股，后者自纽交所退市</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9f96f86a-e055-4d42-9ea6-0aa11bcc35d7.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, Geely Automobile announced that it had officially completed the merger transaction and privatization process of its high-end electric vehicle brand, Zeekr. All preconditions for the various transactions contemplated under the merger agreement (including the privatization and merger) have been met, and the relevant transactions were completed yesterday.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，吉利汽车宣布已正式完成对旗下高端电动车品牌极氪的合并交易与私有化流程。合并协议项下拟进行的各项交易（包括私有化及合并事项）的所有先决条件均已满足，相关交易已于昨天完成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Zeekr was an indirect non-wholly owned subsidiary of Geely Automobile. After the transaction, Zeekr changed from an indirect non-wholly owned subsidiary to an indirect wholly-owned subsidiary of Geely Automobile.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前极氪为吉利汽车的间接非全资附属公司，交易完成后，极氪由间接非全资附属公司变为吉利汽车的间接全资附属公司。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the announcement submitted by Geely Automobile to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, the company has acquired all issued and outstanding Zeekr shares and Zeekr American Depositary Shares. The merged subsidiary has merged with Zeekr, and Zeekr continues to operate as the surviving entity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据吉利汽车向港交所提交的公告，公司已收购所有已发行及发行在外的极氪股份及极氪美国存托股份，合并附属公司已与极氪合并，极氪作为存续实体继续经营。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            With the completion of the transaction, Zeekr has been privatized to become a wholly-owned subsidiary of Geely Automobile and delisted from the NYSE. Zeekr's financial results will continue to be fully consolidated into Geely Automobile Group's consolidated financial statements, and amounts previously attributable to non-controlling shareholder interests will be reclassified and offset, thereby further unifying the asset and profit attribution structure of Geely and Zeekr financially.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着交易完成，极氪已私有化成为吉利汽车的全资附属公司，并从纽交所退市。极氪的财务业绩将继续全部并入吉利汽车集团的综合财务报表，先前归属于非控股股东权益的金额将被重新分类并予以对销，从而在财务上进一步统一吉利与极氪的资产与利润归属结构。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that Geely Automobile and Zeekr signed a merger agreement as early as July this year, which clearly stated that Geely would acquire all Zeekr shares it did not yet hold, and Zeekr shareholders could choose cash or exchange for Geely Automobile shares as consideration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开信息显示，吉利汽车与极氪早在今年 7 月已签署合并协议，当时即明确吉利将收购其尚未持有的全部极氪股份，极氪股东可选择以现金或置换吉利汽车股份作为对价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            With the official completion of this merger and privatization, Zeekr's delisting from the NYSE and return to the Geely system is seen as a crucial step for Geely in advancing its 'One Geely' strategy and strengthening its layout of new energy and smart electric high-end brands.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着本次合并与私有化的正式落地，极氪从纽交所退市、回归吉利体系内部，被视为吉利在推进「一个吉利」战略、强化新能源与智能电动高端品牌布局上的关键一步。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Geely Holding also previously stated that this move is an important step in implementing the spirit of the 'Taizhou Declaration,' which will help further synergize various business segments within the group at both capital and operational levels.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            吉利控股此前亦表示，此举是贯彻《台州宣言》精神的重要进展，有助于在资本层面和运营层面进一步协同集团内各业务板块。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>萝卜快跑将在伦敦开启无人驾驶服务，首次进入英国右舵市场</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">萝卜快跑将在伦敦开启无人驾驶服务，首次进入英国右舵市场</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3be47682-7531-4aba-83df-88654ce45deb.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Xinhua News Agency, yesterday, Baidu's autonomous driving mobility service platform 'Apollo Go' announced that it will partner with a global leading mobility platform to launch autonomous driving tests and mobility services in London, UK, in 2026. This marks its first entry into a right-hand drive market outside of Hong Kong, China.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新华社报道，昨天，百度旗下无人驾驶出行服务平台「萝卜快跑」宣布将携手全球领先出行平台，于 2026 年在英国伦敦开启无人驾驶测试及出行服务，这是其首次进入中国香港以外的右舵市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the end of November last year, Apollo Go was approved for Hong Kong's first pilot license for autonomous vehicles; over the past year, it has expanded its test areas four times in Hong Kong, achieving technological leaps such as multiple vehicles operating simultaneously, passenger testing, route expansion, and speed increase. The data and safe operational experience accumulated on complex right-hand drive urban roads have laid the technical foundation for entering London.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年 11 月底，萝卜快跑获批香港首个自动驾驶车辆先导牌照；过去一年在香港四度扩大测试区域，并实现多车同时运行、载客测试、路段扩展及车速提升等技术跃进，在复杂右舵城市道路中积累的数据与安全运营经验，为进入伦敦奠定技术基础。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Uber has officially announced its cooperation with Apollo Go, and Lyft CEO David Risher also posted on X that they will partner with Apollo Go, planning to test the first dozens of RT6 models in London next year, with the goal of gradually expanding to hundreds of vehicles, pending regulatory approval.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，Uber 已官宣与萝卜快跑合作，网约车公司 Lyft CEO David Risher 也在 X 发文称，将与萝卜快跑合作，计划明年在伦敦测试首批数十辆 RT6 车型，目标逐步扩展至数百辆，目前正等待监管部门批准。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steam 宣布停止支持 32 位客户端</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Steam-宣布停止支持-32-位客户端</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/fc389a85-51dc-413f-a342-76861bc62e8c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to TechPowerUp, Valve announced that the Steam client on Windows is fully transitioning to a 64-bit architecture, and the 32-bit version will cease updates and official support starting January 1, 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 TechPowerUp 报道，Valve 宣布 Steam 客户端在 Windows 端全面转向 64 位架构，32 位版本将于 2026 年 1 月 1 日起停止更新与官方支持。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, the official client update notes on December 19 had clarified this timeline; the adjustment is primarily to simplify maintenance and align with the industry trend of phasing out 32-bit software.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，官方已在 12 月 19 日的客户端更新说明中明确过这一时间表；该调整主要为简化维护并顺应行业淘汰 32 位软件的趋势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Valve's statistics show that users still running 32-bit Windows account for approximately 0.01%, so the affected group is extremely small. The official statement also emphasized that the 64-bit version of Steam supports Windows 11 and Windows 10.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Valve 统计显示，仍在使用 32 位 Windows 的用户占比约为 0.01%，因此受影响群体极小。官方同时强调，64 位版 Steam 支持 Windows 11 与 Windows 10。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this transition, Valve stated that the change only affects the client itself, and users' purchased 32-bit games will still run normally on 64-bit operating systems, unaffected.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在此次转向中，Valve 表示变更仅涉及客户端本身，用户已购的 32 位游戏在 64 位操作系统上仍可正常运行，不受影响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For the small number of players still using older hardware and 32-bit systems, they will no longer receive client security updates or technical support. If hardware permits, upgrading to a 64-bit operating system will allow them to continue receiving official support.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于仍在使用旧硬件与 32 位系统的少量玩家，届时将无法再获得客户端安全更新或技术支持，若硬件允许，升级至 64 位操作系统即可继续获得官方支持。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            From an ecosystem perspective, the memory addressing and performance bottlenecks of 32-bit systems (e.g., only being able to utilize about 4GB of RAM) are no longer suitable for current PC game loads. Unifying to a 64-bit architecture helps the client more efficiently utilize system resources, improving stability and scalability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从生态层面看，32 位系统的内存寻址与性能瓶颈（如仅能利用约 4GB 内存）早已不适配当下 PC 游戏负载，统一至 64 位架构有助于客户端更高效调用系统资源、提升稳定性与可扩展性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, recent Steam updates have introduced Nintendo Switch 2 controller support and optimized gyroscope operation logic.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，Steam 近期更新还引入了任天堂 Switch 2 手柄支持并优化了陀螺仪操作逻辑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>波士顿动力 Atlas 将亮相 CES 2026，现代汽车推进 AI 机器人商业化</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">波士顿动力-Atlas-将亮相-CES-2026，现代汽车推进-AI-机器人商业化</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/89b21f38-e60e-4b0f-9eb2-de02aaea2285.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Hyundai Motor Group officially announced that its subsidiary, Boston Dynamics, will publicly unveil the next-generation Atlas humanoid robot for the first time at CES 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，现代汽车集团官宣，旗下波士顿动力将于 CES 2026 首次公开展示新一代 Atlas 人形机器人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hyundai Motor Group stated in a press release that the live demonstration will take place from January 6-9 local time at the Las Vegas Convention Center, including hourly demonstrations of Atlas, Spot, and MobED, as well as interactive human-robot collaboration scenarios and R&amp;amp;D environment reproductions, highlighting the application of AI robots in industrial and daily settings.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            现代汽车集团在新闻稿中表示，现场展示将于当地时间 1 月 6 – 9 日在拉斯维加斯会展中心进行，包含 Atlas、Spot 与 MobED 的每小时演示以及人机协作的互动场景与研发环境复现，突出 AI 机器人在工业与日常场景的应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Korea JoongAng Daily, Atlas is positioned as a competitor to Tesla's Optimus robot and Figure AI's Figure 02, and has already conducted pilot demonstrations at Hyundai Motor Group's electric vehicle factory in Georgia, USA.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《韩国中央日报》报道，Atlas 被定位为特斯拉擎天柱 Optimus 机器人与 Figure AI 的 Figure 02 的竞争产品，已在现代汽车集团位于美国佐治亚州的电动车工厂开展试点演示。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hyundai Motor completed its acquisition of Boston Dynamics in 2021, and the latter's quadruped robot Spot has already been put into commercial use. Hyundai Motor also plans to invest approximately 50 trillion Korean Won in the AI field between 2026 and 2030, and build a robot manufacturing factory in the United States with an annual production capacity of 30,000 units.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            现代汽车在 2021 年完成对波士顿动力的收购，后者四足机器人 Spot 已投入商业应用。现代汽车还计划在 2026 – 2030 年向 AI 领域投入约 50 万亿韩元，并在美国建设一座年产能 30000 台的机器人制造工厂。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>全国机器人租赁峰会在沪举行，「擎天租」开启机器人租赁新生态</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">全国机器人租赁峰会在沪举行，「擎天租」开启机器人租赁新生态</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c1fb1e10-a251-4fe6-9472-deda8ca18253.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the National Robot Leasing Ecosystem Summit and the &quot;Qingtianzu&quot; Platform Launch Event were held in Shanghai. The conference, themed &quot;Gathering Wisdom and Strength, Co-creating a New Era,&quot; focused on building the robot leasing industry ecosystem and promoting the industry's transformation towards standardization and scale.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，全国机器人租赁生态峰会暨「擎天租」平台发布会在上海举行。大会以「智汇众力，共擎新元」为主题，聚焦机器人租赁产业生态共建，推动行业向标准化、规模化转型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the conference, Jiang Qingsong, partner of Zhiyuan AGIBOT and chairman of Qingtianzu, reviewed the development history of the robot leasing industry and proposed the &quot;Qingtianzu 1234 Strategic Plan&quot;: by 2026, achieve 10+ robot manufacturers, 200+ gold-certified service lessors, 3000+ content creators, and 400,000+ leasing customers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            会上，智元 AGIBOT 合伙人、擎天租董事长姜青松回顾了机器人租赁行业的发展历程，并提出「擎天租 1234 战略计划」：到 2026 年实现 10+ 本体厂家、200+ 金牌服务租赁商、3000+ 内容创作者、400000+ 租赁客户。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that only by uniting the forces of all parties in the industry chain can they jointly open up a new era of robot leasing and realize the vision of &quot;creating infinite productivity with intelligent machines&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，只有凝聚产业链各方力量，才能共同开拓机器人租赁新时代，推动「以智能机器创造无限生产力」的愿景落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Li Yiyan, CEO of Qingtianzu, introduced the platform's core functions. The platform connects users, merchants, and creators, providing content operations and business support. Users can directly place orders in the mall and enjoy service guarantees; merchants can complete onboarding and order management; creators can innovate content and integrate skill packages through the Zhiyuan Lingchuang platform.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            擎天租 CEO 李一言介绍了平台的核心功能。平台通过联通用户端、商家端和创作者，提供内容运营与经营支持，用户可直接在商城下单并享受服务保障；商家可完成入驻、订单管理；创作者则通过智元灵创平台进行内容创新与技能包集成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The platform has established nationwide leasing nodes, reaching 50 core cities, with 600+ service providers and 1000+ devices. It is expected to expand to 200+ cities by 2026, achieving nationwide delivery capability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            平台已建立覆盖全国的租赁节点，触达 50 个核心城市，拥有 600+ 服务商和 1000+ 台设备，预计到 2026 年将扩展至 200+ 城市，实现全国性交付能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the summit, several industry representatives shared their robot application practices and outlooks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            峰会现场，多位行业代表分享了机器人应用实践与展望。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yang Xuanzhi, Deputy Director of Haidilao Information Technology Department, demonstrated the application of intelligent robots in service experience and operational efficiency;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu Yuxiu, General Manager of Zhejiang Silicon-Based Ark Robotics Co., Ltd., proposed a vision for content development ecological cooperation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Han Yi, CEO of Guangzhou Spark Robotics Co., Ltd., elaborated on the co-creation and sharing ecological path;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cao Minghua, Deputy General Manager of PICC Property and Casualty Company Limited Zhejiang Branch, discussed how insurance mechanisms can contribute to high-quality industrial development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the &quot;Qingtianzu&quot; Application Innovation Community was officially unveiled. Pudong State-owned Assets, as an angel investor and strategic partner, provides office and innovation space at Zhangjiang Science Gate Molita and Zhangjiang Robot Valley for the platform and ecosystem enterprises.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，「擎天租」应用创新社区正式揭牌，浦东国资作为天使投资方与战略合作伙伴，为平台及生态企业提供张江科学之门模力塔与张江机器人谷的办公与创新空间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the launch ceremony, representatives from the government, investors, and various parties in the industry chain jointly lit up the platform, marking the official launch of the open robot leasing ecosystem. Robot performances in the outdoor exhibition area also attracted a large audience, with performances such as Peking Opera, crosstalk, calligraphy, song and dance, and Tai Chi demonstrating the possibilities of integrating technology and humanities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            发布仪式上，来自政府、投资方及产业链各方代表共同点亮平台，标志着开放式机器人租赁生态正式启航。外场展区的机器人表演也吸引了大量观众，京剧、相声、书法、歌舞、太极等演出展现了科技与人文融合的可能性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>保时捷中国自建充电站将关停</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">保时捷中国自建充电站将关停</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ce16a26d-008e-46f2-8228-77c254fa65a3.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, Porsche China yesterday issued a &quot;User Notice on the Cessation of Porsche Exclusive Charging,&quot; announcing that its self-built high-power DC charging network will cease operations from March 1, 2026, and relevant stations will be gradually removed from the charging maps in the Porsche App and Porsche WeChat mini-program.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，昨天保时捷中国发布「关于停止保时捷尊享充电的用户通知」，宣布其自建高功率直流充电网络将于 2026 年 3 月 1 日起停止运营，相关站点将从保时捷 App 与保时捷微信小程序的充电地图中逐步移除。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Porsche stated that this adjustment targets the &quot;Exclusive Charging&quot; scenario; charging stations installed within Porsche Centers (dealerships), Porsche Destination Charging stations, and third-party brand charging stations integrated into the Porsche charging map will remain operational.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            保时捷称，此次调整针对的是「尊享充电」场景；安装于保时捷中心（经销商店）内的充电站、保时捷目的地充电站，以及集成到保时捷充电地图的三方品牌充电站仍可正常使用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public data shows that the cessation of operations involves over 300 Porsche Exclusive Charging stations nationwide, covering major first and second-tier cities and key transportation routes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开数据显示，停运涉及全国范围内超过 300 座保时捷尊享充电站，覆盖主要一二线城市与重点交通干线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Porsche emphasized in its user notice and previous responses that it will continue to advance electrification and digital intelligence localized solutions in the Chinese market, with the next pure electric model being the all-new pure electric Cayenne, and that rumors of &quot;Porsche China possibly stopping sales of electric vehicles&quot; are a misinterpretation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            保时捷在用户通知与此前回应中强调，其在中国市场将持续推进电动化与数智化本土解决方案，下一款纯电车型为全新纯电动 Cayenne，对「保时捷中国可能停售电动车」的传闻属误读。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report cited financial results indicating that Porsche's sales revenue for the first three quarters of 2025 was 26.86 billion euros, a year-on-year decrease of 6%; operating profit was 40 million euros, a year-on-year plunge of 99% compared to 4.035 billion euros in the same period last year, with the operating profit margin falling from 14.1% to 0.2%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道援引财报指出，保时捷 2025 年前三季度销售收入为 268.6 亿欧元，同比下降 6%；营业利润为 4000 万欧元，较去年同期 40.35 亿欧元同比暴跌 99%，营业利润率由 14.1% 降至 0.2%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The decline in profits is related to restructuring expenses resulting from strategic adjustments, including the postponement of pure electric vehicle launches and the termination of in-house battery production plans, with additional costs of approximately 2.7 billion euros.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            利润下滑与战略调整带来的重组支出相关，包括推迟纯电车型推出与终止电池自产计划等，额外成本约 27 亿欧元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 不是只有芯片：250 亿美元信用投资人谈 AI 真正的长期机会</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-不是只有芯片：250-亿美元信用投资人谈-AI-真正的长期机会</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3bdc4a14-8292-4140-88ce-34b4f4590178.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Scott Goodwin, co-founder and managing partner of Diameter Capital, a credit investment firm managing approximately $25 billion in assets, stated that the true opportunities in the AI boom extend beyond chips and data centers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，管理约 250 亿美元资产的信用投资机构 Diameter Capital 联合创始人兼管理合伙人 Scott Goodwin 表示，人工智能热潮的真正机会不止于芯片与数据中心。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Goodwin pointed out that AI's long-term cycle will unlock value through broader infrastructure and adoption competition.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Goodwin 指出，AI 的长期周期将通过更广泛的基础设施与采用竞争释放价值。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated on the &quot;Goldman Sachs Exchanges&quot; podcast that the team focuses on less obvious bottlenecks and pricing mismatches in the credit market driven by AI demand, and that this &quot;hyper-micro cycle&quot; will continue and reshape the investment landscape.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他在《Goldman Sachs Exchanges》播客上称，团队关注 AI 需求推动的、在信用市场上不那么显眼的瓶颈与定价错配，这一「超微周期」将持续并重塑投资版图。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Goodwin revealed that Diameter Capital bought unsecured debt from a mid-sized telecom company in 2023, with the logic that as businesses shift from training models to practical applications, demand will move from &quot;just looking at chips&quot; to networks and commercial fiber optics that carry data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Goodwin 透露，Diameter Capital 在 2023 年买入一家中型电信公司的无担保债务，逻辑是当企业从训练模型转向实际应用，需求将从「只看芯片」转向承载数据的网络与商用光纤。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Data must leave the data center, but how? Through the pipeline of commercial fiber optics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, the telecom company signed contracts worth over $10 billion with several hyperscale cloud service providers, and its debt price recovered to par value. In addition, Diameter Capital also made a &quot;heavy bet&quot; on a satellite company related to wireless spectrum, and after the company sold its spectrum assets, its debt also returned to par value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后，该电信公司与多家超大规模云服务商签下逾 100 亿美元合同，其债务价格回升至面值。此外，Diameter Capital 还对一家与无线频谱相关的卫星公司进行「重注」，在该公司出售频谱资产后，其债务亦回到面值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the risk front, Goodwin warned that AI-related credit transactions, especially chip financing, are accumulating &quot;residual value risk&quot; that is difficult to price – some investors are betting on the residual value of hardware years from now, but cutting-edge technology updates frequently, and chips quickly become obsolete for some customers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在风险层面，Goodwin 警示 AI 相关信用交易，尤其是芯片融资，正在累积难以定价的「剩余价值风险」—— 部分投资者押注数年后硬件的残余价值，但前沿技术更新频繁、芯片对部分客户而言很快过时。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;We ask experts from Silicon Valley and large tech companies to assess the residual value of these chips three to seven years from now, but no one can give a definitive answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that the next phase is not just about infrastructure capital expenditure, but about the competitive shifts brought by AI adoption: &quot;Who can leverage AI to lead peers, and who will be the loser?&quot; This competitive cycle will be longer than a pure Capex cycle.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，下一阶段不只是基础设施资本开支，而是围绕 AI 采用带来的竞争位势变化：「谁能借助 AI 领先同行，谁会成为输家？」这一竞争周期将长于纯粹的 Capex 周期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Goodwin's view also responds to the market's debate on the sustainability of AI's high valuations: instead of just betting on the most obvious winners, what's more noteworthy at the credit level are &quot;overlooked bottlenecks&quot; such as network transmission, spectrum, and satellites, as well as the impact pathways of the speed and breadth of enterprise adoption on cash flow and capital structure.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Goodwin 的观点也回应了市场对 AI 高估值可持续性的争论：与其只押注最显眼的赢家，信用层面更值得留意的是网络传输、频谱与卫星等「被忽视的瓶颈」，以及企业落地采用的速度与广度对现金流与资本结构的影响路径。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This means the core of AI transactions is shifting from &quot;manufacturing equipment and building data centers&quot; to &quot;which types of companies can leverage AI for productivity advantages and at what pace,&quot; and re-evaluating risks and returns accordingly.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这意味着 AI 交易的核心从「造设备、建机房」转向「哪类公司以何种节奏把 AI 用出生产力优势」，并据此重估风险与回报。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2699 元起，华为 nova 15 系列正式发布</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2699-元起，华为-nova-15-系列正式发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/42c14b28-43ae-406e-b498-ef14248a8907.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Huawei officially released the new nova 15 series, all models featuring a first-generation Hongfeng lens on the rear, supporting AI-assisted composition, personalized color cards, and 100W wired charging.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，华为正式发布 nova 15 系列新机，全系后置支持第一代红枫镜头，支持 AI 辅助构图，个性色卡及 100W 有线充电。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of battery life, the Huawei nova 15 Standard Edition has a built-in 6000mAh battery, while the nova 15 Ultra and nova 15 Pro are equipped with 6500mAh batteries, with the Ultra model additionally featuring 50W wireless charging.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            续航方面，华为 nova 15 标准版内置 6000mAh 电池，nova 15 Ultra 与 nova 15 Pro 配备 6500mAh 电池，Ultra 机型新增 50W 无线充电。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            nova 15 Ultra:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            nova 15 Ultra:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Kirin 9010S processor;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 50W wireless charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear 50MP RYYB variable aperture main camera, supporting OIS, 50MP RYYB ultra-wide macro, 50MP RYYB periscope telephoto, and a first-generation 1.5MP Hongfeng primary color multispectral lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of pricing:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            价格方面：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nova 15 256GB version starts at 2699 yuan, and the 512GB version at 2999 yuan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nova 15 Pro 256GB for 3499 yuan, 256GB Kunlun Glass for 3599 yuan, 512GB Kunlun Glass for 3899 yuan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nova 15 Ultra 256GB Kunlun Glass for 4199 yuan, 512GB Kunlun Glass for 4499 yuan, 1TB Basalt Tempered Kunlun Glass for 4999 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the nova 15 series supports the &quot;HarmonyOS Ecosystem Daily Check-in Red Packet&quot; event, where users can receive random cash red packets for 30 consecutive days in the Huawei Wallet App.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，nova 15 系列支持「鸿蒙生态日日新签到红包」活动，用户可在华为钱包 App 连续 30 天领取随机现金红包。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1999 元起，夸克 AI 眼镜再上新</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1999-元起，夸克-AI-眼镜再上新</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/cd5cd00f-fa7b-4e50-a9fe-95df2aba7508.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Quark AI Glasses officially launched pre-sales for two new products, with the G1 Fashion Browline model starting at just 1999 yuan, making it the first affordable AI glasses from Qianwen; the popular flagship S1 series added a round tortoiseshell color, offering consumers more choices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，夸克 AI 眼镜正式开启两款新品预售，其中 G1 风尚眉框款最低到手价仅 1999 元，成为千问首款平价 AI 眼镜；热销的旗舰款 S1 系列新增圆框玳瑁配色，为消费者提供更多选择。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            While maintaining an accessible price point, the new G1 keeps its core hardware configuration consistent with the flagship S1 series, allowing users to get a complete AI interactive experience including voice Q&amp;amp;A, real-time translation, information inquiry, and smart photography at a lower price:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新品 G1 在定价亲民的前提下在核心硬件配置上与旗舰 S1 系列保持一致，用户可在更低价格下获得语音问答、实时翻译、信息查询、智能拍摄等完整 AI 交互体验：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with dual flagship chips and dual systems;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features acoustic hardware such as a five-microphone array plus bone conduction, and large-diaphragm high-performance speakers;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 0.6-second rapid capture and 3K video recording;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weighs approximately 40g, featuring a swan-neck adjustable bracket and FDA food-grade silicone nose pads;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in Qianwen AI assistant, supporting cross-scenario invocation of Alibaba ecosystem services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new S1 series continues its flagship positioning, with the new round tortoiseshell model maintaining a leading edge in display, wearability, and imaging, and boasting a more retro and fashionable appearance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            S1 系列新品延续旗舰定位，新增圆框玳瑁款在显示、佩戴与影像方面保持领先优势，外观更具复古与时尚属性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, both new products have started pre-sales on online channels such as Tmall, Douyin, and JD.com, and 604 offline stores in 82 cities nationwide will also successively provide eyewear fitting, experience, and purchasing services.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，两款新品已在天猫、抖音、京东等线上渠道开启预售，全国 82 个城市的 604 家线下门店也将陆续提供配镜、体验与购买服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wu Jia, Vice President of Alibaba Group, previously stated that AI glasses are the sensory hub for human-computer interaction, and equipping glasses with the Qianwen AI assistant can better understand user needs and provide value on a larger scale.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            阿里巴巴集团副总裁吴嘉此前表示，AI 眼镜是人机交互的感官中枢，在眼镜上搭载千问 AI 助手，能够更好理解用户需求，并在更大范围内提供价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小米 17 Ultra 定档 12 月 25 日</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小米-17-Ultra-定档-12-月-25-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8fc20fb6-dc6b-40b1-9d0a-04cab8533717.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Xiaomi officially announced that the Xiaomi 17 Ultra launch event is scheduled for December 25th at 19:00, focusing on imaging upgrades for night scenes and telephoto under the new generation &quot;strategic co-creation mode&quot; with Leica.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小米手机官宣小米 17 Ultra 发布会定档 12 月 25 日 19:00，并在新一代与徕卡的「战略共创模式」下，主打夜景与长焦的影像升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official poster shows the body available in black and white, with a large circular camera module centered, the Leica logo in the middle, an &quot;Ultra&quot; nameplate in the upper left corner, and the side volume buttons changed to two independent round buttons.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方海报显示，机身提供黑、白两种配色，居中大圆相机模组，徕卡标位于中央，左上角印有「Ultra」铭牌，侧边音量键改为两颗独立圆形按键。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Xiaomi also officially announced a new &quot;Starry Green&quot; color scheme, incorporating mineral particles, also featuring two independent round volume buttons and a wrapped mid-frame, with an ultra-large R-angle 2D flat screen on the front, and a body thickness of 8.29mm, touted as &quot;the thinnest Ultra to date.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，小米还官宣了全新「星空绿」配色，融入矿石颗粒，同样采用两颗独立圆形音量键与包裹式中框，正面为超大 R 角 2D 直屏，机身厚度 8.29mm，号称「迄今最薄 Ultra」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding performance configuration, the official statement emphasizes that the new phone continues its &quot;new generation night god&quot; positioning, expected to bring significant imaging upgrades. Online leaks are summarized as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            性能配置方面，官方强调新机延续「新一代夜神」定位，预计在影像上带来明显升级，网传爆料整理如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Qualcomm's fifth-generation Snapdragon 8 Extreme Edition;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear 50-megapixel main camera (OmniVision OV50X, 1-inch large sensor, supports third-generation LOFIC technology) + 50-megapixel ultra-wide-angle + 200-megapixel periscope telephoto;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports dust and water resistance, UWB, and the top-end version is expected to support satellite communication;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battery is expected to be 6800 mAh, supporting 100W fast charging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the price, according to previous reports, Lu Weibing stated during a live broadcast interaction that the Xiaomi 17 Ultra &quot;will definitely increase in price,&quot; with the increase mainly driven by a sharp rise in memory prices, compounded by rising costs for processors, cameras, and other components.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            价格方面，据此前报道，卢伟冰在直播互动中表示，小米 17 Ultra「一定会涨价」，涨幅主要由内存价格猛涨驱动，且叠加处理器、相机等成本上涨。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He recalled mentioning &quot;the last time it was 6499 yuan&quot; when discussing the previous Xiaomi 15 Ultra, stating that memory factors were not fully accounted for at the time. He predicted that 2025-2027 would be a period of rising memory costs, so although the current price increase is significant, it is still low compared to the increase in memory costs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他回顾此前小米 15 Ultra 时提到「最后一次 6499 元」，并称当时未充分计入内存因素，预判 2025—2027 年将是内存成本上涨周期，因此本次涨价幅度虽高，但相较内存成本涨幅仍低。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the Xiaomi Watch 5 smartwatch will also debut at this launch event, featuring a Snapdragon W5 processor, EMG electromyography sensor, ECG electrocardiogram sensor, double-sided artificial sapphire glass, and an integrated forged stainless steel case, positioned as a &quot;fully smart flagship.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，小米 Watch 5 智能手表也将在本次发布会上亮相，搭载骁龙 W5 处理器、EMG 肌电信号传感器、ECG 心电传感器、双面人工蓝宝石玻璃、一体锻造不锈钢表壳，定位为「全智能旗舰」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>可灵 O1 亮相首届香港国际 AI 艺术节</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">可灵-O1-亮相首届香港国际-AI-艺术节</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4bab0ce4-7a01-46dc-b039-fedc50fff5aa.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the first Hong Kong International AI Art Festival, the &quot;AI Creation Global Ecosystem Forum&quot; was held on December 19, 2025. The forum focused on &quot;Cross-boundary Exploration of Technology, Art, and Film and Television&quot; and screened three short films jointly completed by global artists and Keling AI super creators, receiving enthusiastic responses on site.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            首届香港国际 AI 艺术节期间，「AI 创作全球生态论坛」在 2025 年 12 月 19 日举行，论坛以「技术、艺术与影视的跨界探索」为主题，并展映三支由全球艺术家与可灵 AI 超级创作者联合完成的短片，现场获得热烈反响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Art and industry participants explored the reshaping of the creative ecosystem and expressive boundaries by AI technology from multiple dimensions, including computer science, human-computer collaboration, film and television industry, and educational innovation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            艺术与产业参与者从计算机科学、人机协作、影视工业与教育革新多个维度，探讨 AI 技术对创作生态与表达边界的重塑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Keling AI demonstrated the core capabilities of its &quot;Keling O1&quot; model on-site, calling it the world's first unified multimodal video and image creation tool. It aims to break through the limitations of &quot;language description&quot; alone, redefine human-AI interaction, and accelerate the arrival of a tipping point for &quot;producing good content at scale with AI.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            可灵 AI 在现场系统演示了「可灵 O1」模型的核心能力，称其为全球首个统一的多模态视频及图片创作工具，意在突破仅凭「语言描述」的局限，重新定义人类与 AI 的交互方式，加速「用 AI 规模化生产好内容」的临界点到来。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Several guests emphasized AI's tool-like nature and the irreplaceable role of human creators. Hopcroft pointed out that the essence of current AI is &quot;pattern recognition,&quot; which will not replace artists but will change their working methods;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多位嘉宾强调 AI 的工具属性与人类创作者的不可替代性。霍普克罗夫特指出当前 AI 的本质是「模式识别」，其不会取代艺术家但会改变工作方式；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Fei Jun proposed &quot;perceptual ability&quot; and &quot;hybrid intelligence,&quot; emphasizing creation that counters excessive rationality with anti-causal, anti-encoding, and anti-experiential approaches; Wang Hongwei, referencing film history, called on the industry to avoid path dependence and remain open to foster new languages and viewing habits.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            费俊提出「感能」与「混合智能」，强调以反因果、反编码、反经验的创作应对过度理性；王红卫以电影史为参照，呼吁业界避免路径依赖，保持开放以孕育新语言与新观看习惯。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the industry level, producer and visual effects supervisor Ma Wenxian used practical examples to illustrate AI's role in cost reduction and efficiency improvement in special effects preview, voiceprint replication, and local IP development, but emphasized that creators' &quot;precise judgment and control&quot; remain the core value;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在产业层面，监制与视觉特效总监马文现以实际案例说明 AI 在特效预览、声纹复制、本土 IP 开发中的降本增效作用，但强调创作者的「精准判断与把控」仍是核心价值；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Rao Anyi proposed using controllable models and an Agentic AI multi-agent collaborative framework to improve generation accuracy and efficiency, lower the barrier to entry, capture creative intent, and thus bridge the representational differences between humans and machines.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            饶安逸提出以可控模型与 Agentic AI 多智能体协同框架，提升生成精度与效率，降低使用门槛、捕捉创作意图，从而弥合人机之间的表征差异。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Keling AI stated that it will continue to lower the barrier to expression and build a creative ecosystem through technological iteration, creator support, and global competitions, looking forward to the first truly meaningful AI feature film and more milestones.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            可灵 AI 表示，将通过技术迭代、创作者扶持与全球赛事，持续降低表达门槛、建设创作生态，期待迎来第一部真正意义上的 AI 电影长片与更多里程碑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FILA 发布 4810 凌峰科技国家队 3.0 比赛服</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">FILA-发布-4810-凌峰科技国家队-3.0-比赛服</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8dbd7f97-03a0-405a-a129-fd5302d334a0.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, during the &quot;2025 FIS Freestyle Ski Aerials World Cup&quot; at Genting Snow Park in Chongli, Zhangjiakou, sports fashion brand FILA released the new 3.0 competition suit for the Chinese National Freestyle Ski Aerials Team and simultaneously launched a themed documentary titled &quot;Ascending Peaks, Reaching New Heights.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，运动时尚品牌 FILA 在张家口崇礼云顶滑雪公园的「2025 国际雪联自由式滑雪空中技巧世界杯」期间发布中国自由式滑雪空中技巧国家队全新 3.0 比赛服，并同步推出主题纪录片《凌峰而上，再造新高》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new product features FILA 4810 Lingfeng technology, showcasing the long-term collaborative research and adjustment process with the national team regarding the competition suit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新品搭载 FILA 4810 凌峰科技，展示与国家队围绕比赛服的长期共研与调校过程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            FILA stated that the 3.0 competition suit underwent a systematic upgrade in material selection, structural design, and pattern cutting, based on the national team's actual needs in extreme cold and high-speed competition environments, precisely supporting athletes' peak performance in the four dimensions of stability, difficulty, accuracy, and aesthetics.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            FILA 表示，此次 3.0 比赛服基于国家队在极寒高速竞赛环境的真实需求，从材料选择、结构设计与版型剪裁进行系统升级，精准支撑运动员在稳、难、准、美四个维度的极限表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this World Cup, Chinese team members, wearing the new equipment, swept the women's, men's, and mixed team events, winning a total of 3 gold, 3 silver, and 1 bronze medals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在本届世界杯中，中国队员身着该新装备，一举包揽女子、男子及混合团体项目，共计斩获 3 金 3 银 1 铜。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            FILA has been deeply involved in the ice and snow sector for over 50 years, launching the SNOW TIME professional ice and snow product series in 1981.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            FILA 深耕冰雪领域已逾 50 年，1981 年推出 SNOW TIME 专业冰雪产品系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since 2014, FILA has maintained cooperation with the Chinese National Freestyle Ski Aerials Team and will return to its brand origin, Italy, in 2026, continuously supporting the Chinese team in pursuing higher goals with an evolved technological system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自 2014 年起，FILA 与中国自由式滑雪空中技巧国家队保持合作，并将在 2026 年重返品牌发源地意大利主场，以进化的科技体系持续支持中国队征战更高目标。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>央视曝光直播间「大牌尾货」源自旧衣回收箱</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">央视曝光直播间「大牌尾货」源自旧衣回收箱</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/54eef9bc-a7a5-4c76-a59c-81bc9dc51901.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, CCTV's &quot;Financial Investigation&quot; exposed some e-commerce live streams selling low-priced second-hand old clothes under the guise of &quot;big brand overstock&quot; and &quot;new sample garments.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，央视《财经调查》曝光部分电商直播间以「大牌尾货」「新品样衣」为名销售低价二手旧衣。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reporters placed GPS trackers in old clothes recycling bins in different areas of Tieling City. Days later, they discovered the clothes had been transported to a corn storage warehouse, which was filled with &quot;boxed goods&quot; merely covered with rags, emitting a pungent odor; the warehouse manager stated that this location was an old clothes sorting factory.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            记者在铁岭市不同区域旧衣回收箱内放入定位追踪器，数日后发现衣物被运至玉米收储仓库，库房堆满仅用破布裹覆的「箱货」，气味刺鼻；库房管理员称此处为旧衣分拣厂。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The person in charge of the recycling plant stated that a large number of old clothes flow into live-streaming rooms, where those in better condition are refurbished, given new tags, and sold as new products, with considerable sales. This chain transforms old clothes recycling, which has a public welfare nature, into an important source of goods for live-streaming rooms, and the absence of platform product spot checks and authorization reviews has also been questioned.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            回收厂负责人表示，大量旧衣流向直播间，成色较好的被翻新、挂上新吊牌当作新品售卖，且销量不低。这一链条将具有公益属性的旧衣回收异化为直播间重要货源，平台商品抽检与授权审核的缺位也被质疑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, some live-streaming rooms sell shoddy products of unknown origin under the guise of &quot;one-of-a-kind samples,&quot; and impose &quot;take-it-as-is, no returns or exchanges&quot; unfair terms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，有直播间以「孤品样衣」名义售卖质量粗劣、来源不明的商品，并设置「默认为瑕疵品、不退不换」等霸王条款。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Paper commented that the placement of old clothes recycling bins in residential communities is often accompanied by unclear qualifications and the abuse of &quot;public welfare donation&quot; labels. According to relevant regulations, public fundraising requires qualifications; the placement of recycling bins in communities involves changing the use function of common parts owned by residents, and property management, community, and civil affairs departments should verify the qualifications and flow of the recycling entity beforehand.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《澎湃新闻》评论指出，旧衣回收箱在小区设置常伴随资质不清与「公益捐赠」标签滥用，按相关法规，公开募捐需具备资格；小区设置回收箱涉及业主共有部分使用功能改变，物业、社区与民政部门应事前核验回收主体资质与流向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Clothing tags should ideally indicate product name, specifications, material content, washing instructions, safety category, manufacturer's name and address, production date, etc. However, recycled old clothes clearly struggle to meet these requirements, leading to risks of false labeling and counterfeiting.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            衣物吊牌本应标注产品名称、规格型号、成分含量、洗涤说明、安全类别、厂名厂址、生产日期等，但回收旧衣显然难以满足，衍生虚假标注与造假风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Industry data shows that the old clothes recycling market already showed signs of a hundred-billion-level scale as early as 2021; it is estimated that by 2030, China's annual discarded old clothes will rise to 50 million tons, with an average of about 16 pieces discarded per person per year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            业内资料显示，旧衣回收市场早在 2021 年已显露千亿级规模雏形；预计到 2030 年，我国每年丢弃旧衣将升至 5000 万吨，人均每年淘汰约 16 件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some old clothes enter the secondary sales chain directly without cleaning or disinfection, posing hygiene and health risks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分旧衣未清洗、未消杀直接进入二次销售链条，带来卫生与健康风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public opinion and media are calling for relevant departments and platforms to intervene quickly, investigate, and hold accountable according to regulations, to complete key links such as qualification review, authorization verification, product spot checks, and traceability disposal, and to promote standardized and transparent governance of live-streaming e-commerce.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            舆论与媒体呼吁，相关部门与平台应依规快速介入、查处并追责，补齐资质审核、授权核验、商品抽检与溯源处置等关键环节，推动直播电商规范化与透明化治理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>「手机壳界爱马仕」再涨价，华强北 20 元仿货遍地</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">「手机壳界爱马仕」再涨价，华强北-20-元仿货遍地</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e14103d6-ff0a-4c12-8878-189cab34a53e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a report by Time Finance, CASETiFY recently uniformly increased the price of phone cases by 10 yuan in its official flagship store, with customer service stating that &quot;the price is determined by a combination of multiple factors.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《时代财经》报道，CASETiFY 近日在官方旗舰店统一上调手机壳售价 10 元，客服称「价格是由多种因素综合决定」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The brand was co-founded by Wesley Ng and Ronald Yeung in Hong Kong in 2011, and has long been marketed with high prices and trendy collaborations; currently, iPhone 15, 16, and 17 series phone cases are priced at 439 yuan, 479 yuan, and 519 yuan respectively, with the
            &lt;strong&gt;
             highest-priced style in the Tmall store reaching 739 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该品牌由吴培燊与杨子业于 2011 年在香港联合创立，长期以高价与潮流联名为卖点；目前 iPhone 15、16、17 系列手机壳定价分别为 439 元、479 元、519 元，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             天猫店铺中最高价款式达 739 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CASETiFY builds brand awareness through celebrity endorsements, collaborative partnerships, and high-end commercial district locations, continuing personalized customization services and strengthening the recognition of its brand name on the camera frame.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            CASETiFY 以明星种草、联名合作与高端商圈选址构建品牌心智，延续个性化定制服务并强化镜头框品牌名的辨识度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to previous media reports, its annual average sales of phone cases exceeded 3 million units in 2021, maintaining profitability for many years, with revenue of approximately US$300 million (about 2.1 billion RMB) in 2022; recent unconfirmed data claims its 2024 revenue reached 3.6 billion yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据媒体此前报道，2021 年其年均手机壳销量超 300 万件、连续多年保持盈利，2022 年营收约 3 亿美元（约 21 亿人民币）；近期未经官方证实的数据称其 2024 年营收达 36 亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some limited-edition collaborations command significant premiums in the secondary market, such as the
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Crayon Shin-chan co-branded phone stand, originally priced at 509 yuan, reselling for 889 yuan, and the Takashi Murakami co-branded vertical phone case, originally priced at 2189 yuan, reselling for 2589 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分限量联名在二级市场显著溢价，如
            &lt;strong&gt;
             蜡笔小新联名手机支架原价 509 元、转售价 889 元，村上隆联名立式手机壳原价 2189 元、转售价 2589 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In Huaqiangbei, Shenzhen, CASETiFY fakes have become widespread: low-quality fakes retail for 20-30 yuan, wholesale for 10-15 yuan; higher-quality fakes, closer to the genuine product in craftsmanship, retail for about 50-60 yuan, wholesale for about 40 yuan, with some stalls claiming small batch orders can be shipped within 2 days.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在深圳华强北，CASETiFY 仿款已成规模：低仿零售价 20～30 元、批发价 10～15 元；做工更接近正品的高仿零售价约 50～60 元、批发价约 40 元，部分档口称小批量订单可在 2 天内出货。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sales of related fake products on e-commerce platforms are high, with multiple Taobao stores selling over 2,000 units of a single item, and some Pinduoduo stores accumulating over 5 million &quot;group purchases.&quot; The complete accessory industry chain and rapid design imitation put pressure on the high-premium model, which relies on design and drop protection as selling points, leading to profit and brand dilution.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电商平台相关仿款销量高企，淘宝多家店铺单款销量超 2000 件，拼多多有店铺累计「已拼」超过 500 万件。完善的配件产业链和快速跟风的设计，使以设计与防跌为卖点的高溢价模式面临利润与品牌稀释的压力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《匿杀》预售开启，跨年定档 12 月 31 日</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《匿杀》预售开启，跨年定档-12-月-31-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1257fdbf-fbee-4d6d-a56a-2d61a47fd152.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the movie &quot;The Hidden Killer&quot; officially opened for pre-sale and released a new trailer and poster. The film is scheduled for national release on December 31st, aiming for a &quot;stress-relieving New Year's greeting&quot; during the New Year's Eve slot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，电影《匿杀》正式开启预售，并发布全新预告与海报，影片定档 12 月 31 日全国上映，主打跨年档期的「解压贺岁」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film's setting continues the director's &quot;kill&quot; universe: the story revolves around &quot;Hell Painter&quot; Fang Tianyang and &quot;Police War God&quot; Fang Zhengnan, siblings investigating a series of murders. A bloodbath from fifteen years ago and young victims lured by the lie of &quot;shaping the future&quot; form the core suspense.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片设定延续导演的「杀」宇宙：故事围绕「地狱画手」方天阳与「警界战神」方正楠姐弟追查连环命案展开，十五年前的血案与被「塑造未来」谎言诱骗的少年受害者构成核心悬念。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《海绵宝宝：深海大冒险》开启预售，定档元旦</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《海绵宝宝：深海大冒险》开启预售，定档元旦</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d297d4c4-40ac-497b-9f37-3f81c4a39257.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;SpongeBob SquarePants: Deep Sea Adventure&quot; officially announced the start of national pre-sales yesterday, simultaneously releasing a &quot;New Challenge&quot; trailer. It is scheduled for release in mainland China on January 1, 2026, New Year's Day.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《海绵宝宝：深海大冒险》已于昨天官宣开启全国预售，并同步释出「全新挑战」预告，内地定档 2026 年 1 月 1 日元旦上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the film's setting, SpongeBob will journey with the pirate ghost &quot;Flying Dutchman&quot; to the Underworld Sea, facing his biggest challenge yet; Patrick Star accompanies him throughout, cheering on his friend in a direct and sincere manner, continuing the series' nonsensical humor and warm tone.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片设定中，海绵宝宝将随海盗幽灵「飞天魔鬼」前往幽冥海域，面对迄今为止的最大挑战；派大星全程陪伴并以直接、真诚的方式为好友加油，延续系列无厘头笑点与温暖基调。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《他年她日》开启跨年预售</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 04:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《他年她日》开启跨年预售</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251223_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/59fd8b09-94e1-4c92-953a-1b219d099271.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the fantasy romance film &quot;His Years, Her Days&quot; announced the full launch of its New Year's Eve pre-sale, simultaneously releasing the &quot;Love is a Choice&quot; trailer and pre-sale poster; the film is scheduled for release on December 31st for New Year's Eve.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，奇幻爱情片《他年她日》宣布全面开启跨年档预售，并同步释出「爱是选择」版预告及预售海报；影片定档 12 月 31 日跨年上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film uses the time setting of &quot;his year is her day&quot; to convey the waiting and choices in real-life love. The trailer further reveals the cruel time inequality of &quot;Long Year Zone&quot; and &quot;Optimal Day Zone,&quot; enhancing the ritualistic feel of New Year's Eve viewing; the pre-sale poster uses blue daisies as a visual focus, imbuing them with symbolic meanings of &quot;happiness,&quot; &quot;hope,&quot; and &quot;eternal love,&quot; echoing the film's thematic expression of unequal giving and active choice.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片以「他的一年是她的一天」的时间设定承载现实爱情的等待与抉择，预告进一步揭示「长年区」「优日区」的残酷时间不等式，强化跨年观影的仪式感；预售海报以蓝色雏菊为视觉焦点，赋予「幸福」「希望」「永恒的爱」的象征意义，呼应片中对不对等付出与主动选择的主题表达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
