<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Air 国行 eSIM 最新情况，三大运营商均支持</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">iPhone-Air-国行-eSIM-最新情况，三大运营商均支持</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9ddfce8e-196b-4ed8-a9c3-1e34e1689939.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As one of the most anticipated new iPhones this year, the iPhone Air features a brand-new eSIM design without a physical SIM card slot, and therefore could not be launched for sale immediately.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            作为今年最瞩目的新 iPhone 之一，iPhone Air 采用了全新的 eSIM 设计，没有实体 SIM 卡槽，因此未能第一时间启动发售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            iFanr also confirmed this news with Apple officials yesterday morning, and Apple stated that it is working closely with regulatory agencies and will launch the iPhone Air for sale as soon as it receives approval.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            爱范儿也在昨日上午第一时间与苹果官方确认了此消息，苹果官方表示，正与监管机构紧密合作，并将在获批后第一时间启动 iPhone Air 发售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the afternoon, our inquiry with Apple's official website revealed that the iPhone Air's introduction page has been updated with information regarding eSIM:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            下午，据我们查询苹果官方发现，iPhone Air 的介绍页中更新了 eSIM 的相关说明：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;China Mobile, China Telecom, and China Unicom will provide eSIM support for this product, with the specific timing depending on regulatory approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, the official iPhone Air introduction stated that eSIM only supported China Unicom.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在此前，iPhone Air 官方介绍显示，eSIM 仅支持中国联通。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the iPhone 17 series officially began pre-sales at 8 PM last night. According to data cited by Yicai from JD.com:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，iPhone 17 系列昨晚 8 点正式开启预售。据第一财经援引京东数据显示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Just 1 minute after pre-sales began, the transaction volume of the iPhone 17 series surpassed that of the entire day last year, once again setting a new sales record. Among them, the iPhone 17 256GB version's transaction volume significantly exceeded its predecessor year-on-year, becoming the most popular model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that due to 'many Pro features and configurations being brought down, and the price of the basic version (256GB) not increasing (starting price of 5999 yuan)', the iPhone 17's pre-sale reservation volume on JD.com has exceeded 3 million, more than ten times that of the iPhone 16 (around 170,000).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，iPhone 17 因「许多 Pro 功能和配置下放，基础版（256GB）价格没上涨（起售价为 5999 元）」，其在京东的开售前预约量已突破 300 万，是 iPhone 16 的整整十倍还多（17 万左右）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小鹏召回 4.7 万台 P7+：转向助力失效</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小鹏召回-4.7-万台-P7+：转向助力失效</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8a0c18b0-37d4-4456-8984-172952e35c6f.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, according to information disclosed on the website of the State Administration for Market Regulation, Zhaoqing XPeng New Energy Investment Co., Ltd. recently filed a recall plan with the State Administration for Market Regulation:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，据市场监管总局网站披露，肇庆小鹏新能源投资有限公司近日向国家市场监督管理总局备案了召回计划：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The recall number is S2025M0142V and will be implemented starting September 15, 2025, involving some XPeng P7+ vehicles produced between August 20, 2024, and April 27, 2025, totaling 47,490 units.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次召回编号为 S2025M0142V，将自 2025 年 9 月 15 日起实施，涉及 2024 年 8 月 20 日至 2025 年 4 月 27 日期间生产的部分小鹏 P7+ 汽车，共计 47490 辆。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official announcement stated that some vehicles within the scope of this recall may have poor contact in the steering assist motor sensor harness, which could lead to fluctuations in the steering gear sensor signal, triggering the steering fault warning light to illuminate, and causing steering assist failure, posing a safety hazard.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方通报称，本次召回范围内部分车辆因转向助力电机传感器线束接触不良，可能导致转向机传感器信号波动，触发转向故障警告灯点亮，并造成转向助力失效，存在安全隐患。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company will replace the improved steering gear assembly for free for vehicles within the recall scope to eliminate the risk. Owners will be informed of the recall information via mobile app push notifications, phone calls, etc., and can log in to the XPeng Motors APP or call the service hotline '400-783-6688' for details.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            企业将为召回范围内车辆免费更换改进后的转向机总成，以消除风险。车主将通过手机 APP 推送、电话等方式获知召回信息，并可登录小鹏汽车 APP 或拨打服务热线「400-783-6688」获取详情。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>罗永浩「大战」西贝第二轮：前者直播，后者发菜谱</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">罗永浩「大战」西贝第二轮：前者直播，后者发菜谱</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f7407b12-e992-4d21-85f7-8b6e5fdf44f9.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response to Luo Yonghao's recent social media post alleging that Xibei's dishes are 'almost all pre-made dishes,' Xibei officially released 'A Letter to Customers from All Xibei Partners' on social media yesterday, responding to the doubts point by point, disclosing the detailed production processes of the 13 dishes involved, and citing documents from six ministries and commissions to point out that these dishes do not fall under the category of 'pre-made dishes.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对罗永浩日前在社交平台发文称西贝菜品「几乎全都是预制菜」的指控，西贝官方昨日在社交平台发布《西贝全体伙伴致顾客的一封信》，逐条回应质疑，公布涉事 13 道菜品的详细制作流程，并引用六部委文件指出这些菜品不属于「预制菜」范畴。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xibei stated in the letter that as a loyal customer, they appreciate Luo Yonghao's feedback, but
            &lt;strong&gt;
             'as an influential public figure, we firmly oppose and will not tolerate false accusations and inappropriate language against Xibei.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            西贝在信中表示，作为老顾客，感谢罗永浩提出意见，但
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「作为有影响力的公众人物，对西贝的不实指责及不当用语，我们坚决反对，绝不姑息」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xibei stated that it has reviewed the quality of dishes and service on that day and has publicly released the 'operation instruction manuals' for the 13 dishes involved, covering steps such as raw material thawing, cutting, seasoning, and cooking. At the same time, Xibei cited the definition in the 'Notice on Strengthening the Supervision of Pre-made Dish Food Safety and Promoting the High-Quality Development of the Industry' issued by the State Administration for Market Regulation and five other ministries and commissions in 2024, pointing out that the dishes involved do not fall under the category of pre-made dishes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            西贝称已复盘当日菜品出品与服务质量，并将 13 道涉事菜品的「作业指导书」向社会公开，涵盖原料解冻、切配、调味、烹饪等环节。同时，西贝引用 2024 年市场监管总局等六部委发布的《关于加强预制菜食品安全监管 促进产业高质量发展的通知》中的定义，指出涉事菜品不属于预制菜范畴。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response to public concerns, Xibei announced that it would open its kitchens for customer visits starting today, and will gradually open up source visit channels such as places of origin, central kitchen factories, and grassland ranches in the future. Xibei finally stated that it will continue to upgrade its products, services, and experiences, and welcomes supervision from all sectors of society.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            为回应公众关切，西贝宣布即日起向顾客开放后厨参观，未来还将陆续开放原产地、央厨工厂、草原牧场等源头参观渠道。西贝最后表示，将持续在产品、服务与体验方面升级，并欢迎社会各界监督。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that some of the materials displayed by Xibei contained some packaged cooked products. One hour after the aforementioned response was published, Xibei's official Weibo hid the relevant information. (It has since been reopened)
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，西贝展示的部分资料内，存在部分包装熟制品。上述回应消息在发布的一小时后，西贝官方微博将相关信息进行了隐藏。（目前已重新开放）
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from China Blue News, First Scene, and Phoenix Net Technology:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而据中国蓝新闻、第一现场、凤凰网科技报道：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xibei admitted that some dishes are left overnight. Cooked lamb chops have a shelf life of three meals: one meal this morning, one this afternoon, and can still be sold tomorrow morning. The head chef stated that using them overnight would not affect the quality of the served dishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manager Du, Xibei's city partner for the Shenzhen area, stated: Last night, the headquarters requested all employees to taste the dishes ordered by Luo Yonghao and conduct a review on how to further improve the taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Xibei staff member stated in the report that stewed beef preparation starts at 5 AM. A certain amount is prepared before the main meal service begins. 'Some are enough for two or three meals; if not sold out, they are converted to staff meals or disposed of.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, Luo Yonghao also conducted a multi-platform live broadcast regarding the 'pre-made dish' issue, stating that this broadcast was temporary, and
            &lt;strong&gt;
             'Xibei's unprofessional PR team is comparable to our unprofessional live broadcast team.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，罗永浩还针对「预制菜」问题进行了多平台直播，并表示这次直播是临时性的，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「西贝的公关团队不专业跟我们直播团队的不专业有一拼。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Luo Yonghao claimed during the live broadcast that when he ate sea bass at Xibei, it tasted very fishy, like it had been frozen for a long time, but Xibei's PR team said it was fresh. He stated that yesterday, a reporter went to a Xibei store and photographed the sea bass packaging, which listed sea bass as the main ingredient and various additives including yeast extract and compound moisture retention agents, with a shelf life of 18 months.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            罗永浩在直播中称，自己在西贝吃海鲈鱼时就感觉很腥，像是冷冻很久的，西贝公关团队说是新鲜的。其表示，昨日有记者去西贝门店拍到，海鲈鱼的包装上写的主料是海鲈鱼，配料包括酵母提取物、复配水分保持剂等多种，保质期 18 个月。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Luo Yonghao stated that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Xibei's claim of having no pre-made dishes is 100% a lie, because the country has not yet issued relevant standards.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            He called for national standards to be introduced as soon as possible during the live broadcast, saying that it is catering companies being rogue by claiming the definition of pre-made dishes is complex when it is not. He emphasized that although his own live stream has also sold pre-made dishes, consumers knew what they were buying, and there were no issues; pre-made dishes are just another type of canned food.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时罗永浩表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             西贝称没有预制菜是 100% 撒谎，因为国家还没有相关标准出台。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            其在直播中呼吁国标尽快出台，他表示，是餐饮企业耍流氓，说预制菜定义很复杂，其实并不复杂。其强调，虽然自己的直播间也卖过预制菜，但消费者买的时候知道，没任何问题，预制菜就是另一种罐头。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Luo Yonghao also stated that pre-made dishes are legal, and the reason people are angry now is that the lack of transparency regarding pre-made dishes has become unbearable for Chinese consumers. This is not a new issue, and he hopes to protect consumers' right to know.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            罗永浩也表示，预制菜是合法的，现在大家为什么愤怒，因为预制菜不透明这件事已经让中国消费者受不了了，这不是一年两年的事情了，希望维护消费者知情权。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also cited the display board for dish processing grades at Laoxiangji as an example, stating that he hasn't tried Laoxiangji yet but plans to do so in the future.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             'It's not that pre-made dishes can't be made, but they should be like Laoxiangji, setting an industry example by clearly indicating what is freshly made and what is pre-made.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时他还以老乡鸡菜品加工等级划分公示牌为例，表示自己还没吃过老乡鸡，以后准备去试试。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「不是不能做预制菜，但应该像老乡鸡一样，做一个行业表率，注明现做的和预制的。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to an interview with Xibei founder Jia Guolong by &quot;China Entrepreneur Magazine&quot;, the latter revealed that on September 10th and 11th, the total daily turnover of all stores dropped by 1 million yuan respectively, and he also estimated that on September 12th, it would drop by 2-3 million yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另据《中国企业家杂志》专访西贝创始人贾国龙，后者透露 9 月 10、11 日所有门店加起来，日营业额分别掉了 100 万元，其还预估 9 月 12 日会掉 200-300 万元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jia Guolong emphasized that even if the business is shut down, the lawsuit with Luo Yonghao must proceed. However, the final outcome remains unknown. &quot;I can stop doing business, but I must clarify what is right and wrong.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            贾国龙强调，哪怕生意不做了，和罗永浩的官司一定要打。但最终结局会走向何方，仍是未知数。「生意我可以不做，但是非黑白，我必须要说清楚。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>腾讯辟谣前 OpenAI 研究员上亿薪资入职</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">腾讯辟谣前-OpenAI-研究员上亿薪资入职</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/494e9886-894f-494b-9e27-a5094b44aeb5.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday morning, Tencent officially posted an article titled &quot;Good morning, debunking a rumor&quot; on its official WeChat account &quot;Tencent Blackboard News,&quot; explicitly labeling the widely circulated rumor about &quot;former OpenAI Yao Shunyu joining Tencent with a salary of hundreds of millions&quot; as &quot;a rumor.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日早间，腾讯官方在其公众号「鹅厂黑板报」发布帖文「早安，辟个谣」，针对网络流传的「前 OpenAI 姚顺雨以上亿薪资入职腾讯」一事，明确标注为「谣言」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Yao Shunyu graduated from Tsinghua University's Yao Class with a bachelor's degree, later obtained a Ph.D. in Computer Science from Princeton University, and joined OpenAI in 2024. He was deeply involved in core projects such as Computer-Using Agent and Deep Research, and proposed important methods in papers like ReAct, Tree of Thoughts, and Reflexion, with a total citation count exceeding 15,000.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，姚顺雨本科毕业于清华大学姚班，后获普林斯顿大学计算机科学博士学位，2024 年加入 OpenAI，深度参与了 Computer-Using Agent、Deep Research 等核心项目，并在 ReAct、Tree of Thoughts、Reflexion 等论文中提出重要方法，总引用量超 1.5 万次。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In May this year, he was selected for the &quot;35 Innovators Under 35&quot; China list by &quot;MIT Technology Review,&quot; becoming the youngest person on the list.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 5 月，他入选《MIT 科技评论》「35 岁以下科技创新 35 人」中国区榜单，成为最年轻的上榜者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that in a conversation with Zhang Xiaojun and Li Guangmi in May this year, he discussed the future of WeChat and AI, believing that the real threat comes from &quot;something very different,&quot; rather than competition from similar products.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，今年 5 月在一次与张小珺、李广密的对谈中，他曾谈及微信与 AI 的未来，认为真正的威胁来自「很不一样的东西」，而非同类产品竞争。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Multiple sources previously indicated that this 27-year-old prodigy has already resigned from OpenAI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而此前的多方消息源显示，这位 27 岁的天才少年已从 OpenAI 离职。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>库克谈 iPhone Air：轻到像会从手中飞走</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">库克谈-iPhone-Air：轻到像会从手中飞走</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://www.apple.com.cn/v/iphone-air/a/images/overview/design/hero_design__xv9gyjqhdiai_large.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple officially launched the new iPhone Air at its latest press conference. This model's biggest highlight is its &quot;astonishing thinness and lightness,&quot; featuring an ultra-light titanium frame design, with both its weight and thickness setting new records for the iPhone series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果在最新发布会上正式推出了全新 iPhone Air，这款机型以「令人震惊的轻薄」为最大亮点，采用超轻钛金属边框设计，重量与厚度均刷新了 iPhone 系列纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to the iPhone 17 Pro, the Air is 36% thinner, but there are trade-offs in battery life and camera performance. Apple CEO Tim Cook described the phone in an interview as
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;feeling like it could fly away in your hand.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            He added that he would sometimes pick up the ultra-thin new phone just because he &quot;wanted to float in the air a bit.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比 iPhone 17 Pro，Air 薄了 36%，但在电池续航和相机性能上有所取舍。苹果 CEO Tim Cook 在接受采访时形容，这款手机
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「似乎会在你手中飞走」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。他还补充道，自己会在某些时刻拿起那部超薄新机，只因为「想要在空中飘一飘」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple's VP of Design, Alan Dye, further pointed out,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;The iPhone Air represents another step closer to Steve Jobs' original concept of 'a single sheet of glass.'&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而苹果设计副总裁 Alan Dye 更是指出，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「iPhone Air 代表着我们朝着乔布斯当年提出的「一整块玻璃」概念又近了一步。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In discussions after the new product launch, many employees working at Apple Park admitted that they would likely use both the Pro and Air models simultaneously to meet the needs of different scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在新品发布会后的交流中，不少在苹果园区工作的员工坦言，他们很可能会同时使用 Pro 与 Air 两款机型，以满足不同场景的需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Molly Anderson, a member of Apple's design team, stated:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果设计团队成员 Molly Anderson 表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;This has been our long-standing dream: to create an incredibly thin and astonishingly light iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Anderson also repeatedly mentioned that a phone is not just something people &quot;own&quot; or &quot;use,&quot; but also an accessory that can be &quot;worn.&quot; To this end, Apple simultaneously launched multiple protective cases and cross-body straps, making the iPhone Air a true fashion item.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Anderson 还多次提到，手机不仅是人们「拥有」或「使用」的物品，更是一种可以「佩戴」的配饰。为此，苹果同步推出了多款保护壳与斜挎背带，让 iPhone Air 成为真正的时尚单品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lev Tanju, co-founder of London skateboard brand Palace, stated bluntly:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            伦敦滑板品牌 Palace 联合创始人 Lev Tanju 直言：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;I didn't need a thinner phone originally, but now I feel — oh no, I need a thinner phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that the iPhone Air's design might hint at Apple's next major move — a foldable iPhone. Industry insiders predict that this foldable device could debut as early as next year. When asked about this, Cook did not reveal many details:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，iPhone Air 的设计可能预示着苹果下一步的重大动作 —— 折叠屏 iPhone。有业内人士预测，这款折叠机最快可能在明年亮相。而库克在被问及此事时并未透露太多细节：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;We are very good at keeping secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that the development of the foldable phone will continue several innovations from the iPhone Air, including core technologies such as the ultra-light titanium frame.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，折叠机的研发将延续 iPhone Air 的多项创新，包括超轻钛金属框架等核心技术。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蚂蚁集团发布全球首个智能眼镜可信连接技术框架</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蚂蚁集团发布全球首个智能眼镜可信连接技术框架</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/50c8a16b-d1e0-475e-933b-65553b230f46.jpeg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, at the 2025 Inclusion · Bund Conference, Ant Group officially launched &quot;gPass,&quot; the world's first trusted connection technology framework for smart glasses, endowing smart glasses with financial-grade security capabilities and building a secure and trustworthy digital service ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，在 2025 Inclusion · 外滩大会上，蚂蚁集团正式推出全球首个智能眼镜可信连接技术框架「gPass」，为智能眼镜赋予金融级安全能力，构建安全可信的数字服务生态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, &quot;gPass&quot; is developed around three core capabilities: &quot;security, interaction, and connection,&quot; aiming to achieve secure, trustworthy, and instant information interaction between AI glasses and intelligent agents. Chen Liang, CTO of Ant Group's Greater Security, stated that &quot;gPass&quot; has opened up Ant's financial-grade security capabilities, which will support the evolution of AI glasses from &quot;basic tools&quot; to &quot;personal intelligent agents.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，「gPass」围绕「安全、交互、连接」三大核心能力展开，致力于实现 AI 眼镜与智能体之间的安全、可信、即时信息交互。蚂蚁集团大安全 CTO 陈亮表示，「gPass」开放了蚂蚁金融级安全能力，将支撑 AI 眼镜从「基础工具」演进为「个人智能体」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             At the security level, &quot;gPass&quot; provides technologies such as trusted identity circulation, end-to-end encryption, and device authentication to ensure &quot;the device belongs to the user,&quot; and has adapted Android and RTOS dual-system chip-level security solutions.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             在安全层面，「gPass」提供可信身份流通、端到端加密、设备认证等技术，确保「设备是本人」，并已适配 Android 与 RTOS 双系统芯片级安全方案。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             In terms of interaction, &quot;gPass&quot; integrates non-perceptual identity verification methods such as voiceprint, iris, and fingerprint to achieve convenient verification that &quot;the user is the person themselves.&quot;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             交互方面，「gPass」集成声纹、虹膜、指纹等无感核身方式，实现「用户是本人」的便捷验证。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             In terms of connection, &quot;gPass&quot; can perceive the user's time and spatial environment, supporting cross-device synchronization, multi-modal reminders, and instant interaction.
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             连接方面，「gPass」可感知用户所处的时间与空间环境，支持跨端同步、多模态提醒与即时交互。
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, &quot;gPass&quot; has been first applied in smart glasses from brands like Rokid, Xiaomi, Quark, and RayNeo, enabling the &quot;look to pay&quot; function. In the future, it will also unleash its potential in fields such as culture and tourism, travel, and healthcare, for example, realizing AI consultations, appointment reminders, and medication interpretations as accompanying health services in medical scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，「gPass」已率先应用于 rokid、小米、夸克、雷鸟等品牌的智能眼镜中，实现「看一下支付」功能。未来在文旅、出行、医疗等领域也将释放潜能，例如在医疗场景中实现 AI 问诊、就诊提醒、药品解读等伴随式健康服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 与微软又「和好」：签署新协议</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-与微软又「和好」：签署新协议</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Verge, Microsoft and OpenAI announced yesterday that they have signed a non-binding Memorandum of Understanding (MOU), marking the &quot;next phase&quot; of their collaboration. Both parties stated that they are actively finalizing the contractual terms of the ultimate agreement and will continue to provide advanced AI tools to global users with security at the core.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Verge 报道，微软与 OpenAI 于昨日宣布已签署一份非约束性的谅解备忘录（MOU），标志着双方合作进入「下一阶段」。双方表示，正在积极推进最终协议的合同条款敲定，并将继续以安全为核心，为全球用户提供先进的 AI 工具。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since 2019, Microsoft has invested $13 billion in OpenAI and shares in the revenue generated by ChatGPT and its API. It is worth noting that while maintaining the partnership, Microsoft also views OpenAI as a competitor and allows it to use computing resources from other cloud service providers, while increasing investment in its self-developed AI models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自 2019 年以来，微软已向 OpenAI 投资 130 亿美元，并分享 ChatGPT 及其 API 所带来的收入。值得注意的是，微软在保持合作的同时，也将 OpenAI 视为竞争对手，并允许其使用其他云服务提供商的算力资源，同时加大对自研 AI 模型的投入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI revealed in another statement that its non-profit parent company will continue to control the for-profit business, holding equity valued at over $100 billion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 在另一份声明中透露，其非营利性母公司将继续掌控营利性业务，持有价值逾 1000 亿美元的股权。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, the company's restructuring plan is facing scrutiny from some charities and non-profit organizations, with the Attorneys General of California and Delaware having launched investigations into the matter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，该公司的重组计划正面临部分慈善机构和非营利组织的质疑，加利福尼亚州与特拉华州的总检察长已对此展开调查。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In late July this year, Bloomberg reported that Microsoft and OpenAI were in advanced talks aimed at reaching a new agreement to ensure Microsoft's continued access to OpenAI's latest technology, even if OpenAI declares the achievement of &quot;Artificial General Intelligence&quot; (AGI).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 7 月底，据彭博社报道，微软与 OpenAI 正在进行深入谈判，目标是达成一项新协议，以确保微软能够持续获取 OpenAI 的最新技术，即便 OpenAI 宣告实现「通用人工智能」（AGI）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>追觅汽车完成首轮融资</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">追觅汽车完成首轮融资</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On September 12, just two weeks after its official announcement, Dreame Auto completed its first round of financing, potentially becoming the fastest car manufacturing company to achieve its first round of funding.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            9 月 12 日，距官宣刚两周，追觅汽车已完成首轮融资，或成为最快实现首轮融资的造车企业。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Currently, Dreame Auto is selecting a factory site adjacent to Tesla's German factory, and the new factory's area is expected to be 1.2 times that of Tesla's Berlin factory.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             目前追觅汽车正在毗邻特斯拉德国工厂所在地进行建厂选址，新工厂面积预计是特斯拉柏林工厂的 1.2 倍。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Just this week, news broke that Yu Hao, founder and CEO of Dreame Technology, led a team to Germany to select a factory site for Dreame Auto. It is worth mentioning that this is the first time a Chinese technology company has established a comprehensive factory in the heartland of European high-end manufacturing, marking a new era for Dreame's globalization strategy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            就在本周，外界刚刚传出消息，追觅科技创始人兼 CEO 俞浩携团队赴德国，为追觅汽车进行工厂选址。值得一提的是，这是中国科技企业首次在欧洲高端制造腹地落地综合性工厂，同时标志着追觅全球化战略迈入全新纪元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the area where Dreame Auto is selecting its site has thousands of component suppliers, forming a complete industrial chain covering precision manufacturing, electronics, and material science; in the future, it will also have the opportunity to directly share the localized supply network of core automotive components with local brands, significantly shortening the R&amp;amp;D cycle and reducing logistics costs, and efficiently covering the entire Europe.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，追觅汽车选址所在的辐射地区，拥有上千家零部件供应商，形成覆盖精密制造、电子电气、材料科学的完整产业链；未来还将有机会直接与当地品牌共享汽车核心零部件的本地化供应网络，大幅缩短研发周期并降低物流成本，并将网络高效覆盖整个欧洲。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dreame stated that its business has now been deployed in over 100 countries and regions worldwide, with over 6,000 offline stores, serving over 30 million families, and exceeding 11 million members. The mature global marketing network will provide strong support for Dreame Auto's international promotion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            追觅方面表示，其业务现已在全球 100 多个国家和地区布局，拥有超 6000 家线下门店、服务家庭超 3000 万、会员数突破 1100 万。而成熟的全球营销网络将为追觅汽车的国际化推广提供强大支撑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Technologically, Dreame relies on its core technical accumulations in high-speed digital motors, AI algorithms, robot sensing, and control, and has gradually migrated these to areas such as automotive electric drive systems, intelligent cockpits, and autonomous driving. As of May 2025, Dreame has obtained 3,155 global authorized patents and cumulatively applied for 6,379 patents.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            技术方面，追觅依托高速数字马达、AI 算法、机器人传感与控制等核心技术积累，已逐步向汽车电驱系统、智能座舱、自动驾驶等领域迁移。截至 2025 年 5 月，追觅已获全球授权专利 3155 件，累计申请专利 6379 件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Dreame founder Yu Hao had posted vehicle renderings on social media and announced that the prototype would debut at the International Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in the United States at the end of the year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，追觅创始人俞浩曾在社交平台发布车型渲染图，并宣布样车将于年底在美国国际消费电子展（CES）上首发。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c716bcc5-4fac-4490-9ce7-bd9fd577d178.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Leveraging China's R&amp;amp;D advantages and integrating Germany's top manufacturing standards, Dreame Auto aims to build a world-class automotive brand. This round of financing will accelerate the development of Dreame Auto's core technologies and its first product, while simultaneously supporting its global expansion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            依托中国研发优势，集合德国制造的顶尖标准，追觅汽车旨在打造世界一流汽车品牌。本轮融资将加速推进追觅汽车核心技术及首款产品研发，同步支撑其全球化扩张。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阿里百度「上马」自研芯片 英伟达回应</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">阿里百度「上马」自研芯片-英伟达回应</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Information, citing informed sources, Alibaba and Baidu have begun using self-developed chips to train AI models, partially replacing Nvidia products.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Information 援引知情人士报道，阿里巴巴与百度已开始使用自研芯片训练 AI 模型，部分替代英伟达产品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report states that Alibaba has been using self-developed chips in small AI models since the beginning of this year; Baidu is attempting to use Kunlun P800 chips to train a new version of its &quot;Ernie Bot&quot; model. This move is seen as a significant shift in China's technology and AI sectors, which will further impact Nvidia's business in China.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道称，阿里巴巴自今年年初起已在小型 AI 模型中使用自研芯片；百度则在尝试利用昆仑 P800 芯片训练新版本的「文心一言」模型。此举被视为中国科技与 AI 领域的重要转变，将进一步冲击英伟达在华业务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Affected by the US's continuous tightening of export restrictions on advanced AI chips, Chinese companies are accelerating their self-developed chip layouts and adopting more domestic technologies under policy pressure. However, the report also pointed out that the two companies have not completely abandoned Nvidia and are still using its chips in the development of cutting-edge models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            受美国不断收紧先进 AI 芯片出口限制影响，中国企业正加快自研芯片布局，并在政策压力下更多采用国产技术。但报道也指出，两家公司并未完全放弃英伟达，仍在最前沿模型的开发中使用其芯片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from Alibaba employees, Alibaba's AI chip performance is already comparable to Nvidia H20. It is understood that H20 is currently Nvidia's strongest AI chip available for sale in China, but its computing power is still inferior to the H100 or Blackwell series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据阿里员工通过报道透露，阿里巴巴的 AI 芯片性能已足以与英伟达 H20 相媲美。据悉，H20 是目前英伟达在中国可销售的最强 AI 芯片，但算力仍不及 H100 或 Blackwell 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Nvidia responded: &quot;Competition is inevitable... We will continue to work hard to win the trust and support of mainstream developers worldwide.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英伟达方面回应称：「竞争无可避免……我们将继续努力赢得全球主流开发者的信任与支持。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>卢伟冰：小米空调 Q2 出货量超 540 万台</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">卢伟冰：小米空调-Q2-出货量超-540-万台</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ccc7c158-f758-4599-8f21-20d691cd35b0.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Lu Weibing, Partner and President of Xiaomi Group, posted on Weibo, sharing his latest thoughts on Xiaomi's home appliance business. He stated:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小米集团合伙人、总裁卢伟冰在微博发文，分享了对小米大家电业务的最新思考。他表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Xiaomi's home appliance business is growing rapidly, with Xiaomi air conditioners shipping over 5.4 million units in the second quarter of this year. Sales have seen a growth rate of over 50% for three consecutive quarters, achieving counter-trend growth with &quot;both volume and price increasing.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing pointed out that despite the fierce price war in the industry during the first half of the year, Xiaomi did not choose &quot;to sacrifice price for volume&quot; but insisted on promoting high-end development through innovation. He emphasized that internal competition is not the solution; continuous investment in innovation is what can turn a &quot;red ocean&quot; into a &quot;blue ocean.&quot; The high-end positioning of home appliances is not just a business choice but also a significant step in Xiaomi's full-category high-end strategy, following mobile phones and automobiles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            卢伟冰指出，尽管上半年行业价格战激烈，但小米并未选择「以价换量」，而是坚持通过创新推动高端化发展。他强调，行业内卷不是解法，持续投入创新才能将「红海」变为「蓝海」，大家电的高端化不仅是业务选择，更是继手机、汽车之后，小米全品类高端化的重要进展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Lu Weibing also introduced the recent innovation highlights of Xiaomi's home appliances in the article:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，卢伟冰在文中还介绍了小米大家电近期创新亮点：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Air conditioners: Adhering to the high-end route, achieving both volume and price increases;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washing machines: Introducing &quot;super electrolysis&quot; technology to enhance healthy washing and care standards;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refrigerators: Equipped with &quot;micro-ice fresh&quot; preservation technology, allowing fresh meat to remain unfrozen below zero degrees;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisions: The new generation &quot;Master Picture Quality Engine&quot; combines AI models with custom picture quality chips to deliver a more realistic visual experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing stated that home appliances are a century-old track, an industry without a fixed pattern, only continuous innovation. Xiaomi hopes to work with industry veterans to open up broader space for the home appliance industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            卢伟冰表示，大家电是百年赛道，没有格局固化的行业，只有持续不断的创新。小米希望与行业前辈携手，为家电行业开拓更广阔的空间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 沃尔沃 CEO：电动化浪潮将淘汰一些西方车企</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-沃尔沃-CEO：电动化浪潮将淘汰一些西方车企</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8518acd8-2cf0-4b5c-baad-f96aaf49d990.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Volvo CEO Hakan Samuelsson stated in an interview with Bloomberg that the global automotive industry is accelerating towards electrification and there is &quot;no turning back.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，沃尔沃首席执行官哈坎·塞缪尔森（Hakan Samuelsson）在接受彭博社采访时表示，全球汽车行业正加速迈向电动化，「无法回头」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He predicted that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             in about 10 years, cars will be fully electrified and more affordable, but this process will trigger a new round of industry restructuring:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他预测，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             大约 10 年后，汽车将全面实现电动化且成本更低，但这一过程中将引发新一轮行业重组：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Some companies will adapt to the new environment and survive, while others will be eliminated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Samuelsson pointed out that Chinese brands already hold more than half of the domestic market share and are accelerating their entry into the European market, which puts pressure on European and American car manufacturers. He believes that in the future, two to three highly competitive Chinese brands will emerge in the global market, comparable to the status of Ford, General Motors, Toyota, and Volkswagen in the era of internal combustion engine vehicles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            塞缪尔森指出，中国品牌在本土市场已占据超过一半份额，并正加速进入欧洲市场，这对欧洲和美国车企构成压力。他认为，未来全球市场将出现两到三个极具竞争力的中国品牌，与福特、通用、丰田和大众在燃油车时代的地位相当。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When discussing Volvo's strategy, Samuelsson emphasized that rapid electrification remains the core direction, but before charging infrastructure becomes widespread, the company will launch more plug-in hybrid models as a transition. He also admitted that the company is facing difficult challenges due to factors such as software failures, new model delays, and tariffs, but it has developed plans to boost sales and re-establish its technological leadership.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在谈及沃尔沃的战略时，塞缪尔森强调，快速电动化仍是核心方向，但在充电设施尚未普及前，公司将推出更多插电式混合动力车型作为过渡。他同时承认，受软件故障、新车型延迟以及关税等因素影响，公司正面临艰难挑战，但已制定计划提升销量并重振技术领先地位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He concluded by discussing Volvo's relationship with Geely: &quot;The stronger the Chinese automotive industry, the more valuable the relationship with Geely,&quot; and stated that Volvo will continue to seek technological and cost advantages in the global market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他最后还谈到沃尔沃与吉利：「中国汽车工业越强大，与吉利的关系就越有价值」，并表示沃尔沃将继续在全球市场中寻求技术与成本优势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPPO 新机将提供哈苏影像套装</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OPPO-新机将提供哈苏影像套装</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4ae6c73b-7bee-49de-a560-98928c64b3de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, blogger &quot;Camera Demon&quot; posted that OPPO will jointly launch a co-branded imaging kit with Hasselblad, expected to be released in October.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，博主「相机入魔」发文透露，OPPO 将与哈苏共同推出联名影像套装，并预计 10 月发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the introduction,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the imaging kit is directly designed and customized by Hasselblad
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , and it is also the industry's first photography kit created by a camera brand; it features an industry-first magnetic photography grip; and provides a Hasselblad professional external teleconverter (the blogger also stated that the image quality and resolution performance are highly anticipated).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             该影像套装由哈苏直接设计和定制的
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，同时也是行业首个由相机品牌打造的摄影套装；采用行业首创的磁吸摄影手柄；提供哈苏专业外挂增距镜（博主还表示画质和解析力表现非常值得期待）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, OPPO Find product manager Zhou Yibao reposted and confirmed the relevant news, stating that &quot;the leaked images differ from the actual situation.&quot; He also revealed that this imaging kit is designed for the Find X9 Pro, and the standard version also has imaging accessories designed for it.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后 OPPO Find 产品负责人周意保转发并确认了相关消息，并表示「爆料图与实际情况有出入」。其还透露，本次影像套装为 Find X9 Pro 打造，另外标准版也设计了影像配件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The leaked images show that the camera cutout for this imaging kit is located in the upper left corner of the device, featuring a square design, with an additional cutout outside the lens, possibly for a flash.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从爆料图显示，该影像套装的镜头开孔位于机身左上角，采用正方形设计，镜头外还有一枚疑似闪光灯的开孔。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, blogger &quot;Digital Chat Station&quot; also revealed core specifications for the OPPO Pad 5.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，博主「数码闲聊站」还透露了 OPPO Pad 5 的核心规格爆料。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to their information, the OPPO Pad 5 will feature a 12.1-inch 3K 144Hz LCD screen, powered by a Dimensity 9400+ processor; it will have a rated battery capacity of 10165mAh, paired with 67W fast charging; and will use an 8MP single camera.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据其消息，OPPO Pad 5 将配备 12.1 寸 3K 144Hz LCD 屏幕，采用天玑 9400+ 处理器；电池额定容量为 10165mAh，搭配 67W 快充；采用 8MP 单摄。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding body design, the blogger stated that the OPPO Pad 5 will offer three color options: purple, silver, and gray, with a body weight of 579g; the new product is expected to be released alongside the Find X9 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            机身设计方面，该博主表示本次 OPPO Pad 5 将带来紫色、银色、灰色三种颜色选择，机身重量为 579g；新品有望与 Find X9 系列一同发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BOSE 发布新款消噪耳机 QuietComfort Ultra II</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">BOSE-发布新款消噪耳机-QuietComfort-Ultra-II</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6e033651-6b36-42e4-be75-829dc2ff1d43.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Bose officially released its new generation flagship over-ear headphones, the QuietComfort Ultra II noise-cancelling headphones, and announced that young actor, singer, and trendsetter Wang Hedi has become its global brand ambassador.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Bose 昨日正式发布新一代旗舰头戴式耳机 QuietComfort 消噪耳机 Ultra II，并宣布青年演员、歌手、潮流主理人王鹤棣成为全球品牌代言人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new generation QC Ultra II noise-cancelling headphones continue the series' core advantages, with further upgrades in sound quality, noise cancellation, and wearing experience:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新一代 QC 消噪耳机 Ultra II 延续了该系列的核心优势，在音质、降噪与佩戴体验上进一步升级：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports Bose's patented CustomTune smart in-ear sound calibration, precisely optimizing sound effects and noise cancellation based on the wearer's ear canal structure; adds USB-C wired digital lossless audio transmission, supporting 16-bit/44.1kHz or 48kHz audio signals; introduces a new &quot;Cinema Mode&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upgraded noise cancellation algorithm, with smoother and more natural filtering of sudden noises;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battery life up to 30 hours, extendable to 45 hours when noise cancellation is off, and supports use while charging; supports Bluetooth 5.4 multipoint connection, compatible with SBC, AAC, and aptX Adaptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of price, the QC Ultra II is priced at 3599 yuan, and two Bose × Wang Hedi limited edition co-branded gift boxes have also been launched:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            价格方面，QC Ultra II 售价为 3599 元，另外还推出两款 Bose × 王鹤棣限量联名礼盒：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Little D&quot; Limited Edition Co-branded Gift Box (including QC Ultra II noise-cancelling headphones): 3599 yuan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Little Devil&quot; Limited Edition Co-branded Gift Box (including QC Ultra II noise-cancelling earbuds): 2299 yuan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f8e44341-dc91-40e3-8317-29071708809b.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>美团首款 AI Agent 公测</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">美团首款-AI-Agent-公测</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/049ec5d6-3e3d-4fd6-9eb7-51f27fe94a65.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Meituan announced that its first life assistant AI Agent App, &quot;Xiaomei,&quot; has officially launched.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，美团宣布其首款生活助手 AI Agent App「小美」已正式上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to official introductions, &quot;Xiaomei&quot; has been simultaneously launched on both iOS and Android platforms. Users can download the app and enter the unified public beta code &quot;DAYONE&quot; to start the public beta.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据官方介绍，「小美」已在 iOS 与 Android 平台同步上架，下载 App 并输入统一公测暗号「DAYONE」即可开启公测。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that &quot;Xiaomei&quot; is powered by Meituan's self-developed model LongCat-Flash-Chat, released earlier this month, and has been fully integrated into core Meituan App services such as food delivery, travel, and hotel booking.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，「小美」搭载了月初发布的美团自研模型 LongCat-Flash-Chat，并已全面接入美团 App 的外卖、旅游、酒店预订等核心业务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After &quot;Xiaomei&quot; automatically locates or the user manually selects an address, users can perform various operations such as searching for life services, ordering food delivery, and booking hotels via voice or text commands.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在「小美」自动定位或手动选择地址后，用户可通过语音或文字指令实现生活服务搜索、点外卖、订酒店等多种操作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阿尔巴尼亚任命 AI 政府部长</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">阿尔巴尼亚任命-AI-政府部长</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Cailian Press, on the 11th local time, Albanian Prime Minister Edi Rama announced the new cabinet list, with one special member drawing global attention — the artificial intelligence &quot;Diella&quot; officially appointed as the Minister of Public Procurement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据财联社报道，当地时间 11 日，阿尔巴尼亚总理埃迪·拉马公布新一届内阁名单，其中一位特殊成员引发全球关注 —— 人工智能「迪埃拉」正式出任公共采购部长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;Diella&quot; means &quot;sun&quot; in Albanian and is the first non-physical, AI-virtually generated cabinet member.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Rama stated that in the future, the decision-making power for tenders across government ministries will gradually be transferred to &quot;Diella,&quot; which will review and objectively evaluate every tender contract signed between the government and private enterprises, with the goal of making Albania &quot;a country 100% free of corruption in public tenders.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「迪埃拉」在阿尔巴尼亚语中意为「太阳」，是首位非实体、由人工智能虚拟生成的内阁成员。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            拉马表示，未来政府各部的招标决定权将逐步移交给「迪埃拉」，由其审查并客观评估每一份政府与私营企业签订的招标合同，目标是让阿尔巴尼亚成为「公共招标 100% 无腐败的国家」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For a long time, public procurement contracts have been a high-incidence area for corruption scandals in the country. This move is seen as a significant step for Albania in promoting anti-corruption and digital governance. Rama also revealed that a dedicated department will be established to support &quot;Diella&quot; and promote the implementation of AI technology in more government departments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            长期以来，公共采购合同一直是该国腐败丑闻的高发领域，这一举措被视为阿尔巴尼亚推动反腐与数字化治理的重要一步。拉马还透露，将设立专门部门为「迪埃拉」提供支持，并推动 AI 技术在更多政府部门落地应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            'Diella' is not making her debut. Earlier this year, she launched on the government's e-platform as a virtual AI assistant, dressed in traditional Albanian attire, to help citizens and businesses obtain government documents, provide voice command services, and issue documents with electronic seals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            「迪埃拉」并非首次亮相。今年年初，她以身穿阿尔巴尼亚传统服饰的虚拟形象，在政府电子平台上线，担任 AI 虚拟助手，帮助公民和企业获取政府文件、提供语音指令服务，并签发带有电子印章的文件。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            External attention also focuses on 'Diella's' oversight mechanisms and potential risks. The Albanian government has not yet disclosed details of its human supervision, nor has it explained how to prevent the possibility of AI manipulation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外界关注的焦点还包括「迪埃拉」的监督机制与潜在风险。阿尔巴尼亚政府尚未公布其人类监管细节，也未说明如何防范 AI 被操纵的可能性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Albania is currently an EU candidate country, and Rama hopes to achieve full membership by 2030, but analysts believe this goal is quite challenging.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            阿尔巴尼亚目前是欧盟候选国，拉马希望在 2030 年前实现正式入盟，但分析人士认为这一目标颇具挑战。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SHEIN 首个碳中和物流园区获认证</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">SHEIN-首个碳中和物流园区获认证</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sina Finance, Bureau Veritas, a global third-party testing, inspection, and certification body, recently issued a 'Carbon Neutrality Verification Opinion Letter' to a logistics park of cross-border e-commerce SHEIN in Zhaoqing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪财经报道，近日全球第三方测试、检验和认证机构必维国际检验集团（Bureau Veritas）向跨境电商 SHEIN（希音）位于肇庆的一家物流园区颁发了《碳中和核查意见书》。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The document shows that the park has become SHEIN's first certified 'carbon-neutral' logistics park, with plans to maintain carbon neutrality until 2050.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文件显示，该园区成为 SHEIN 首个通过认证的「碳中和」物流园区，并计划保持碳中和状态至 2050 年。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the certification results, the park achieved carbon emission reductions from January to December 2024 through renewable energy applications and energy-saving measures, while balancing unreduced and residual emissions through carbon offsets. This project is considered a phased progress towards the company's long-term net-zero emission goals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据认证结果，该园区在 2024 年 1 月至 12 月期间，通过可再生能源应用与节能措施完成碳减排，对未减排和残余部分则通过碳抵消方式实现平衡。该项目被视为企业实现长期净零排放目标的阶段性进展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, the Science Based Targets initiative (SBTi) verified SHEIN's emission reduction targets: based on 2023 levels, Scope 1 and Scope 2 absolute emissions will be reduced by 42% by 2030, and Scope 3 by 25%; by 2050, absolute greenhouse gas emissions across all three scopes are expected to decrease by 90%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，科学碳目标倡议组织（SBTi）已验证 SHEIN 的减排目标：以 2023 年为基准，到 2030 年范围 1 和范围 2 绝对排放量将减少 42%，范围 3 减少 25%；到 2050 年，三个范围的温室气体绝对排放量预计减少 90%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to carbon neutrality certification, some parks and research centers previously passed TÜV Rheinland's 'Zero Waste to Landfill Management System Certification'. In terms of transportation, SHEIN plans to deploy over 130 new energy electric vehicles by 2025 to replace diesel trucks, which is expected to reduce carbon emissions by nearly 10,000 tons annually.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除碳中和认证外，部分园区及研究中心此前还通过了德国莱茵 TÜV 的「废弃物零填埋管理体系认证」。在运输环节，SHEIN 计划在 2025 年投放超 130 辆新能源电车，以替代柴油卡车，预计可全年减少碳排放近万吨。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>电影《风林火山》定档 10 月 1 日</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">电影《风林火山》定档-10-月-1-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6ea9a64e-2547-4ce2-a451-c2744b0d2222.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The crime action film 'Feng Lin Shan Huo' (lit. Wind, Forest, Mountain, Fire), directed by Juno Mak and starring Takeshi Kaneshiro, Sean Lau, Tony Leung Ka-fai, Louis Koo, and Gao Yuanyuan, is officially set for national release on October 1st. As the only crime blockbuster during the National Day holiday, the film brings together a top-tier cast from the Chinese film industry and is hailed as a dark epic featuring 'all ruthless characters'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            由导演麦浚龙执导，金城武、刘青云、梁家辉、古天乐、高圆圆主演的犯罪动作片《风林火山》正式定档 10 月 1 日全国上映。作为国庆档唯一犯罪题材大片，影片集结华语影坛顶级阵容，被誉为「全员狠角」的暗黑巨制。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of a deadly struggle between drug dealers, police, and assassins on a snowy night in Hong Kong: high-energy scenes such as a human bomb in a hospital, indiscriminate shootings in Causeway Bay, and a runaway bus crashing into a building are staged one after another. In the trailer, the spectacle of heavy snow in Hong Kong intertwines with violent aesthetics, creating a highly impactful visual experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述毒贩、警方、杀手三方势力在港岛雪夜中的生死角逐：医院人肉炸弹、铜锣湾无差别射杀、公交车失控撞楼等高能场面轮番上演。预告片中，香港漫天大雪的奇观与暴力美学交织，营造出极具冲击力的视觉体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official 'Killing Intent Lurking' poster uses a black, white, and gray palette, with dark red bloodstains particularly striking against the snow, and the positioning of the five core characters subtly hinting at a power struggle.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方释出的「杀机四伏」版海报以黑白灰为基调，暗红血迹在雪地中格外刺眼，五位核心角色的站位暗藏势力博弈。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Fun Thing｜苹果高管尝试掰弯 iPhone Air</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">One-Fun-Thing｜苹果高管尝试掰弯-iPhone-Air</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/23d563a4-975a-436e-a51f-ee1098d91add.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Apple's marketing chief Greg Joswiak and hardware engineering chief John Ternus demonstrated the durability of the iPhone Air live on Tom's Guide's interview program.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，苹果营销主管 Greg Joswiak 与硬件工程主管 John Ternus 在 Tom’s Guide 的访谈节目中现场演示了 iPhone Air 的耐用性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The iPhone Air model is only 5.6 mm thick, starts at 7999 yuan, features a unibody design made of aerospace-grade titanium, eliminating traditional seams and connection points to reduce structural weaknesses. The screen is equipped with second-generation Ceramic Shield glass and boasts IP68 water and dust resistance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            iPhone Air 机型厚度仅 5.6 毫米，起售价 7999 元，采用五级钛合金一体成型机身，去除了传统接缝与连接点，减少结构弱点。屏幕配备二代超瓷晶玻璃，并具备 IP68 级防水防尘性能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the interview, Greg Joswiak even tossed the phone to host Mark Spoonauer across from him and invited him to try bending it. The results showed that the phone slightly bent but quickly returned to its original state, completely unharmed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在访谈过程中，Greg Joswiak 甚至当场将手机抛向对面的主持人 Mark Spoonauer 并邀请对方尝试弯折。结果显示手机轻微弯曲后迅速恢复毫发无损。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            John Ternus explained that the iPhone Air allows for limited elastic deformation under stress and immediately springs back. This design philosophy originated from the unibody manufacturing process of the 2008 MacBook Air, which is more challenging to produce but significantly enhances feel and strength.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            John Ternus 解释称，iPhone Air 在受力时允许有限度弹性形变并立即回弹，这一设计理念源自 2008 年 MacBook Air 的一体成型工艺，制造难度更高，但能显著提升手感和强度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding battery safety, Apple has added a metal casing to the iPhone Air's lithium battery, making it part of the device's structural integrity, thereby providing additional protection during bending. The official statement indicates that the device can withstand daily pocket pressure, drops, and occasional excessive bending tests.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在电池安全性方面，苹果为 iPhone Air 锂电池加装金属外壳，使其成为机身结构的一部分，从而在弯折时提供额外保护。官方表示，该机可承受日常口袋压力、跌落及偶尔的过度弯曲测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>周末看什么｜《捕风追影》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">周末看什么｜《捕风追影》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2b9c6b34-a025-4eea-b52e-9509d2af293a.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Directed by Yang Zi, 'Catching Wind and Chasing Shadows' stars Jackie Chan, Zhang Zifeng, Tony Leung Ka-fai, Ci Sha, Wen Junhui, and others. It currently holds a Douban rating of 8.2, with over 270,000 people participating in the evaluation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《捕风追影》由杨子执导，成龙、张子枫、梁家辉、此沙、文俊辉等主演，目前豆瓣评分为 8.2 分，超过 27 万人参与评价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of a group of genius thieves who steal hundreds of millions in assets and successfully evade the police's 'Sky Eye' tracking system with their superb anti-reconnaissance skills.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述了一伙天才盗匪劫走数亿资产，并凭借高超反侦察能力成功逃脱警方「天眼」系统追踪。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When the Macao Judiciary Police Bureau ran out of options, they invited back Huang Dezhong (Jackie Chan), a tracking expert who had retired for many years, to lead a 'mysterious tracking team,' including young police officer He Qiuguo (Zhang Zifeng), to engage in a high-stakes cat-and-mouse game with the mastermind Fu Longsheng (Tony Leung Ka-fai).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            澳门司警局无计可施之际，请回隐退多年的跟踪专家黄德忠（成龙 饰），带领包括年轻司警何秋果（张子枫 饰）在内的「神秘跟踪队」，与幕后主谋傅隆生（梁家辉 饰）展开高智商猫鼠博弈。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>买书不读指南｜《制造消费者》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">买书不读指南｜《制造消费者》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/54a49cd7-0724-446b-becf-cd4c769410c0.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since Thorstein Veblen introduced 'conspicuous consumption' in 'The Theory of the Leisure Class' in 1899, consumption has gradually permeated the social fabric. Entering the 20th century, it even replaced production to become the core of people's lives. Baudrillard pointed out in 'The Consumer Society' that people no longer consume the goods themselves, but rather the symbols and cultural meanings they carry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自 1899 年范伯伦在《有闲阶级论》中提出「炫耀性消费」以来，消费逐渐渗透进社会肌理。进入 20 世纪，它甚至取代生产，成为人们生活的核心。鲍德里亚在《消费社会》中指出，人们消费的不再是商品本身，而是其承载的符号与文化意义。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this book, &quot;Manufacturing Consumers,&quot; French scholar Antoine Galluzzo views the history of consumption as a history of accelerated circulation of goods and images, and also a process where markets and media mutually shape each other.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在这本《制造消费者》中，法国学者安东尼·加卢佐将消费史视为商品与图像流通加速的历史，也是市场与媒体相互塑造的过程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The book starts by examining the development of transportation and the increasing complexity of global division of labor in the 19th century, revealing how modern people, while distanced from production, developed a fetishistic worship of commodities. The proliferation of advertising images not only reinforced this worship but also reshaped people's identity. As Baudrillard said, consumption is a &quot;permanent violence,&quot; and this brief history spanning two centuries outlines the accelerating trajectory of this force.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            书中从 19 世纪交通运输的发展与全球分工的复杂化切入，揭示现代人在远离生产的同时，如何形成了对商品的拜物崇拜。广告图像的扩散不仅强化了这种崇拜，也重塑了人们的身份认同。正如鲍德里亚所言，消费是一种「永久性的暴力」，而这部跨越两个世纪的简史，勾勒出这种力量不断加速的轨迹。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>游戏推荐｜《无主之地 4》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">游戏推荐｜《无主之地-4》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/9.13_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/69dc8e17-8638-4412-8dfe-5fc05ad95fa0.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Borderlands 4&quot; received an 8-point rating in the IGN review and broke the series' concurrent player record on the Steam platform just one hour after its release.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《无主之地 4》在 IGN 评测中获得 8 分评价，并在发售仅一小时后刷新了系列在 Steam 平台的同时在线人数纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to statistics, &quot;Borderlands 4&quot; PC version was released earlier than its multi-platform global launch, with concurrent players on Steam exceeding 148,000, ranking sixth on the platform at the time. This surpassed the peak record of 124,678 set by &quot;Borderlands 2&quot; 13 years ago, and was also significantly higher than &quot;Borderlands 3&quot;s 93,820 and &quot;Borderlands: The Pre-Sequel&quot;s 68,238.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据统计，《无主之地 4》PC 版提前于全球多平台发售上线，在 Steam 平台的同时在线玩家数突破 14.8 万，位列当时平台第六位，超过了《无主之地 2》13 年前创下的 124,678 峰值纪录，也远高于《无主之地 3》的 93,820 与《无主之地：前传》的 68,238。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The IGN review believes that while maintaining the series' absurd narrative and dark humor, this title for the first time fully transitions to an open-world design, and has made significant innovations in combat, action systems, and enemy design.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            IGN 评测认为，本作在保持系列荒诞叙事与黑色幽默的同时，首次全面转向开放世界设计，并在战斗、动作系统与敌人设计上进行了大幅革新。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Players can explore four major regions on the new planet Kyros, freely traversing using tools such as grappling hooks, gliders, and summonable vehicles. The combat system adds new actions like double jumps, omnidirectional dodges, and swimming. Enemy types are also richer, including mechanical spiders that deflect bullets and monsters that require breaking crystal armor. Boss battles introduce special mechanics, enhancing strategy and memorability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            玩家可在全新的凯罗斯星球探索四大区域，利用钩爪、滑翔翼、可随时召唤的载具等工具自由穿梭。战斗系统新增二段跳、全方向闪避、游泳等动作，敌人类型也更丰富，包括反弹子弹的机械蜘蛛、需击碎水晶护甲的怪物等。Boss 战引入特殊机制，提升了策略性与记忆点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifanr.com/tags/%e6%97%a9%e6%8a%a5&quot;&gt;
            早报
           &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
