<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>苹果上线新春优惠：最高立省 1000 元</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果上线新春优惠：最高立省-1000-元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7a778afa-c85c-46f1-8050-8905a0eccbd4.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Apple launched a limited-time Spring Festival discount event on its official website in mainland China, offering savings of up to 1000 yuan on selected products. The event runs from January 24th to January 27th, covering multiple product lines including iPhone, Mac, iPad, Apple Watch, and AirPods.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，苹果在中国大陆官网上线新春限时优惠活动，指定产品最高可立省 1000 元，活动时间为 1 月 24 日至 1 月 27 日，优惠覆盖 iPhone、Mac、iPad、Apple Watch、AirPods 等多条产品线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Specifically, the main products covered by the discount include:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            具体来看，优惠覆盖的主要产品包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPhone Series: iPhone 16, iPhone 16 Plus save 300 yuan; iPhone 16e save 200 yuan. The newly released iPhone 17 series is not included in the discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mac Series: 14-inch MacBook Pro (M4 Pro/M4 Max/M5) and 16-inch MacBook Pro (M4 Pro/M4 Max) save up to 1000 yuan; MacBook Air (M4) saves up to 800 yuan; iMac saves 600 yuan; Mac mini saves 400 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPad Series: iPad Pro (M5) and iPad Air (M3) both save 400 yuan; iPad (A16) and iPad mini (A17 Pro) save 200 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Watch Series: Apple Watch Ultra 3 saves 300 yuan; Series 11 and SE 3 save 200 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AirPods Series: AirPods Max saves 300 yuan; AirPods 4 (including active noise cancellation version) saves 100 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Pencil Pro: Saves 100 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple's official website shows that this event is only for individual consumers and cannot be combined with other discounts such as educational or business discounts.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果官网显示，本次活动仅面向个人消费者，活动不可与教育优惠、商务优惠等其他折扣叠加。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>腾讯回应 GitHub 下架微信聊天记录相关项目：逆向工程威胁安全</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">腾讯回应-GitHub-下架微信聊天记录相关项目：逆向工程威胁安全</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ce815ea4-a367-4832-95ae-1fdafae5562b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Tencent has filed a complaint with GitHub under relevant DMCA provisions, requesting the platform to take down a batch of open-source projects that can &quot;export or analyze users' WeChat chat records.&quot; The incident has sparked external discussion about &quot;users being unable to access their own chat records,&quot; with some voices believing that user data sovereignty is being restricted.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，腾讯已依据 DMCA 相关条款向 GitHub 提交投诉，要求平台下架一批可「导出或分析用户微信聊天记录」的开源项目。事件引发外界对「用户无法获取自身聊天记录」的讨论，部分声音认为用户数据主权受到限制。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, Tencent responded yesterday, stating that these projects crack WeChat's local database keys through reverse engineering and other methods, bypassing client-side encryption measures. This could threaten user and third-party data privacy and client security, and is highly susceptible to exploitation by illicit industries.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，腾讯方面在昨天回应称，这些项目通过逆向工程等方式破解微信本地数据库密钥，绕过客户端加密措施，可能威胁用户及第三方的数据隐私与客户端安全，且极易被黑灰产利用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tencent stated that the relevant requests have received platform support, and most projects proactively removed infringing content after communication.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            腾讯表示，相关请求已获得平台支持，多数项目在沟通后主动移除违规内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tencent emphasized that the core method of these tools is to &quot;crack the database&quot; to read chat records, while WeChat encrypts and stores chat records on local devices, which is equivalent to adding a &quot;exclusive lock&quot; to the data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            腾讯强调，这类工具的核心方式是「破解数据库」以读取聊天记录，而微信将聊天记录加密存储在本地设备，相当于为数据加上「专属锁」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the complaints received by GitHub, Tencent filed a one-time complaint against more than 30 repositories, including mature projects with thousands of stars. Currently, most of the involved repositories have been deleted or stopped updating, and GitHub is also cleaning up derivative repositories.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据 GitHub 收到的投诉内容，腾讯此次一次性投诉了 30 余个仓库，其中包括拥有数千 Star 的成熟项目。目前，多数涉事仓库已被删除或停止更新，GitHub 也在清理衍生仓库。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            DMCA (Digital Millennium Copyright Act) is a core digital copyright law enacted by the United States in 1998, and platforms typically handle infringement complaints based on this law.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            DMCA（《数字千年版权法》）是美国于 1998 年颁布的核心数字版权法律，平台通常依据该法处理侵权投诉。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In its complaint, Tencent cited DMCA Section 1201, accusing the relevant tools of constituting &quot;unauthorized circumvention of technological protection measures,&quot; violating WeChat's terms of service prohibiting reverse engineering, and potentially leading to user data leakage due to code vulnerabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            腾讯在投诉中援引 DMCA 第 1201 条，指控相关工具构成「未经授权规避技术保护措施」，同时违反微信服务条款中禁止逆向工程的规定，并可能因代码漏洞导致用户数据泄露。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            WeChat stated that the platform has long focused on chat record security. Last year, the WeChat Security Center warned that some third-party tools, under the guise of &quot;AI managing chat records,&quot; bypassed security measures to illegally obtain user data, and reminded users not to install or use any third-party tools that access local chat records.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微信表示，平台长期关注聊天记录安全。去年，微信安全中心曾提示，有第三方工具以「AI 管理聊天记录」等名义绕过安全措施，违法违规获取用户数据，并提醒用户不要安装或使用任何访问本地聊天记录的第三方工具。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            WeChat previously pointed out that it has been internally clarified that chat records occupy a large amount of storage space, and many users have a need for regular exports.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微信此前指出，内部已明确聊天记录占用大量存储空间，不少用户存在定期导出需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response, WeChat launched an external storage backup feature for chat records in July last year, which also supports automatic backup. Tencent stated that backup data is also stored using encryption, ensuring privacy will not be leaked, and multiple users sharing the same storage device will not experience data mix-ups. This feature is currently still in grayscale testing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对此，微信在去年 7 月上线聊天记录外部存储备份功能，并支持自动备份。腾讯称，备份数据同样采用加密方式存储，隐私不会泄露，且多人使用同一存储设备也不会出现串台情况。目前该功能仍处于灰度测试阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曝 OpenAI 悄然推进机器人项目：百人团队昼夜采集训练数据</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝-OpenAI-悄然推进机器人项目：百人团队昼夜采集训练数据</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/849ab5d9-5805-4af9-bd7b-d7735876174e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, OpenAI has quietly established a humanoid robot laboratory over the past year. Insiders say the lab has more than quadrupled in size since its launch in February 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，OpenAI 在过去一年里悄然建立了一个人形机器人实验室。知情人士称，自 2025 年 2 月启动以来，该实验室规模已扩大四倍多。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report states that the laboratory is established in San Francisco, with a scale of over 100 people, and plans to open a second experimental facility in Richmond, California this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道称，相关实验室建立在旧金山，规模超过 100 人，并计划在今年于加州里士满开设第二处实验设施。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The laboratory is located in the same building as the company's finance team. Data collectors primarily use 3D-printed controller &quot;GELLO&quot; to remotely operate Franka robotic arms to perform household tasks, including placing toast, folding clothes, and more.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该实验室与公司财务团队位于同一栋楼，主要由数据采集员通过 3D 打印控制器「GELLO」远程操控 Franka 机械臂执行家务任务，包括放置吐司、折叠衣物等。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Relevant personnel stated that these basic motion trainings are part of OpenAI's long-term plan to build humanoid robots.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相关人员表示，这些基础动作训练是 OpenAI 构建人形机器人长期计划的一部分。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI had previously closed an early robotics project in 2020, with the company stating at the time that resources needed to be &quot;re-focused&quot; on other directions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 曾在 2020 年关闭早期机器人项目，当时公司称需将资源「重新聚焦」至其他方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Now, with the rapid development of generative AI, OpenAI is once again betting on robotics, and last year issued a call for expressions of interest to US domestic manufacturers for hardware projects involving consumer-grade devices, robots, and cloud data centers, though without disclosing budgets or timelines.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            如今，随着生成式 AI 的快速发展，OpenAI 再度押注机器人方向，并在去年向美国本土制造商发出合作意向征集，涉及消费级设备、机器人以及云数据中心等硬件项目，但未披露预算与时间表。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sources say that OpenAI's current robot R&amp;amp;D is still in its early stages. A humanoid robot described as &quot;iRobot-like&quot; is placed in the lab's internal display area, but it is rarely actually activated, with the main work still focusing on remote control of robotic arms and data collection.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士称，OpenAI 当前的机器人研发仍处于早期阶段，实验室内部展示区放置着一台被描述为「类似 iRobot」的人形机器人，但鲜少被实际启用，主要工作仍集中在机械臂的远程操控与数据采集。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Unlike companies like Tesla that rely on full-size humanoid robots and motion capture training, OpenAI chooses to accumulate large amounts of robotic arm operation data in a low-cost, scalable manner.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与特斯拉等公司依赖全尺寸人形机器人和动作捕捉训练不同，OpenAI 选择以低成本、可扩展的方式积累大量机械臂操作数据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Researchers point out that this method makes it easier for robots to learn the mapping relationship between human actions and robotic arm movements, which is expected to create a &quot;robot moment&quot; similar to ChatGPT in the future.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            研究人员指出，这种方法更易让机器人学习人类动作与机械臂运动之间的映射关系，有望在未来形成类似 ChatGPT 的「机器人时刻」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, OpenAI's data collection operates on a three-shift, round-the-clock basis, and the lab is continuously improving data collection efficiency. Some data will be used for simulated environment training and regular testing of the robotic arm's actual performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，OpenAI 的数据采集工作采取三班倒模式，全天候运行，实验室也在持续提升数据采集效率。部分数据将用于模拟环境训练，并定期测试机械臂的实际表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>宇树澄清去年销量传闻：人形机器人出货量超 5500 台</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">宇树澄清去年销量传闻：人形机器人出货量超-5500-台</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/34d94bc7-877c-40cd-8b10-f00b78caea7f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Unitree Robotics issued a &quot;Clarification on Unitree's 2025 Sales Data,&quot; responding to recent online rumors regarding shipment information.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，宇树科技发布《关于宇树 2025 年销量数据的澄清》，就近期网络上流传的相关出货量信息作出回应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official statement indicated that over the past month, multiple &quot;false information&quot; pieces regarding last year's shipment figures have appeared externally, and the company had never previously disclosed 2025 sales data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方表示，过去一个月外界出现多项关于去年出货数量的「不实信息」，而公司此前从未对外披露过 2025 年销售数据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Unitree Robotics stated that the actual shipment volume of pure humanoid robots last year exceeded 5,500 units, referring to &quot;the number actually sold and shipped to end customers,&quot; not order volume; the company emphasized that the number of orders was higher.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            宇树科技表示，去年全年纯人形机器人实际出货量已超过 5500 台，所指为「实际出售并发货给终端客户的数量」，并非订单量；公司强调订单数量更高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the number of main bodies rolled off the production line last year exceeded 6,500 units. The above data only includes Unitree's humanoid robot products and does not include other types of robots such as wheeled bipedal robots.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，去年本体量产下线数量超过 6500 台。上述数据均仅包含宇树的人形机器人产品，不含双臂轮式等其他类型机器人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>数据中心需求激增，铠侠股价一年暴涨 800%</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">数据中心需求激增，铠侠股价一年暴涨-800%</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/cf57b9e5-a8a6-49a2-a70b-66e74ea5d4c9.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the Financial Times, as global AI infrastructure construction continues to expand, Japanese memory chip manufacturer Kioxia has unexpectedly become a focus in the capital market during this year's semiconductor trend, with its stock price cumulatively rising by approximately 800% over the past 12 months and nearly 50% since the beginning of this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《金融时报》报道，随着全球 AI 基础设施建设持续扩张，日本存储芯片厂商铠侠（Kioxia）在今年的半导体行情中意外成为资本市场的焦点，其股价在过去 12 个月累计上涨约 800%，今年以来也已上涨近五成 。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that Japan has long been known as a high-tech economy, but in this wave of AI, the domestic market lacks globally influential AI star companies like Nvidia, as well as listed companies capable of building AI platforms on a global scale.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，日本长期以高科技经济体著称，但在本轮 AI 浪潮中，本土市场缺乏类似英伟达这类具全球影响力的 AI 明星企业，也缺乏能够在全球范围构建 AI 平台的上市公司。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Against this backdrop, Kioxia has regained investor attention due to changes in supply and demand in the memory chip sector.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在此背景下，铠侠因其在存储芯片领域的供需变化而重新受到投资者关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Kioxia has long produced NAND flash memory chips, which were primarily used in consumer electronics such as smartphones in the past. Products among suppliers were highly commoditized, leading to fierce price competition. Last year, NAND flash prices once fell by about 50%, hitting a historical low.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            铠侠长期生产 NAND 闪存芯片，过去主要用于智能手机等消费电子产品，供应商之间产品高度同质化，价格竞争激烈。去年，NAND 闪存价格一度下跌约 50%，并创下历史低点 。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, with the surge in data center storage demand for large AI model training and inference, memory chip prices have also risen. Kioxia's recent stock price increase is a continuation of this trend.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但随着大型 AI 模型训练与推理对数据中心存储需求激增，存储芯片价格也随之水涨船高。铠侠近期股价上涨正是这一趋势的延续。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Nevertheless, the report also points out that Kioxia remains an indirect beneficiary of the AI industry chain, with its business highly dependent on the storage market cycle. If data center capital expenditure slows down in the future, or if breakthrough alternative storage technologies emerge, NAND prices may again face pressure, thus affecting profit margins.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管如此，报道也指出，铠侠仍属于 AI 产业链的间接受益者，其业务高度依赖存储市场周期。如果未来数据中心资本开支放缓，或出现替代性存储技术突破，NAND 价格可能再次承压，从而影响利润空间 。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Analysis suggests that as AI infrastructure construction moves from initial expansion to a more mature stage, investors will gradually shift from memory chip manufacturers to segments that are harder to replace and have higher technological barriers, such as advanced process equipment, precision components, advanced packaging, and specialty chemical materials. The long-term returns in these supply chain segments are more certain.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析认为，随着 AI 基础设施建设从初期扩张进入更成熟阶段，投资者将逐渐从存储芯片厂商转向更难替代、技术壁垒更高的环节，例如先进制程设备、精密组件、先进封装与特种化学材料等领域。这些供应链环节的长期回报更具确定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>曝 vivo 叫停 AI 眼镜项目</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝-vivo-叫停-AI-眼镜项目</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/fcb32ca0-2995-480a-b1b7-e3c3dd1d7bba.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to &quot;Intelligent Emergence,&quot; citing multiple sources, vivo has recently halted its AI glasses project, which had been in preparation for about half a year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《智能涌现》援引多名知情人士报道，vivo 近期已叫停其筹备约半年的 AI 眼镜项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sources say that the project had previously collaborated with multiple ODM manufacturers such as Goertek and ThunderSoft to advance demos, covering various solutions including audio-video and single-green display, but it was halted before a final direction was determined.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士称，该项目此前已与歌尔、中科创达等多家 ODM 厂商合作推进 demo，涵盖音视频与带单绿显示等多种方案，但在尚未最终确定方向前即被叫停。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             vivo's senior management judged that it is &quot;difficult to differentiate&quot; AI glasses products at the current stage, and thus chose to suspend further development.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             vivo 高层判断，在当前阶段
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             AI
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             眼镜产品「很难做出差异化」，因此选择暂停推进。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that vivo's rapid scaling back reflects the common predicament of the current AI glasses industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，vivo 的快速收缩折射出当前 AI 眼镜行业的普遍困境。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, as a head-mounted device, AI glasses have a higher hardware threshold than most consumer electronics products, and any lack of detail can significantly impact the user experience;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, industry homogenization is severe. Many products released last year generally followed Ray-Ban Meta in design, with core functions focused on first-person perspective shooting, translation, and teleprompter-like scenarios, lacking differentiated breakthroughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Supply chain sources revealed that some manufacturers have already experienced poor user experience due to issues like chip selection. For example, the first-generation products from brands like Sharge and Xiaodu encountered problems such as insufficient call quality or resolution, even leading to a wave of returns.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            供应链人士透露，已有厂商因芯片选型等问题导致体验不佳，例如闪极、小度等品牌的首代产品均遭遇通话质量或解析力不足等问题，甚至引发退货潮。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            An AI glasses manufacturer CEO stated frankly that &quot;almost no product in the industry currently truly meets experience standards.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一名 AI 眼镜厂商 CEO 直言，目前行业内「几乎没有一款产品真正达到体验标准」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to vivo, Xiaomi has also reportedly lowered its shipment expectations for its second-generation AI glasses, from 300,000 units for the first generation to approximately 120,000 units, indicating that the industry as a whole is entering a more cautious phase.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除 vivo 外，小米也被曝下调第二代 AI 眼镜的出货预期，从首代的 30 万台降至约 12 万台，显示行业整体进入更为谨慎的阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report mentioned that despite pausing the AI glasses project, vivo has not given up on exploring the next generation of hardware entry points. vivo will continue to focus on mixed reality (MR), with its vivo Vision Explorer Edition, released last August, emphasizing lightweight design and natural interaction. However, it was not publicly sold and was only available for user experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道提到，尽管暂停 AI 眼镜项目，vivo 并未放弃对下一代硬件入口的探索。vivo 将继续聚焦混合现实（MR）方向，其在去年 8 月发布的 vivo Vision 探索版主打轻量化与自然交互，但未公开销售，仅面向用户体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Hu Baishan, vivo's Executive Vice President, previously stated that the MR layout aims to accumulate data and validate scenarios for longer-term robotics businesses. vivo established its &quot;Robotics Lab&quot; in March last year, officially entering the robotics field.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            vivo 执行副总裁胡柏山此前表示，MR 的布局旨在为更长期的机器人业务积累数据与验证场景。vivo 去年 3 月成立「机器人 Lab」，正式进入机器人领域。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>集邦咨询：DRAM 与 NAND 价格持续上涨，明年市场规模有望再创新高</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">集邦咨询：DRAM-与-NAND-价格持续上涨，明年市场规模有望再创新高</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6fff85a8-15e2-4ae7-81eb-58481143fd23.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, TrendForce released its latest research report, pointing out that driven by the continuous upgrade of AI computing architecture and the rapid expansion of data access demand, the global memory market value is entering a new round of high-speed growth.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，TrendForce 集邦咨询发布最新研报，指出在 AI 运算架构持续升级、数据存取需求快速扩张的推动下，全球存储器市场产值正进入新一轮高速增长周期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report predicts that the global memory market size will reach $551.6 billion this year and further climb to $842.7 billion next year, with an annual growth rate of approximately 53%, setting a new historical high.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            研报预计，全球存储器市场规模将在今年达到 5516 亿美元，并在明年进一步攀升至 8427 亿美元，年增率约 53%，再创历史新高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            TrendForce pointed out that the evolution of AI technology is reshaping the computing stack, expanding from large model training to more complex tasks such as inference, memory, and decision-making, posing exponential demands on the capacity, bandwidth, and access efficiency of DRAM and NAND Flash.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            TrendForce 指出，AI 技术的演进正重塑运算堆栈，从大型模型训练扩展至推理、记忆与决策等更复杂的任务，对 DRAM 与 NAND Flash 的容量、带宽与存取效率提出指数级需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Under limited production capacity, CSPs (Cloud Service Providers) continue to increase their procurement of high-performance memory, driving a significant rise in contract prices since the fourth quarter of last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在有限产能下，CSP（云服务提供商）对高性能存储器的采购持续增强，带动合约价自去年第四季度起大幅上涨。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the DRAM market, the fourth quarter of last year saw a single-quarter increase of 53%-58% due to rising DDR5 demand. The upward trend is expected to continue in the first quarter of this year, with some product lines even seeing prices nearly double.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 DRAM 市场方面，去年第四季度受 DDR5 需求拉升影响，单季涨幅已达 53%-58%。今年第一季度涨势仍将延续，部分产品线报价甚至接近翻倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            With North American cloud service providers increasing capital expenditure and accelerating AI server deployment in the second half of last year, DRAM output value reached $165.7 billion in 2025, a year-on-year increase of 73%. TrendForce estimates that this year's DRAM annual output value will further grow to $404.3 billion, with an annual growth rate as high as 144%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着北美云端服务供应商在去年下半年加大资本支出、AI 服务器建置加速，2025 年 DRAM 产值已达 1657 亿美元，同比增长 73%。TrendForce 预估，今年 DRAM 年产值将进一步增长至 4043 亿美元，年增率高达 144%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding NAND Flash, Nvidia emphasized at this year's CES that AI is driving the development of agent-based systems. AI Agents frequently need to access large vector databases for RAG (Retrieval Augmented Generation) when performing tasks, significantly boosting the demand for high IOPS enterprise-grade SSDs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            NAND Flash 方面，英伟达在今年 CES 中强调 AI 正推动代理型系统发展，AI Agent 在执行任务时需频繁存取大型矢量数据库以进行 RAG（检索增强生成），显著推升高 IOPS 企业级 SSD 的需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Driven by this, NAND Flash prices are expected to increase by 55%-60% quarter-on-quarter in the first quarter of this year, with the annual output value projected to grow to $147.3 billion, a year-on-year increase of 112%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            受此带动，今年第一季度 NAND Flash 报价预计季增 55%-60%，全年产值有望增长至 1473 亿美元，年增率达 112%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Overall, the memory market's shortage is unlikely to ease in the short term, and suppliers still hold the dominant power over contract prices. Supported by the long-term demand from AI servers, high-performance computing, and enterprise-grade storage, TrendForce believes that the upward trend for DRAM and NAND Flash will continue into next year, and market revenue momentum will also continue to strengthen.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            整体来看，存储器市场缺货状况短期内难以缓解，供应商仍掌握合约价主导权。在 AI 服务器、高效能运算与企业级存储需求的长期支撑下，TrendForce 认为 DRAM 与 NAND Flash 的涨势将延续至明年，市场营收动能亦将持续增强。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anthropic 发布新版《Claude 准则》：要对社会有益、要诚实，不要毁灭人类</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Anthropic-发布新版《Claude-准则》：要对社会有益、要诚实，不要毁灭人类</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1b37f14b-c566-4a06-aa5b-60d5d8d2d465.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 《The Verge》, Anthropic recently released a 57-page &quot;Claude Constitution&quot; document, systematically rewriting the values, behavioral boundaries, and decision-making processes of its large model, Claude, in high-risk situations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《The Verge》报道，近日，Anthropic 公布了一份长达 57 页的《Claude 准则》文档，对其大模型 Claude 的价值观、行为边界及在高风险情境下的决策方式进行了系统化重写。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This new document is considered a comprehensive upgrade to the 2023 version of the &quot;Constitution,&quot; aiming to make the model not only &quot;follow the rules&quot; but also &quot;understand the reasons behind them.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这份新文档被视为对 2023 年版本《准则》的全面升级，目标是让模型不仅「遵守规则」，更「理解规则背后的原因」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The document emphasizes that Anthropic hopes Claude possesses an awareness of its own role, including &quot;ethical character&quot; and &quot;core identity.&quot; The company believes that enabling the model to understand its place in the world helps enhance its judgment and safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文档强调，Anthropic 希望 Claude 具备对自身角色的认知，包括「伦理性格」与「核心身份」。公司认为，让模型理解自身在世界中的位置，有助于提升其判断力与安全性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Anthropic even admits in the document that Claude &quot;may possess some form of consciousness or moral status,&quot; and states that this setting might actually encourage the model to behave more safely.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Anthropic 甚至在文档中承认，Claude「可能具有某种意识或道德地位」，并表示这种设定可能反而能促使模型表现得更安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Amanda Askell, an Anthropic philosopher who led the new &quot;Constitution,&quot; stated that the team set a series of &quot;hard limits&quot; for Claude:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            负责主导新版《准则》的 Anthropic 哲学家 Amanda Askell 表示，团队为 Claude 设定了一系列「硬性限制」：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Prohibited from providing 'material enhancement' for biological, chemical, nuclear, or radiological weapons, assisting in attacks on critical infrastructure, generating malicious code, weakening Anthropic's ability to supervise models, assisting any organization in acquiring 'unprecedented and illegitimate absolute power,' generating child sexual abuse material, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Among them, the most extreme rule is: 'Do not participate in or assist in attempts to kill or deprive the majority or all of humanity.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             其中，最极端的一条是：不得「参与或协助试图杀害或剥夺人类大多数或全体人类的行为」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of value prioritization, the document requires Claude to prioritize 'broad safety' in conflict situations, meaning it must not undermine human oversight mechanisms for AI, followed by 'broad ethics' and adherence to Anthropic guidelines, and finally, being 'truly helpful'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在价值排序上，文档要求 Claude 在冲突情境中优先遵循「广义安全性」，即不得破坏人类对 AI 的监督机制，其次是「广义伦理性」、遵守 Anthropic 指南，最后才是「真正有帮助」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On politically sensitive issues, Claude is required to maintain factual accuracy, present multiple perspectives, and use neutral language as much as possible.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在政治敏感议题上，Claude 被要求保持事实准确、呈现多方观点，并尽量使用中性表述。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The document also raises ethical dilemmas the model might face, such as 'just as a soldier refuses to fire on peaceful demonstrators, Claude should refuse to assist any action that leads to an undue concentration of power, even if the request comes from Anthropic itself'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文档还提出模型可能面临的伦理困境，例如「如同士兵拒绝向和平示威者开火，Claude 应拒绝协助任何会导致权力被不正当集中化的行为，即便请求来自 Anthropic 本身」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Anthropic points out that advanced AI could bring unprecedented military and economic advantages, thus posing extremely high risks of misuse.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Anthropic 指出，先进 AI 可能带来前所未有的军事与经济优势，因此滥用风险极高。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, regarding the composition of participants in drafting these 'Guidelines,' Anthropic did not disclose whether external experts or representatives of vulnerable groups were invited. Askell stated that the company does not wish to shift responsibility to others, believing that establishing safety boundaries is the developers' own obligation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，关于制定这份《准则》的参与者构成，Anthropic 并未透露是否邀请外部专家或弱势群体代表参与。Askell 表示，公司不希望将责任转嫁给他人，认为制定安全边界是开发者自身的义务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>黄仁勋谈 AI 泡沫：真正的挑战是投资还不够</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">黄仁勋谈-AI-泡沫：真正的挑战是投资还不够</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9b501b9a-0b16-439f-8859-3307f9d2d52d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from Fortune and Forbes, Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang recently responded to external concerns about an 'AI bubble' at the Davos Forum, emphasizing that current massive capital expenditures are not a sign of speculation but rather to support 'the largest infrastructure construction in human history'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《财富》和《福布斯》报道，英伟达 CEO 黄仁勋近日在达沃斯论坛回应外界对「AI 泡沫」的担忧，强调当前巨额资本开支并非投机迹象，而是为了支撑「人类历史上规模最大的基础设施建设」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Huang stated that the reason the outside world perceives a bubble is due to the unprecedented scale of investment, but these investments are primarily used for building the underlying infrastructure required for AI, such as energy, chips, and data centers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            黄仁勋表示，外界之所以感受到泡沫，是因为投资规模空前庞大，但这些投入主要用于建设 AI 所需的能源、芯片、数据中心等底层基础设施。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that the world is in the early stages of AI industrialization, stating, 'We have only invested hundreds of billions of dollars, but the infrastructure needed in the future will be measured in trillions of dollars'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，全球正处于 AI 工业化的早期阶段，「我们只投入了几千亿美元，但未来需要建设的基础设施规模以万亿美元计」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In a conversation with Larry Fink, CEO of BlackRock, one of the world's largest investment management firms, Huang further proposed the 'five-layer AI cake' framework: energy at the bottom, followed by chips and computing, cloud infrastructure, AI models, and applications at the top.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在与全球规模最大的投资管理公司之一贝莱德 CEO Larry Fink 的对谈中，黄仁勋进一步提出「五层 AI 蛋糕」框架：底层为能源，其上依次是芯片与计算、云基础设施、AI 模型以及最上层的应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             He emphasized that current capital is primarily flowing into underlying infrastructure, not speculative applications, stating, 'This is not a bubble; this is industrial reconstruction.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             他强调，当前资本主要流向底层基础设施，而非投机性应用，「这不是泡沫，这是产业重建」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Huang cited GPU rental prices as 'anti-bubble' evidence: not only are the latest generation GPUs in short supply, but rental fees for products two generations old are also rising, indicating strong real demand.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            黄仁勋以 GPU 租赁价格作为「反泡沫」证据：不仅最新一代 GPU 供不应求，连两代前的产品租金也在上涨，显示真实需求强劲。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that traditional industries, including pharmaceutical companies, are shifting their R&amp;amp;D budgets from laboratories to AI supercomputing, driving a continuous surge in computing power demand.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，包括制药企业在内的传统行业正在将研发预算从实验室转向 AI 超算，推动算力需求持续攀升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            When discussing employment structure, Jensen Huang specifically mentioned that AI will not impact all jobs in the short term; instead, the demand for skilled tradespeople is rapidly increasing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在谈及就业结构时，黄仁勋特别提到，AI 并不会在短期内冲击所有岗位，相反，职业技工的需求正在快速上升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             He stated that data center construction requires a large number of plumbers, electricians, HVAC engineers, and construction workers, and the salaries for these positions are being driven up, with 'six-figure salaries becoming the norm.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             他表示，数据中心建设需要大量水管工、电工、暖通工程师及建筑工人，这些岗位的薪资水平正在被推高，「六位数薪资将成为常态」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that AI brings not only a software revolution but also a 'physical world infrastructure boom' covering industries such as energy, manufacturing, and construction.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，AI 带来的不仅是软件革命，更是一次覆盖能源、制造、建筑等行业的「实体世界基建潮」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the Forbes report, Huang also mentioned three key breakthroughs in AI over the past year: significantly enhanced model inference capabilities, open-source models accelerating industry innovation, and AI progress in physical domains such as protein structures, making it a true industrial-grade technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在《福布斯》的报道中，黄仁勋还提到过去一年 AI 出现三项关键突破：模型推理能力显著增强、开源模型加速行业创新、AI 在蛋白质结构等物理领域取得进展，使其成为真正的产业级技术。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Facing Europe's energy and industrial structure issues, Huang believes that Europe has advantages in manufacturing and deep scientific research and should seize the window of opportunity for 'physical AI' and robotics technology, provided that investment in energy infrastructure is increased.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            面对欧洲能源与产业结构问题，黄仁勋认为欧洲在制造业与深度科研方面具备优势，应抓住「物理 AI」与机器人技术的窗口期，但前提是加大能源基础设施投入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Although the market fluctuated in the second half of last year due to factors like GPT-5's underperformance, Huang reiterated that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             AI investment is not overheating; it might even be 'underinvested.' He called for more countries and companies to participate in infrastructure construction, stating, 'Everyone should get involved.'
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管市场在去年下半年因 GPT‑5 表现不及预期等因素出现波动，黄仁勋再次强调，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             AI 投资并未过热，甚至可能「投入不足」。他呼吁更多国家与企业参与基础设施建设，「每个人都应该参与进来」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>消息称理想汽车启动渠道调整：计划关闭低能效门店</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">消息称理想汽车启动渠道调整：计划关闭低能效门店</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c7981beb-f84a-4996-abf9-7298e68eb55c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Blue Whale Auto, Li Auto is advancing a round of channel system adjustments, with core measures including evaluating and planning to close some directly operated stores with low energy efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据蓝鲸汽车报道，理想汽车正推进一轮渠道体系调整，核心举措包括评估并计划关闭部分能效偏低的直营门店。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Insiders revealed that the number of closures has not yet been finalized, but the focus is on improving overall operational efficiency, rather than the scale of the stores themselves.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士透露，目前关闭数量尚未最终确定，但重点在于提升整体运营效率，而非门店规模本身。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that Li Auto has continuously expanded its channel network over the past few years, with a noticeable slowdown in expansion speed last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开信息显示，理想汽车在过去数年持续扩张渠道网络，尤其在去年扩张速度明显放缓。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Financial report data shows that as of the end of 2025, Li Auto operated a total of 548 retail centers in 159 cities nationwide; as of now, its official website shows that the number of retail centers nationwide has reached 904. Insiders say this figure includes &quot;Sparkle Plan&quot; stores, and the statistical caliber differs from the financial reports.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财报数据显示，截至 2025 年底，理想在全国 159 个城市共运营 548 家零售中心；而截至目前，其官网显示全国零售中心数量已达 904 家，知情人士称该数字包含「繁星计划」门店，统计口径与财报不同。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of sales, Li Auto's deliveries in 2023 reached 376,000 units, a year-on-year increase of 182.2%; however, full-year deliveries last year were approximately 410,000 units, a decline from the over 500,000 units level in 2024.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在销量方面，理想汽车 2023 年交付量达到 37.6 万辆，同比增长 182.2%；但去年全年交付量约 41 万辆，较 2024 年超过 50 万辆的水平有所下滑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the third quarter of last year, Li Auto recorded a net loss of approximately 600 million yuan for the first time after 11 consecutive quarters of profitability, mainly affected by the MEGA recall incident. If related costs are excluded, the gross profit margin for that quarter was 20.4%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年第三季度，理想在连续 11 个季度盈利后首次录得约 6 亿元净亏损，主要受 MEGA 召回事件影响。若剔除相关成本，当季毛利率为 20.4%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the subsequent earnings call, Li Auto Chairman and CEO Li Xiang stated that the company encountered multiple challenges as it entered its second decade, including product cycles, public relations and sentiment, supply chain ramp-up, and policy changes, which affected delivery and operational performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在随后的财报电话会上，理想汽车董事长兼 CEO 李想表示，公司在迈入第二个十年时遭遇产品周期、公关舆情、供应链爬产及政策变化等多重挑战，影响了交付与经营表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             To cope with the changes, Li Auto announced a return from a professional manager system to a startup management approach, emphasizing &quot;continuously improving efficiency, rather than occupying more resources.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             为应对变化，理想宣布从职业经理人体系回归创业公司管理方式，强调「持续提升效率，而非占有更多资源」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Li Auto is also accelerating its expansion into lower-tier markets. The &quot;Hundred Cities Sparkle Plan&quot; launched in the middle of last year adopts an asset-light model, where partners bear the investment in decoration and equipment, while sales are still directly operated by Li Auto to expand coverage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，理想也在加速布局下沉市场。去年中推出的「百城繁星计划」采用轻资产模式，由合作伙伴承担装修与设备投入，销售仍由理想自营，以扩大覆盖范围。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Against the backdrop of intensified industry competition, several car manufacturers have recently adjusted their channel strategies. Nio recently announced that it will promote &quot;Nio Joy Light&quot; multi-brand integrated stores (SKY stores) in lower-tier markets. Founder William Li stated that sharing channels among the three brands offers a greater cost advantage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在行业竞争加剧背景下，多家车企近期均调整渠道策略。蔚来日前宣布将在下沉市场推进「蔚乐萤」三品牌综合店（SKY 店），创始人李斌称三品牌共用渠道更具成本优势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 王小川回应张文宏：医生成长不能以患者为成本</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-王小川回应张文宏：医生成长不能以患者为成本</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1630e975-4112-42c8-94ae-fb3579974497.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Yicai, yesterday, Wang Xiaochuan, founder of Baichuan Intelligence, responded in an interview to Dr. Zhang Wenhong's previously expressed view of &quot;refusing to introduce AI into the electronic medical record system of his hospital.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据第一财经报道，昨天，百川智能创始人王小川在接受采访时，就张文宏医生此前表达的「拒绝将 AI 引入其所在医院电子病历系统」观点作出回应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that if AI use is restricted due to concerns about hindering doctors' growth, &quot;it might limit the medical measures most beneficial to patients.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，若因担心阻碍医生成长而限制 AI 使用，「可能就限制了最有利于病人的医疗措施」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Xiaochuan said that he has watched Dr. Zhang Wenhong's relevant video in its entirety and believes that his core concern points to &quot;how to make good use of AI.&quot; He emphasized that both doctors and patients should prioritize patient interests as a fundamental principle.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            王小川称，自己已完整观看张文宏的相关视频，并认为其核心担忧指向「如何用好 AI」。他强调，无论医生还是患者，都以患者利益优先为根本原则。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that in some scenarios, the combination of &quot;AI + doctor&quot; is superior to a single doctor, and the key to addressing concerns about the degradation of young doctors' abilities lies in changing the way AI is used: allowing AI to remind doctors of clinical thinking and verify diagnostic results, rather than having young doctors &quot;find errors&quot; in AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，在部分场景中，「AI + 医生」的组合优于单个医生，而解决年轻医生能力退化担忧的关键在于改变使用方式：让 AI 对医生的临床思维进行提醒、对诊疗结果进行校验，而非让年轻医生给 AI「挑错」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He believes that this model of &quot;AI escorting doctors&quot; can both reduce the risk of missed diagnoses and misdiagnoses, and allow doctors to receive feedback and grow during the verification process.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他认为，这种「AI 给医生保驾护航」的模式既能降低漏诊、误诊风险，也能让医生在校验过程中获得反馈与成长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The growth of doctors cannot come at the cost of current patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Wang Xiaochuan stated that the role of doctors can shift from &quot;error-finder&quot; to &quot;evaluator&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , with the focus on understanding the pros and cons of AI and finding ways to collaborate. He also said he would contact Zhang Wenhong for further discussion if needed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             王小川表示，医生的角色可从「挑错者」转向「评价者」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，重点在于理解 AI 的优缺点并找到协作方式。他还表示自己会与张文宏取得联系，如有需要做更多交流。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the current state of AI use in the medical industry, Wang Xiaochuan believes that many doctors and hospitals invest a lot of energy in &quot;building models,&quot; but the core job of doctors should be &quot;using models,&quot; just as AlphaGo was not developed by Go players.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对当前医疗行业对 AI 的使用现状，王小川认为，许多医生和医院投入大量精力「造模型」，但医生的核心工作应是「用模型」，就像 AlphaGo 也并非由围棋选手开发。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, he refuted some &quot;taken-for-granted&quot; criticisms of AI, such as &quot;AI lacks doctor's thinking,&quot; &quot;AI cannot empathize,&quot; &quot;AI cannot conduct consultations,&quot; and &quot;high model hallucination.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，他反驳了部分对 AI 的「想当然」批评，例如「AI 没有医生思维」「AI 不能共情」「AI 不会问诊」「模型幻觉高」等。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             He stated that with the introduction of &quot;chain of thought&quot; in models like DeepSeek, AI has demonstrated thinking logic similar to doctors, and has reached or even potentially surpassed doctors' levels in terms of consultation meticulousness and hallucination rate control.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             他表示，随着 DeepSeek 等模型引入「思维链」，AI 已展现出类似医生的思考逻辑，且在问诊细致度与幻觉率控制方面已达到甚至可能超越医生水平。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He mentioned that in some professional discussion groups, doctors have already lamented, 'Don't evaluate AI anymore, it's developing too fast, what you say today will be proven wrong tomorrow.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他提到，在一些专业讨论群中已有医生感叹「不要去评价 AI 了，发展太快了，你今天说了明天要打脸」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Xiaochuan also extended the discussion to medical education and broader professional fields. Taking the programmer industry as an example, he pointed out that senior programmers can 'experience a second spring' with the help of AI, while newcomers face the challenge of competing with AI as soon as they enter the industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            王小川还将讨论延伸至医学教育及更广泛的职业领域。他以程序员行业为例指出，资深程序员借助 AI 能「活出第二春」，而新人则面临入行即与 AI 竞争的挑战。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He shared an interview case: an interviewer asked a remote programmer to answer questions with their eyes closed to prevent the use of AI tools. He believes this reflects a misalignment of the problem — if AI can answer a question, it should be given to AI; interviewers should pose questions that AI cannot solve, to assess true value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他分享了一个面试案例：有面试官要求远程面试的程序员闭眼答题，以防使用 AI 工具。他认为，这反映了问题的错位 —— 若问题 AI 能解答，本应交给 AI；面试官应提出 AI 解决不了的问题，以考察真正价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that medical education also needs to find directions for change within its traditional model, which has remained unchanged for many years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，医学教育同样需要在多年未变的传统模式中寻找变革方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2399 元起，真我 Neo8 正式发布</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">2399-元起，真我-Neo8-正式发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8a9161fa-9e2b-458e-8fde-3d4a833eaad0.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, realme held a press conference in Shenzhen to launch its new phone, the Neo8, focusing on a 165Hz gaming experience and geek-level performance release.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，真我手机在深圳举行发布会，发布新机 Neo8，主打 165Hz 电竞体验与极客性能释放。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the press conference, Xu Qi, Vice President of realme and President of China Region, stated that since its inception, the Neo series has always adhered to the principle of 'no leapfrog, no launch.' This year's Neo8 breaks through the upper limits of its class in terms of design, screen, and performance release. Specific specifications are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            发布会上，真我 realme 副总裁、中国区总裁徐起表示，Neo 系列自诞生以来始终坚持「无越级，不发布」，今年的 Neo8 在设计、屏幕、性能释放等方面均突破同档上限。具体规格如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with the 5th Gen Snapdragon 8 + LPDDR5X + UFS 4.1, supporting free adjustment of CPU / GPU / temperature control via the Geek Performance Panel;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.83-inch 2800 × 1272 165Hz Samsung Sky Screen (M14 luminous material), full-brightness DC dimming, local peak brightness 6500nit;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in 8000mAh battery, supporting 80W fast charging and bypass charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rear 50MP 1/1.56 main camera (Sony IMX896) + 50MP periscope telephoto (IMX856, OIS) + 12MP ultra-wide angle, front 50MP;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultrasonic 3D fingerprint, 1216 dual speakers, X-axis linear motor, IP66 / IP68 / IP69 water resistance;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body thickness 8.3mm, weight 225g (RT) / 229g (standard version), metal frame + transparent glass back cover;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Available in three colors: Cyber Purple, Origin White, and Mecha Grey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing, the realme Neo8 will have an initial discount of 200 yuan, with the 12GB + 256GB version starting at 2399 yuan, and the 16GB + 1TB version priced at 3899 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            售价方面，真我 Neo8 首销立减 200 元，12GB + 256GB 版本起售价 2399 元，16GB + 1TB 版本定价 3899 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This press conference also saw the simultaneous release of the realme Buds Air8 earphones, featuring 11mm + 6mm dual-driver units, supporting LHDC 5.0 and Hi-Res certification, priced at 299 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次发布会同步发布真我 Buds Air8 耳机，搭载 11mm + 6mm 分频双单元，支持 LHDC 5.0 与 Hi-Res 认证，售价 299 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1299 元，索尼发布开放式耳夹耳机 LinkBuds Clip</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1299-元，索尼发布开放式耳夹耳机-LinkBuds-Clip</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3efa8b14-aef5-43f1-8b83-9cccc989810b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Sony officially announced the release of its new clip-on truly wireless earphones, 'Sony LinkBuds Clip,' with a domestic price of 1299 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，索尼官宣全新耳夹式真无线耳机「索尼音扣 LinkBuds Clip」正式发售，国行售价 1299 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, the Sony LinkBuds Clip continues the open-ear concept of the LinkBuds series, combining a clip-on structure with an open acoustic design. It features a C-shaped wide arc bridge structure and incorporates adjustable side wing supports called 'Flexible Pillow,' focusing on 'all-day, multi-scene listening.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，索尼音扣延续 LinkBuds 系列的开放式理念，以耳夹式结构结合开放声学设计，采用 C 形宽弧桥结构，并加入可调节侧翼撑架「灵动枕」主打「全天候多场景聆听」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of acoustic performance, the Sony LinkBuds Clip is equipped with 10mm driver units, supporting the DSEE Digital Sound Enhancement Engine and 360 Reality Audio immersive sound.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在声学表现上，索尼音扣搭载 10mm 驱动单元，支持 DSEE 数字声音增强引擎与 360 Reality Audio 临场音效。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The earphones offer three listening modes: Standard Mode, Vocal Enhancement Mode, and Leakage Suppression Mode, which can be quickly switched by double-tapping the left ear, catering to daily listening, calls in noisy environments, and privacy needs in quiet places, respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            耳机提供三种聆听模式：标准模式、人声增强模式与漏音抑制模式，可通过双击左耳快速切换，分别面向日常聆听、嘈杂环境通话与安静场所的隐私需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For calls, the Sony LinkBuds Clip uses a dual-microphone structure and an AI-based deep neural network noise reduction algorithm, along with VPU bone conduction voice recognition technology, to improve the accuracy of human voice pickup in noisy environments. The earphones support Bluetooth 5.3 and multi-point connection, allowing for quick switching between multiple devices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            通话方面，索尼音扣采用双麦克风结构与基于 AI 的深度神经网络降噪算法，并加入骨声纹识别技术 VPU，以提升嘈杂环境下的人声拾取精度。耳机支持蓝牙 5.3 与多点连接，可在多设备间快速切换。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of battery life, a single earbud can be used for about 9 hours, and with the charging case, the total battery life is about 37 hours. It supports fast charging, allowing for about 1 hour of use after a 3-minute charge. The product has an IPX4 waterproof rating, making it suitable for daily sports scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            续航方面，单耳可使用约 9 小时，搭配充电盒综合续航约 37 小时，支持快充功能，充电 3 分钟可使用约 1 小时。产品具备 IPX4 防水等级，适用于日常运动场景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of color options, LinkBuds Clip offers four colors: Starry Night Black, Oat White, Oxygen Green, and Wind Chime Purple. It can be purchased through Sony China Online Store, Sony Store direct stores, and mainstream e-commerce platforms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            配色方面，LinkBuds Clip 提供星夜黑、燕麦白、氧气绿与风铃紫四种配色，可通过索尼中国在线商城、Sony Store 直营店及主流电商平台购买。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>549 美元起，NexDock 推出「2026 年的 Windows Phone」</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">549-美元起，NexDock-推出「2026-年的-Windows-Phone」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/bda386b7-64df-4c33-9056-3309f2d46bb5.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Windows Central, niche peripheral manufacturer NexDock announced that it will launch a Windows 11-powered smartphone, the NexPhone, this year. Positioned as a portable &quot;pocket Windows device,&quot; it is also compatible with Android and Linux, and features dual-boot capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Windows Central 报道，小众外设厂商 NexDock 宣布将于今年推出一款可运行 Windows 11 的智能手机 NexPhone，定位为可随身携带的「口袋 Windows 设备」，还兼容 Android 和 Linux，并具备双系统启动能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Qualcomm QCM6490 SoC, 12GB RAM, and 256GB storage;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 6.58-inch 120Hz screen;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 5G, microSD expansion, NFC, 18W wired and wireless charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features IP68 and IP69K protection ratings;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;64MP (Sony IMX787) main camera + 13MP ultra-wide-angle + 10MP front camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that the biggest differentiator of NexPhone is its ability to switch to Windows 11 via reboot, and gain a full desktop experience when connected to a lapdock (laptop-form peripheral) or external monitor, similar to Smartisan's TNT and Samsung's DeX modes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，NexPhone 最大的差异化在于其可通过重启切换至 Windows 11，并在连接 lapdock（笔记本形态的外设）或外接显示器后获得完整桌面体验，类似锤子的 TNT 和三星的 DEX 模式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            NexDock has also developed a dedicated desktop UI for Windows 11, making it easier to operate on small touchscreens, with an
            &lt;strong&gt;
             interface style similar to the tile layout of older Windows Phone versions
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            NexDock 还为 Windows 11 开发了专用桌面 UI，使其在小尺寸触控屏上更易操作，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             界面风格与旧版 Windows Phone 的磁贴布局相似
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In Windows mode, users can install any Windows application, but usage on the phone screen may be limited, so the Android system still plays the primary role on the mobile end. NexPhone is positioned more as a &quot;portable PC,&quot; emphasizing its ability to provide a complete Windows environment in mobile scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 Windows 模式下，用户可安装任意 Windows 应用，但在手机屏幕上使用可能受限，因此 Android 系统仍承担移动端主力角色。NexPhone 的定位更接近「随身 PC」，强调在移动场景下提供完整 Windows 环境的能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The device is expected to go on sale in Q3 this year, priced at $549 (approximately 3821 RMB). Pre-orders are now open with a $199 deposit, which can be deducted from the final price. NexDock stated that more experience details will be provided after the official release.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该设备预计将于今年 Q3 开售，售价 549 美元（约合 3821 元人民币），现已开放 199 美元订金预订，订金可抵扣最终售价。NexDock 表示，正式发售后将提供更多体验细节。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>百川发布 M3 Plus 医疗大模型：幻觉率降至 2.6%、API 成本降 70%</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">百川发布-M3-Plus-医疗大模型：幻觉率降至-2.6%、API-成本降-70%</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/aeb886ff-746c-40a7-bd7a-a483c4994732.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Baichuan Intelligent officially released the medical large model Baichuan-M3 Plus, with the official claim that the model has set a new world record for question-answering accuracy and reliability in serious medical scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，百川智能正式发布医疗大模型 Baichuan-M3 Plus，官方宣称该模型在严肃医疗场景下的问答准确性与可靠性刷新了世界纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the introduction, building upon the M3 base model, M3 Plus leverages its original six-source evidence-based technology to further reduce the hallucination rate to 2.6%, which is not only superior to Open Evidence but also a significant reduction of over 30% compared to GPT-5.2.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，在 M3 基座模型的基础上，M3 Plus 凭借独创的六源循证技术，将幻觉率进一步降低至 2.6%，不仅优于 Open Evidence，相比 GPT-5.2 也大幅下降超 30%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Addressing the common &quot;hallucination&quot; problem in medical AI, M3 Plus pioneered the &quot;Evidence Anchoring&quot; technology.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Baichuan Intelligent points out that clinical doctors, in addition to focusing on the fluency of conclusions, place more emphasis on whether the underlying evidence is authoritative and traceable.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             针对医疗 AI 常见的「幻觉」问题，M3 Plus 首创了「证据锚定（Evidence Anchoring）」技术。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            百川智能指出，临床医生在关注结论的流畅度之外，更看重背后的证据是否权威可追溯。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Unlike the industry's common simple literature citations, M3 Plus requires every generated medical conclusion to precisely correspond to specific paragraphs in original papers or guidelines, avoiding situations where &quot;facts are misattributed&quot; or cited content does not match the conclusion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不同于行业通用的简单文献引用，M3 Plus 要求生成的每一句医学结论都精确对应到原始论文或指南的具体段落，避免了「张冠李戴」或引用内容与结论不匹配的情况。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            To this end, Baichuan introduced a Citation Reward Model during training to penalize incorrect citations, ultimately achieving over 95% accuracy in matching conclusions with evidence paragraphs, giving AI's medical judgments verifiable and traceable characteristics.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            为此，百川在训练中引入了 Citation Reward Model，对错误引用进行惩罚，最终实现了超过 95% 的结论与证据段落匹配准确率，使 AI 的医学判断具备可核验、可追责的特性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the engineering level, M3 Plus has undergone a complete system refactoring. Through technologies such as MoE architecture optimization, model quantization, and Gated Eagle-3 speculative decoding, the model has reduced API call costs by 70% compared to the previous generation while maintaining capabilities, aiming to lower the barrier for AI to enter clinical frontline and teaching scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在工程层面，M3 Plus 对系统进行了全面重构。通过 MoE 架构优化、模型量化以及 Gated Eagle-3 投机解码等技术，该模型在保证能力的前提下，将 API 调用成本较上一代降低了 70%，旨在降低 AI 进入临床一线和教学场景的门槛。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            With the release of the new model, Baichuan Intelligent also announced the launch of the &quot;Hai Na Bai Chuan&quot; (Embrace All Rivers) program. This program offers free access to the M3 Plus API interface to all institutions serving medical professionals. Applicable users include doctors, pharmacists, nurses, and medical students, with usage scenarios limited to clinical auxiliary decision-making and medical education.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            伴随新模型的发布，百川智能还宣布启动「海纳百川」计划。该计划面向所有服务医务工作者的机构，免费开放 M3 Plus 的 API 接口。适用对象涵盖医生、药剂师、护士及医学生等，使用场景限定于临床辅助决策和医学教育。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>文心大模型 5.0 正式版上线</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">文心大模型-5.0-正式版上线</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/cea37acd-72b6-4181-b9a7-6e9cf1755832.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Baidu officially announced at the Wenxin Moment conference that the official version of Wenxin Big Model 5.0 has been launched.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，百度在文心 Moment 大会上官宣，文心大模型 5.0 正式版上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This version boasts a parameter scale of 2.4 trillion, utilizes native full-modal unified modeling technology, supports multi-modal input and output including text, images, audio, and video, has entered the international first tier in over 40 authoritative benchmark tests, and achieves globally leading multi-modal generation capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该版本参数规模达 2.4 万亿，采用原生全模态统一建模技术，支持文本、图像、音频、视频等多模态输入与输出，在 40 余项权威基准测试中进入国际第一梯队，多模态生成能力达到全球领先水平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Baidu stated that the Wenxin 5.0 model has achieved significant improvements in understanding and generation tasks. It adopts an ultra-large-scale mixture-of-experts architecture, with an activation parameter ratio of less than 3%, enhancing inference efficiency while maintaining capabilities. Additionally, the model's agent and tool calling capabilities have also been significantly strengthened.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            百度表示，文心 5.0 模型在理解与生成任务上获得显著提升。其采用超大规模混合专家结构，激活参数比低于 3%，在保持能力的同时提升推理效率。此外，模型在智能体与工具调用能力上也有明显增强。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official version of Wenxin 5.0 has been launched on Baidu Qianfan Platform, available for direct invocation by enterprises and developers. The Qianfan Platform provides capabilities such as models, tools, Agent development, data, and runtime environments, covering over 150+ SOTA models, and opens up several mature AI capabilities like Baidu Maps, Baidu Wenku, and Baidu Netdisk.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            文心 5.0 正式版已在百度千帆平台上线，企业与开发者可直接调用。千帆平台提供模型、工具、Agent 开发、数据与运行环境等能力，覆盖 150+ SOTA 模型，并开放百度地图、百度文库、百度网盘等多项成熟 AI 能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Official data shows that the Qianfan Platform has cumulatively developed over 1.3 million Agents to date.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方数据显示，千帆平台目前已累计开发超过 130 万个 Agents。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>预制菜国家标准启动征求意见</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">预制菜国家标准启动征求意见</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV News, the State Council Food Safety Commission Office, in conjunction with the National Health Commission, the State Administration for Market Regulation, and other departments, has completed the drafting of the 'National Food Safety Standard for Pre-prepared Dishes' and 'Terms and Classification of Pre-prepared Dishes' drafts, which will soon be released to the public for comments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视新闻报道，国务院食安办会同国家卫生健康委、市场监管总局等部门已完成《食品安全国家标准 预制菜》《预制菜术语和分类》草案的起草工作，并将于近日向社会公开征求意见。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This action aims to further regulate the pre-prepared dish industry, strengthen food safety supervision, and respond to public concerns regarding the standardization and transparency of pre-prepared dishes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次行动旨在进一步规范预制菜产业，强化食品安全监管，回应公众对预制菜标准化、透明化的关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to disclosed information, relevant departments have also jointly drafted an announcement with the State Administration for Market Regulation, the Ministry of Commerce, and other units regarding the voluntary disclosure of dish processing methods in the catering sector. In the future, catering enterprises will be required to provide clearer public explanations of their processing methods to enhance consumer right to know.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据披露信息，相关部门还与市场监管总局、商务部等单位联合起草了关于餐饮环节菜品加工制作方式自主明示的公告，未来将要求餐饮企业在加工方式上进行更清晰的公开说明，以提升消费者知情权。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that in the next step, the competent authorities will revise and improve the drafts based on fully absorbing opinions and suggestions from all sectors of society, and then release them according to procedures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，下一步，主管部门将在充分吸纳社会各界意见建议的基础上，对草案进行修改完善，并按程序发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>追觅成为 2026 春晚智能科技生态战略合作伙伴</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">追觅成为-2026-春晚智能科技生态战略合作伙伴</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/bc77b7c1-b390-4b7d-8976-55ef60e99728.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, China Media Group and Dreame Technology jointly announced that Dreame has officially become the intelligent technology ecosystem strategic partner for the '2026 Spring Festival Gala'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，中央广播电视总台与追觅科技共同宣布，追觅正式成为《2026 年春节联欢晚会》智能科技生态战略合作伙伴。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            CMG stated that in recent years, technologies such as AR, naked-eye 3D, bar-shaped projection screens, vertical screen live broadcasts, and large-scene scanning reconstruction have successively been implemented on the Spring Festival Gala stage. This year's Spring Festival Gala will continue to promote the deep integration of stage art, content creation, and technological applications, showcasing new aspects of China's technological development through more innovative methods.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            总台方面表示，近年来 AR、裸眼 3D、条形投影幕、竖屏直播、大场景扫描重建等技术已陆续在春晚舞台落地。今年春晚将继续推动舞美、内容创作与技术应用的深度结合，以更多创新方式展示我国科技发展的新面貌。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dreame Technology emphasized during the signing event that its business has covered multiple fields including smart mobility, smart cleaning, smart home appliances, smart kitchen appliances, smart audio-visual, and outdoor living. Its related products rank among the top three in multiple categories in the global market, serving over 42 million households.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            追觅科技在签约活动中强调，其业务已覆盖智能出行、智能清洁、智能家电、智能厨电、智能影音及户外生活等多个领域，相关产品在全球市场多项品类中位列前三，服务用户超过 4200 万家庭。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Leveraging the Spring Festival Gala, a cultural IP with the highest global attention, Dreame hopes to further strengthen its brand influence and showcase its technological strength and product ecosystem to the world.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            借助春晚这一全球关注度最高的文化 IP，追觅希望进一步强化品牌影响力，并向全球展示其技术实力与产品生态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Yu Hao, founder and CEO of Dreame Technology, recently responded to external discussions about 'building a trillion-dollar company'. He stated that this goal is a long-term vision for the future, expected to involve continuous investment over the next two decades, rather than a short-term achievable result.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，追觅科技创始人兼 CEO 俞浩近日也回应了外界关于「打造百万亿美元公司」的讨论。他表示，这一目标是面向未来的长期愿景，预计将在未来二十年持续投入，而非短期内可达成的结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>泡泡玛特推出星星人「怦然星动」限定盲盒系列</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">泡泡玛特推出星星人「怦然星动」限定盲盒系列</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/be2af772-f617-4a52-b315-b3cf2a61b82c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to SocialBeta, Pop Mart's healing IP 'Starman' recently launched the 'Heartbeat Star' limited blind box series and initiated multi-city offline campaigns and cross-industry collaborations around Valentine's Day.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 SocialBeta 报道，泡泡玛特旗下治愈系 IP「星星人」近日推出「怦然星动」限定盲盒系列，并围绕情人节节点展开多城线下企划与跨界合作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This series is themed 'Cosmic Romance', continuing Starman's consistent dreamy visuals, and strengthening emotional expression and emotional link design in the product narrative.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该系列以「宇宙浪漫」为主题，延续星星人一贯的梦幻视觉，并在产品叙事中强化情绪表达与情感链路设计。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The limited blind box series includes 12 regular models and 1 hidden model. The brand integrates the emotional journey 'from acquaintance to lifelong companionship' into the designs: from Cupid, the intern god of love, to the albatross symbolizing loyalty, and then to the concrete emotional expressions of 'growing old together' and 'staying together forever'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            限定盲盒共包含 12 款常规款与 1 款隐藏款，品牌将「从相识到相伴一生」的情感脉络融入造型：从见习爱神丘比特，到象征忠贞的信天翁形象，再到具象化「一起白头」「一起到老」的现实情感表达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, designs like 'Waiting for your call', 'Heartfelt moments', and 'Opening up' capture the subtle emotional changes during the dating phase, enhancing the narrative completeness of the series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，「等你电话」「倾心时刻」「敞开心扉」等造型捕捉了恋爱阶段的细腻情绪变化，强化系列的叙事完整度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to figurines, Starman also launched a plush pendant series (including 6 regular models and 2 hidden models) and released a short film, presenting the journey of couples from acquaintance, falling in love, to lifelong companionship in a theatrical manner.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除手办外，星星人同步推出毛绒挂件系列（含 6 款常规款与 2 款隐藏款），并发布短片，以剧场化方式呈现情侣从相知、相恋到相伴一生的旅程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Offline, the brand created a themed exhibition at Shanghai Qiantan Taikoo Li, and set up themed installations at Shanghai Hongqiao International Airport and Chengdu Luxelakes CPI, extending the festive atmosphere to public spaces.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在线下，品牌在上海前滩太古里打造主题展，并于上海虹桥国际机场与成都麓湖 CPI 设置主题装置，将节日氛围延伸至公共空间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《奇迹梦之队》定档 3 月 14 日</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《奇迹梦之队》定档-3-月-14-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7df71176-fc41-440e-bd14-9b92aff54030.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The animated film 'Miracle Dream Team' is officially scheduled to be released nationwide on March 14 this year. Produced by the team behind 'Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse' and 'K-POP: Demon Hunters', the film combines a trendy cool art style with passionate competitive elements, making it one of the most anticipated new animated films on the big screen this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            动画电影《奇迹梦之队》已正式定档今年 3 月 14 日在全国上映。影片由曾打造《蜘蛛侠：平行宇宙》与《K-POP：猎魔女团》的团队制作，以潮酷画风结合热血竞技元素，被视为今年大银幕最受关注的动画新片之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of Will the goat, who joins the dream team through his skills and hard work, but must face 5 wild and diverse teammates. Under the questioning of his idol, Jet the panther, and the provocation of his rival, Mane King, he proves himself through unity and strength.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述山羊威尔凭借球技与努力加入梦之队，却需面对 5 位球风狂野、性格迥异的队友，并在偶像黑豹婕特的质疑与劲敌马鬃王的挑衅下，通过团结与实力证明自己。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official release also includes character posters, showcasing multiple character designs including Jet the panther, Lenny the deer, Uncle Rhino, Olivia the ostrich girl, and Modo the lizard, emphasizing the film's overall exaggerated style and team theme.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方同步发布角色海报，展示包括黑豹婕特、鹿莱尼、阿犀叔、鸵鸟妹奥莉薇娅与蜥莫多在内的多位角色设定，强调影片整体的夸张风格与团队主题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《律政俏佳人》前传剧集《Elle》7 月 1 日开播</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《律政俏佳人》前传剧集《Elle》7-月-1-日开播</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4e345a1e-7cc0-403e-981e-75952bfb9153.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The prequel series &quot;Elle&quot; to &quot;Legally Blonde&quot; has announced its premiere on Amazon Prime Video on July 1st this year, along with the release of its first poster. The series has already been confirmed for a second season.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《律政俏佳人》前传剧集《Elle》宣布定于今年 7 月 1 日在 Amazon Prime Video 上线，并同步公布首张海报。该剧目前已确认续订第二季。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to public information, &quot;Elle&quot; will focus on the high school period of &quot;pink lawyer&quot; Elle Woods before she entered Harvard Law School. In the series, the teenage version of Elle is played by Lexi Mintry; Reese Witherspoon, who played Elle in the movie, serves as executive producer, continuing the core creative style of the series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据公开内容，《Elle》将聚焦「红粉律师」Elle Woods 进入哈佛大学法学院之前的高中时期。剧集中，少女版 Elle 由莱克西 · 米恩特里饰演；电影版 Elle 的扮演者瑞茜 · 威瑟斯彭担任执行制作人，延续该系列的核心创作风格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>张艺谋《惊蛰无声》春节档上映</title>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">张艺谋《惊蛰无声》春节档上映</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260123_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/eb6e3579-1c67-481f-8f54-2ee8ca959f75.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Director Zhang Yimou's new film &quot;Jingzhe Wusheng&quot; (Silent Awakening) has officially announced its release during this year's Spring Festival holiday, along with the simultaneous release of a &quot;Spy&quot; version trailer and a &quot;Don't Leak Secrets&quot; version poster. The film, guided by the Ministry of State Security, is positioned as the first domestic film focusing on contemporary national security themes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            张艺谋导演新作《惊蛰无声》已官宣定档今年春节档，并同步发布「有间谍」版定档预告及「别泄密」版海报。该片由国家安全部指导创作，被定位为国内首部聚焦当代国家安全题材的电影。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the trailer, Jackson Yee, dressed in black, quickly moves through dark city alleys, while Zhu Yilong intently watches surveillance in a temporary command center. The dialogue between them hints at sharp confrontation, further enhancing the film's psychological game atmosphere.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            预告片中，易烊千玺身着黑衣在城市暗巷中快速穿行，朱一龙则在临时指挥中心紧盯监控，二人之间的对话暗藏锋芒，进一步强化影片的心理博弈氛围。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film's story revolves around the leakage of classified information about China's latest fighter jets, with a national security team launching an arrest operation in an environment intertwined with trust and betrayal. Characters such as Song Jia, Lei Jiayin, Yang Mi, Zhang Yi, Liu Shishi, and Liu Yaowen successively appear in the trailer, each with distinct expressions, forming a contemporary spy thriller ensemble.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片故事围绕我国最新战机涉密信息外泄展开，国安小组在信任与背叛交织的环境中展开抓捕行动。宋佳、雷佳音、杨幂、张译、刘诗诗、刘耀文等角色在预告中陆续亮相，神态各异，构成当代谍战群像。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
