<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>微信辟谣「封号新规」传言：正常社交不会受限</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微信辟谣「封号新规」传言：正常社交不会受限</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/b9324a43-6d45-4521-b5d8-f4cbfca29f7f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, WeChat collectively debunked the so-called &quot;WeChat new rules&quot; circulating online, explicitly denying various claims about &quot;account ban new rules,&quot; and announced typical cases of Moments rumors from last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，微信对网络流传的所谓「微信新规」进行集中辟谣，明确否认外界关于「封号新规」的多种说法，并公布去年朋友圈谣言的典型案例。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            WeChat stated that claims appearing online such as &quot;Tencent WeChat Moments new rules,&quot; &quot;too many friends will lead to a ban,&quot; and &quot;unchanged address will lead to a ban&quot; are all false information. WeChat emphasized that it has never released any so-called &quot;account ban new rules,&quot; and normal social behavior will not be restricted.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微信方面表示，网络上出现的「腾讯微信朋友圈新规」「好友太多会被封」「地址不变会被封」等均属不实信息。微信强调，从未发布过任何所谓的「封号新规」，正常社交行为不会受到限制。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Officials pointed out that these rumors are mostly fabricated by black and gray industry groups. After illegally acquiring accounts, they disguise their illicit activities like using plugins to add friends and sending mass fraudulent messages as &quot;platform rules&quot; to spread externally, aiming to mislead the public.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方指出，这类谣言多由黑灰产团伙编造，其通过非法手段获取账号后，为掩盖外挂加好友、群发欺诈信息等违规行为，伪装成所谓「平台规则」对外传播，以混淆视听。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            WeChat further explained that the platform manages accounts based on public rules such as the &quot;WeChat Personal Account Usage Guidelines,&quot; and account handling is based on abnormal behavior patterns, not the so-called &quot;new rules&quot; circulating among the public.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微信进一步解释称，平台依据《微信个人账号使用规范》等公开规则进行管理，账号处置均基于异常行为模式，而非坊间流传的所谓「新规」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to WeChat-related rumors, last year the internet also saw various types of false information used for scams under the guise of policies, including &quot;five social insurances and one housing fund subsidy,&quot; &quot;parenting subsidy requiring a deposit,&quot; and &quot;Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area policy dividends distribution,&quot; all of which were explicitly refuted by relevant departments. Furthermore, claims such as &quot;AI exam prediction accuracy 98%&quot; and &quot;AI lottery number prediction 100% winning&quot; were also confirmed to be false marketing or scams.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除微信相关谣言外，去年网络还出现多类借政策名义实施诈骗的虚假信息，包括「五险一金补贴」「育儿补贴需交保证金」「粤港澳大湾区政策红利发放」等，均被相关部门明确辟谣。此外，关于「AI 押题命中率 98%」「AI 预测彩票号码百分百中奖」等说法，也被证实为虚假营销或骗局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regulatory authorities remind users to raise their vigilance, not to easily believe unverified information, to pay attention to authoritative content released through official channels, and to jointly maintain a healthy online environment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            监管部门提醒，用户应提高警惕，不轻信未经证实的信息，关注官方渠道发布的权威内容，共同维护健康的网络生态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>苹果推出 AirPods Pro 3 马年特别款</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果推出-AirPods-Pro-3-马年特别款</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/345f7177-29c3-4202-b6b3-b43f5adae25b.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Apple's official website launched the AirPods Pro 3 Year of the Horse special edition and Year of the Horse themed phone cases. The former features a charging case with an exclusive laser-engraved Year of the Horse Emoji, priced at 1899 yuan; the latter is inspired by the agility of a horse, featuring a pink, red, orange, and yellow gradient design, compatible with the entire iPhone 17 series and Air, priced at 449 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，苹果官网上架了 AirPods Pro 3 马年特别款和马年主题手机保护壳，前者充电盒采用激光镌刻独家马年 Emoji，售价 1899 元；后者以骏马灵动感为灵感，采用粉色、红色、橙色与黄色渐变设计，适配 iPhone 17 全系和 Air，售价 449 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to physical accessories, Apple also simultaneously launched Year of the Horse WeChat red envelope covers, which all users can claim for free. The overall design features a light gold color scheme, incorporates a horse head element into the Apple logo, and is adorned with auspicious cloud patterns below.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除实体配件外，苹果还同步上线了马年微信红包封面，所有用户可免费领取，整体设计以淡金配色呈现，并在苹果 logo 中融入马头元素，下方点缀祥云图案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Apple also released Year of the Horse themed wallpapers covering iPhone, iPad, Mac, and Apple Watch.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，苹果还推出覆盖 iPhone、iPad、Mac 与 Apple Watch 的马年主题壁纸。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小米深夜通报 KOL 事件调查结果</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小米深夜通报-KOL-事件调查结果</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/54f7fffd-2539-4656-8a76-b312fc0ee2a0.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Late last night, Xiaomi Company Spokesperson's official Weibo account issued an announcement stating that after a special investigation and management discussion, it was determined that the team's business contact with the relevant KOL &quot;seriously violated company principles and severely hurt the feelings of Mi Fans,&quot; constituting a serious breach of conduct.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天深夜，小米公司发言人官方微博发布公告称，经专项调查和管理层讨论，认定此次团队与相关 KOL 的商务接触「严重违背公司原则，也严重伤害米粉感情」，属于严重违规行为。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company dismissed the responsible person involved, and simultaneously identified Xu Fei, Vice President and CMO of Xiaomi Group, and Xu Jieyun, General Manager of the Group's Public Relations Department, as having committed management dereliction of duty, giving them a public reprimand, deducting their relevant performance scores for 2025, and canceling their 2025 annual bonus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司对涉事负责人作出辞退处理，同时对小米集团副总裁兼 CMO 许斐、集团公关部总经理徐洁云认定为管理失职，给予通报批评，扣除其 2025 年相关绩效成绩，并取消 2025 年度奖金。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After completing the preliminary investigation the day before, Xu Jieyun had already stated on social media that the team had immediately terminated all possible collaborations with the relevant KOL and pledged not to cooperate in the future. This announcement further provides the official investigation conclusions and organizational disciplinary results.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在前一日完成初步调查后，徐洁云已在社交平台表示，团队已立刻终止与相关 KOL 的一切可能合作，并承诺未来不再合作，此次公告则是进一步给出正式调查结论和组织处分结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This controversy originated from online rumors that &quot;Xiaomi planned to conduct commercial cooperation with a specific self-media KOL,&quot; which sparked strong opposition from some Mi Fans. Many users left comments in Xu Jieyun's and Lei Jun's social media comment sections to boycott the relevant cooperation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次风波起源于网传「小米计划与某特定自媒体 KOL 开展商业合作相关传闻」，引发部分米粉强烈反对，不少用户在徐洁云及雷军的社交媒体评论区留言抵制相关合作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After public opinion fermented, Xiaomi quickly launched an internal investigation and responded first on the evening of January 5th, then announced the detailed handling decision late last night.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            舆论发酵后，小米快速启动内部调查并在 1 月 5 日晚先行回应，随后在昨天深夜公布详细处理决定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>英伟达计划于今年一季度重启 RTX 3060 生产</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">英伟达计划于今年一季度重启-RTX-3060-生产</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/956cb8a0-f470-4213-8660-7c7cc4f4101e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Wccftech, Nvidia plans to restart production of the GeForce RTX 3060 in the first quarter of this year to address the current tight supply of graphics cards and DRAM.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Wccftech 报道，英伟达计划在今年第一季度重新启动 GeForce RTX 3060 的生产，以应对当前显卡与 DRAM 供应紧张的问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Although shipments of RTX 4060 and RTX 5060 are increasing, due to tight GDDR7 supply and rising costs, Nvidia updated its plans with partners on January 5th, confirming that the RTX 3060 will return to the retail market in Q1 this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管 RTX 4060 与 RTX 5060 的出货量正在提升，但由于 GDDR7 供应吃紧、成本上涨，英伟达已在 1 月 5 日向合作伙伴更新计划，确认 RTX 3060 将在今年 Q1 回归零售市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The RTX 3060 series has been gradually discontinued since 2024, but this graphics card, launched in 2021, remains one of the most popular models on the Steam platform.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            RTX 3060 系列自 2024 年起逐步停产，但这款于 2021 年推出的显卡至今依旧是 Steam 平台上最受欢迎的型号之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that the DRAM supply shortage has directly affected the RTX 5060, which uses GDDR7, potentially driving up prices and leading to limited supply.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，DRAM 供应短缺已直接影响到采用 GDDR7 的 RTX 5060，不仅可能推高价格，也导致供货受限。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the 60 series product line targets the mass market, Nvidia needs to provide alternative solutions for its partners, thus reactivating the RTX 3060 production line has become a currently viable path.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            作为面向大众市场的 60 系列产品线，英伟达需要为合作伙伴提供替代方案，因此重新启用 RTX 3060 生产线成为当前可行路径。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The RTX 3060 was previously released in two versions: 12 GB (192-bit) and 8 GB (128-bit). The 12 GB version received better reviews, while the 8 GB version caused controversy due to bandwidth limitations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            RTX 3060 曾推出 12 GB（192-bit）与 8 GB（128-bit）两种版本，其中 12 GB 版本评价较好，而 8 GB 版本因带宽限制曾引发争议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>新款小米 SU7 官宣，预计 4 月上市</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">新款小米-SU7-官宣，预计-4-月上市</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3e9b885b-4844-4467-8b23-bfc5ba7c0923.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Today, Xiaomi Auto officially announced that the new generation SU7 is expected to be officially launched in April this year, and will introduce a new color, &quot;Capri Blue&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天，小米汽车官方发布预告，新一代 SU7 预计将于今年 4 月正式上市，并将带来新颜色「卡布里蓝」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to news from Kuaikeji, it is rumored online that modified prototypes of the new Xiaomi SU7 have successively arrived at stores. Key upgrades include the power architecture, charging efficiency, intelligent driving hardware, chassis, and comfort features. The leaked upgrade list is as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            来自快科技的消息称，网传新款小米 SU7 改款样车已陆续抵达门店，升级重点包括动力架构、充电效率、智能驾驶硬件、底盘以及舒适配置等，升级清单爆料整理如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new car will upgrade from the current 400 V architecture to a standard 800 V high-voltage platform across all models, supporting 5C super fast charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or will come standard with roof-mounted LiDAR across all models, equipped with Nvidia Thor U chips;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battery is upgraded to the second-generation Kirin battery, with an energy density of approximately 189 Wh/kg (current model is 152 Wh/kg), and the CLTC range is expected to increase to 820 kilometers;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power system is replaced with a new motor model &quot;TZ220XY102&quot;, with a rated power corresponding to approximately 299 horsepower;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new car's hidden door handles may be changed to a mechanical structure to improve issues with low-temperature failure and malfunction rates;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front trunk is upgraded from a manual structure to an electric suction design, supporting automatic opening and closing with a light touch of a button;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may come standard with seat ventilation, heating, and massage functions across all models, and the length of the rear seat cushions will be optimized to improve leg support;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W-HUD head-up display will be standard, and a 10-inch AR-HUD will project driving and navigation information, supporting adaptive brightness adjustment;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closed dual-chamber air suspension is expected to be upgraded to 5-level height adjustment (current model has 4 levels) to adapt to different road conditions, and by optimizing the sound insulation design, the in-car noise will be reduced by approximately 3 decibels;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of magnetic attachment points inside the car will also increase, and the external 1/4 threaded interface is rumored to support external power supply functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the ordering page for the new generation SU7 has been launched on the Xiaomi Auto App, with official pre-orders starting from 10:00.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，新一代 SU7 的订购页面已上线小米汽车 App，10:00 起正式开启预订。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MiniMax 港股 IPO 超额认购 1209 倍，将于 1 月 9 日正式上市</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">MiniMax-港股-IPO-超额认购-1209-倍，将于-1-月-9-日正式上市</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/69f2fc9d-27c3-45a3-a7e5-53ed7a9289c7.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Shanghai Xiyu Technology MiniMax completed its public offering yesterday. According to Futu Securities data, the total IPO margin financing ultimately exceeded HKD 253.3 billion, with the public offering portion being oversubscribed by as much as 1209 times.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上海稀宇科技 MiniMax 已于昨天完成公开招股。据富途证券数据，本次 IPO 孖展金额最终超过 2533 亿港元，公开发售部分超额认购倍数高达 1209 倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the prospectus, MiniMax's global offering comprises approximately 25.38 million shares, with an offering price range of HKD 151 to HKD 165 per share, expecting to raise between approximately HKD 3.834 billion and HKD 4.189 billion. The company plans to list on the main board of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on January 9.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            按照招股文件，MiniMax 全球发售股份总数约为 2538 万股，发售价区间为每股 151 至 165 港元，预计募资规模约 38.34 亿至 41.89 亿港元。公司计划于 1 月 9 日在港交所主板挂牌。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Shanghai Securities News&quot; pointed out that MiniMax, an AI company with an average employee age of only 29, took four years from its establishment to complete its IPO, setting a new record for the shortest time from founding to listing for a global AI enterprise.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《上海证券报》指出，作为一家员工平均年龄仅 29 岁的 AI 公司，MiniMax 从成立到完成 IPO 用时四年，刷新了全球 AI 企业从创立到上市的最短纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As of last September, the company had over 212 million individual users in more than 200 countries and regions worldwide. In the first nine months of last year, revenue grew by over 170% year-on-year, with overseas market revenue accounting for more than 70%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            截至去年 9 月，公司在全球超过 200 个国家及地区拥有逾 2.12 亿个人用户，去年前 9 个月营收同比增长超过 170%，其中海外市场收入占比超过 70%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            MiniMax has introduced 14 cornerstone investors this time, covering international long-term funds, technology companies, and Chinese institutions, including Aspex, Eastspring, Mirae Asset, ADIA, Alibaba, and E Fund, with a total subscription amount of HKD 2.723 billion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            MiniMax 此次引入 14 名基石投资者，覆盖国际长线基金、科技企业及中资机构，包括 Aspex、Eastspring、Mirae Asset、ADIA、阿里巴巴及易方达等，合计认购金额达 27.23 亿港元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Against the backdrop of an overall warming new stock market, &quot;Hong Kong Economic Times&quot; pointed out that new stock subscriptions have remained strong this year, with market expectations generally placing MiniMax's oversubscription rate at nearly a thousand times, and some semi-new stocks also experiencing a catch-up rally.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在新股市场整体升温的背景下，《香港经济日报》指出，今年新股认购持续火热，市场普遍预期 MiniMax 认购倍数将达近千倍，部分半新股亦出现补涨行情。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>郑州中原保时捷「跑路」后续：门店已确认停业、被移出经销网络</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">郑州中原保时捷「跑路」后续：门店已确认停业、被移出经销网络</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/14abf411-c312-4e0c-a2e2-3be1ea41424e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, the highly anticipated &quot;runaway&quot; incident involving Zhengzhou Zhongyuan Porsche has seen the latest developments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，备受关注的郑州中原保时捷「跑路」事件迎来最新进展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Porsche China confirmed that due to the termination of the authorization agreement with investor Dong'an Holding Group Co., Ltd., the Zhengzhou Zhongyuan Porsche Center officially ceased its dealership business on December 31 last year and was removed from the brand's dealer network. Car owners have recently been receiving SMS notifications from Porsche China.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            保时捷中国确认，由于与投资方东安控股集团有限公司的授权协议终止，郑州中原保时捷中心已于去年 12 月 31 日正式停止经销业务，并被移出品牌经销商网络。车主近日陆续收到来自保时捷中国的短信通知。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official statement, Porsche's nationwide universal packages can be transferred to other dealerships. Owner profiles, subsequent vehicle after-sales services, and unused official extended warranty services and official service packages can continue to be used at the nearby Zhengzhou Zhengkai Porsche Center. However, 4S store self-operated packages issued by Dong'an Holding itself are not covered.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据官方说明，保时捷发行的全国通用套餐可转移至其他门店，车主档案、车辆后续售后服务及未使用的官方延长保修服务、官方服务套餐，可前往临近的郑州郑开保时捷中心继续使用。但由东安控股自行发行的 4S 店自营套餐不在承接范围内。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the issues reported by some car owners concerning the inability to deliver new car documents and deposit problems, Porsche China stated that it is actively communicating with the parties involved and the credit banks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对部分车主反映的新车单证无法交付及定金问题，保时捷中国表示正与涉事方及授信银行积极沟通。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The incident first gained attention in late December last year, with many netizens claiming that the center appeared to be &quot;deserted.&quot; On December 25 last year, Porsche China apologized for this and stated that it was verifying the facts with the police and relevant departments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            事件最早在去年 12 月下旬引发关注，多位网友称该中心出现「人去楼空」情况。去年 12 月 25 日，保时捷中国曾就此致歉，并称正与警方及相关部门核查事实。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The next day, Dong'an Holdings issued an announcement, stating that its Zhengzhou Zhongyuan Porsche Center, Guiyang Mengguan Porsche Center, and Zhengzhou Dongjin Volkswagen store would suspend operations, employees would be on leave, salaries would be paid according to the local minimum living standard, and a plan for handling issues such as employee accounts, wages, social security, customer certificates, supplier debts, and customer deposits was announced.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            次日，东安控股发布通告，宣布旗下郑州中原保时捷中心、贵阳孟关保时捷中心及郑州东锦大众店暂停营业，员工放假，薪酬按当地最低生活标准发放，并公布了员工账款、工资、社保、客户合格证、供应商欠款及客户定金等问题的处理计划。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Financial reports show that Porsche's global sales in the first three quarters of last year were 212,500 units, a year-on-year decrease of 6%; sales in the Chinese market were 32,200 units, a year-on-year decrease of 26%. During the same period, global operating profit was only 40 million euros, a year-on-year decrease of 99%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财报显示，去年前三季度保时捷全球销量为 21.25 万辆，同比下降 6%；中国市场销量为 3.22 万辆，同比下滑 26%。同期全球经营利润仅 4000 万欧元，同比下滑 99%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Porsche China closed more than seven dealerships last year, including the Beijing Chang'an Porsche Center, which had been operating for 24 years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            保时捷中国去年已关闭超过七家门店，包括经营 24 年的北京长安保时捷中心。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Pan Lich, President and CEO of Porsche China, once stated that the number of sales outlets would be reduced from 150 to 120 by the end of last year, and further adjusted to about 80 by the end of this year, to cover core cities and provinces, supplemented by after-sales service outlets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            保时捷中国总裁及 CEO 潘励驰曾表示，将在去年底前将销售网点从 150 家缩减至 120 家，并计划在今年底进一步调整至约 80 家，以覆盖核心城市与省份，并辅以售后服务网点补充。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>追觅跨界造车首秀：1876 马力超跑亮相 CES，四电机零百 1.8 秒</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">追觅跨界造车首秀：1876-马力超跑亮相-CES，四电机零百-1.8-秒</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a98d4cf7-b427-404b-a692-a89e69ba8d60.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dreame's first supercar concept car debuted at CES this year, officially named 'Kosmera Nebula 1'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            追觅首款超跑概念车在今年 CES 亮相，正式命名为「Kosmera Nebula 1」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to information from CarNewsChina, the car was primarily developed by Xingchen Future (Suzhou) Automotive Technology Co., Ltd. (formerly 'Dreame Auto'), positioned as a four-door electric supercar, featuring a four-motor layout with a combined power of 1399 kW (1876 hp), and a 0-100 km/h acceleration time of 1.8 seconds.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 CarNewsChina 方面信息，该车由星宸未来（苏州）汽车科技有限公司（原「追觅汽车」）主导开发，定位四门电动超跑，采用四电机布局，综合功率达 1399 kW（1876 hp），零百加速时间为 1.8 秒。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The body uses a large amount of carbon fiber material, with a low-slung front cabin, paired with L-shaped headlights, six-spoke wheels, and a fixed large rear wing, making the overall aerodynamic package extremely aggressive.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            车身采用大量碳纤维材质，前舱线条低趴，搭配 L 型头灯、六辐轮圈与固定式大尾翼，整体空气动力学套件极为激进。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The rear features a full-width taillight with a honeycomb matrix design. The concept car does not have traditional door handles, but the official statement indicates that it will be mass-produced for the global market in the future, with plans to build a factory in Berlin.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            车尾贯穿式尾灯采用蜂窝矩阵设计，概念车未设置传统门把手，但官方表示未来将面向全球市场推进量产，并计划在柏林建设工厂。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Dreame has been active in the new energy sector, with its 'Starry Sky Project' establishing 11 new companies in Shanghai and Jiaxing over three consecutive days at the end of last year, covering areas such as research and retail, demonstrating its rapid deployment in the new energy vehicle industry chain.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            追觅此前在新能源领域动作频繁，旗下「星空计划」在去年底连续三天于上海、嘉兴成立 11 家新公司，业务覆盖科研与零售等方向，显示其在新能源汽车产业链的快速布局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>长城汽车取消「大小周」全面实行双休</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">长城汽车取消「大小周」全面实行双休</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8aa3d2ef-0588-4e94-9e09-4b9bc686b5fd.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Dahe Daily, Great Wall Motor officially abolished the 'big and small week' work schedule this year, fully implementing a two-day weekend system, which sparked a strong reaction from employees. After Great Wall employees learned the news in early January, there were scenes of collective cheering in the canteen.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《大河报》报道，长城汽车今年正式取消大小周，全面实行双休制度，引发员工强烈反响。长城员工在今年 1 月初得知消息后，食堂内出现集体欢呼场面。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some employees stated that the system of 'monthly single/double weekends — big and small weeks — big and small weeks + high-temperature leave' has been continuously iterated over the years, and now they finally have a full two-day weekend.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Although the 10 days of high-temperature leave were canceled, 5 of those days originally had to be deducted from annual leave, and employees generally believe that 'a stable two-day weekend throughout the year is more cost-effective'.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            有员工表示，过去多年「每月单双休—大小周—大小周+高温假」的制度不断迭代，如今终于迎来完整双休。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             尽管随之取消了 10 天高温假，但其中 5 天原本需抵扣年假，员工普遍认为「全年稳定双休更划算」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This adjustment comes against a backdrop of widespread pressure on car manufacturers. In the first three quarters of last year, although Great Wall Motor achieved market share growth, its net profit declined by 16.97% year-on-year due to high marketing and channel investments. Promoting a two-day weekend system despite a general decline in industry profitability is seen by many employees as a positive signal of 'returning the right to rest to employees'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这一调整发生在车企普遍承压的背景下。去年前三季度，长城汽车虽实现市占率增长，但因营销与渠道投入高企，净利润同比下滑 16.97%。在行业盈利普遍下降的情况下仍推进双休，被不少员工视为「把休息权还给员工」的积极信号。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In recent years, the high-intensity work pace of domestic car manufacturers has attracted much attention. AlixPartners data shows that the average R&amp;amp;D cycle for domestic new energy vehicle companies is only 1.6 years, while overseas brands require 5.4 years. A faster pace brings competitive advantages but also leads to widespread employee overwork.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            过去几年，国内车企的高强度工作节奏备受关注。艾睿铂数据显示，国内新能源车企平均研发周期仅 1.6 年，而海外品牌需 5.4 年。更快的节奏带来竞争优势，也导致员工普遍超负荷工作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the 'May Day Overtime Incident' in 2023, some departments at Great Wall had to work normally during the holiday due to tasks for the Shanghai Auto Show, and employees actually only got one extra day off, with folding beds temporarily becoming standard office equipment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2023 年「五一加班事件」中，长城部分部门因上海车展任务需在假期正常上班，员工实际仅多休息 1 天，折叠床一度成为办公室标配。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last year, the car market showed a trend of 'high sales, low growth,' with several car manufacturers experiencing a decline in net profit. The China Association of Automobile Manufacturers and the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology pointed out in May last year that disorderly price wars and other forms of 'involutionary' competition were the main reasons for the decline in industry efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            去年车市呈现「高销量低增长」趋势，多家车企净利润下滑。中国汽车工业协会与工信部在去年 5 月指出，无序价格战等内卷竞争是行业效益下滑主因。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Subsequently, companies like BYD and Dongfeng pledged to shorten payment terms, BYD and CATL announced salary increases at the end of the year, and Great Wall implemented a two-day weekend, showing clear signs of industry cooling down.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随后，比亚迪、东风等企业承诺压缩账期，年底比亚迪与宁德时代宣布涨薪，长城落实双休，行业降温迹象明显。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, the EU Anti-Forced Labour Regulation, set to be implemented by the end of 2027, requires products exported to the EU not to involve forced labor, including overtime exceeding 40 hours per week, even if voluntary. Industry insiders believe that if work systems are not adjusted, car manufacturers' exports will face risks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，2027 年底即将实施的《欧盟反强迫劳动法案》要求出口欧盟的产品不得涉及强迫劳动，包括每周超 40 小时加班，即便自愿也不被允许。业内人士认为，若不调整工作制度，车企出口将面临风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Driven by multiple factors, car manufacturers are beginning to shift from pursuing scale to pursuing high-quality growth. BYD adjusted its strategy in the middle of last year, focusing on high-margin models; the success of models like Xiaomi SU7, BYD Fangchengbao, and Great Wall Tank also shows that precise segmentation of the market offers greater advantages than mere price-performance competition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在多重因素推动下，车企开始从追求规模转向追求高质量增长。比亚迪去年中期已调整策略，聚焦高毛利车型；小米 SU7、比亚迪方程豹、长城坦克等车型的成功也显示，精准细分市场比单纯性价比竞争更具优势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蔚来第 100 万台量产车下线</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蔚来第-100-万台量产车下线</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/49e635ab-1683-4c68-b9b2-9019882c5b2f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Nio officially announced that its 1 millionth mass-produced vehicle has officially rolled off the production line at the Xinqiao Second Factory in Hefei, Anhui.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，蔚来官宣第 100 万台量产车已在安徽合肥的新桥二工厂正式下线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The 1 millionth mass-produced vehicle to roll off the line is a Starry Green new ES8. Nio donated it to the Anhui Mozi Quantum Technology Foundation to support the research travel of experts in the field of quantum technology. Pan Jianwei, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, accepted the vehicle on behalf of the research team at the scene and expressed gratitude for Nio's support for scientific innovation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次下线的第 100 万台量产车为一台星辰绿全新 ES8，蔚来将其捐赠给安徽墨子量子科技基金会，用于支持量子科技领域专家的科研出行。中国科学院院士潘建伟在现场代表科研团队接车，并表示感谢蔚来对科研创新的支持。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            NIO simultaneously launched the ET9 Million Commemorative Limited Edition to pay tribute to innovation leaders in various industries.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            蔚来同步推出 ET9 百万纪念限量版，以致敬各行业的创新引领者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            NIO founder, chairman, and CEO William Li stated at the event that 1 million units is a new starting point, and NIO is entering its third development phase focused on high-quality growth. It will continue to invest in R&amp;amp;D around 12 full-stack core technology systems and plans to increase the number of charging and battery swap stations nationwide to 10,000 each by 2030.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            蔚来创始人、董事长兼 CEO 李斌在活动中表示，100 万台是新的起点，蔚来正迈入以高质量增长为核心的第三发展阶段，将继续围绕 12 项全栈核心技术体系投入研发，并计划到 2030 年将全国充换电站数量提升至各 1 万座。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, according to Sina Tech, William Li emphasized in an interview that rising memory prices are putting immense pressure on the automotive industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，据新浪科技报道，李斌接受采访时强调，内存涨价给汽车行业带来巨大压力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The rise in memory prices is a huge pressure on the automotive industry, as it competes with AI, computing centers, and the mobile phone industry. Currently, the cost pressure from rising memory prices has not yet been passed on to terminal sales prices and remains within NIO's tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Against the backdrop of rising memory prices, William Li also urged people to buy cars sooner rather than later.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             在内存涨价的背景下，李斌还喊话，希望大家买车要早一点。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Fu Bingfeng, Executive Vice President and Secretary-General of the China Association of Automobile Manufacturers, pointed out that NIO has accumulated important experience in technological innovation and high-end practices, providing a model for brand elevation and technological breakthroughs in China's new energy vehicle industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国汽车工业协会常务副会长兼秘书长付炳锋指出，蔚来在技术创新与高端化实践方面积累了重要经验，为中国新能源汽车产业的品牌向上与技术突破提供了示范。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This year, China's new energy vehicle production is expected to exceed 15 million units, and Chinese car companies' global new car sales are likely to surpass Japanese car companies for the first time, further solidifying China's leading position in the global automotive industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年，中国新能源汽车产量预计突破 1500 万辆，中国车企全球新车销量有望首次超越日本车企，进一步巩固中国在全球汽车产业中的领先地位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the event, NIO also signed a framework agreement with Chery Automobile and JAC Motors to jointly build a collaborative innovation platform, and reached a car-chip collaborative industrialization cooperation with Longsoon Semiconductor, further promoting the coordinated development of the regional industrial ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            活动现场，蔚来还与奇瑞汽车、江淮汽车签署共建协同创新平台框架协议，并与龙迅半导体达成车芯协同产业化合作，进一步推动区域产业生态协同发展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As of now, NIO has cumulatively invested 65 billion yuan in technology R&amp;amp;D and 18 billion yuan in charging and battery swap infrastructure. It has built 8,541 charging and battery swap stations nationwide, providing over 96 million battery swap services. These investments are gradually transforming into user value and long-term competitiveness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            截至目前，蔚来在技术研发领域累计投入 650 亿元，在充换电基础设施领域累计投入 180 亿元，全国已建成 8541 座充换电站，累计提供换电服务超过 9600 万次。这些投入正逐步转化为用户价值与长期竞争力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            William Li stated that NIO will continue to deeply cultivate the Chinese market and expand into global markets in a more stable manner, committed to bringing intelligent electric mobility experiences to more users.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            李斌表示，蔚来将继续深耕中国市场，并以更稳健方式拓展全球市场，致力于将智能电动出行体验带给更多用户。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 Related Reading:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/85diAMLLseJxGYszXfnJ3A&quot;&gt;
             NIO, which delivered its best-ever performance, only prepared 3 models for 2026
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 相关阅读：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/85diAMLLseJxGYszXfnJ3A&quot;&gt;
             交出历史最好成绩单的蔚来，只为 2026 准备了 3 款车
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>特斯拉中国推 5 年 0 息购车方案</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">特斯拉中国推-5-年-0-息购车方案</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/835e4de0-ba68-4511-9be3-c78dca5d49a4.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Tesla China announced the launch of a 7-year ultra-low interest car purchase plan covering Model 3, Model Y, and Model Y L, and for the first time offered a 5-year 0% interest option on the Model Y L.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，特斯拉中国宣布推出覆盖 Model 3、Model Y 及 Model Y L 的 7 年超低息购车方案，并首次在 Model Y L 上提供 5 年 0 息选项。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to data released by Tesla, the down payment for Model 3/Y starts from 79,900 yuan, with monthly payments as low as 1,918 yuan; the down payment for Model Y L starts from 99,900 yuan, with monthly payments as low as 2,947 yuan; under the 5-year 0% interest plan, the lowest monthly payment for Model Y L is 3,985 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据特斯拉公布的数据，Model 3/Y 首付 7.99 万元起，月供最低可至 1918 元；Model Y L 首付 9.99 万元起，月供最低 2947 元；在 5 年 0 息方案下，Model Y L 月供最低为 3985 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Tesla recently adjusted prices in overseas markets. On December 31 last year, both Model 3 and Model Y saw price reductions in the South Korean market, with the Model 3 Performance All-Wheel Drive version dropping to 59.99 million Korean Won (approximately 289,800 RMB), a decrease of 9.4 million Korean Won from the previous price; two Model Y models also saw reductions of about 3 million Korean Won (approximately 14,500 RMB).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，特斯拉近期在海外市场同步调整价格。去年 12 月 31 日，韩国市场的 Model 3 与 Model Y 均出现下调，其中 Model 3 高性能全轮驱动版降至 5999 万韩元（约 28.98 万元人民币），较此前价格下调 940 万韩元；两款 Model Y 车型也下调约 300 万韩元（约 1.45 万元）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Behind these price strategy adjustments, Tesla is facing its second consecutive year of global sales decline. Data released for Q4 2025 shows that Tesla produced over 434,000 new vehicles in the quarter, a year-on-year decrease of 5.5%; deliveries exceeded 418,000 vehicles, a year-on-year decrease of approximately 16%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在价格策略调整的背后，特斯拉正面临连续第二年的全球销量下滑。今年公布的 2025 年四季度数据显示，特斯拉当季生产超过 43.4 万辆新车，同比下降 5.5%；交付超过 41.8 万辆，同比下降约 16%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Looking at the full-year performance, Tesla's global deliveries in 2025 were 1.636 million units, a year-on-year decrease of approximately 8.6%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从全年表现来看，特斯拉 2025 年全球交付量为 163.6 万辆，同比下降约 8.6%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this is the first time Tesla has been surpassed by BYD in full-year sales of pure electric vehicles. BYD's cumulative sales last year reached 4.6024 million units, a year-on-year increase of 7.73%, with pure electric vehicles reaching 2.2567 million units, a significant year-on-year increase of 27.86%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，这是特斯拉首次在全年纯电车型销量上被比亚迪超越。比亚迪去年累计销量 460.24 万辆，同比增长 7.73%，其中纯电车型达 225.67 万辆，同比大增 27.86%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>英特尔发布第三代酷睿 Ultra：首款 1.8nm 芯片亮相 CES</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">英特尔发布第三代酷睿-Ultra：首款-1.8nm-芯片亮相-CES</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c9787947-ddeb-46d2-85cd-a0cde02cab44.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Intel officially launched its third-generation Intel Core Ultra processor at CES 2026. This is the first computing platform built on the Intel 18A process node and will be progressively available starting this month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，英特尔 CES 2026 上正式发布第三代英特尔酷睿 Ultra 处理器，这是首款基于 Intel 18A 制程节点打造的计算平台，将于本月起陆续面市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jim Johnson, Intel Senior Vice President and General Manager of the Client Computing Group, stated that the new platform offers significant improvements in power efficiency, CPU performance, and GPU integration, providing stronger support for local AI inference and compatibility with traditional x86 applications.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英特尔高级副总裁兼客户端计算事业部总经理 Jim Johnson 称，新平台在能效、CPU 性能与 GPU 集成方面均有显著提升，为本地 AI 推理与传统 x86 应用兼容性提供更强支撑。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among the mobile product lines released this time, the new Core Ultra X9 and X7 processors are key highlights.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次发布的移动端产品线中，全新酷睿 Ultra X9 与 X7 处理器成为核心亮点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both integrate Intel Arc graphics cards;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flagship model is equipped with up to 16 CPU cores, 12 Xe cores, and 50 TOPS NPU computing power;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official data shows that its multi-threaded performance can be improved by up to 60% compared to the previous generation platform, gaming performance by up to 77%, and it achieves a maximum battery life of 27 hours in reference designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official statement emphasizes that the new platform is competitive in key edge AI workloads such as large language model inference, end-to-end video analysis, and visual-language-action models, and brings better total cost of ownership due to SoC-level integration.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方强调，新平台在大语言模型推理、端到端视频分析与视觉语言动作模型等关键边缘 AI 工作负载中具备竞争力，并因 SoC 级整合带来更优的总体拥有成本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Intel's announced timeline, the first batch of consumer laptops equipped with the third-generation Core Ultra began pre-sales yesterday and will be globally available starting January 27.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据英特尔公布的时间表，首批搭载第三代酷睿 Ultra 的消费级笔记本电脑已于昨天开启预售，并将于 1 月 27 日起在全球上市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>开创 Wi-Fi 8 生态，联发科推出 Filogic 8000 系列平台</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">开创-Wi-Fi-8-生态，联发科推出-Filogic-8000-系列平台</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/18943015-474d-4cb2-9dec-24b50e90829d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, MediaTek officially launched its Filogic 8000 series chips at CES 2026, becoming one of the first chip platforms for the Wi-Fi 8 ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，联发科在 CES 2026 上正式发布 Filogic 8000 系列芯片，成为首批面向 Wi‑Fi 8 生态的芯片平台之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This series is centered on &quot;Ultra High Reliability,&quot; emphasizing low latency, anti-interference capability, and stable performance in multi-device environments. MediaTek simultaneously released a white paper systematically outlining the technical paths of Wi-Fi 8 in collaborative networks, spectrum efficiency, and latency optimization, including:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该系列以「超高可靠度」（Ultra High Reliability）为核心，强调低延迟、抗干扰能力与多设备环境下的稳定表现。联发科同步发布白皮书，系统阐述 Wi‑Fi 8 在协同式网络、频谱效率、延迟优化等方向的技术路径，包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-AP collaboration technologies such as Coordinated Spatial Reuse (Co-SR) and Coordinated Beamforming (Co-BF) are used to reduce interference and improve overall transmission efficiency;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mechanisms such as Dynamic Subchannel Operation (DSO), Non-Primary Channel Access (NPCA), and In-Device Coexistence (IDC) are used to improve spectrum utilization in crowded environments;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technologies such as Enhanced Long Range (ELR) and Distributed Resource Units (dRU) are used to improve coverage and edge device experience;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long-tail latency is reduced through smarter rate adaptation, APPDU aggregation, and other methods, targeting real-time scenarios such as XR, online gaming, and industrial automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            MediaTek stated that the Filogic 8000 series will cover various terminals such as gateways, enterprise-grade APs, mobile phones, TVs, laptops, and IoT devices, with the first chip expected to be delivered this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            联发科表示，Filogic 8000 系列将覆盖网关、企业级 AP、手机、电视、笔记本电脑与物联网设备等多类终端，首款芯片预计将在今年交付。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, ASUS will also launch a Wi-Fi 8-labeled router at CES 2026, but its technical specifications remain uncertain as the industry standard has not yet been officially finalized.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，华硕也将在 CES 2026 推出一款标注 Wi‑Fi 8 的路由器，但由于行业标准尚未正式确定，其技术规格仍存在不确定性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>德州仪器发布新一代汽车芯片组合，面向 L3 自动驾驶全面升级</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">德州仪器发布新一代汽车芯片组合，面向-L3-自动驾驶全面升级</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Texas Instruments announced several new semiconductor products and development resources for the automotive industry, covering high-performance computing SoCs, 4D imaging radar transceivers, and 10BASE-T1S Ethernet PHYs, aiming to enhance vehicle safety, intelligence, and autonomous driving capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，德州仪器宣布推出多款面向汽车行业的新型半导体产品与开发资源，覆盖高性能计算 SoC、4D 成像雷达发射器及 10BASE‑T1S 以太网 PHY，旨在提升车辆的安全性、智能化与自动驾驶能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scalable TDA5 high-performance computing SoC series: designed for central computing architectures, providing edge AI computing power from 10 TOPS to 1200 TOPS per second, with an energy efficiency ratio exceeding 24 TOPS/W, and supporting up to L3 autonomous driving;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TDA5 SoC virtual development kit: jointly launched by Texas Instruments and Synopsys, it helps engineers shorten the R&amp;amp;D cycle by up to 12 months through digital twin technology;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWR2188 single-chip 8-transmit 8-receive 4D imaging radar transceiver: integrates 8 transmitters and 8 receivers into a single chip, supports satellite and edge architectures, improves performance by approximately 30% compared to existing solutions, and enables high-precision detection at distances &amp;gt;350 m;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DP83TD555J-Q1 10BASE-T1S Ethernet PHY: integrates a media access controller, features nanosecond-level time synchronization, power over data line, and high reliability, extending Ethernet to vehicle edge nodes while reducing harness complexity and cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Texas Instruments stated that with its end-to-end system solutions, automakers can deploy higher levels of autonomous driving capabilities in different vehicle models and accelerate the mass production and implementation of next-generation ADAS and SDV.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            德州仪器表示，借助其端到端系统方案，汽车制造商可在不同车型中部署更高等级的自动驾驶能力，并加速下一代 ADAS 与 SDV 的量产落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The TDA54 software development kit is now available, and TDA54-Q1 SoC samples are expected to be open for trial to specific automotive customers by the end of this year. Pre-production samples of the AWR2188 transceiver and DP83TD555J-Q1 PHY are already available through the Texas Instruments official website TI.com.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            TDA54 软件开发套件现已上线，TDA54‑Q1 SoC 样品预计将在今年底前向特定汽车客户开放试用。AWR2188 发射器与 DP83TD555J‑Q1 PHY 的量产前样品已可通过德州仪器官网 TI.com 获取。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>海信发布全新 RGB‑Mini LED：全球首创四色芯背光亮相 CES</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">海信发布全新-RGB‑Mini-LED：全球首创四色芯背光亮相-CES</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/43e33853-de1d-4e7f-8291-48f6a2a8acc3.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Hisense officially released its new generation RGB‑Mini LED display technology at CES 2026, and launched the first flagship TV UX series equipped with Linglong 4-core true color backlight. The new technology has the following highlights:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，海信在 CES 2026 上正式发布全新一代 RGB‑Mini LED 显示技术，并推出首款搭载玲珑 4 芯真彩背光的旗舰电视 UX 系列。新技术有以下亮点：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light source is upgraded to Linglong 4-core true color backlight, introducing a fourth cyan self-luminous chip on the basis of the original red, green, and blue primary color Mini LED luminous chips, forming the world's first four-color core architecture. The color gamut reaches 110% BT.2020, a 10% improvement compared to current high-end QD‑Mini LED;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, relying on the Linglong 5-sided packaging process and color separation algorithm, Hisense has solved common problems such as &quot;color bleeding,&quot; &quot;color halo,&quot; and &quot;color shift&quot; in color backlights, further improving color purity;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The self-developed Xinxin AI picture quality chip H7 can maintain high color gamut performance in dark and high-brightness scenes, solving the problem of insufficient color in OLED at medium brightness and &quot;bleaching&quot; in QD‑Mini LED in high-brightness scenes, achieving high color gamut presentation across the entire brightness range;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introducing professional-grade 3D LUT technology and providing features such as the Light and Shadow Magic Console, it achieves end-to-end color calibration from content input to screen presentation, aiming to faithfully restore the original creator's intent and provide users with a color experience closer to professional monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the product level, Hisense announced that the UX series won the &quot;CES 2026 Honoree Award&quot; and will be launched first in the Chinese market in March this year. Hisense also showcased its RGB‑Mini LED product lineup covering 75–116 inches, including the UX, U7S Pro, and E8S series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在产品层面，海信宣布 UX 系列获得「CES 2026 荣誉奖」，并将于今年 3 月率先在中国市场上市。海信同时展示了覆盖 75–116 英寸的 RGB‑Mini LED 产品阵容，包括 UX、U7S Pro 与 E8S 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The China Electronic Video Industry Association pointed out in the &quot;RGB‑Mini LED Technology White Paper&quot; that a true RGB‑Mini LED must simultaneously possess &quot;RGB three-color independent Mini LED + 3D dimming technology.&quot; Hisense further iterated the four-color core architecture on this basis, maintaining its leading position in technological speed.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国电子视像行业协会在《RGB‑Mini LED 技术白皮书》中指出，真正的 RGB‑Mini LED 必须同时具备「RGB 三色独立 Mini LED + 三维控光技术」。海信在此基础上进一步迭代四色芯架构，以技术速度保持领先。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 苏姿丰 CES 演讲：AI 将无处不在，未来需「百倍算力」支撑增长</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-苏姿丰-CES-演讲：AI-将无处不在，未来需「百倍算力」支撑增长</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/feedcf50-de2c-4d4c-8eab-a0d192f1651f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            AMD CEO Lisa Su recently delivered a keynote speech at CES 2026, comprehensively outlining the company's technological layout in the era of AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            AMD CEO 苏姿丰近日在 CES 2026 发表主题演讲，全面阐述公司在 AI 时代的技术布局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lisa Su stated that since the release of ChatGPT, the number of active AI users worldwide has grown from 1 million to 1 billion, a scale that would have taken the internet decades to achieve. AMD expects active AI users to further grow to 5 billion by 2030.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苏姿丰表示，自 ChatGPT 发布以来，全球使用 AI 的活跃用户已从 100 万增长至 10 亿，这一规模原本需要互联网几十年才能达到。AMD 预计，到 2030 年，活跃 AI 用户将进一步增长至 50 亿。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             She pointed out that for AI to truly be &quot;ubiquitous,&quot; global computing power must increase 100-fold in the coming years.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             她指出，要让 AI 真正做到「无处不在」，全球算力必须在未来几年提升 100 倍。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of software, AMD stated that ROCm software's AI performance increased by up to five times last year, support for Ryzen and Radeon platforms doubled, and downloads grew tenfold year-on-year. The company also launched the Adrenalin Edition AI Bundle to simplify local AI environment deployment, covering applications such as image generation, local large models, and PyTorch.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在软件方面，AMD 表示去年 ROCm 软件的 AI 性能最高提升五倍，Ryzen 与 Radeon 平台的支持范围翻倍，下载量同比增长十倍。公司还推出 Adrenalin Edition AI Bundle，以简化本地 AI 环境部署，覆盖图像生成、本地大模型与 PyTorch 等应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the hardware level, Lisa Su emphasized that the core of AI infrastructure is no longer single-chip performance, but rather the deep synergy of CPU, GPU, networking, and software. AMD showcased the Helios open dual-width rack platform developed in collaboration with Meta, weighing nearly 7000 pounds and described as a &quot;monster-grade rack.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在硬件层面，苏姿丰强调 AI 基础设施的核心不再是单一芯片性能，而是 CPU、GPU、网络与软件的深度协同。AMD 展示了与 Meta 合作的 Helios 开放式双宽机架平台，其重量接近 7000 磅，被形容为「怪兽级机架」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Several industry guests also emphasized the computing power bottleneck at the event. OpenAI co-founder Greg Brockman pointed out that truly ubiquitous general AI requires &quot;billions of GPUs&quot; worth of computing power, a level far from being reached globally today.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            多位行业嘉宾也在现场强调算力瓶颈。OpenAI 联合创始人 Greg Brockman 指出，真正普及的通用 AI 需要「数十亿颗 GPU」级别的算力，而当前全球远未达到这一水平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Companies such as Luma AI, Liquid AI, and World Labs showcased the latest advancements based on the AMD platform, including multimodal video generation, lightweight foundational models, and 3D world generation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Luma AI、Liquid AI、World Labs 等公司展示了基于 AMD 平台的多模态视频生成、轻量化基础模型与 3D 世界生成等最新进展。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, AMD also demonstrated AI applications in healthcare, robotics, and space exploration, including a space computing platform developed in collaboration with Blue Origin, and the use of large-scale models to accelerate experimental processes in drug discovery.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，AMD 还展示了 AI 在医疗、机器人与太空探索领域的应用，包括与 Blue Origin 合作的航天计算平台，以及在药物研发中利用大规模模型加速实验流程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In her speech, Lisa Su stated that AI is the most important technology of the past 50 years, and AMD will continue to promote the popularization of AI, making &quot;AI for Everyone&quot; a reality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苏姿丰在演讲中表示，AI 是过去 50 年中最重要的技术，AMD 将继续推动 AI 普及化，让「所有人都能享受 AI」（AI for Everyone）成为现实。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>599 美元，极米推出 MemoMind 智能眼镜</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">599-美元，极米推出-MemoMind-智能眼镜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5a987c78-4208-4ba4-8b95-de52f1854b12.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, projector manufacturer XGIMI officially launched its own brand smart glasses series &quot;MemoMind&quot; at CES 2026, introducing two new products with different positioning, marking the formal entry of this renowned projector manufacturer into the AR wearable device market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，投影仪制造商极米在 CES 2026 上正式发布自有品牌智能眼镜系列「MemoMind」，并推出两款定位不同的新品，标志着这家以投影设备闻名的厂商正式进入 AR 可穿戴设备市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The flagship Memo One features a binocular display and integrated speakers, enabling audiovisual interaction with an AI assistant; the Memo Air is a lightweight version, weighing only 28.9 grams, equipped with a monocular display, targeting more portable use scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            旗舰款 Memo One 采用双目显示屏并集成扬声器，可通过视听交互方式与人工智能助手联动；另一款 Memo Air 为轻量化版本，仅 28.9 克，搭载单目显示屏，面向更轻便的使用场景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            XGIMI stated that the new series of smart glasses is based on its long-term accumulation in optics and engineering, aiming to achieve a more natural daily wearing experience with a lightweight design. The MemoMind series offers 8 frame styles and 5 temple combinations, and supports prescription lenses, emphasizing fashion attributes and personalized choices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            极米表示，新系列智能眼镜基于其在光学与工程领域的长期积累，目标是在轻量化设计下实现更自然的日常佩戴体验。MemoMind 系列提供 8 种镜框、5 种镜腿组合，并支持适配近视镜片，强调时尚属性与个性化选择。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            XGIMI stated that this series of glasses is essentially the hardware carrier for its AI assistant, capable of functions such as translation, text summarization, note-taking, event reminders, and contextual guidance. The platform will automatically switch between OpenAI, Microsoft Azure, and Alibaba's Tongyi Qianwen three major models based on task requirements to achieve optimal processing results.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            极米称，该系列眼镜本质上是其 AI 助手的硬件载体，可实现翻译、文本摘要、笔记记录、事项提醒及场景化指引等功能。平台将根据任务需求在 OpenAI、微软 Azure 与阿里巴巴通义千问三大模型间自动切换，以获得最优处理结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Memo One will soon open for pre-sale, priced at $599, with the domestic price yet to be announced. XGIMI also revealed that more derivative models will be launched later.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Memo One 将于近期开启预售，定价为 599 美元，国内售价尚未公布。极米同时透露，后续还将推出更多衍生型号。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>英伟达发布 DLSS 4.5：动态多帧生成与路径追踪全面升级</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">英伟达发布-DLSS-4.5：动态多帧生成与路径追踪全面升级</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/82dab7e1-b6a1-486d-bd57-52885dd63804.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, at CES 2026, NVIDIA officially launched DLSS 4.5 and announced several significant upgrades centered around path tracing, AI generation, display technology, and RTX AI PCs, covering various aspects such as gaming performance, visual quality, and developer workflows.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，在 CES 2026 上，英伟达正式推出 DLSS 4.5，并宣布多项围绕路径追踪、AI 生成、显示技术与 RTX AI PC 的重要升级，覆盖游戏性能、视觉质量与开发者工作流等多个方向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DLSS 4.5 is the core highlight of this update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new version introduces dynamic multi-frame generation and adds a 6x multi-frame generation mode, which can generate up to 5 additional frames on top of traditional rendered frames, allowing GeForce RTX 50 series GPUs to maintain smooth performance above 240 FPS even in 4K 240Hz scenarios with path tracing enabled.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新版引入动态多帧生成功能，并新增 6 倍多帧生成模式，可在传统渲染帧基础上额外生成多达 5 帧，让 GeForce RTX 50 系列 GPU 在开启路径追踪的 4K 240Hz 场景下依然保持 240 FPS 以上的流畅表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            NVIDIA stated that dynamic multi-frame generation and 6x multi-frame generation are expected to be launched this spring. DLSS Super Resolution has also been simultaneously upgraded to the second-generation Transformer model, covering over 400 games and applications, and will be released alongside DLSS 4.5.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英伟达表示，动态多帧生成与 6 倍多帧生成预计将于今年春季上线。DLSS 超分辨率也同步升级至第二代 Transformer 模型，覆盖超过 400 款游戏与应用，将随 DLSS 4.5 一同发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA also announced the official debut of RTX Remix Logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This system allows modders to trigger dynamic visual effects based on real-time game events, offering over 900 settings options to add custom effects to more than 165 classic games without needing source code access. This update will be rolled out later this month via the NVIDIA App.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该系统允许 Modder 基于实时游戏事件触发动态视觉效果，提供超过 900 项设置选项，无需访问源代码即可为 165 款以上经典游戏添加自定义特效。该更新将于本月稍晚通过 NVIDIA App 推出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding AI game characters, NVIDIA showcased the latest advancements in NVIDIA ACE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In &quot;Total War: Pharaoh,&quot; an ACE-powered dynamic AI advisor will be added, providing real-time guidance based on player actions, game status, and database information, while maintaining character consistency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《全面战争：法老》中将加入由 ACE 驱动的动态 AI 顾问，可根据玩家操作、游戏状态与数据库信息提供实时指导，并保持角色设定一致性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In &quot;PUBG: Battlegrounds,&quot; the ACE-powered PUBG Ally gains long-term memory capabilities, remembering past player behaviors and referencing relevant information during interactions. It is expected to undergo limited-time testing in Arcade mode in the first half of this year, supporting English, Korean, and Chinese.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《绝地求生》中，ACE 驱动的 PUBG Ally 获得长期记忆能力，可记住玩家过往行为并在互动中引用相关信息，预计将于今年上半年在 Arcade 模式限时测试，支持英文、韩文与中文。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new generation of G-SYNC Pulsar esports monitors has been launched this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This series achieves an effective dynamic clarity of over 1,000Hz through variable frequency backlight strobing technology and incorporates G-SYNC Smart Ambient Light functionality, which automatically adjusts brightness and color temperature based on ambient light, providing clearer dynamic visuals and a more stable visual experience for high-speed gaming scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该系列通过可变频率背光频闪技术实现超过 1,000Hz 的有效动态清晰度，并加入 G-SYNC 智能环境光功能，可根据环境光线自动调节亮度与色温，为高速游戏场景提供更清晰的动态画面与更稳定的视觉体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For RTX AI PCs, NVIDIA announced several performance upgrades for video, image, and text generation, including:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 RTX AI PC 方向，英伟达公布多项面向视频、图像与文本生成的性能升级，包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to 3x performance increase for generative video and image, and up to 60% reduction in VRAM usage through PyTorch-CUDA optimization and native support for NVFP4 / FP8 precision in ComfyUI;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integration of RTX Video Super Resolution in ComfyUI to accelerate 4K video generation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing NVFP8 quantization optimization for Lightricks' LTX-2 model;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing AI Blueprint for generating 4K AI videos for Blender 3D scenes;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerating Ollama and llama.cpp, with up to 35% improvement in small language model inference performance;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Providing RTX acceleration for Nexa.ai Hyperlink's new video search function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            NVIDIA stated that these improvements will further enhance the advantages of local RTX AI PCs in terms of privacy, security, and low latency, enabling users to run advanced AI video, image, and language workflows more efficiently.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英伟达表示，这些改进将进一步提升本地 RTX AI PC 在隐私性、安全性与低延迟方面的优势，使用户能够更高效地运行先进的 AI 视频、图像与语言工作流。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES 2026：ROG 推出幻 16 双屏旗舰与全新 Air 系列轻薄本</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">CES-2026：ROG-推出幻-16-双屏旗舰与全新-Air-系列轻薄本</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/855abd4c-f7ba-4d96-ac31-1912168e6389.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, ROG Republic of Gamers unveiled several new versatile laptops in its Phantom series during CES 2026 in Las Vegas, USA. All models are equipped with third-generation Intel Core Ultra series processors, covering diverse scenarios such as creation, gaming, and AI workflows.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，ROG 玩家国度在美国拉斯维加斯 CES 2026 期间发布多款幻系列全能笔记本新品，均搭载第三代英特尔酷睿 Ultra 系列处理器，覆盖创作、游戏与 AI 工作流等多元场景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The ROG Phantom 16 Dual Screen is the core product of this launch:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            ROG 幻 16 双屏是本次发布的核心产品：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features two 16-inch screens, which combined can provide an equivalent viewing area of over 21 inches;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both screens feature 2.8K resolution, 120 Hz refresh rate, 0.2 ms response time, and 1100 nits peak brightness;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up to Intel Core Ultra 9 386H processor and NVIDIA GeForce RTX 5090 Laptop GPU, with a total core power consumption of up to 150W for the entire machine, and GPU performance release up to 135W;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen is covered with Corning Gorilla Glass and DXC anti-scratch and anti-reflective coating, supporting touch operation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paired with a six-speaker array to further enhance the immersive audio-visual experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The ROG Phantom 14 Air 2026 is positioned as a thin and light creative laptop:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            ROG 幻 14 Air 2026 定位轻薄创作本：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also updated to Core Ultra 9 386H, with an optional RTX 5070 Ti Laptop GPU;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body weight approximately 1.57 kg, thickness 1.59 cm;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All models are equipped with a 2.8K 120 Hz Nebula Display, with peak brightness increased to 1100 nits and covering 100% DCI-P3 color gamut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The ROG Phantom 16 Air 2026 is designed for large-screen creative scenarios:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            ROG 幻 16 Air 2026 面向大屏创作场景：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports up to RTX 5090 Laptop GPU, with a total core power consumption of up to 175W for the entire machine;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body still maintains its thin and light characteristics at approximately 1.95 kg and 1.49 cm;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a 16-inch 2.5K 240 Hz Nebula Display, with a peak brightness of 1100 nits;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Includes an ambient light sensor, a new hinge structure, and a surface temperature control system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            ROG stated that the new generation of Phantom series aims to provide creators and professional users with more flexible productivity tools through its dual-screen form factor, high-performance platform, and thin and light design, while continuing to strengthen the brand's product layout in high-end esports and creative fields.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            ROG 表示，新一代幻系列旨在通过双屏形态、高性能平台与轻薄设计，为创作者与专业用户提供更灵活的生产力工具，并继续强化品牌在高端电竞与创作领域的产品布局。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alienware 外星人扩充游戏本矩阵：新 OLED、新处理器与超薄机型齐发</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Alienware-外星人扩充游戏本矩阵：新-OLED、新处理器与超薄机型齐发</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/564f5f95-7423-4184-922a-1a654889bac9.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Alienware comprehensively upgraded its gaming PC product matrix at CES 2026, with significant updates across its laptop and desktop lines, and for the first time introduced anti-glare OLED technology to its laptop product line, further strengthening its competitiveness in the high-end gaming device market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Alienware 外星人在 CES 2026 上全面升级其游戏 PC 产品矩阵，从笔记本到台式机均迎来大幅更新，并首次将防眩光 OLED 技术引入笔记本产品线，进一步强化其在高端游戏设备市场的竞争力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Alienware 16 Area-51 and Alienware 16X Aurora are among the first models to feature high-end anti-glare OLED panels. Officially, the new panels can reduce screen glare by 32% and minimize fingerprint residue.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外星人 16 Area-51 与外星人 16X Aurora 成为首批搭载高端防眩光 OLED 面板的机型。官方称，新面板可将屏幕眩光降低 32%，并减少指纹残留。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the panel features 0.2ms response time, HDR True Black 500 certification, 620 nits HDR peak brightness, 120% DCI-P3 color gamut, and is VESA HDR ClearMR 9000 certified, supporting AI pixel protection and high-strength structural testing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，该面板具备 0.2ms 响应时间、HDR True Black 500 认证、620 尼特 HDR 峰值亮度、120% DCI-P3 色域，并通过 VESA HDR ClearMR 9000 认证，支持 AI 像素保护与高强度结构测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of performance, the Alienware 16X Aurora, Alienware 16 Area-51, and Alienware 18 Area-51 have all been upgraded to Intel Core Ultra 200HX processors and NVIDIA GeForce RTX 50 series GPUs, further enhancing gaming performance in high-load scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在性能方面，外星人 16X Aurora、外星人 16 Area-51 与外星人 18 Area-51 均升级至英特尔 Core Ultra 200HX 处理器与英伟达 GeForce RTX 50 系列 GPU，进一步提升高负载场景下的游戏表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Alienware also announced that this year it will launch Area-51 desktop PCs featuring an 80-liter full-tower chassis, new ultra-thin gaming laptops approximately 17mm thick, and more attractively priced mainstream gaming laptops.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            外星人还宣布将在今年推出采用 80 升全塔式机箱的 Area-51 台式机、厚度约 17 毫米的全新超薄游戏本，以及价格更具吸引力的主流级游戏本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>三星 CES 2026 发布「AI 生活伴侣」愿景，展示全场景智能生态</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">三星-CES-2026-发布「AI-生活伴侣」愿景，展示全场景智能生态</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/97d6deff-824f-4e3e-8f79-30204c3d1404.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Samsung Electronics officially unveiled its future-oriented &quot;AI Life Companion&quot; vision at the CES 2026 &quot;The First Look&quot; event, showcasing an AI product matrix centered around three major scenarios: entertainment, home, and health.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，三星电子在 CES 2026「The First Look」活动上，正式发布了其面向未来的「AI 生活伴侣」愿景，展示了围绕娱乐、家居与健康三大场景的 AI 产品矩阵。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of entertainment experience, Samsung announced:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在娱乐体验方面，三星发布了：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI TV product line, represented by the 130-inch Micro RGB, features a wider color spectrum and more delicate picture quality, equipped with the Micro RGB AI chip engine Pro for precise control over RGB colors;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samsung Vision AI Companion (VAC) further expands TV usage scenarios, supporting cross-device content recommendations, voice interaction, and lifestyle suggestions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new Music Studio series wireless WiFi speakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, Samsung announced that its 2026 TV products will fully support HDR10+ ADVANCED and the new Eclipsa Audio spatial sound system.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，三星还宣布 2026 年电视产品将全面支持 HDR10+ ADVANCED 与全新的 Eclipsa Audio 空间音效系统。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the home scenario, Samsung showcased:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在家居场景中，三星展示了：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A smart home appliance ecosystem centered around SmartThings. As of last December, SmartThings users exceeded 430 million;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upgraded Family Hub refrigerator, equipped with Google Gemini-based AI Vision, can track ingredients in and out and provide recipe recommendations;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features like FoodNote weekly reports and Voice ID recognition, with enhanced AI capabilities added to laundry, garment care, and cleaning devices;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bespoke AI Jet Bot Steam Ultra, powered by the Qualcomm Dragonwing processor, features liquid recognition and home monitoring capabilities, and won a CES Innovation Award for its full-scenario interconnected experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the health sector, Praveen Raja, head of the Digital Health Department at Samsung Research America (SRA), introduced Samsung's vision for proactive health protection.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在健康领域，美国三星研究院（SRA）数字健康部门负责人 Praveen Raja 介绍了三星的主动式健康守护愿景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Samsung plans to provide personalized guidance for exercise, sleep, and diet by coordinating mobile phones, wearables, and home appliances, and to issue timely warnings when potential health risks are detected.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            三星计划通过手机、可穿戴设备与家电协同，为用户提供运动、睡眠与饮食的个性化指导，并在检测到潜在健康风险时及时预警。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Samsung is also advancing research into early dementia detection based on wearable devices. Samsung Knox and Knox Matrix provide data security for the entire ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            三星还在推进基于可穿戴设备的痴呆症早期检测研究。Samsung Knox 与 Knox Matrix 则为整个生态系统提供数据安全保障。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>霸王茶姬回应「印度制茶」视频：涉事门店停业整顿、店员被辞退</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">霸王茶姬回应「印度制茶」视频：涉事门店停业整顿、店员被辞退</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1b847c34-5785-4f2a-a659-5b42b2ea4251.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, CHAGEE issued a statement responding to the investigation and handling of the online video showing &quot;staff making tea with bare hands,&quot; which drew widespread attention and topped Weibo's hot search list.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，霸王茶姬发表声明，回应「店员徒手制茶」网络视频的调查与处理情况，引发广泛关注并登上微博热搜。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The statement confirmed that the video was filmed at the Longwen Baolong Plaza store in Zhangzhou, Fujian. The employee involved was imitating a popular online meme, posing for the camera with damaged materials before closing. The materials were not sold to the public, and the site was routinely cleaned and disinfected after filming.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            声明确认视频拍摄地点为福建漳州龙文宝龙广场店，涉事店员为模仿网络热门梗，在打烊前使用当天报损物料摆拍，相关物料未对外售卖，现场也在拍摄后完成常规清洁消毒。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company emphasized that the actions in question severely violated company regulations and crossed the brand's bottom line for food safety and honest operation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司强调，涉事行为严重违反公司相关规章制度，触碰品牌食品安全与诚信经营底线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Based on the investigation results, CHAGEE announced the immediate and indefinite suspension of the involved store for rectification; the employee involved was dismissed due to severe disciplinary violations; and the store manager and regional supervisor were demoted for dereliction of management and supervision duties.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            基于调查结果，霸王茶姬宣布对涉事门店即刻起无限期停业整顿；涉事店员因严重违纪被辞退；门店店长及区域督导因管理监督失职被降职处理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The video released by the party involved showed a store employee squeezing lemon slices with bare hands without wearing gloves and stirring with their hand in the cup, raising netizens' concerns about food safety. The party involved later explained that it was imitating the &quot;Indian milk tea&quot; meme and that damaged goods were used.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            当事人发布的视频显示，店员未佩戴手套徒手捏挤柠檬片并将手伸入杯中搅拌，引发网友对食品安全的质疑。当事人随后解释称系模仿「印度奶茶」梗，且使用的是报损商品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Another store employee stated that the store's production process explicitly requires not touching materials with bare hands. Currently, the party's social media account has been set to private, and all related videos have been deleted.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另一名门店员工则表示，门店制作流程明确要求不得徒手接触材料。目前，当事人社交账号已转为私密，相关视频均已被删除。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《王者荣耀》去年吸金超 20 亿美元</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《王者荣耀》去年吸金超-20-亿美元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/bda8268f-87ff-4145-a921-84f4f01e018f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, &quot;Honor of Kings&quot; continued to demonstrate strong revenue-generating capabilities last year, with its global annual revenue in 2025 (excluding third-party Android channels in China) exceeding $2 billion, firmly securing a leading position in the global mobile game market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，《王者荣耀》在去年继续展现强劲吸金能力，2025 年全年全球收入（不含中国第三方安卓渠道）突破 20 亿美元，稳居全球手游市场头部位置。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Data from analytics firm Sensor Tower shows that in December last year, a total of 33 Chinese publishers entered the TOP100 global mobile game publisher revenue list, collectively generating $1.95 billion, accounting for 34.6%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析机构 Sensor Tower 数据显示，去年 12 月共有 33 家中国厂商进入全球手游发行商收入榜 TOP100，合计吸金 19.5 亿美元，占比 34.6%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tencent, thanks to the stable performance of multiple products, retained its title as the global mobile game publisher revenue champion for December last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            腾讯凭借多款产品的稳定表现，蝉联去年 12 月全球手游发行商收入冠军。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Honor of Kings&quot; continues to maintain user stickiness by relying on strategies such as annual IP collaborations and commercialization upgrades for its professional league (KPL);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Battle of Golden Spatula&quot; saw a 50% month-on-month revenue increase due to the new &quot;League of Legends Legends&quot; season and limited-edition skin events;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Delta Force&quot; became a dark horse for growth, with its annual revenue skyrocketing 29 times year-on-year, and cumulative grossing exceeding $500 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the China App Store's mobile game revenue chart for December last year, Tencent's &quot;Honor of Kings,&quot; &quot;Battle of Golden Spatula,&quot; &quot;Delta Force,&quot; and &quot;Peace Elite&quot; took the top four spots.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在中国 App Store 去年 12 月手游收入榜中，腾讯旗下《王者荣耀》《金铲铲之战》《三角洲行动》《和平精英》包揽前四。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Following closely behind Tencent, Century Games (Dotemu) secured the runner-up position in the global mobile game publisher revenue list, thanks to the stable performance of &quot;Whiteout Survival&quot; and the growth momentum of &quot;Tasty Travels: Merge Game.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            紧随腾讯之后，点点互动凭借《无尽冬日》的稳定表现，以及《Tasty Travels: Merge Game》（《食光旅行》）的增长势头，位列全球手游发行商收入榜亚军。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Whiteout Survival&quot; has surpassed $4 billion in cumulative global revenue, while &quot;Tasty Travels&quot; entered a high-growth phase after intensive operations began in May last year, with its December revenue increasing by 30% month-on-month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《无尽冬日》全球累计收入已突破 40 亿美元，而《食光旅行》在去年 5 月启动密集运营后进入高速增长通道，12 月收入环比提升 30%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Papergames' &quot;Love and Deepspace&quot; celebrated its second anniversary in December last year and launched version 5.0, &quot;Love, Universe, Poetic Throne,&quot; driving a 161% month-on-month surge in China iOS revenue, rising to 6th place on the chart.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            叠纸网络的《恋与深空》在去年 12 月迎来上市两周年庆典，并推出 5.0 版本「爱，宇宙，诗王座」，带动中国 iOS 收入环比激增 161%，升至榜单第 6 名。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After the open-world wuxia mobile game &quot;Where Winds Meet&quot; launched its anniversary version &quot;Drinking Horses Across Autumn Waters,&quot; its daily grossing rapidly climbed, topping the China iOS bestseller list for the first time and entering the revenue TOP10 list for the first time with a 95% month-on-month increase.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            开放世界武侠手游《燕云十六声》推出周年庆版本「饮马渡秋水」后，日流水快速攀升，首次登顶中国 iOS 畅销榜，并以 95% 的环比增幅首次进入收入榜 TOP10。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Lemon Games (Lemon Microfun), relying on the performance of flagship products like &quot;Gossip Harbor,&quot; &quot;Seaside Escape,&quot; and &quot;Flambé: Merge &amp;amp; Cook&quot; during the Christmas and New Year events, saw robust revenue growth of 10%, with annual revenue surging 165% year-on-year, entering the TOP10 global mobile game publisher revenue list for December last year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，柠檬微趣依靠《Gossip Harbor》《Seaside Escape》《Flambé: Merge &amp;amp; Cook》等旗舰产品在圣诞与新年活动期间的表现，收入稳健增长 10%，全年收入同比激增 165%，跻身去年 12 月全球手游发行商收入榜 TOP10。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>星巴克 × 亚朵推出联合会员，住宿与咖啡权益全面互通</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">星巴克-×-亚朵推出联合会员，住宿与咖啡权益全面互通</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0dd0b80f-0ebd-4cb7-9854-59d51e85aeff.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starbucks China announced yesterday a partnership with Atour Group to launch a joint membership program, offering Starbucks Rewards members multiple value-added benefits covering accommodation, travel, and coffee consumption. This collaboration continues Starbucks' ongoing expansion in &quot;coffee + travel&quot; scenarios since last year, further broadening its &quot;Star Friends Circle.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星巴克中国昨日宣布与亚朵集团达成合作，推出联合会员计划，为星享俱乐部会员带来覆盖住宿、出行与咖啡消费的多重增值权益。本次合作延续星巴克自去年以来在「咖啡+出行」场景的持续布局，进一步扩容其「星朋友圈」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Both parties stated that the joint membership program will cover the full-tier membership systems of Starbucks and Atour. Users can complete binding via both companies' apps or WeChat mini-programs to receive multiple accommodation benefits, including &quot;room upgrades, double breakfast, and late check-out.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            双方表示，联合会员计划将覆盖星巴克与亚朵的全等级会员体系。用户可通过双方 App 或微信小程序完成绑定，领取包括「升级好房、双人早餐、延迟退房」在内的多项住宿福利。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the event, Starbucks Gold members can receive up to 12 Atour Gold member priority access benefits, equivalent to experiencing Atour Gold member core benefits for 360 days a year; Diamond members can upgrade 3 of these to Atour Platinum member priority access, additionally receiving up to 18 room upgrade vouchers and other benefits. Silver and Jade members can also regularly receive Atour no-threshold discount coupons, realizing &quot;membership is privilege.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星巴克金星会员在活动期间至高可领取 12 次亚朵金会员先享权，相当于一年可体验 360 天亚朵金会员核心权益；钻星会员则可将其中 3 次升级为亚朵铂金会员先享权，额外获得至高 18 张升房券等权益。银星与玉星会员也可定期领取亚朵无门槛立减券，实现「会员即权益」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding reciprocal benefits, Atour Black Gold, Platinum, and Gold members, after binding as joint members, can receive 6, 3, and 1 Starbucks Rewards Stars, respectively.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在反向权益方面，亚朵黑金、铂金与金会员绑定联合会员后，可分别获得 6 颗、3 颗及 1 颗星巴克好礼星星。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During their stay at Atour Hotels, eligible joint members can enjoy double Stars for purchases made through designated Starbucks channels. Atour Hotels have also launched joint-themed dining robots, allowing guests to order freshly brewed Starbucks coffee in their rooms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            入住亚朵酒店期间，符合条件的联合会员在星巴克指定渠道消费可享双倍积星。亚朵酒店还上线了联合主题配餐机器人，支持住客在房间内点选星巴克现制咖啡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to accommodation benefits, Starbucks is also simultaneously enhancing travel scenario services. Members can use Stars to redeem services such as concierge car pick-up/drop-off at airports, airport lounges, and fast-track security, and enjoy additional benefits like &quot;free in-flight Wi-Fi and a complimentary medium-sized coffee.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除住宿权益外，星巴克也同步强化出行场景服务。会员可使用星星兑换礼宾专车接送机、机场贵宾厅、机场快速安检等服务，并享受「免费机上 Wi-Fi、中杯赠饮咖啡」等额外福利。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since the comprehensive upgrade of the Starbucks Rewards program in June last year, Starbucks has continued to expand its membership system. As of November last year, Starbucks China's membership size had exceeded 160 million, with 90-day active members reaching 25 million.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自去年 6 月星享俱乐部全面升级以来，星巴克持续扩展会员体系。截至去年 11 月，星巴克中国会员规模已突破 1.6 亿，90 天活跃会员达 2500 万。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starbucks has currently established a four-tier growth system: Silver, Jade, Gold, and Diamond Star. Members can accumulate &quot;Good Gift Stars&quot; to redeem various benefits such as beverages, digital membership cards, and airport pick-up/drop-off services. The &quot;Happy Together Day&quot; launched last year has also become an important event day for members to earn extra stars.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星巴克目前构建了银星、玉星、金星、钻星四级成长体系，会员可通过累积「好礼星星」兑换饮品、数字会员卡、接送机服务等多样化权益。去年起推出的「一起开星日」也成为会员获取额外星星的重要活动日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As for Atour, as of the end of September last year, the group had 1,948 hotels in operation, with over 108 million registered members, covering six major accommodation brands and multiple retail brands.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            亚朵方面，截至去年 9 月末，集团在营酒店数量达 1948 家，累计注册会员超过 1.08 亿，旗下覆盖六大住宿品牌及多个零售品牌。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Atour stated that this collaboration starts from real travel scenarios, hoping to combine its &quot;peace of mind&quot; philosophy with Starbucks' &quot;everyday warmth&quot; to provide users with a more reassuring travel experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            亚朵表示，本次合作以真实出行场景为起点，希望将其「身心安顿」理念与星巴克的「日常温度」结合，为用户提供更具确定感的旅途体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>经典恐怖片《闪灵》确认引进</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">经典恐怖片《闪灵》确认引进</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e5326baa-f2ac-41f1-9296-1c571c560931.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Stanley Kubrick's classic psychological horror film &quot;The Shining&quot; has been confirmed to debut in Chinese mainland cinemas this year. This marks the film's first official public screening in mainland China since its release in the United States on May 23, 1980.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            斯坦利 · 库布里克执导的经典心理恐怖电影《闪灵》已确认将在今年首次登陆中国内地院线。这是该片自 1980 年 5 月 23 日在美国上映以来，首次在中国内地正式公映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Warner Bros. Pictures' official social media yesterday released multiple sets of film-related emojis hinting at release plans, and news from Kuaikeji further confirmed that &quot;The Shining&quot; will be introduced to the mainland market in a newly restored version.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            华纳兄弟电影官方社交媒体昨日发布多组与影片相关的 emoji 暗示上映计划，而后来自快科技的消息进一步确认，《闪灵》将以全新修复版本引进内地市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, this version had been re-released in IMAX in North America, South Korea, and other regions, but whether an IMAX version will be simultaneously available in mainland China is still awaiting official announcement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，该版本已在北美、韩国等地推出 IMAX 重映，但内地是否同步提供 IMAX 版本仍有待官方公布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;The Shining&quot; is adapted from Stephen King's novel of the same name, produced by Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc. of the United States, and is hailed as a &quot;textbook for horror films.&quot; The film creates a unique psychological thriller atmosphere with its avant-garde audiovisual language, symmetrical composition, long takes, and highly oppressive soundtrack.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《闪灵》改编自斯蒂芬 · 金同名小说，由美国华纳兄弟娱乐公司出品，被誉为「恐怖片教科书」。影片以其超前的视听语言、对称构图、长镜头运用及极具压迫感的配乐，构建出独特的心理惊悚氛围。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>报告：游戏改编影视激增，《博德之门 3》被点名为下一个爆款候选</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">报告：游戏改编影视激增，《博德之门-3》被点名为下一个爆款候选</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/aeb745d8-f294-43c3-ac53-9065ef120437.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Hollywood Reporter, British market research firm Ampere Analysis recently released a report stating that since 2019, video game adaptation projects have been continuously heating up in Hollywood.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 The Hollywood Reporter 报道，英国市场研究机构 Ampere Analysis 最近发布报告称，自 2019 年以来，电子游戏改编影视项目在好莱坞持续升温。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that from 2019 to last year, a total of 272 film and television adaptations based on game IPs were greenlit, with last year being the peak, reaching 62 newly greenlit projects.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Unlike earlier trends that leaned more towards animation, the market is clearly shifting towards live-action adaptations
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , a trend further accelerated by the success of &quot;The Last of Us&quot; and &quot;Minecraft The Movie.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，2019 年至去年共有 272 部基于游戏 IP 的影视改编作品获得立项，其中去年是高峰期，新立项项目达到 62 部。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             与早期更偏向动画形式不同，市场正明显转向真人改编
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，这一趋势在《最后生还者》和《我的世界大电影》成功后进一步加速。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report further mentions that in the past six months alone, 18 new game adaptation projects were approved, 78% of which were live-action film and television works. By last year, 69% of approved game adaptation projects opted for live-action format, a proportion that doubled from the previous year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报告进一步提到，仅在过去半年内，就有 18 部新的游戏改编项目获批，其中 78% 为真人影视作品。到去年，获批的游戏改编项目中已有 69% 选择真人形式，比例较前一年翻倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Major content platforms such as Warner, Paramount, Netflix, Comcast, Amazon, and Disney have all secured at least 10 &quot;flagship&quot; game IPs for theatrical films or streaming series development:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            华纳、派拉蒙、Netflix、康卡斯特、亚马逊、迪士尼等大型内容平台均已拿下至少 10 个「旗舰级」游戏 IP，用于院线电影或流媒体剧集布局：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, Warner and Paramount lean more towards theatrical distribution, while Amazon, Disney, Netflix, and Comcast prefer to strengthen user stickiness through long-form series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，华纳和派拉蒙更偏向院线发行，而亚马逊、迪士尼、Netflix 和康卡斯特则偏好通过长剧集强化用户黏性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ampere Analysis screens game IPs for &quot;cross-media adaptation potential&quot; based on 8 key indicators, including narrative completeness, adaptation format (live-action or animation), reachable audience size, series launch year, IP popularity, individual work popularity, work freshness, and ESRB age rating.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Ampere Analysis 基于 8 项关键指标筛选游戏 IP 的「跨媒介改编潜力」，包括叙事完整度、改编形式（真人或动画）、可触达受众规模、系列首发年份、IP 热度、单独作品热度、作品的新鲜度以及 ESRB 年龄分级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Research lead Ronald Santa-Cruz stated that the more lenient the age rating, the wider the audience an adaptation can cover without significantly altering the original story. Games rated E or E10+ have a significantly higher probability of their adapted series being renewed compared to M-rated works.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            研究负责人 Ronald Santa-Cruz 表示，年龄分级越宽松，改编作品在不大幅改动原作故事前提下可覆盖的受众越广，评级为 E 或 E10+ 的游戏，其改编剧集获得续订的概率显著高于 M 级作品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Under this model, Ampere Analysis named 4 game IPs that have not yet been &quot;exhausted&quot; by adaptation rights but possess high adaptation potential, namely:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在这一模型下，Ampere Analysis 点名了 4 个尚未被改编权「吃干抹净」但具备高改编潜力的游戏 IP，分别是：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Role-playing game &quot;Baldur's Gate 3&quot; (ESRB rating M, released in 2023);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese action game &quot;Black Myth: Wukong&quot; (ESRB rating T);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Independent platform action game &quot;Hollow Knight&quot; (ESRB rating T);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And survival horror game &quot;Sons of the Forest&quot; (ESRB rating M).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, &quot;Baldur's Gate 3&quot; is not only based on the &quot;Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons&quot; universe setting, but also widely recognized for its narrative and character development, becoming the first work to sweep the Game of the Year awards from 5 major mainstream game awards, and is considered by Ampere as an adaptation candidate &quot;already ready for prime time&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，《博德之门 3》不仅基于「龙与地下城」宇宙设定，在叙事和角色塑造上也获得广泛认可，成为首个横扫 5 大主流游戏奖项评选年度游戏奖的作品，被 Ampere 视为「已经为黄金档做好准备」的改编候选。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《绿液惊魂》发布预告</title>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 04:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《绿液惊魂》发布预告</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20260107_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/00158090-0583-4f4e-9ead-64015c2a9256.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The thrilling sci-fi comedy film &quot;Green Liquid Horror&quot; was officially announced yesterday for the first time, set to be released in mainland cinemas, with its latest trailer and poster simultaneously released. The film is scheduled for release in the UK on February 6th this year, and the official statement indicates it will be shown in cinemas nationwide, with the specific release date yet to be determined.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            惊悚科幻喜剧电影《绿液惊魂》昨日首次官宣，即将在内地影院上映，并同步发布最新预告与海报。影片英国定档今年 2 月 6 日，官方表示将于全国院线上映，具体档期待定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film's core selling point is its &quot;heavy-taste grotesque&quot; style, with the story revolving around two night shift employees, Sweetheart and Naomi, who accidentally discover an alien parasitic fungus.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片以「重口味怪诞派」风格为核心卖点，故事围绕两名夜班员工甜点心与内奥米意外发现外星寄生真菌展开。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the fungus rapidly spreads, the two are forced to seek help from retired agent Robert, forming a temporary team of three to try and prevent the world from being corrupted amidst the chaotic environment of splashing green liquid.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            随着真菌高速蔓延，二人被迫向退休特工罗伯特求助，三人组成临时小队，在绿液四溅的混乱环境中试图阻止世界被腐蚀。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
