<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>汽车安全新国标发起意见征求：乘用车默认零百加速不小于 5 秒</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">汽车安全新国标发起意见征求：乘用车默认零百加速不小于-5-秒</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to IT Home, the Ministry of Public Security announced on November 10 that, in accordance with the standard revision plan of the National Standardization Administration Committee, the Ministry of Public Security has organized and completed the draft for comments of the national standard &quot;Technical Conditions for Road Vehicle Operation Safety,&quot; and is now soliciting public opinions. Some of the contents are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 IT 之家消息，公安部 11 月 10 日公告，根据国家标准化管理委员会标准制修订计划，公安部已组织完成了《机动车运行安全技术条件》国家标准的征求意见稿，现公开征求意见。部分内容如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             New Energy Vehicles:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             新能源汽车：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adds requirements for Type A regenerative braking systems and standardizes the application of &quot;single pedal&quot; mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requires electric and plug-in hybrid passenger vehicles to have a pedal misapplication acceleration suppression function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requires that when the vehicle speed exceeds 10km/h, the driver's side display screen should be turned off and prohibited from enabling entertainment video playback and gaming functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarifies that power batteries for pure electric vehicles and plug-in hybrid vehicles should comply with the provisions of GB 38031, and the vehicle body should be equipped with directional pressure relief and pressure balancing devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The draft for comments also adds:
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;After each power-on / ignition (excluding engine automatic start-stop), passenger vehicles should be in a default operating state with a 0-100 km/h acceleration time of no less than 5s.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            征求意见稿还增加
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「乘用车每次上电 / 点火后（发动机自动启停除外），应处于百公里加速时间不小于 5s 的默认工作状态。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The draft points out that in recent years, there have been frequent accidents involving uncontrolled acceleration in pure electric vehicles and plug-in hybrid vehicles, mostly due to drivers' insufficient preparation and control skills when using high-acceleration modes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            意见稿指出，近年来，纯电动汽车、插电式混合动力汽车启动加速失控事故多发，其多是由于驾驶人使用高加速模式时，对高加速模式的驾驶准备和操控能力不足。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            To this end, it is required that vehicles be in a default operating state with lower acceleration performance when first started, so that drivers must consciously take certain actions when using high-acceleration modes, in order to improve their driving readiness. According to statistics, the 0-100 km/h acceleration time for most driving school training vehicles and most fuel-powered passenger cars is generally greater than 5s, which new and experienced drivers are more accustomed to, making misoperation less likely.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            为此，要求车辆刚启动时处于加速性能较低的默认工作状态，让驾驶人使用高加速模式时需有意识的采取一定操作，以期提高其驾驶准备。据统计，目前驾校教练车和大多数燃油乘用车的百公里加速时间普遍大于 5s，新老司机对于这种加速度更为适应，不易误操作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Trucks:
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             货车：
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All trucks (excluding garbage trucks and low-speed vehicles) are required to be equipped with an automatic emergency braking system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trucks with a total mass greater than or equal to 4500kg (excluding garbage trucks) and special purpose vehicles with a rated load capacity (or lifting capacity) greater than or equal to 1000kg are required to be equipped with a lane departure warning function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All trucks (excluding garbage trucks and low-speed vehicles) are required to be equipped with an electronic stability control system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vehicles transporting dangerous goods and trucks with three or more axles are required to be equipped with a driver attention monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trucks with a total mass greater than or equal to 4500kg are required to be equipped with a panoramic imaging monitoring system or a blind spot monitoring system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For pure electric semi-trailer tractors, in addition to various facilities permanently installed on the vehicle that can serve as side protection devices, if there is a longitudinal gap greater than 1m, side protection to prevent personnel entanglement should be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>奇瑞就「天门山挑战测试意外」致歉</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">奇瑞就「天门山挑战测试意外」致歉</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chery Automobile has just issued an apology statement regarding the unexpected situation during the Tianmen Mountain challenge test. According to Chery's official statement:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            刚刚，奇瑞汽车发布关于天门山挑战测试意外情况的致歉声明。据奇瑞官方表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;At 12:00 on November 12, 2025, the Fengyun X3L's extreme challenge test project in the Tianmen Mountain Scenic Area, Zhangjiajie, Hunan, was interrupted due to a sudden accident, attracting widespread attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response, Chery expressed its sincerest apologies to the Tianmen Mountain Scenic Area, tourists, partners, and all friends concerned about this matter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对此，奇瑞表示向天门山景区、游客、合作伙伴及所有关心此事的朋友们致以最诚挚的歉意。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to its preliminary investigation and verification, the direct cause of this accident was the unexpected detachment of the shackle at the fixing point of the test device's safety rope, which then led to the rope entangling the right wheel, obstructing power output, causing the vehicle to slide down and hit the guardrail, damaging part of it. Fortunately, this accident did not result in any personal injuries or damage to the natural environment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            经其初步调查核实，此事故的直接原因是，测试装置的安全防护绳固定点卸扣意外脱落，进而导致防护绳缠绕右侧车轮，动力输出受阻，车辆下滑撞击护栏，造成部分护栏受损。所幸本次意外未造成人员受伤以及自然环境的破坏。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Chery's official statement also indicated that the test results exposed its insufficient estimation of potential risks and oversight in controlling details during the planning and execution of this test, especially regarding the public's concerns arising from choosing to conduct tests in a public scenic area. Chery stated that it is &quot;deeply reflecting&quot; on this.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，奇瑞官方也表示，上述测试结果暴露了其在策划和执行此次测试过程中，对潜在风险的预估不足，对细节的把控存在疏漏，特别是对选择在风景区公开场所开展测试引发的公众担忧，奇瑞方面表示「深刻反思」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Chery also expressed deep apologies for the damage caused to the Tianmen Mountain site by this test and pledged to fully repair it, bear compensation responsibility, and handle all follow-up work.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，对于此次测试造成的天门山场地损失，奇瑞也深表歉意，并承诺将全力修复并承担赔偿责任，做好所有善后工作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI 天才少女官宣加入小米</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">AI-天才少女官宣加入小米</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/641f9705-d109-4792-bc1e-6f2a23302fb8.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to &quot;Grain Factory Researcher Will,&quot; &quot;AI prodigy&quot; Luo Fuli recently announced on her WeChat Moments that she has joined Xiaomi's &quot;MiMo&quot; team, stating that &quot;intelligence will eventually move from language to the physical world&quot; and &quot;we are fully committed to the AGI in our minds.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据「粮厂研究员 Will」消息，「AI 天才少女」罗福莉日前在朋友圈官宣，自己已加入小米「MiMo」团队，并表示「智能终将从语言迈向物理世界」「全力奔赴我们心目中的 AGI」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In February this year, media reported that Luo Fuli had started her new job. Before the Chinese New Year this year, Lei Jun stated during a live broadcast that he hoped to poach Luo Fuli with an annual salary of tens of millions to lead a team at Xiaomi to conduct research on large AI models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 2 月，曾有媒体报道称罗福莉已到新岗位上班。而在今年春节前，雷军曾在直播时表示，自己希望用千万年薪挖角罗福莉，请她到小米带领团队从事 AI 大模型研究。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Luo Fuli earned her master's degree from Peking University's Institute of Computational Linguistics and has outstanding research experience and achievements in the field of natural language processing. Subsequently, Luo Fuli worked at Alibaba's DAMO Academy Machine Intelligence Lab; in 2022, Luo Fuli participated in the development of DeepSeek's MoE model, DeepSeek-V2.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，罗福莉硕士毕业于北京大学计算语言学研究所，并在自然语言处理领域有着杰出的研究经历和成果。此后，罗福莉在阿里巴巴的达摩院机器智能实验室工作；2022 年，罗福莉参与 DeepSeek 的 MoE 模型 DeepSeek-V2 的开发。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi's &quot;MiMo&quot; team has also announced and open-sourced several models this year, including the multimodal large model &quot;Xiaomi MiMo-VL,&quot; the inference large model &quot;Xiaomi MiMo,&quot; and the native end-to-end speech large model &quot;Xiaomi-MiMo-Audio.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而小米的「MiMo」团队，也已在今年公布并开源多款模型，包含多模态大模型「Xiaomi MiMo-VL」、推理大模型「Xiaomi MiMo」、原生端到端语音大模型「Xiaomi-MiMo-Audio」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>火绒安全「手撕」鲁大师流量劫持黑幕</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">火绒安全「手撕」鲁大师流量劫持黑幕</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 11, Huorong Security published an article titled &quot;Hide-and-Seek Harvesting: Unveiling the Traffic Hijacking Scandal of Lu Master and Related Enterprises,&quot; stating:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 11 日，火绒安全发布一篇名为《「捉迷藏」 式收割：撕开鲁大师为首系列企业流量劫持黑幕》的文章，并表示：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Recently, Huorong Security Lab monitored and found that multiple software vendors, including Chengdu Qilu Technology Co., Ltd. and Tianjin Xingren'an Technology Co., Ltd., are building a large-scale promotion industry chain through cloud-controlled configuration, remotely enabling promotion modules to achieve traffic monetization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Huorong Security stated that the aforementioned software vendors issue configuration commands through the cloud, dynamically controlling the software's promotion behavior, and the promotion methods of different companies and their products vary.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            火绒安全称，上述软件厂商通过云端下达配置指令，动态控制软件的推广行为，不同公司及其产品的推广方式各有差异。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Huorong Security takes Lu Master, a product of Chengdu Qilu Technology, as an example; its promotion behaviors include but are not limited to:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            火绒安全以成都奇鲁科技旗下的鲁大师为例，其推广行为涵盖但不限于：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using browser pop-ups to promote &quot;Legend&quot; type web games;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pop-up installation of third-party software without explicit user permission;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tampering with JD.com web links and inserting Jingfen promotion parameters to earn commissions; popping up Baidu search boxes with channel identifiers;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedding browser extensions that are promotional in nature and disguised as normal applications, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Huorong Security pointed out that although traffic promotion has always been a common profit model for internet companies, these vendors have used various technical countermeasures to hinder security analysis and behavior reproduction, deliberately concealing their actions that harm user experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            火绒安全指出，尽管流量推广向来是互联网公司常用的盈利模式，然而这些厂商却运用了多种技术对抗手段，以阻碍安全分析与行为复现，蓄意隐匿其损害用户体验的行为。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It also stated that the aforementioned software vendors monetize user traffic without fully informing users or deliberately vaguely informing them of relevant situations. By disguising themselves as legitimate applications, they play &quot;hide-and-seek&quot; with users, making it difficult for users to identify and locate the true source of promotion. These entities employ various means to circumvent online public opinion supervision and evade public scrutiny.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其还表示，上述软件厂商在未充分向用户告知或故意模糊告知相关情况的前提下，利用用户流量进行变现操作。通过伪装成正规应用的方式，与用户「捉迷藏」，使用户难以识别并定位真正的推广源头。这些主体采用各种手段规避网络舆论监督，逃避公众审查。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Interestingly, Huorong Security also mentioned in the article that the promotion modules and Lua promotion scripts in most software will detect browser history to avoid specific groups of people. The detection content includes page titles and visited URLs in the history.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            有趣的是，火绒安全还在文中提到，多数软件中的推广模块及 Lua 推广脚本会检测浏览器历史记录，以规避特定人群，检测内容包括历史记录中的页面标题和访问网址。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             During the process of hijacking the browser, it will detect whether the user has visited Zhou Hongyi's Weibo. If the detection result is that it has been visited, no promotion will be carried out.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             其中在劫持浏览器的过程中，会对用户是否访问过周鸿祎的微博进行检测，若检测结果为已访问，则不会进行推广。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPhone 霸榜双 11 销量榜</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">iPhone-霸榜双-11-销量榜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9733095d-9b09-49d1-92aa-8afc0ce4c496.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to data from JD.com platform cited by Sina Technology, as of 23:59:59 on November 11, Apple, Xiaomi, and vivo ranked among the top three in sales on the platform during the Double 11 shopping festival. The top three in sales revenue for the same period were also Apple, Xiaomi, and vivo.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪科技援引京东平台数据显示，截至 11 月 11 日 23:59:59，苹果、小米、vivo 位列该平台双 11 销量榜前三，该时期的销售额榜单前三同样是苹果、小米、vivo。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding specific models,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             in the overall sales ranking across all price segments, iPhone 17 Pro Max, iPhone 17 Pro, and iPhone 17 dominated the top three,
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            followed by models such as REDMI K80, Honor X70, and REDMI Turbo 4 Pro.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            具体机型方面，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             全价格段总销量榜中，iPhone 17 Pro Max、iPhone 17 Pro、iPhone 17 霸榜前三，
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            而后为 REDMI K80、荣耀 X70、REDMI Turbo 4 Pro 等机型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             in the price segment above 6000 yuan, with iPhones taking the top three spots, Xiaomi 17 Pro Max ranked fourth, becoming the number one domestic phone in the over 6000 yuan price range.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             6000 元以上价位段，在 iPhone 包揽前三名的情况下，小米 17 Pro Max 排名第四，成为国产 6000 元以上价位第一。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Xiaomi also released its Double 11 final battle report:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，小米还发布了双 11 收官战报：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Cumulative payments across all channels reached 29 billion. Xiaomi phones ranked first in sales among domestic phones on major e-commerce platforms, and Xiaomi 17 Pro Max secured both the top spot in sales volume and sales revenue for domestic phones in the over 6000 yuan price segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lu Weibing, Partner and President of Xiaomi Group, stated that Xiaomi phones have ranked first in domestic phone sales during Double 11 for three consecutive years, while Xiaomi founder Lei Jun posted a message expressing &quot;thanks for everyone's support.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米集团合伙人、总裁卢伟冰表示，小米手机已经连续 3 年双 11 获得国产手机销量第一，而小米创办人雷军发文表示「感谢大家的支持」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>索尼：PS5 累计卖出近 8500 万台</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">索尼：PS5-累计卖出近-8500-万台</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Sony Group announced its financial results for the second quarter of fiscal year 2025 (ending September 30, 2025). Let's look at the overall picture first:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，索尼集团公布了其 2025 财年第二季（截至 2025 年 9 月 30 日）的财报信息，先看整体：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Revenue was 3.11 trillion yen (approximately 142.8 billion RMB); net profit was 311.4 billion yen (approximately 14.3 billion RMB), a year-on-year increase of 7%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, revenue increased by 5% year-on-year, benefiting from the strong growth of the Music and Imaging &amp;amp; Sensing Solutions (I&amp;amp;SS) segments and favorable exchange rates.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，受益于音乐、影像传感器解决方案（I&amp;amp;SS）两大部门的强劲增长及汇率利好，营收同比增长 5%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the impressive data,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             PlayStation 5 (PS5) global shipments reached 84.2 million units, with 3.9 million units shipped this quarter
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , a year-on-year increase of 100,000 units; meanwhile, PlayStation Network's monthly active users reached 119 million. It is worth mentioning that the game &quot;Spirit of Mount Yotei&quot; has sold over 3.3 million copies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在亮眼数据上，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             PlayStation 5（PS5）全球出货量达 8420 万台，本季度出货量达 390 万台
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，同比增长 10 万台；同时，PlayStation Network 月活跃用户数达 1.19 亿。值得一提的是，游戏《羊蹄山之魂》销量已突破 330 万。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, operating profit for the Game &amp;amp; Network Services (G&amp;amp;NS) business fell to 120.4 billion yen (approximately 5.5 billion RMB), a significant 13% drop compared to the same period last year (approximately 6.4 billion RMB). The financial report shows that the decline in operating profit was mainly due to a total of 49.8 billion yen in one-time expenses.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            但游戏和网络服务业务（G&amp;amp;NS）营业利润降至 1204 亿日元（约合人民币 55 亿元），相较去年同期（约合人民币 64 亿元）大幅下滑 13%。财报显示，营业利润的下滑，主要原因是计提了总计 498 亿日元的一次性费用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sony emphasized that if these two one-time factors were excluded, the G&amp;amp;NS division's operating profit would actually have increased by 23% year-on-year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            索尼强调，若排除这两项一次性因素，G&amp;amp;NS 部门的营业利润实际上较去年同期增长了 23%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>贾跃亭：当年小米在乐视面前根本没有还手之力</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">贾跃亭：当年小米在乐视面前根本没有还手之力</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1991db6d-afd8-43f4-b6bc-4af26e1bc946.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the Douyin account &quot;Futurist Alliance&quot; released a video clip of Jia Yueting's speech.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，抖音账号「未来主义者联盟」发布了一段贾跃亭讲话的视频切片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the beginning of the video,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Jia Yueting talked about the competition between LeEco and Xiaomi back then, and frankly stated: &quot;Xiaomi had no power to fight back against us (back then).&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该视频一开头，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             贾跃亭就谈及了当年乐视与小米的竞争，并直言：「（当年）小米在我们面前根本没有还手之力。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jia Yueting stated that LeEco's &quot;collapse&quot; at that time was not due to poor products, poor technology, or lack of users. On the contrary, the products were extremely competitive, globally competitive. In terms of technology, many unique technologies were created. And in terms of users and market, it was truly invincible.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            贾跃亭表示，当时乐视这种「崩塌」，不是因为产品不行、技术不行、没有用户。而恰恰相反，产品极具竞争力，全球都极具竞争力。技术，创造了很多独一无二的技术。而在用户端和市场端，真的是所向披靡。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to IT Home, in August 2016, LeEco was exposed to have financial problems with its suppliers, and was subsequently &quot;forced to pay debts&quot; by dozens of suppliers. In November of the same year, Jia Yueting admitted that there were indeed problems with the capital chain.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 IT 之家报道，2016 年 8 月乐视被爆供应商出现资金问题，随后被数十家供应商「逼债」，同年 11 月贾跃亭承认资金链的确出了问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            And in June this year, Jia Yueting posted: From LeEco to FF (Faraday Future), for those who haven't given up on us, beyond gratitude, I feel more guilt.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在今年 6 月，贾跃亭曾发文称：从乐视到 FF（法拉第未来），那些没放弃我们的人，我除了感动之外，其实更多的是愧疚。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He also stated that FF must survive, not just for himself and the company's employees, but for everyone who has continuously supported FF. Jia Yueting said that the team will always stand with the shareholders, and boldly declared that &quot;FF and FX will definitely succeed and create the greatest value for shareholders.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其还表示，FF 必须活下去，不只是为了他自己和公司员工，而是为了所有一直支持 FF 的人。贾跃亭称，团队会永远和股民站在一起，并豪言称「FF 和 FX 一定能成功，为股民创造最大价值」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In May, Jia Yueting released a video stating that &quot;debt repayment is one of the most important goals in his life, and it is also very important for FF.&quot; He also said at the time that once he could repay his debts and return to China, many of FF's credibility issues would be resolved, and he emphasized that &quot;FF must be brought back to China.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            5 月，贾跃亭发布视频称「还债是其人生中的最重要目标之一，同时对 FF 也非常重要。」其当时还称，一旦要是能够还债能够回国，那其实 FF 很多信誉问题就迎刃而解，并强调「一定要把 FF 带回中国」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>鸿蒙智行或再添一「界」，华为申请注册「齐界」商标</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">鸿蒙智行或再添一「界」，华为申请注册「齐界」商标</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1b8f4e84-d430-45e7-a573-708c055cb041.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to recent data from the Trademark Office of the China National Intellectual Property Administration, &quot;Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.&quot; (address: Huawei Headquarters Office Building, Bantian, Longgang District, Shenzhen, Guangdong Province) applied for a trademark named &quot;Qijie&quot; on June 16, 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据国家知识产权局商标局近期数据显示，申请人「华为技术有限公司」（地址为广东省深圳市龙岗区坂田华为总部办公楼）于 2025 年 6 月 16 日申请了一个名为「齐界」的商标。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The data shows that the &quot;Qijie&quot; trademark covers goods/services such as automobiles, car bodies, car wheel hubs, hybrid vehicles, car seats, electric vehicles, autonomous vehicles, car chassis, and car wheels.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从数据显示，「齐界」这一商标涵盖汽车、汽车车身、汽车车轮毂、混合动力汽车、汽车座椅、电动汽车、自动驾驶汽车、汽车底盘、汽车车轮等商品/服务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, there is no further information available regarding &quot;Qijie.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前暂无其他更多关于「齐界」相关信息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that Harmony Intelligent Mobility's fifth series, &quot;Shangjie,&quot; was announced this year, and officially launched its first model, &quot;Shangjie H5,&quot; in September, with a starting price of 159,800 yuan, targeting the smart car market below 200,000 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，鸿蒙智行第五界「尚界」于今年公布，并在 9 月正式带来了旗下首款车型「尚界 H5」，起售价 15.98 万元，定位 20 万元以下智能汽车市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Shangjie H5 is the first model of the &quot;Shangjie&quot; brand, co-developed by Huawei and SAIC Group. It is equipped with the Qiankun Zhijia ADS 4 system and comes standard with 3 4D millimeter-wave radars and a 192-line lidar across all models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，尚界 H5 是华为与上汽集团合作打造的「尚界」品牌首款车型，搭载乾崑智驾 ADS 4 系统，全系标配 3 颗 4D 毫米波雷达、192 线激光雷达。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>李飞飞的 AI「造世神器」官宣向全体用户开放</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">李飞飞的-AI「造世神器」官宣向全体用户开放</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ee702fca-edbe-43cf-b188-f672278654e5.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Just now, Li Feifei's World Labs company officially announced that its 3D world generation model &quot;Marble&quot; is now open to all users, and a wave of new features has been released all at once:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            刚刚，李飞飞旗下的 World Labs 公司官宣，其 3D 世界生成模型「Marble」向全体用户开放，还一次性放出了一大波新功能：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multimodal generation: Supports various input methods such as text, single image, multiple images/videos, and 3D layouts;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI-native editing: Allows for local replacement and structural adjustments to the generated 3D world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World expansion and combination: Automatically fills in edge areas and stitches multiple scenes together;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chisel: Build frameworks with blocks, and AI automatically fills in style details;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full format export: Supports various formats such as Gaussian point clouds, triangular meshes, and videos, which can be directly imported into game engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding pricing:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            价格方面：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free Version: 7000 points per month, generates up to 4 worlds, supports text/image/panorama input. Suitable for trial users, but advanced features are locked;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard Version ($20/month): 20000 points per month, 12 worlds, unlocks multi-image/video input, Chisel mode, and basic export functions;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro Version ($35/month, $1 for the first month): 40000 points, 25 worlds, supports scene expansion, video enhancement, high-resolution mesh export, and includes commercial use authorization;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flagship Version ($95/month): 120000 points, 75 worlds, all features unlocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, a few days before Marble's release, Fei-Fei Li specifically published a lengthy article elaborating on her vision—Spatial Intelligence. The core points can be summarized as:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，在 Marble 发布前几天，李飞飞专门发表了一篇长文阐述她的愿景——空间智能（Spatial Intelligence）。核心观点可以总结为：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;While large language models possess strong linguistic abilities, they know almost nothing about the physical world. They cannot accurately estimate distances, directions, cannot &quot;rotate&quot; objects in their minds, nor can they predict basic physical laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;In contrast, the core of human intelligence is not language, but the ability to understand and manipulate three-dimensional space. From driving a car to catching keys, from designing buildings to discovering the DNA double helix structure—all rely on spatial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蚂蚁 gPass 实现全球首个智能眼镜内置虹膜核身支付功能</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蚂蚁-gPass-实现全球首个智能眼镜内置虹膜核身支付功能</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7efad819-21f3-42ce-9551-aa88a11e4687.jpeg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Ant Group's gPass trusted connection technology for smart terminals achieved a significant upgrade, launching the world's first iris verification payment solution integrated into smart glasses, which officially debuted at the Singapore FinTech Festival.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，蚂蚁集团智能终端可信连接技术 gPass 实现重要升级，推出全球首个集成于智能眼镜的虹膜核身支付方案，并在新加坡金融科技节上正式亮相。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Ant International Alipay+, along with multiple smart glasses manufacturers such as Xiaomi and Xingji Meizu, are jointly promoting the implementation of various solutions in international payment scenarios, utilizing cutting-edge AI and AR (Augmented Reality) technologies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，蚂蚁国际 Alipay+，和小米、星纪魅族等多家智能眼镜制造商，运用前沿 AI 和 AR（增强现实）技术，共同推动多种类方案在国际支付场景中的落地应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This gPass technology, by capturing and comparing over 260 biometric feature points and combining AI with liveness detection technology, can effectively resist advanced attack methods such as screen re-photography and 3D masks; meanwhile, with its self-developed imaging enhancement algorithm, the system maintains a high recognition rate even under complex lighting conditions, truly achieving &quot;one glance verification&quot; for contactless identity authentication.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次 gPass 技术通过捕捉并比对 260 余个生物特征点，结合 AI 与活体检测技术，可有效抵御屏幕翻拍、3D 面具等高阶攻击手段；同时借助自研的成像增强算法，系统在复杂光线下仍能保持高识别率，真正实现「一眼即验」的非接触式核身。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As a technical framework possessing three core capabilities—&quot;security, interaction, and connectivity&quot;—gPass has built a multimodal biometric authentication system based on the original voiceprint authentication.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            作为具备「安全、交互、连接」三大核心能力的技术框架，gPass 在原有声纹认证基础上构建了多模态生物认证体系。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of privacy protection, gPass innovatively adopts a lightweight &quot;one person, one key&quot; encryption scheme, ensuring full-link security for biometric data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在隐私保护方面，gPass 创新地采用「一人一密」的轻量化加密方案，确保生物特征数据全链路安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that Ant Group is collaborating with ecosystem partners such as hardware manufacturers and e-wallet service providers to jointly promote technical compliance, ensuring that solutions meet privacy regulatory requirements in different regions and building a trusted payment environment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，蚂蚁集团正与硬件制造商、电子钱包服务商等生态伙伴协同推进技术合规，确保方案符合不同地区的隐私监管要求，共建可信支付环境。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>微软 AI CEO 要求团队每周至少 4 天线下办公</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微软-AI-CEO-要求团队每周至少-4-天线下办公</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Microsoft AI CEO Mustafa Suleyman recently implemented a strict in-office work policy for his team:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Business Insider 报道，微软 AI CEO Mustafa Suleyman 近期对自己的团队实施严格的线下办公政策：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Team members are required to work in the office at least four days a week, a standard that exceeds Microsoft's general three-day in-office policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Suleyman responded through the report, stating that he personally strongly believes in a face-to-face work culture. He also admitted that he dislikes traditional offices with doors that can be locked.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Suleyman 通过报道回应表示，他本人非常相信面对面的工作文化。同时他自己坦言，不喜欢有门、会被锁上的传统办公室。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response, Suleyman also designed his office layout to be open-plan—with 20-30 open desks where employees can interact with each other.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对此，Suleyman 还将自己的办公室布局设为开放式——里面有 20-30 张开放式办公桌，员工之间可以相互交流。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Suleyman believes that an open work environment and face-to-face interaction can greatly boost collaboration efficiency, stating, &quot;Everyone knows where everyone else is, the whole environment is vibrant, and it also creates more informal collaboration.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Suleyman 认为，开放式工作环境和面对面能够极大地促进协作效率，「每个人都能知道其他人在哪，整个环境充满了活力，并且还能创造更多非正式的协作。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 Meta 首席 AI 官：氛围编程将成为 AI 新时代的入场券</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-Meta-首席-AI-官：氛围编程将成为-AI-新时代的入场券</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Meta's Chief AI Officer Alexandr Wang (Wang Tao) stated in an interview with the TBPN podcast that if today's teenagers want to stand out in a rapidly changing economic future, they should deeply explore AI tools.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，Meta 首席 AI 官 Alexandr Wang（汪滔）在接受 TBPN 播客采访时表示，如果当今的青少年想在快速变化的经济未来中脱颖而出，他们应该深入探索 AI 工具。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Tao believes that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the greatest opportunity for the next generation of youth lies in mastering artificial intelligence.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            He emphasized that young people should invest thousands of hours in learning and experimenting with AI models, and master their intricacies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            汪滔认为，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             下一代青年最大的机遇在于掌握人工智能。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            其强调，年轻人应该投入数千小时学习和实验 AI 模型，并且掌握其门路。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the currently popular Vibe Coding, Wang Tao even believes they should 'learn it quickly.' He stated that the group of young people who can grow up with these AI tools will have a huge advantage in the future economy. Wang Tao even called it 'the Bill Gates, Zuckerberg moment of today.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对时下火热的氛围编程（Vibe Coding），汪滔更是认为「赶紧学」，他表示，那一群能与这些 AI 工具一同长大的年轻人，能够在未来的经济体中拥有巨大优势。汪滔更是称之为「现在就是比尔·盖茨、扎克伯格时刻」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Although Vibe Coding was emphasized, Wang Tao's overall core message was to express a practical and experimental learning method.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             虽然强调了氛围编程，但汪滔整体核心是想表达出一种实践性、实验性的学习方法。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Vibe Coding does not rely on formal courses or tutorials, but rather encourages young people to use AI programming tools to build, test, and break things. It's a process of learning by doing—prompting AI models, analyzing their responses, iterating code, and gradually understanding how these systems 'think' and perform tasks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            氛围编程不依赖于正式课程或教程，而是鼓励年轻人借助 AI 编程工具来构建、测试和打破事物。这是一个通过实践学习的过程——提示 AI 模型、分析其响应、迭代代码，并逐渐理解这些系统如何「思考」和执行任务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 正式发布 GPT-5.1</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-正式发布-GPT-5.1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, OpenAI officially released the GPT-5.1 model, and for the first time allowed users to meticulously 'tune' the model's chat style.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，OpenAI 正式发布了 GPT-5.1 模型，并且首次允许用户细致地「调教」模型的聊天风格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Two versions of GPT-5.1 were released this time: GPT-5.1 Instant and GPT-5.1 Thinking:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次 GPT-5.1 共发布了两个版本，分别为 GPT-5.1 Instant 和 GPT-5.1 Thinking：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            GPT-5.1 Instant:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GPT-5.1 Instant：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More obedient: It can now more reliably follow user instructions and accurately answer the specific question we truly want to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptive Reasoning: This is the first time this feature has been introduced in the Instant model. This means that when it encounters difficult problems, it will intelligently decide to think first, thereby providing more thorough and accurate answers; while for simple problems, it still maintains an extremely fast response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            GPT-5.1 Thinking:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GPT-5.1 Thinking：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Improved Efficiency: It can now more precisely allocate thinking time, spending more time on complex problems (more thorough answers) and responding faster to simple problems (shorter waiting times).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easier to Understand: Its answers are now clearer, using fewer industry terms and undefined vocabulary. This allows us to effortlessly understand it when using it for complex tasks or explaining technical concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equally Warm: The Thinking model's default tone has also become warmer and more empathetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/16a26a04-6bc3-4daf-b8ba-44740377d60c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The focus of this update is ChatGPT's personalized experience.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             OpenAI's goal is to allow users to effortlessly adjust ChatGPT's tone and style to the most comfortable state.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Building upon the existing default, friendly, and efficient options, three new official styles have been added:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而本次更新重点，即 ChatGPT 的个性化体验。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             OpenAI 的目标是，是让用户毫不费力地将 ChatGPT 的语气和风格，调整到最舒服的状态。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            在原有的默认、友好、高效基础上，新增了三种官方风格：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional: Suitable for formal occasions such as work and writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Candid: More direct, no beating around the bush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quirky: As the name suggests, it will become more interesting and unconventional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to these direct choices and a richer set of basic styles and tones, OpenAI is experimenting with a new feature that allows users to fine-tune ChatGPT's characteristics directly from the settings.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除了这种直接选择，更丰富的基本风格和语调，OpenAI 正在实验一项新功能，允许用户直接从设置中微调 ChatGPT 的特征。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, the GPT-5.1 model's System Card introduces OpenAI's in-depth considerations in this regard. For the first time, OpenAI has added two new, more human-centric dimensions to the model's safety evaluation: Mental Health and Emotional Reliance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，在 GPT-5.1 的模型介绍 System Card 里，介绍了 OpenAI 在这方面的深入考量。OpenAI 首次在模型的安全评估中，加入了两个全新的、更人性化的维度：心理健康（Mental Health）和情感依赖（Emotional Reliance）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starting from November 12, paid users (Pro, Plus, Go, Business) will gradually receive GPT-5.1; free and unregistered users will follow after the paid user rollout is complete; enterprise and education users will have a 7-day early bird toggle switch (off by default), after which they will all be upgraded to GPT-5.1.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 12 日开始，付费用户（Pro, Plus, Go, Business）将逐步推送 GPT-5.1；免费和未登录用户则将在付费用户推送完毕后跟进；企业和教育版用户拥有 7 天的早鸟期切换开关（默认关闭），之后将统一升级到 GPT-5.1。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steam 主机官宣，明年开售</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Steam-主机官宣，明年开售</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/53e81915-d671-4ffc-b7f4-2115bf07e85c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Early this morning, Steam officially announced its console product, Steam Machine, which
            &lt;strong&gt;
             boasts &quot;6 times the performance of Steam Deck&quot; and will go on sale in 2026.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天凌晨，Steam 正式公布旗下主机产品 Steam Machine，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             拥有「Steam Deck 的 6 倍性能」，将于 2026 年开售。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The machine features a cuboid design, with a replaceable front cover (magnetic attachment), and also includes an indicator light strip that supports displaying download progress and other content. The front has 2 USB-A 3.2 Gen 1 ports and 1 microSD card slot, while the back has USB-A 2.0, USB-C 3.2 Gen 2, DP 1.4, HDMI 2.0, and Gigabit Ethernet.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            机器外观采用正方体设计，正面盖板支持更换（磁吸式），同时具备提示灯带，支持显示下载进度等内容。正面拥有 2 枚 USB-A 3.2 Gen 1 接口以及 1 枚 microSD 卡槽，背部拥有 USB-A 2.0、USB-C 3.2 Gen 2、DP 1.4、HDMI 2.0、千兆以太网。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of performance, the Steam Machine is equipped with a semi-custom AMD Zen 4 6c / 12T (up to 4.8GHz, 30W TDP) and 28 semi-custom AMD RDNA3 CUs (2.45GHz maximum sustained frequency, 110W TDP), featuring 16GB DDR5 + 8GB GDDR6 VRAM, and offering 512GB and 2TB NVMe SSD models.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            性能方面，Steam Machine 搭载半定制的 AMD Zen 4 6c / 12T（最高可达 4.8GHz、30W TDP）和 28 个半定制 AMD RDNA3 CU（2.45GHz 最高持续频率，110W TDP），配备 16GB DDR5 + 8GB GDDR6 VRAM，提供 512GB 和 2TB 两种型号 NVMe SSD。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Other features include 2x2 Wi-Fi 6E support, a dedicated Bluetooth 5.3 antenna, and an integrated 2.4GHz Steam Controller wireless adapter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其他方面，Steam Machine 支持 2×2 Wi-Fi 6E，拥有蓝牙 5.3 专用天线，集成 2.4GHz Steam Controller 无线适配器。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that while the Steam Machine runs SteamOS, it can also function as a PC.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，Steam Machine 虽运行 SteamOS，但同时也能作为一台 PC。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insta360 发布 Ace Pro 2 影像大师套餐</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Insta360-发布-Ace-Pro-2-影像大师套餐</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2259566f-53ba-49d2-8d17-8c040a6767a2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Insta360 released the Ace Pro 2 Imaging Master Kit and peripheral accessories:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，影石 Insta360 发布了 Ace Pro 2 影像大师套装及周边配件：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professional Street Shooting Handle: A new integrated endurance street shooting handle that supports direct connection to Ace Pro 2, allowing 1-2x lossless zoom via the handle's slide zoom, and has a built-in 2010mAh battery;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pocket Printer: Designed specifically for Ace Pro 2, it can connect directly to the camera via Bluetooth and print 3-inch photos;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple External Lenses: Cinematic Widescreen Lens (supports direct shooting in classic 2.35:1 widescreen aspect ratio) / Adjustable Macro Lens (supports 10-75cm adjustable focal length) / Ultra-wide-angle Lens (diagonal FOV up to 189°) / Black Mist Filter / Star Filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A total of three bundle versions were launched: Play &amp;amp; Shoot Bundle (includes handle, printer,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             priced at 4098 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ) / Imaging Master Set Limited Edition (includes handle, screen hood, cinematic widescreen lens/black mist filter,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             priced at 4198 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ) / Imaging Master Set All-in-one Edition (
            &lt;strong&gt;
             priced at 5498 yuan
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次共推出三个套装版本：玩拍套装（含手柄、打印机，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             售价 4098 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ）/影像大师套装限定版（含手柄、屏幕遮光罩、电影宽屏镜头/黑柔镜头，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             售价 4198 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ）/影像大师套餐全能版（
            &lt;strong&gt;
             售价 5498 元
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>荣耀 500 外观亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">荣耀-500-外观亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f26d31e9-26b5-45d9-80e8-fed6b15d6310.jpeg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, blogger &quot;Digital Chat Station&quot; released real photos of the Honor 500 Super Standard Edition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，博主「数码闲聊站」公布了荣耀 500 超级标准版的真机图。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The released information shows that the Honor 500 Super Standard Edition will feature a metal right-angle frame + front and rear flat panel design, with an integrated cold-carved glass back cover, a large R-angle screen, and a through-type horizontal arrangement for the rear camera module.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公布的信息显示，荣耀 500 超级标准版将采用金属直角中框+前后直板的设计，后盖采用一体冷雕玻璃设计，屏幕采用大 R 角，后置摄像头模组采用贯穿式横向摆放。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new phone will be equipped with a dual-camera setup, but the real photos suggest there might be another lens above the flash. Below the power button, there's a physical AI button, identical to the Honor Magic 8 series. Additionally, the new phone will use the Qualcomm Snapdragon 8s Gen4 processor.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新机将配备双摄组合，但从真机图显示，闪光灯上方疑似还有一枚镜头。电源键下方配备与荣耀 Magic 8 系列同款的 AI 实体按键。另外，新机将采用高通骁龙 8s Gen4 处理器。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Honor 500 series will also offer a Super Pro version.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            荣耀 500 系列还将提供超级 Pro 版。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小红书内测发文件功能</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小红书内测发文件功能</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e4e1bd8f-b483-4d86-82bb-bbaef2fc5891.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sina Technology,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Xiaohongshu is internally testing a &quot;file sharing&quot; feature, allowing users to directly attach documents to notes and support one-click preview and download.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪科技报道，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             小红书正在内测「发文件」功能，用户可在笔记中直接挂文档，并支持一键预览下载。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that a note can support uploading a maximum of one file not exceeding 100MB, and currently supports doc, docx, pdf, ppt, and pptx formats.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，一篇笔记最多支持上传一个不超过 100MB 的文件，目前支持 doc、docx、pdf、ppt、pptx 格式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaohongshu's official customer service confirmed this, stating, &quot;This feature is currently in internal testing and is only visible to some users in mainland China.&quot; They also noted, &quot;Currently, foldable screens do not support this feature, and the platform is gradually improving related functionalities.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对此小红书官方客服予以确认，并表示，「该功能目前内测中，目前仅支持大陆部分用户可见。」并提示，「目前折叠屏还不支持这一功能，平台在逐步完善相关功能。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the reason for internally testing the &quot;file sharing&quot; feature, Xiaohongshu customer service explained that it aims to enhance user experience, meet user needs, and strengthen the platform's community attributes. When asked if the feature would be commercialized in the future, the representative stated, &quot;There are no relevant plans yet.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对于内测「发文件」功能的原因，小红书客服解释称，此举旨在提升用户体验，满足用户的需求，强化平台的社区属性。当被问及该功能未来是否会进行商业化，对方表示，「还没有相关计划。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPPO Reno 15 多个实况玩法公布</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OPPO-Reno-15-多个实况玩法公布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a85e72f7-e809-43fa-a12e-59b2c094e89a.gif&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, OPPO officially announced the live photo shooting capabilities of the Reno 15 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨日，OPPO 官方公布了 Reno 15 系列的实况照片拍摄能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is revealed that the new phone supports five major live features: 'Out-of-the-box Live Puzzle', '0.6x Ultra-wide Angle Front Live Selfie', '4K Live Multi-shot', 'Front and Rear Simultaneous Live Shooting', and 'CCD Flash Live'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据透露，新机支持「出圈实况拼图」「前置 0.6 倍超广角实况自拍」「4K 实况一拍多出」「前后同拍实况」「CCD 闪光实况」五大实况功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new phone is also equipped with a 200-megapixel main camera lens and an 85mm telephoto lens; it offers four color options: 'Starlight Bow', 'Aurora Blue', 'Cannelé Brown', and 'Honey Gold'; the screen adopts an ultra-narrow four-equal-side straight screen (bezel is 1.15mm).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新机还配备 2 亿像素主摄镜头和 85mm 长焦；提供「星光蝴蝶结」「极光蓝」「可露丽棕」「蜜糖金」四种配色；屏幕采用极窄四等边直屏（边框为 1.15mm）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The OPPO Reno 15 series will be officially released on November 17.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OPPO Reno 15 系列将于 11 月 17 日正式发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>奔驰新款 GLB 内饰曝光：提供类星空顶版本</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">奔驰新款-GLB-内饰曝光：提供类星空顶版本</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/91130d9f-54e5-44b3-9dc7-8f61e0286625.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a recent report by motor1, Mercedes-Benz recently announced interior information for its new generation GLB model.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 motor1 日前报道，梅赛德斯-奔驰近期公布了旗下新一代 GLB 车型的内饰信息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            From the released information, the new car's cabin intelligence and lighting effects are quite striking:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公布的信息来看，新车在座舱智能化以及灯光效果较为亮眼：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The center console adopts a triple-screen design with two large screens and one small screen, where the passenger screen size will be consistent with the center screen size; it is worth noting that the triple-screen is an optional configuration and not provided in the standard version;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The center console retains some physical buttons and uses manual air conditioning vents;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The panoramic roof offers a starlight-like design, with the specific pattern being the Mercedes-Benz three-pointed star LOGO shape; at the same time, the panoramic roof provides a dimmable system; however, like the triple screen, this panoramic roof is an optional configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new generation GLB will offer two versions, seven-seater and five-seater, with the second row of the seven-seater version supporting front and rear sliding. The new car is expected to offer two versions: pure electric and mild hybrid:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新一代 GLB 将提供七座和五座两个版本，其中七座版本二排支持前后滑动。新车预计提供纯电及轻混两个版本：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pure electric: offers rear-wheel drive single motor and 4Matic dual motors;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mild hybrid: equipped with a 1.5T four-cylinder engine + eight-speed dual-clutch automatic transmission, offering front-wheel drive and full-time four-wheel drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new car will be officially released on December 8.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新车将于 12 月 8 日正式发布。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>乐高 ✕《塞尔达传说》将于 2026 年推出</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">乐高-✕《塞尔达传说》将于-2026-年推出</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/da568602-daaf-4edf-916d-ab3fdb0897a7.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, LEGO officially announced that its new set with 'The Legend of Zelda' will be launched in 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，乐高官方正式宣布，其与《塞尔达传说》的新版套装将于 2026 年推出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The released trailer shows Link facing the villain Ganon, while Princess Zelda can also be seen in the background. The official announcement did not reveal more other content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从公布的预告片显示，林克将面对反派吉农，同时背景中也可看到塞尔达公主。官方并未公布更多其他内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, LEGO had released a 'Great Deku Tree' version set with 'The Legend of Zelda'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，乐高曾与《塞尔达传说》推出过「德库树」版本套装。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>星巴克被吐槽爆改成县城奶茶店</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">星巴克被吐槽爆改成县城奶茶店</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/79a0f1f4-c31a-4285-9a16-b87ec3d02055.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the topic 'Starbucks criticized for being renovated into a county town milk tea shop' trended on hot searches.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，「星巴克被吐槽爆改成县城奶茶店」相关话题登上热搜。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Many netizens posted that Starbucks' recent store playlist has become a 'great broadcast of nostalgic golden oldies', finding the song selection 'too old-fashioned' and 'too noisy', with some even complaining it 'feels like a hypermarket'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            有多位网友发文表示，星巴克近期门店歌单变成了「怀旧金曲大放送」，认为歌单选曲「太土」「太吵」，甚至有网友吐槽「像大卖场」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a search by iFanr, Starbucks China announced on November 11 that it recently launched a 'Millennium Classics' playlist. Additionally, according to Vista Kan Tianxia citing Starbucks customer service personnel, the theme for this holiday season is 'Millennium Joy', and stores will play the millennium playlist to enhance the experience. Netizen complaints will be recorded and feedback provided.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据爱范儿查询发现，星巴克中国于 11 月 11 日发文宣布，近期开启「千禧年代经典」歌单。另据 Vista 看天下援引星巴克客服人员消息，本次节日档期的主题是「千禧的快乐」，门店是为了增强体验，会播放千禧歌单，对于网友的吐槽会记录并反馈。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starbucks China responded to this: 'From November 4th to November 17th, every day from 1-3 PM and 5-7 PM, Starbucks stores nationwide are playing the 'Millennium Golden Oldies' limited playlist on time, including many popular Chinese songs.' 'We hope to relive and share beautiful memories from the millennium with our customers through classic music.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而星巴克中国对此回应：「11 月 4 日-11 月 17 日，每天下午 1-3 点及 5-7 点，全国星巴克门店正准时播放」千禧金曲「限定歌单，包括众多脍炙人口的中文歌曲。」「我们希望借由经典的音乐，与顾客一同重温分享千禧年以来的美好回忆。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>山姆回应极速达小票不显示商品价格</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">山姆回应极速达小票不显示商品价格</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiupai News, some netizens recently complained that Sam's Club shopping receipts no longer show the specific price of each item after an update.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据九派新闻报道，近日有网友吐槽山姆购物小票更新后未显示每件商品具体价格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the aforementioned game, Sam's Club responded through reports, stating, &quot;Sam's Club highly values member information protection and shopping experience. We recently updated the Express Delivery receipts to further strengthen the protection of member information.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对上述游戏，山姆方面通过报道回应表示，「山姆高度重视会员信息保护与购物体验。我们近期对极速达小票进行了更新，进一步强化了对会员信息的保护。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sam's Club, the information displayed on the receipt is intended to help quickly and conveniently verify items and quantities during pickup and delivery.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据山姆方面介绍，该单据显示的信息旨在帮助取货与收货时更快速、方便地核对商品和数量。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The product and price details of Express Delivery orders are fully displayed in the member's own App order details and can be saved long-term, making it convenient for members to check at any time. In-store offline shopping receipts still retain complete price details.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            极速达订单的商品与价格明细在会员自己的 App 订单详情内均有完整展示，并可以长期保存，方便会员随时核对。门店线下购物小票依然保留完整的价格明细。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response, lawyer Chen Liang, director of Hubei Haolv Law Firm, stated that consumers have the right to know the true situation of the goods they purchase or use, or the services they receive, and have the right to require operators to indicate information such as the product name, price, and unit of measurement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对此，湖北好律律师事务所主任陈亮律师表示，消费者享有知悉其购买、使用的商品或者接受的服务的真实情况的权利，有权要求经营者标明商品的品名、价格和计价单位等信息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The unit price, quantity, and total price of individual items on the Express Delivery order receipt are core transaction information. As long as personal sensitive information such as member's name and full mobile number are processed, personal privacy will not be leaked.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而极速达订单小票上的商品单商品单价、数量、总价等属于交易核心信息，只要对会员姓名、完整手机号等个人敏感信息进行处理，并不会泄露个人隐私。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>电影《8 号出口》官宣引进</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">电影《8-号出口》官宣引进</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e582139f-d4e9-4b24-8cf6-a49698bd93fb.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the film 'Exit 8' announced its upcoming release in mainland China, with the release date yet to be determined.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，电影《8 号出口》宣布将引进中国内地，档期待定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, 'Exit 8' is a thriller directed by Genki Kawamura, with Kentaro Hirase and Genki Kawamura as screenwriters, starring Kazunari Ninomiya, and is set to be released in Japan on August 29, 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，《8 号出口》是川村元气执导，平濑谦太朗、川村元气担任编剧，二宫和也主演的惊悚片，于 2025 年 8 月 29 日在日本上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is adapted from the game of the same name developed by KOTAKE CREATE, telling the story of a man trapped in an infinitely looping underground passage who seeks a way to escape.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片改编自 KOTAKE CREATE 开发的同名游戏，讲述了被困在无限循环的地下通道的男人探寻离开此处的方法的故事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>匠妹将出演《爱丽丝梦游仙境》改编版真人电影</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">匠妹将出演《爱丽丝梦游仙境》改编版真人电影</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c65b79d8-6c6d-4394-825f-f7e064fcdebd.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Hollywood Reporter, pop singer 'Artisan Girl' Sabrina Carpenter will star in a live-action musical film based on 'Alice in Wonderland.' The title has not yet been announced, and the film is being shot by Universal Pictures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《好莱坞报道》消息，流行女歌手「匠妹」塞布丽娜·卡彭特（Sabrina Carpenter）将主演一部基于《爱丽丝梦游仙境》改编的真人版音乐电影，目前片名暂未公布，影片由环球影院拍摄。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that Carpenter will also serve as a producer for the film. It is reported that Lorene Scafaria will direct and write the film. Marc Platt, producer of the film version of 'Wicked,' and two producers from the renowned production company Alloy Entertainment will also co-produce.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，匠妹还将担任该片的制片人。据悉，该片由洛琳·斯卡法莉娅（Lorene Scafaria）担任导演、编剧。影版《魔法坏女巫》的制作人马克·普拉特（Marc Platt）和来自知名制作公司 Alloy Entertainment 的两名制作人也将共同担任制片人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report states that this is a passion project for Carpenter. About a year ago, she approached the studio with specific ideas and a lookbook. As the concept was continuously refined, producers and director Lorene also joined in.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道称，这对于匠妹来说是一项倾注心血的计划，她在大约一年前就带着具体的想法和一本造型图册与工作室洽谈，随着概念的不断完善，制片人以及导演洛琳也加入进来。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《玩具总动员 5》发布先导预告</title>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《玩具总动员-5》发布先导预告</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.12_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/51c93577-9772-45dc-91e1-d9e4bcedd88c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sina Movies, 'Toy Story 5' recently released a teaser trailer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪电影消息，《玩具总动员 5》日前发布先导预告。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the film will tell the story of Woody, Buzz Lightyear, and other toys facing electronic products that children are now addicted to. Additionally, 50 malfunctioning Buzz Lightyears form a villain army.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，影片将讲述胡迪、巴斯光年等玩具要面对如今让小朋友沉迷的电子产品，此外 50 个故障的巴斯光年组成了反派军团。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, and Joan Cusack return to voice characters, with Anna Faris and Ernie Hudson newly joining. Conan O'Brien voices a wacky training toy named Smarty Pants, and Greta Lee voices a frog-shaped high-tech tablet named Lilypad. It will be released in North America on June 19 next year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            汤姆·汉克斯、蒂姆·艾伦、琼·库萨克回归配音，安娜·法瑞斯、厄尼·哈德森新加盟，柯南·奥布莱恩配音一个疯疯癫癫的训练用玩具 Smarty Pants，格蕾塔·李配音青蛙形状的高科技平板 Lilypad，明年 6 月 19 日北美上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifanr.com/tags/%e6%97%a9%e6%8a%a5&quot;&gt;
            早报
           &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
