<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>卢伟冰点评 Air 手机，华为、荣耀或将加入</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">卢伟冰点评-Air-手机，华为、荣耀或将加入</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1f0987bb-561e-4981-a965-f1469f7b0841.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Ultra-thin phones&quot; have sparked widespread discussion with the release of the iPhone Air, and now there are reports that Huawei and Honor will also enter this field.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            「超薄手机」随着 iPhone Air 的发布引起了广泛讨论，而目前有消息指出，华为与荣耀也将加入这一领域。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, a Xiaohongshu blogger exposed the real Huawei Mate70 Air device, and more details were revealed: the device continues the family design, adopts a wide-ratio equal-depth quad-curved screen, and its body thickness is only 6.x mm, earning it the title of &quot;thinnest Mate ever.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，小红书博主曝光了华为 Mate70 Air 真机，更多细节也被披露：该机延续家族式设计，采用宽比例等深四曲屏，机身厚度仅 6.x mm，被称为「史上最薄 Mate」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to previous reports, the new device is expected to be equipped with the Kirin 9020 chip, with up to 16GB of RAM, and may also support both SIM card and eSIM technologies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据此前报道，新机预计搭载麒麟 9020 芯片，最高配备 16GB 内存，同时可能兼顾 SIM 卡与 eSIM 技术。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Honor R&amp;amp;D engineer @HonorCaoGong responded to user demand for ultra-thin phones on Weibo yesterday, stating directly: &quot;It will happen.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，荣耀研发工程师@荣耀曹工昨天在微博回应了用户对于超薄手机的需求，并直言：「会有的」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Xiaomi Group President Lu Weibing commented on Weibo yesterday that the Air series is &quot;a very bold and innovative attempt&quot; in design, but extreme thinness and lightness inevitably sacrifice experiences such as battery life, heat dissipation, and performance, and market acceptance remains to be seen.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，小米集团总裁卢伟冰昨天在微博上评价称，Air 系列在设计上「是非常大胆的创新尝试」，但极致轻薄不可避免地牺牲了续航、散热和性能等体验，市场接受度仍待观察。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>余承东：鸿蒙生态将实现「三分天下有其一」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">余承东：鸿蒙生态将实现「三分天下有其一」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/d02ea9b1-a3cf-40f0-a745-eaa78f7f4203.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to NetEase Tech, Richard Yu, Chairman of Huawei Consumer BG, recently revealed in an internal letter that the number of devices equipped with HarmonyOS 5 has exceeded 23 million, marking HarmonyOS ecosystem's entry into a healthy development phase.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据网易科技报道，华为终端 BG 董事长余承东近日在一封内部信中透露，搭载鸿蒙 5 的终端设备数量已突破 2300 万，标志着鸿蒙生态进入良性发展阶段。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The letter pointed out that within 24 hours of the HarmonyOS 6 system's release, the upgrade volume reached 3 million, setting a historical record, with new features such as AI one-click video creation and family fraud prevention receiving positive market feedback.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            信中指出，鸿蒙 6 系统发布后 24 小时内升级量达到 300 万，创下历史纪录，其中 AI 一键成片、亲情防诈等新功能获得市场积极反馈。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the letter, Richard Yu called on employees to actively experience HarmonyOS 6 to promote system optimization. He emphasized that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Huawei's next goal is to achieve 40 million to 60 million user coverage in the short term, eventually reaching hundreds of millions, striving to &quot;occupy one-third of the operating system market&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            余承东在信中呼吁员工积极体验鸿蒙 6，以推动系统优化。他强调，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             华为下一步目标是在短期内实现 4000 万至 6000 万用户覆盖，最终达到上亿规模，力争在操作系统市场「三分天下有其一」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The letter also mentioned that Huawei will continue to focus on consumer experience and developer ecosystem construction, and proposed an ecological cultural orientation of &quot;openness and altruism, experience first, and long-termism,&quot; aiming to accelerate the growth of the HarmonyOS ecosystem through continuous optimization and cooperation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            信中还提到，华为将继续聚焦消费者体验与开发者生态建设，并提出「开放利他、体验至上、长期主义」的生态文化导向，旨在通过持续优化和合作推动鸿蒙生态加速成长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>星巴克与博裕成立合资企业，估值超 130 亿美元</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">星巴克与博裕成立合资企业，估值超-130-亿美元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5835d0ab-c608-431f-b3a9-29e4413dbc00.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Today, Starbucks announced a strategic partnership with Boyu Capital, a Chinese alternative asset management company. The two parties will form a joint venture to jointly operate Starbucks' retail business in the Chinese market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今天，星巴克宣布，与中国另类资产管理公司博裕投资达成战略合作，双方将成立合资企业，共同运营星巴克在中国市场的零售业务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Under the agreement, Boyu will hold up to 60% equity in the joint venture, while Starbucks will retain 40% equity and continue to be the owner and licensor of the brand and intellectual property. The transaction is based on an enterprise value of approximately $4 billion (excluding cash and debt), and Boyu will acquire corresponding interests.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据协议，博裕将持有合资企业至多 60% 股权，星巴克保留 40% 股权，并继续作为品牌与知识产权的所有者和授权方。交易基于约 40 亿美元（不计现金与债务）的企业价值，博裕将获得相应权益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Starbucks expects the overall value of its China retail business to exceed $13 billion, covering three parts: proceeds from the sale of a controlling interest to Boyu, the value of the interest retained in the joint venture, and brand licensing revenue continuously paid over the next ten years or more.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星巴克预计，其中国零售业务的整体价值将超过 130 亿美元，涵盖三部分：向博裕出让控股权益所得、在合资企业中保留的权益价值，以及未来十年或更长时间内持续支付的品牌授权收益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The newly established joint venture will be headquartered in Shanghai and will be responsible for managing the current 8,000 stores across the Chinese market, with plans to gradually expand to 20,000 stores in the future. Starbucks Chairman and CEO Laxman Narasimhan stated: &quot;Boyu's experience and expertise in the local market will accelerate Starbucks' expansion into smaller cities and emerging regions.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新成立的合资企业将以上海为总部，负责管理目前遍布中国市场的 8000 家门店，并计划未来逐步扩展至 20000 家。星巴克董事长兼首席执行官倪睿安表示：「博裕在本地市场的经验与专长，将加速星巴克在中小城市及新兴区域的拓展。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Huang Yuzheng, Partner at Boyu Capital, pointed out: &quot;Starbucks has established a high-end brand image in China, and we see huge opportunities for further localization and innovation.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            博裕投资合伙人黄宇铮指出：「星巴克在中国已建立高端品牌形象，我们看到了进一步本土化和创新的巨大机遇。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Liu Wenjuan, CEO of Starbucks China, added: &quot;This cooperation will unleash greater market potential and create more value for customers and partners.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            星巴克中国 CEO 刘文娟补充称：「此次合作将释放更大市场潜力，为顾客和伙伴创造更多价值。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>广州地铁回应「摇一摇」广告争议：已立即关闭</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">广州地铁回应「摇一摇」广告争议：已立即关闭</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/29022543-eb67-4231-b5a2-77461c693956.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Paper, the &quot;shake-to-open&quot; advertisement on the Guangzhou Metro App's ride code page has attracted attention due to its impact on the QR code scanning function for boarding. Recently, many netizens reported on social platforms that this advertisement frequently popped up during morning and evening rush hours, seriously interfering with gate-passing efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据澎湃新闻报道，广州地铁 App 乘车码页面「摇一摇」广告因影响扫码乘车功能引发关注。近日，多名网友在社交平台反映，该广告在早晚高峰时段频繁弹出，严重干扰过闸效率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, when reporters reopened the Guangzhou Metro App, they found that the &quot;shake-to-open&quot; advertisement was no longer on the ride code page. Guangzhou Metro responded by saying that it would continue to listen to passenger opinions, optimize user experience, and ensure that the ride function is not interfered with by advertisements.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，记者再次打开广州地铁 App 时发现，乘车码页面已无「摇一摇」广告。广州地铁方面则回应表示，将持续听取乘客意见，优化用户体验，确保乘车功能不受广告干扰。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Guangzhou Metro customer service had responded that &quot;not everyone dislikes advertisements,&quot; suggesting that users with concerns provide individual feedback. However, Guangzhou Haizhu District Market Supervision Administration pointed out that if the advertisement is true or suspected of violating regulations, it will be investigated and dealt with in accordance with the &quot;Advertising Law,&quot; and violators may face fines of 5,000 to 30,000 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，广州地铁客服曾回应称「并非所有人都不喜欢广告」，建议有困扰的用户单独反馈。但广州市海珠区市场监督管理局指出，若广告属实或涉嫌违规，将依据《广告法》进行查处，违规者或面临 5000 元至 3 万元罚款。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>特斯拉人形机器人最新进展曝光</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">特斯拉人形机器人最新进展曝光</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1c456a64-8ef1-45cb-b9ca-c41dc2d7439f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Tesla is collecting training data through a large number of human actions in its glass lab at its engineering headquarters to help the humanoid robot Optimus learn to imitate human behavior.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，特斯拉正在其工程总部的玻璃实验室中，通过大量人工动作采集训练数据，以帮助人形机器人擎天柱（Optimus）学习模仿人类行为。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that dozens of staff members repeatedly perform daily actions such as &quot;wiping tables,&quot; &quot;opening curtains,&quot; and &quot;holding cups&quot; hundreds of times a day while wearing head-mounted cameras and heavy equipment. This data is used to optimize the robot's performance in scenarios such as factory operations, housework, and caregiving.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，数十名工作人员每天在头戴摄像头和背负重型设备的情况下，反复执行如「擦桌子」「开窗帘」「端杯子」等日常动作，每个动作需重复数百次。这些数据被用于优化机器人在工厂作业、家务和护理等场景中的表现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tesla CEO Elon Musk stated in the company's Q3 earnings call that Optimus &quot;has the potential to become the most important product in history,&quot; and predicted that annual production could reach 1 million units in the future, ultimately contributing about 80% of the company's value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            特斯拉 CEO Elon Musk 在公司三季度财报电话会议上表示，擎天柱「有潜力成为史上最重要的产品」，并预测未来年产量可达 100 万台，最终贡献公司约 80% 的价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report cited several current and former employees who said that the job was demanding and somewhat absurd, requiring staff to complete AI-generated action commands such as &quot;chicken dance,&quot; &quot;imitating gorillas,&quot; and &quot;pretending to vacuum&quot; in a short period. Some employees suffered back and neck injuries due to carrying equipment, and some experienced severe dizziness during remote control operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道援引多名现任及前任员工称，该岗位工作强度大且带有一定荒诞性，工作人员需在短时间内完成「鸡舞」「模仿大猩猩」「假装吸尘」等 AI 生成的动作指令。部分员工因背负设备导致背部和颈部受伤，亦有人在远程操控环节出现严重晕眩。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since June this year, Tesla has gradually abandoned motion capture suits and remote control, shifting to collecting data with multi-angle cameras and introducing haptic gloves to capture more refined hand movements. Experts point out that this method helps expand data coverage but also highlights the robot's shortcomings in balance and autonomy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自今年 6 月起，特斯拉逐步放弃动作捕捉服和远程操控，转向以多角度摄像头采集数据，并引入触觉手套以捕捉更精细的手部动作。专家指出，这种方法有助于扩大数据覆盖范围，但也凸显了机器人在平衡和自主性上的不足。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Optimus has publicly demonstrated functions such as folding clothes, performing kung fu moves, and distributing candy in Times Square. However, experts warn that these demonstrations are mostly &quot;best-case scenarios&quot; and do not represent the robot's true cognitive abilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，Optimus 已在公开场合展示过折叠衣物、表演功夫动作以及在纽约时报广场派发糖果等功能。但专家提醒，这些演示多为「最佳场景」，并不代表机器人已具备真正的认知能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 收入远超 130 亿美元，奥特曼预测 2027 年突破 1000 亿</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-收入远超-130-亿美元，奥特曼预测-2027-年突破-1000-亿</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/43858eb1-417c-44f9-98b4-8342cad6e307.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Fortune, OpenAI CEO Sam Altman stated in a recently aired Bg2 podcast that the company's annual revenue has &quot;far exceeded $13 billion&quot; and is expected to reach $100 billion by 2027.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《财富》报道，OpenAI CEO Sam Altman 在日前播出的 Bg2 播客中表示，公司年收入已「远超 130 亿美元」，并预计到 2027 年有望达到 1000 亿美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that OpenAI's revenue growth is &quot;rapidly rising&quot; and will rely on the continuous expansion of ChatGPT, AI cloud services, and consumer device businesses to drive future growth.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，OpenAI 的营收增长「正在快速上升」，并将依靠 ChatGPT 的持续扩张、AI 云服务以及消费级设备业务推动未来增长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman also responded to external doubts, stating that despite the company's continuous losses, it is supporting its expansion through large-scale infrastructure collaborations with companies such as Nvidia, Broadcom, and Oracle. He pointed out that OpenAI is betting on AI creating immense value in areas like scientific automation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Altman 同时回应外界质疑，称尽管公司持续亏损，但正在通过与英伟达、博通和甲骨文等企业达成大规模基础设施合作来支撑扩张。他指出，OpenAI 正在押注 AI 在科学自动化等领域创造巨大价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Microsoft CEO Satya Nadella also stated on the show that OpenAI's business execution &quot;exceeded all expectations&quot; and called its development speed astonishing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            微软 CEO Satya Nadella 也在节目中表示，OpenAI 的业务执行「超出所有预期」，并称其发展速度令人惊讶。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Microsoft's previous financial report showed that due to expenses related to its cooperation with OpenAI, the company recognized a $4 billion charge last quarter, implying OpenAI's loss for the quarter was approximately $12 billion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前微软财报显示，因与 OpenAI 合作产生的相关支出，公司在上季度确认了 40 亿美元的费用，暗示 OpenAI 当季亏损约 120 亿美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Altman also mentioned that if OpenAI goes public in the future, he &quot;hopes short sellers will suffer significant losses on the stock price.&quot; However, he also admitted that if computing power is insufficient, the company's revenue might not meet expectations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Altman 还提到，若 OpenAI 未来上市，他「希望做空投资者会在股价上遭遇重大损失」。不过他也承认，若计算能力不足，公司营收可能无法达到预期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, Amazon Web Services (AWS) also announced today a multi-year strategic partnership with OpenAI, totaling $38 billion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除此之外，亚马逊云服务（AWS）还在今天宣布，与 OpenAI 宣布达成一项为期多年的战略合作，总额达 380 亿美元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI will immediately run and expand its core AI workloads on AWS's global infrastructure, leveraging hundreds of thousands of NVIDIA GPUs and compute power scalable to tens of millions of CPUs, to meet demands ranging from ChatGPT inference to next-generation model training, with all deployments expected to be completed by the end of 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI 将立即在 AWS 的全球基础设施上运行并扩展其核心 AI 工作负载，借助数十万颗 NVIDIA GPU 和可扩展至数千万 CPU 的算力支持，以满足从 ChatGPT 推理到下一代模型训练的需求，所有部署预计在 2026 年底前完成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>威马汽车停工近两年后发声：称「好事将近」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">威马汽车停工近两年后发声：称「好事将近」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3f8d1483-f7b7-4b05-8390-a5034ba8ea4d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After nearly two years of production halt, WM Motor announced yesterday via its official Weibo and WeChat accounts that &quot;good things are coming, please stay tuned,&quot; accompanied by the caption &quot;What is thought of often will surely be answered.&quot; This move is interpreted by outsiders as a signal that the company is about to announce new strategies, new products, or restart operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            威马汽车在停工近两年后，于昨天通过官方微博和微信发布消息称「好事将近，敬请期待」，并配文「念念不忘，必有回响」。这一动态被外界解读为公司即将公布新战略、新产品或重启业务的信号。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            WM Motor was founded in 2015 and was once a representative enterprise among domestic new energy vehicle startups. Its first model, the WM EX5, launched in 2018, once won the championship for single-model deliveries among new forces.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            威马汽车成立于 2015 年，曾是国内造车新势力的代表企业。2018 年推出的首款车型威马 EX5 一度获得新势力单车交付量冠军。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, since 2023, affected by intensified market competition, tight capital chains, and fluctuating raw material prices, the company has fallen into serious difficulties, with factory shutdowns, payment arrears, and hindered after-sales service. Founder Shen Hui also left China in October of that year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            然而，自 2023 年起，受市场竞争加剧、资金链紧张及原材料价格波动等因素影响，公司陷入严重困境，工厂停产、资金拖欠、售后受阻，创始人沈晖也于当年 10 月离开中国。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In October 2023, the Shanghai No. 3 Intermediate People's Court accepted WM Motor's pre-restructuring application. In January 2024, the court officially initiated restructuring proceedings and confirmed that the company's liabilities exceeded 20 billion yuan, while its assets were less than 4 billion yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2023 年 10 月，上海市第三中级人民法院受理威马的预重整申请。2024 年 1 月，法院正式启动重整程序，并确认公司负债超过 200 亿元、资产不足 40 亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In April this year, the court approved the restructuring plan, with Shenzhen Xiangfei Automobile Sales Co., Ltd. taking over four WM Motor subsidiaries, promoting the resumption of mass production of WM EX5 and E.5 at the Wenzhou base, and achieving capacity recovery by August.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 4 月，法院批准重整计划，由深圳翔飞汽车销售有限公司接管威马旗下四家公司，推动威马 EX5 和 E.5 在温州基地恢复量产，并于 8 月实现产能恢复。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>连续四年调价，台积电 2026 年先进制程拟涨价 3%-10%</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">连续四年调价，台积电-2026-年先进制程拟涨价-3%-10%</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/fefa022a-9c38-4fd1-ba70-b8b6da1465ca.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Economic Daily, advanced process capacity continues to be in short supply, and TSMC has initiated annual price negotiations ahead of schedule.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《经济日报》报道，先进制程产能持续供不应求，台积电已提前启动年度议价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Industry sources indicate that TSMC has been communicating with customers since September regarding price increase plans for advanced processes in 2026, to cope with rising production costs. The increase will vary depending on the customer's procurement scale and cooperative relationship.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            业界消息显示，台积电自 9 月起陆续与客户沟通 2026 年先进制程涨价计划，以应对生产成本上升。涨幅将依客户采购规模与合作关系而异。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Research institutions and legal entities estimate that advanced process quotes for 2026 are expected to rise by 3% to 10%. While the overall increase is moderate, it is higher than this year. This marks TSMC's fourth consecutive year of price adjustments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            研究机构与法人预估，2026 年先进制程报价有望上涨 3% 至 10%，整体涨幅虽属温和，但已高于今年。这是台积电连续第四年调升报价。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding the market-focused 3-nanometer family processes, quotes are expected to increase by at least a single-digit percentage in 2026. TSMC did not comment on market rumors and reiterated that its &quot;pricing strategy is always strategy-driven, not opportunity-driven,&quot; emphasizing continued close cooperation with customers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在市场关注的 3 纳米家族制程方面，预计 2026 年报价至少上涨个位数百分比。台积电未对市场传闻发表评论，并重申「定价策略始终以策略导向，而非机会导向」，强调将持续与客户紧密合作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小红书上线「原画直出」功能，保持相册级画质</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小红书上线「原画直出」功能，保持相册级画质</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ff370970-1ad6-478e-92fc-35baa815cd41.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaohongshu's official account &quot;Original Painting Potato&quot; recently announced the &quot;Original Painting Direct Output&quot; feature, aiming to solve problems such as color distortion, blurry details, and HDR highlight loss that occur after users upload images.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小红书官方账号「原画薯」近日官宣「原画直出」功能，旨在解决用户上传图片后出现的颜色失真、细节模糊和 HDR 高光丢失等问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the introduction, this feature supports HDR photos and Live Photos, maintaining consistent colors and details with the album after upload, achieving a &quot;what you see is what you get&quot; display effect.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，该功能支持 HDR 照片与实况照片，可在上传后保持与相册一致的色彩与细节，实现「所见即所得」的展示效果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaohongshu also stated that this move is a response to creators' long-standing feedback regarding image quality loss, aiming to enhance the professionalism of platform content and user experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小红书方面还表示，此举是回应创作者长期以来关于画质损失的反馈，意在提升平台内容的专业性与用户体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RTX 3060 成 Steam 最受欢迎显卡，Windows 11 占比突破 63%</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">RTX-3060-成-Steam-最受欢迎显卡，Windows-11-占比突破-63%</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9023849f-7329-4ac7-a496-4a49aacc5520.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Valve announced the results of the October 2025 Steam Hardware &amp;amp; Software Survey.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，V 社（Valve）公布了 2025 年 10 月 Steam 软硬件调查结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding graphics cards:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            显卡方面：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
             NVIDIA GeForce RTX 3060 desktop graphics card jumped to the top with a 4.47% share, an increase of 0.06% from last month;
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
             英伟达 GeForce RTX 3060 桌面版显卡以 4.47% 的份额跃升至榜首，较上月增加 0.06%；
            &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previously top-ranked RTX 4060 Mobile dropped to second place, with a share of 4.30%, a decrease of 0.54% month-on-month;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RTX 4060 Desktop version ranked third, accounting for 4.17%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding operating systems, Windows 11's share continued to rise to 63.57%, an increase of 0.53% month-on-month, further widening the gap with Windows 10.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            操作系统方面，Windows 11 占比继续上升至 63.57%，环比增长 0.53%，与 Windows 10 的差距进一步扩大。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of memory configuration, 16 GB RAM remains mainstream, accounting for 41.49%. For monitor resolution, 1920×1080 resolution monitors are the most popular, accounting for 53.47%, an increase of 0.24% month-on-month; 2560×1440 resolution ranks second, accounting for 19.93%, a decrease of 0.59% month-on-month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            内存配置方面，16 GB RAM 依旧是主流，占比 41.49%。显示器分辨率方面，1920×1080 分辨率显示器最受欢迎，占比 53.47%，环比增长 0.24%；2560×1440 分辨率位居第二，占比 19.93%，环比下降 0.59%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the VR headset market, Meta Quest 3 continues to lead with a 26.48% share, a decrease of 0.20% month-on-month; Meta Quest 2 follows closely with a 25.25% share, a decrease of 0.92% month-on-month. Devices like Valve Index and Pico 4 maintain single-digit percentages.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在 VR 头显市场，Meta Quest 3 以 26.48% 的份额继续保持领先，环比下降 0.20%；Meta Quest 2 以 25.25% 的份额紧随其后，环比下降 0.92%。Valve Index、Pico 4 等设备则保持在个位数占比。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>微信鸿蒙版重大更新，新增群聊视频通话与聊天备份</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">微信鸿蒙版重大更新，新增群聊视频通话与聊天备份</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/89f61477-3f0e-4abb-aea7-5af4f749e7ac.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to China News Service, the HarmonyOS PC version of WeChat received a major version update yesterday, launching over 40 practical features at once and simultaneously fixing more than 40 bugs. This update focuses on chat management, video communication, file collaboration, and the mini-program ecosystem, significantly improving cross-device operational efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据中新网报道，鸿蒙电脑版微信昨日迎来重大版本更新，一次性上线超过 40 项实用功能，并同步修复 40 余项 BUG。此次更新重点聚焦聊天管理、视频通信、文件协作及小程序生态，显著提升跨端操作效率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding chat features, users can back up mobile WeChat chat history to HarmonyOS PCs to prevent loss of critical information; it also supports setting reminders for chat content, helping users better manage their schedules. File handling experience has also been improved, with unsent files and videos directly shareable or quotable, and Office documents quickly opened via the system's default program. The screenshot function adds an option to hide chat windows and optimizes hotkeys, reducing the risk of privacy leaks.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在聊天功能方面，用户可将手机微信聊天记录备份至鸿蒙电脑，避免关键信息丢失；同时支持对聊天内容设置提醒，帮助用户更好管理日程。文件处理体验亦有提升，未下载的文件和视频可直接转发或引用，Office 文档可通过系统默认程序快速打开。截图功能新增隐藏聊天窗口选项，并优化快捷键，降低隐私泄露风险。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Favorites content can be shared with one click, group chats now have video call functionality, supporting multi-person remote collaboration. The quote function has been extended to text, images, videos, and emojis, ensuring more efficient group discussions. Public account content forwarding, downloading, and commenting features have been enhanced, and mini-program operational stability has been significantly optimized, reducing delays and freezes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            收藏夹内容可一键分享，群聊新增视频通话功能，支持多人远程协作。引用功能扩展至文字、图片、视频及表情，确保群聊讨论更高效。公众号内容转发、下载及留言功能得到补足，小程序运行稳定性也大幅优化，减少延迟与卡顿。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this update achieves a high degree of functional consistency across HarmonyOS, macOS, and Windows, allowing users to download updates via AppGallery and unlock a smoother cross-platform experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，本次更新实现了 HarmonyOS、macOS 与 Windows 三端功能的高度一致，用户可通过 AppGallery 下载更新，解锁更流畅的跨平台体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the WeChat development ecosystem team officially released the new &quot;WeChat Developer Tools 2.0&quot; developer preview version at yesterday's &quot;WeChat Tech Open Class.&quot; The new tools feature significant improvements in kernel, interaction, and intelligence:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，微信开发生态团队还在昨天的「微信技术公开课」上正式发布全新「微信开发者工具 2.0」开发者预览版，新版工具在内核、交互和智能化方面均有显著改进：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7a33ed7b-f6b2-4b89-968b-3d95dead7e18.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interface and Interaction: The overall structure, editor, and simulator have been completely revamped, and the Toolbar redesigned, offering more spacious code area and an immersive development environment;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editor Kernel: The underlying architecture has been rebuilt to support more modern plugin extensions, enhancing coding fluidity and efficiency;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intelligent Programming Capabilities: Through an abstract service layer, AI can directly invoke tool component states. For example, when a mini-program encounters an error, AI can automatically retrieve debugging information and complete the fix;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Task Planning and Execution: Deep integration of &quot;Programming Assistant CodeBuddy&quot; supports intelligent development workflows from algorithm implementation to complete mini-program projects;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-program Adaptation: Built-in exclusive knowledge base, end-to-end process integration, and intelligent debugger integration further optimize the development experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the WeChat team has opened RC pre-release versions (≥ 2.01.2510241) and Nightly development versions (≥ 2.01.2510302) for developers to experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，微信团队已开放 RC 预发布版本（≥ 2.01.2510241）及 Nightly 开发版本（≥ 2.01.2510302）供开发者体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>高德加速出海：AutoSDK 国际版支持 19 种语言与本地化服务</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">高德加速出海：AutoSDK-国际版支持-19-种语言与本地化服务</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c3729f7b-27c4-4865-a2a4-d9011aef8549.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Amap officially released AutoSDK International, aiming to help Chinese car manufacturers build a unified and flexible in-car navigation solution in the global market through a &quot;Lego-style&quot; modular architecture.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，高德地图于正式发布 AutoSDK 国际版，旨在通过「乐高式」模块化架构帮助中国车企在全球市场构建统一且灵活的车载导航解决方案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the product integrates full-link capabilities such as positioning, search, map rendering, route planning, and basic navigation information, and supports core functions like offline navigation and ISA information broadcasting.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，该产品集成定位、搜索、地图渲染、路线规划、基础导航信息等全链路能力，并支持离线导航与 ISA 信息播报等核心功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Amap AutoSDK International currently covers over 170 countries and regions including Europe, Southeast Asia, the Middle East, South America, Australia and New Zealand, Central Asia, and Africa, supporting 19 mainstream languages such as English, Spanish, Portuguese, French, German, Thai, Arabic, and Turkish.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高德 AutoSDK 国际版目前已覆盖欧洲、东南亚、中东、南美、澳新、中亚、非洲等超过 170 个国家和地区，支持英语、西班牙语、葡萄牙语、法语、德语、泰语、阿拉伯语、土耳其语等 19 种主流语言。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of product design, AutoSDK International continues Amap's &quot;Lego-style&quot; modular concept from China, helping car manufacturers quickly develop professional navigation applications globally while meeting personalized customization needs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在产品设计上，AutoSDK 国际版延续了高德在国内的「乐高」式模块化理念，帮助车企在全球范围内快速开发专业导航应用，同时满足个性化定制需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Amap emphasized that this version can maintain a unified core product experience across different markets and enhance user experience through features such as multi-language rendering, multi-route planning, and large intersection map guidance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            高德强调，该版本能够在不同市场保持统一的核心产品体验，并通过多语种渲染、多路线规划和路口大图引导等功能提升用户体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of engineering support, Amap, relying on years of experience collaborating with domestic car manufacturers, has established partnerships with over 40 car factories and more than 100 brands, and is concurrently delivering over 200 projects.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在工程支持方面，高德依托多年与国内车企合作的经验，已与 40 余家车厂、100 余个品牌建立合作关系，并并行交付超过 200 个项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, Amap has established independent operating entities in the EU, Southeast Asia, and other regions, and built data centers in Germany, Singapore, and other locations to enhance its localized service capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，高德已在欧盟、东南亚等地设立独立运营主体，并在德国、新加坡等地建设数据中心，以提升本地化服务能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 美国数据分析巨头 CEO：大学教育「已崩坏」 公司直接招聘高中生</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-美国数据分析巨头-CEO：大学教育「已崩坏」-公司直接招聘高中生</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9e8bd637-1854-49ef-97f0-798262bbdcb2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to The Wall Street Journal, Palantir, a big data software and services company widely known for its U.S. government contracts, is attempting to break traditional educational paths by launching an experimental training program for high school graduates.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《华尔街日报》报道，因美国政府合同而广受关注的大数据软件与服务公司公司帕兰提尔（Palantir）正在尝试打破传统教育路径，启动一项面向高中毕业生的实验性研修项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The project's first cohort admitted 22 students, who can secure full-time job opportunities after completing the training without needing a university degree.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该项目首批录取 22 名学生，参与者无需大学学位即可在完成培训后获得全职工作机会。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Palantir CEO Alex Karp stated that American universities are 'neither reliable nor necessary' for cultivating excellent employees.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            帕兰提尔 CEO 亚历克斯·卡普表示，美国大学在培养优秀员工方面「既不可靠，也非必要」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He criticized the current higher education system for deviating from meritocracy and the pursuit of excellence. The company thus launched a program called the 'Merit Fellowship Program,' aiming to directly select potential talent from high school graduates.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他批评当前的高等教育体系已偏离优绩主义和卓越追求。公司因此推出名为「优绩研修项目」的计划，旨在直接从高中毕业生中选拔潜在人才。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The project lasts for 4 months, beginning with a 4-week seminar on Western Civilization, covering American history, culture, and leadership case studies. Fellows are then assigned to internal company teams, directly participating in real-world projects in industries such as healthcare, insurance, and defense.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该项目为期 4 个月，以一场为期 4 周的西方文明研讨会开篇，涵盖美国历史、文化与领导力案例研究。研修生随后被分配至公司内部团队，直接参与医疗、保险、国防等行业的实际项目。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Palantir executives stated that this process aims to test whether trainees can quickly adapt to high-intensity work environments.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            帕兰提尔高管称，这一过程旨在测试学员是否能快速适应高强度的工作环境。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some fellows chose to join Palantir while also receiving university admission offers, sparking controversy among families and educational advisors. Some students stated that despite their lack of experience, the company granted them unprecedented responsibility and autonomy. If they perform well, they will receive full-time positions after the project concludes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            部分研修生在获得大学录取通知的同时选择加入帕兰提尔，引发家庭和教育顾问的争议。一些学生表示，尽管缺乏经验，但公司给予了他们前所未有的责任与自主权。若表现优异，他们将在项目结束后获得全职职位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7499 元，越疆发布全球首款家庭智能体 Rover X1</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7499-元，越疆发布全球首款家庭智能体-Rover-X1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6de19cbd-8665-45c5-bee1-2e4a75541ed9.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Youjiang Robotics officially released Rover X1, the world's first household intelligent robot dog, positioned as a 'practical intelligent agent' for the consumer market. It aims to break the previous polarization in the robot dog market between expensive industrial equipment and low-function electronic pets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，越疆机器人正式发布全球首款家庭智能体机器狗 Rover X1，定位消费级市场的「实用智能体」，旨在突破此前机器狗市场在高价工业设备与低功能电子宠物之间的两极分化局面。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dual vision tracking system: achieves omnidirectional perception and autonomous decision-making, enhancing mobility in complex home environments;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All-terrain wheel-leg structure and intelligent load-bearing capacity: capable of stable movement across various terrains such as floors, grass, and small inclines, and possesses the ability to carry daily items;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-developed open platform: supports multi-role switching, covering diverse applications such as outdoor exploration, home security, programming education, and emotional companionship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of application scenarios, Rover X1 can not only serve outdoor adventures as a 'mobile photographer' and 'load-bearing companion' but also undertake home security tasks such as night patrol and detection of unfamiliar areas.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在应用场景方面，Rover X1 不仅能作为「移动跟拍师」和「负重伙伴」服务户外探险，还可承担夜间巡逻、陌生区域侦测等家庭安防任务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, its open system supports graphical and code programming, making it suitable for educational use. At the emotional companionship level, Rover X1 can perform tasks such as backpack escort and clothing delivery, and enhance family interaction experience through voice interaction and light expressions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，其开放系统支持图形化与代码编程，适合教育场景使用。在情感陪伴层面，Rover X1 能完成书包护送、衣物递送等任务，并通过语音互动与灯光表情增强家庭互动体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Youjiang Rover X1 is available for purchase on the official store, priced at 7499 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，越疆 Rover X1 已在官方商城开放购买，售价 7499 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rokid 携手 BOLON 推出 AI 智能眼镜</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Rokid-携手-BOLON-推出-AI-智能眼镜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/37906373-5bfc-4a4a-b9dc-e32430a05058.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Rokid published an article on its official WeChat public account, announcing that it will jointly hold a new product launch event with BOLON Eyewear on November 13th in Zhejiang, themed 'Wear New Fashion,' to introduce the new generation of BOLON smart glasses, featuring a deep integration of AI functions and fashion design.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，Rokid 乐奇在官方微信公众号发文，官宣将于 11 月 13 日联合 BOLON 眼镜在浙江举办主题为「戴上新时尚」的新品发布会，推出新一代 BOLON 智能眼镜，主打 AI 功能与时尚设计的深度融合。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Rokid stated that the new product continues its lightweight and high-performance genes, equipped with the latest AI interaction technology, supporting functions such as voice control, information prompts, real-time translation, and smart navigation, covering multi-scenario needs for office, life, and entertainment. The addition of the BOLON brand allows it to maintain a minimalist style in design and craftsmanship, enhance wearing comfort, and continue its brand philosophy of 'looking good with you'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Rokid 乐奇方面表示，新品延续轻量化与高性能基因，搭载最新 AI 交互技术，支持语音控制、信息提示、实时翻译、智能导航等功能，覆盖办公、生活与娱乐等多场景需求。BOLON 品牌的加入使其在设计与工艺上保持极简风格，并强化佩戴舒适性，延续其「陪你好好看」的品牌理念。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>美团 LongCat 团队推出全模态大模型，支持实时音视频交互</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">美团-LongCat-团队推出全模态大模型，支持实时音视频交互</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/fbdaa88a-6627-485f-85e9-21f996d2c125.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Meituan's LongCat team officially released and open-sourced the brand new large model, LongCat-Flash-Omni.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，美团 LongCat 团队正式发布并开源全新大模型 LongCat-Flash-Omni。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Building upon the efficient architecture of the LongCat-Flash series, this model integrates multimodal perception and speech reconstruction modules, achieving low-latency real-time audio and video interaction capabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该模型在延续 LongCat-Flash 系列高效架构的基础上，集成多模态感知与语音重建模块，实现了低延迟的实时音视频交互能力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            LongCat-Flash-Omni boasts a total parameter count of 560 billion (27 billion active parameters), supports a 128K tokens context window and over 8 minutes of audio-visual interaction, demonstrating leading performance across multimodal tasks including text, image, audio, and video.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            LongCat-Flash-Omni 总参数规模达 5600 亿（激活参数 270 亿），支持 128K tokens 上下文窗口及超过 8 分钟的音视频交互，在文本、图像、音频和视频等多模态任务中均展现出领先性能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Comprehensive evaluations show that the model achieves state-of-the-art open-source levels in benchmarks like Omni-Bench and WorldSense, and approaches or even surpasses some closed-source models in tasks such as speech recognition, speech generation, and video understanding.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            综合评估显示，该模型在 Omni-Bench、WorldSense 等基准测试中达到开源最先进水平，并在语音识别、语音生成、视频理解等任务上接近甚至超越部分闭源模型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, LongCat-Flash-Omni has been open-sourced simultaneously on Hugging Face and Github platforms. The official App is also available for download in app stores, supporting internet search and voice call functions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，LongCat-Flash-Omni 已在 Hugging Face 与 Github 平台同步开源，官方 App 也已上线，可在应用商店下载，支持联网搜索与语音通话功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🤗 Hugging Face:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni&quot;&gt;
             https://huggingface.co/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🤗 Hugging Face：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni&quot;&gt;
             https://huggingface.co/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            💻 Github:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            💻 Github：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/meituan-longcat/LongCat-Flash-Omni
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>三星确认 2 月 25 日召开发布会，Galaxy S26 系列将亮相</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">三星确认-2-月-25-日召开发布会，Galaxy-S26-系列将亮相</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a98a91bc-ab96-4932-bc23-cca1040cccc1.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to TweakTown, Samsung will hold an &quot;AI Focus&quot; Galaxy Unpacked event in San Francisco on February 25, 2026, to officially launch the new generation of Galaxy S26 series smartphones.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 TweakTown 报道，三星将在 2026 年 2 月 25 日于旧金山举办「AI 聚焦」Galaxy Unpacked 发布会，正式推出新一代 Galaxy S26 系列智能手机。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The product lineup for this launch includes the Galaxy S26, S26 Plus, and S26 Ultra. Notably, the S26 Ultra will feature Samsung's self-developed Exynos 2600 processor, marking the first time Samsung has re-adopted its in-house chip in a flagship model since the Galaxy S22 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次发布的产品阵容包括 Galaxy S26、S26 Plus 和 S26 Ultra。值得注意的是，S26 Ultra 将搭载三星自研的 Exynos 2600 处理器，这是自 Galaxy S22 系列以来，三星首次在旗舰机型中重新采用自研芯片。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Exynos 2600 is manufactured based on the 2nm GAA process, with significantly improved performance. Reports indicate that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the chip is 59% faster than Apple's A19 Pro in Geekbench 6 multi-core tests
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , signaling Samsung's strong return to the high-end chip market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Exynos 2600 基于 2nm GAA 工艺制造，性能表现大幅提升。据报道，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             该芯片在 Geekbench 6 多核测试中比苹果 A19 Pro 快 59%
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，显示出三星在高端芯片领域的强势回归。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>广东即将发放新一轮消费券</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">广东即将发放新一轮消费券</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c0fadb1d-1eae-4dd5-937e-fc0b68d2b739.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Guangdong Provincial Government yesterday announced the &quot;Enjoy Warm Winter, Travel Guangdong&quot; Consumption Season Activity Overall Plan. The plan indicates that the event, which started on November 1st, will run until the end of March 2026, aiming to boost consumption growth in culture and tourism, catering, retail, sports, and other sectors through multi-level promotional measures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            广东省政府昨日公布《「粤享暖冬 乐游广东」消费季活动总体方案》。方案显示，活动已于 11 月 1 日启动，将持续至 2026 年 3 月底，旨在通过多层次促消费举措，推动文旅、餐饮、零售、体育等领域的消费增长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding specific measures, Guangdong will issue &quot;Guangdong Quality Purchase&quot; consumption vouchers, covering multiple categories such as new energy passenger vehicles, fuel vehicles meeting National VI standards, 8 types of home appliances, 5 types of electronic products, 6 types of sports goods, and local specialty products, allowing consumers to receive a one-time subsidy. Additionally, the event also includes six major preferential policies such as dining vouchers, hotel discounts, convenient transportation measures, and &quot;invoice lotteries.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在具体措施上，广东将发放「广东优品购」消费券，覆盖新能源乘用车、符合国六标准燃油车、8 类家电、5 类电子产品、6 类体育用品及地市特色优品等多个品类，消费者可获得一次性补贴。同时，活动还包括餐饮消费券、酒店优惠、交通便利措施及「发票抽奖」等六大优惠政策。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>饿了么 App 更名为「淘宝闪购」</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">饿了么-App-更名为「淘宝闪购」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e5a062b5-7c39-4da9-bc26-cbed5e5231a5.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, netizens revealed that the Ele.me App has been officially renamed &quot;Taobao Flash Buy&quot; after updating its version number to 12.0.2.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，有网友爆料，饿了么 App 在版本号更新至 12.0.2 后，已正式更名为「淘宝闪购」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Public information shows that starting from April 30, 2025, Taobao's &quot;Hour Delivery&quot; has been upgraded to &quot;Taobao Flash Buy&quot; and serves as a primary entry point within the Taobao App, collaborating with Ele.me to provide instant retail services covering various categories such as food delivery, supermarket convenience, and digital products.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公开资料显示，自 2025 年 4 月 30 日起，淘宝「小时达」升级为「淘宝闪购」，并作为淘宝 App 内的一级入口，联合饿了么提供即时零售服务，覆盖外卖、超市便利、数码等多个品类。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this adjustment, Ele.me continues to provide supply, logistics, and technical support. Related order identifiers, rider uniforms, and customer service scripts have also been gradually changed from &quot;Ele.me&quot; to &quot;Taobao Flash Buy.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            饿了么在此次调整中继续承担供给、运力和技术支持，相关订单标识、骑手制服及客服话术等也已逐步由「饿了么」更换为「淘宝闪购」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>上海迪士尼将建第四座主题酒店 并扩建消费体验区</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">上海迪士尼将建第四座主题酒店-并扩建消费体验区</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/dcf1943a-9928-4222-9a75-4d570de76dc7.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Shanghai Observer, Shanghai Disney Resort announced yesterday that it has welcomed its 100 millionth visitor since opening and simultaneously unveiled expansion plans: a fourth themed hotel will be built near the park's main entrance, along with new shopping, dining, and entertainment areas, to meet the continuously growing demand from visitors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据上观新闻报道，昨天上海迪士尼度假区宣布迎来开园以来的第一亿名游客，并同步公布扩建计划：将在乐园主入口附近建设第四座主题酒店，同时新增购物、餐饮及娱乐体验区，以满足持续增长的游客需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that the fourth themed hotel in this expansion will be the closest accommodation facility to the park, allowing guests to walk directly into the park. The hotel will incorporate Disney story elements to provide an immersive accommodation experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，此次扩建的第四座主题酒店将成为距离乐园最近的住宿设施，宾客可步行入园。酒店将融入迪士尼故事元素，提供沉浸式住宿体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Concurrently, the resort will also add a new shopping venue similar to a &quot;Disney World Store,&quot; where visitors can purchase exclusive merchandise without entering the park, further enriching the consumer experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，度假区还将新增一处类似「迪士尼世界商店」的购物场地，游客无需入园即可购买独家商品，进一步丰富消费体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ordinary 上海开设「功效商店」，以反促销挑战双十一</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">The-Ordinary-上海开设「功效商店」，以反促销挑战双十一</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/99222c76-1980-40ec-927c-99519265298c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Skincare brand The Ordinary opened its first large-scale offline experience space, &quot;The Efficacy Store,&quot; on Julu Road in Shanghai from October 25th to November 11th, challenging traditional marketing models during the Double Eleven period with a &quot;no promotion&quot; pop-up format.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            护肤品牌 The Ordinary 于 10 月 25 日至 11 月 11 日在上海巨鹿路开设首个大型线下体验空间「功效商店」，以「拒绝促销」的快闪形式挑战双十一期间的传统营销模式。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The store uses a nearly 3-meter-high &quot;mountain of cash&quot; installation to directly address industry overpricing, highlighting how celebrity endorsements, luxurious packaging, and marketing gimmicks inflate prices. A &quot;16 Skin Type Test&quot; area is set up on-site, guiding consumers to precisely match products through 6 core questions and offering full-line trials.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该店以近 3 米高的「钞票山」装置直指行业溢价问题，强调明星代言、豪华包装与营销噱头推高价格的现象。现场设立「16 型肌肤测试」区，通过 6 组核心问题帮助消费者精准匹配产品，并提供全线试用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In fact, this is not the first time the brand has used an artistic approach to reflect on industry overpricing. In April this year, The Ordinary held an immersive pop-up in New York, using installation art to expose inflated prices.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            事实上，这并非品牌首次以艺术化方式反思行业溢价。今年 4 月，The Ordinary 曾在纽约举办沉浸式快闪，以装置艺术揭示虚高价格。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since its inception, the brand has consistently advocated for minimalist packaging and transparent pricing, rejecting celebrity endorsements and complex marketing. This campaign further strengthens its 'efficacy skincare' positioning, calling for consumption to return to rationality and essence.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            自创立以来，品牌宣称始终坚持极简包装与透明定价，拒绝明星代言和复杂营销。此次活动进一步强化其「功效护肤」定位，呼吁消费回归理性与本质。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《鬼灭之刃：无限城篇》内地定档 11 月 14 日</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《鬼灭之刃：无限城篇》内地定档-11-月-14-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7ecaf352-2f86-4ac3-9e85-168fb3a63062.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The movie 'Demon Slayer: Kimetsu no Yaiba - The Hashira Training Arc, Chapter One: Akaza's Assault' was officially announced yesterday to be released in mainland China on November 14, along with a release date trailer. This marks the series' first appearance on the big screen in mainland China.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电影《鬼灭之刃：无限城篇 第一章 猗窝座再袭》已于昨天官宣将于 11 月 14 日在中国内地上映，并同步发布定档预告。这是该系列首次登陆内地大银幕。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The trailer opens with a dialogue clash between Muzan Kibutsuji and Kagaya Ubuyashiki, revolving around the concept of 'eternal immortality,' highlighting the opposition between humans and demons in their views on life.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            预告片以鬼舞辻无惨与产屋敷耀哉的台词交锋开篇，围绕「永恒不灭」的理念展开，凸显人类与鬼族在生命观上的对立。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As the opening work of the 'Infinity Castle' trilogy, the film has set multiple records in Japan and has risen to become the highest-grossing Japanese film globally, while also entering the top five on the 2025 global box office chart.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片作为「无限城」三部曲的开篇之作，已在日本本土创造多项纪录，并跃升为日本影史全球总票房冠军，同时进入 2025 年全球票房榜前五。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《过往人生》确认引进内地</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《过往人生》确认引进内地</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/165c98db-ef46-416a-bd7a-76acc79cf44f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the global phenomenon and dark horse film 'Past Lives' was officially announced for release in mainland China. Produced by American A24 Films, the movie was written and directed by rising Hollywood director Celine Song, marking her debut feature film.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，全球现象级口碑黑马电影《过往人生》官宣引进内地。本片由美国 A24 影业出品，好莱坞新锐导演席琳 · 宋编剧并执导，这是她的首部长片作品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            'Past Lives' tells a story of 'in-yeon' (destiny/providence) spanning 24 years and connecting the Eastern and Western hemispheres. Based on the director's own experiences, the film focuses on the real-life situations and emotional choices of East Asian women.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《过往人生》讲述了一段横跨 24 年、连接东西半球的「因缘」故事。影片以导演自身经历为蓝本，聚焦东亚女性的现实处境与情感抉择。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film performed brilliantly during the international awards season, having won over 18 international prestigious awards and received nominations for Best Picture and Best Original Screenplay at the 96th Academy Awards.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片在国际颁奖季表现亮眼，已斩获超过 18 项国际权威大奖，并获得第 96 届奥斯卡最佳影片和最佳原创剧本提名。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《美国恐怖故事》第 13 季官宣阵容</title>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《美国恐怖故事》第-13-季官宣阵容</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251104_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/ad415037-481b-485e-9d36-6aa7d67e3b33.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Deadline, writer Ryan Murphy confirmed the cast for 'American Horror Story' Season 13 yesterday on Halloween. The season is expected to air in 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Deadline 报道，编剧 Ryan Murphy 于昨天在万圣节当天确认《美国恐怖故事》第 13 季演员阵容，该季预计将在 2026 年播出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This season's cast includes Ariana Grande, Sarah Paulson, Evan Peters, Angela Bassett, Kathy Bates, Emma Roberts, Billie Lourd, Gabourey Sidibe, Leslie Grossman, and the highly anticipated return of Jessica Lange. All of the aforementioned actors have previously participated in Murphy's film and television projects.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本季阵容包括 Ariana Grande、Sarah Paulson、Evan Peters、Angela Bassett、Kathy Bates、Emma Roberts、Billie Lourd、Gabourey Sidibe、Leslie Grossman，以及重磅回归的 Jessica Lange。上述演员均曾参与过 Murphy 旗下的影视作品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Notably, Jessica Lange had previously stated publicly that she would not return to the series, but her confirmed appearance this time is the biggest surprise. She played Constance Langdon in the first season 'Murder House' in 2011 and served as a core character in multiple seasons.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，Jessica Lange 此前在公开场合明确表示不会再回归该系列，但此次确认出演成为最大惊喜。她曾在 2011 年首季《Murder House》中饰演 Constance Langdon，并在多季中担任核心角色。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, Ariana Grande previously appeared as Chanel #2 in Murphy's 'Scream Queens' and will collaborate again with Emma Roberts and Billie Lourd this time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，Ariana Grande 曾在 Murphy 的《Scream Queens》中出演 Chanel #2，本次将与 Emma Roberts 和 Billie Lourd 再度合作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
