<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>英特尔或重返「果链」，代工低端 M 系列芯片</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">英特尔或重返「果链」，代工低端-M-系列芯片</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/954214c2-5364-4606-990d-42a1b686017f.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, renowned analyst Ming-Chi Kuo posted on X, stating that Intel is expected to re-enter Apple's computer supply chain in 2027, becoming the foundry for its lowest-end M-series processors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，知名分析师郭明錤在 X 发布消息称，英特尔有望在 2027 年重新进入苹果电脑供应链，成为其最低端 M 系列处理器的代工方。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ming-Chi Kuo pointed out that Apple has signed a non-disclosure agreement with Intel and has obtained the PDK 0.9.1GA toolkit for the 18AP advanced process, with project progress currently meeting expectations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            郭明錤指出，苹果已与英特尔签署保密协议，并取得了 18AP 先进制程的 PDK 0.9.1GA 工具包，目前项目进展符合预期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple is awaiting Intel's planned release of the PDK 1.0/1.1 suite in Q1 2026. If progress is smooth, Intel could begin mass production and shipment of the lowest-end M-series processors as early as Q2-Q3 2027.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果正等待英特尔计划在 2026 年一季度发布的 PDK 1.0/1.1 套件，若进展顺利，英特尔最快将在 2027 年二至三季度开始量产出货最低端 M 系列处理器。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple's standard M chips are primarily used in MacBook Air and iPad Pro, with shipments estimated at around 20 million units in 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果的标准版 M 芯片主要用于 MacBook Air 与 iPad Pro，2025 年的出货量约为 2000 万颗。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Analysts expect that with the launch of new MacBook Air models featuring &quot;iPhone-level chips&quot; in 2026, shipments of low-end M-series processors could remain between 15 million and 20 million units over the next two years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            分析师预计，随着 2026 年新款配备「iPhone 级别芯片」的 MacBook Air 上市，未来两年低端 M 系列处理器的出货量可能维持在 1500 万至 2000 万颗之间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ming-Chi Kuo emphasized that while the order volume is limited, its significance is substantial.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            郭明錤强调，这笔订单规模有限，但意义重大。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For Apple, finding an advanced process &quot;second supplier&quot; beyond TSMC helps with supply chain risk management and aligns with the U.S. government's &quot;Made in America&quot; policy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对苹果而言，找到台积电之外的先进制程「二供」有助于供应链风险管理，并符合美国政府推动的「美国制造」政策。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            For Intel, securing Apple's order is not just a revenue contribution; it also signifies that its foundry business may have weathered its toughest phase, with prospects for winning more tier-one client orders for 14A and more advanced processes in the future.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            对英特尔而言，拿下苹果订单不仅是营收贡献，更意味着其代工业务可能已熬过最艰难阶段，未来在 14A 及更先进制程上有望争取更多一线客户订单。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, market sources indicate that, besides Apple, Google and Meta may also seek advanced packaging services from Intel. As TSMC's CoWoS packaging capacity is already occupied by GPU manufacturers like Nvidia and AMD, Intel's EMIB and Foveros technologies are considered more viable alternatives.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，市场消息称，除苹果外，Google 与 Meta 也可能寻求英特尔提供先进封装服务。由于台积电 CoWoS 封装产能已被英伟达与 AMD 等 GPU 厂商占据，英特尔的 EMIB 与 Foveros 技术被视为更可行的替代方案。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>最高优惠 2000 元，苹果北京上海直营店上线国家补贴</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">最高优惠-2000-元，苹果北京上海直营店上线国家补贴</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/84c9f563-2e4a-466a-8e8f-15fcc074d334.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Apple's official website showed that direct stores in Beijing and Shanghai have officially joined the national subsidy policy, allowing consumers to enjoy discounts of up to 2,000 yuan when purchasing designated products. For example, an iPhone 17 256GB, originally priced at 5,999 yuan, would only cost 5,499 yuan after a 500 yuan full-amount subsidy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，苹果官网显示，北京、上海地区直营店正式加入国家补贴政策，消费者在购买指定产品时可享最高 2000 元优惠。以 iPhone 17 256GB 为例，原价 5999 元，500 元满额补贴后仅需 5499 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Apple confirmed that this subsidy is only available at offline direct stores in Beijing and Shanghai; consumers who place orders online need to consult the store for specific procedures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            苹果方面确认，此次补贴仅限北京和上海的线下直营门店，线上下单的消费者需到门店咨询具体流程。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, in August and September of this year, direct stores in both Beijing and Shanghai participated in the subsidy, but the Beijing region later suspended it, while Shanghai continued to implement it. After this adjustment, only direct stores in Beijing and Shanghai nationwide are participating in the national subsidy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，今年 8、9 月份，北京与上海的直营门店均曾参与补贴，但北京地区随后暂停，上海则持续执行。此次调整后，全国范围内仅北京和上海的直营门店参与国补。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Apple's official website, this subsidy covers not only iPhones but also a full range of devices including iPads, Apple Watches, and Macs. The specific policy provisions are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据苹果官网信息，本次补贴覆盖范围不仅限于 iPhone，还包括 iPad、Apple Watch 与 Mac 等全系设备。政策具体规定如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the final price of a single iPhone, iPad, or Apple Watch item does not exceed 6,000 yuan, an additional 15% national subsidy can be enjoyed, with a maximum reduction of 500 yuan per item;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mac products can enjoy an additional 20% reduction on the final price, with a maximum reduction of 2,000 yuan per item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It should be noted that iPhones, iPads, and Apple Watches with a unit price exceeding 6,000 yuan are not covered by the subsidy. Additionally, orders participating in the subsidy cannot be combined with the &quot;iPhone Annual Upgrade Program,&quot; Apple Trade In program, or AppleCare+ service plan. Orders also do not support partial refunds, exchanges, or price protection refunds.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            需要注意的是，单价超过 6000 元的 iPhone、iPad、Apple Watch 不在补贴范围内。同时，参与补贴的订单不可与「iPhone 年年焕新计划」、Apple Trade In 换购计划或 AppleCare+ 服务计划叠加。订单亦不支持部分退款、换货或保价退差。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The policy requires consumers purchasing at direct stores in Beijing and Shanghai to present identification and provide real-name information, completing procedures such as unsealing, activation, and photo archiving on-site; otherwise, they cannot enjoy the subsidy. Relevant information is collected and processed by the Beijing Branch of UnionPay Merchant Services Co., Ltd.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            政策要求消费者在北京和上海直营店购买时需出示身份证件并提供实名信息，现场完成拆封、激活及拍照存档等流程，否则无法享受补贴。相关信息由银联商务支付股份有限公司北京分公司收集和处理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jiemian News cited market data, pointing out that Apple's iPhone 17 series, launched this year, saw significant sales growth in its first month on the market, with some markets experiencing a 22% year-on-year increase, while the global smartphone market as a whole declined by 2.7% during the same period. In the Chinese market, iPhone sales accounted for a quarter of the total mobile phone sales in October, with 80% coming from the new iPhone 17 series.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            界面新闻援引市场数据指出，苹果今年推出的 iPhone 17 系列在上市首月销量增长显著，部分市场同比提升 22%，而同期全球智能手机市场整体下滑 2.7%。在中国市场，10 月份 iPhone 销量占据当月手机总销量的四分之一，其中 80% 来自新款 iPhone 17 系列。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>长沙地铁官方确认全面查验充电宝 3C 认证</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">长沙地铁官方确认全面查验充电宝-3C-认证</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/385b3d93-438d-4bff-aec7-eacbc48eee0d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Changsha Metro recently began implementing safety inspection measures for power banks carried by passengers, requiring verification of 3C certification marks. This move stems from previous incidents of power bank spontaneous combustion, leading relevant departments to further tighten regulations to enhance public transport safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            长沙地铁近期开始执行对乘客随身携带充电宝的安全检查措施，要求查验 3C 认证标识。此举源于此前发生的充电宝自燃事件，相关部门为加强公共交通安全而进一步收紧规定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            China Newsweek reported that the Changsha Metro customer service hotline confirmed that passengers carrying power banks without 3C certification marks will be asked to remove them from the station or switch to other modes of transport. Staff noted that the measure was officially implemented recently, and instances of inadequate enforcement at some stations will be corrected and training strengthened.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国新闻周刊报道称，长沙地铁客服热线确认，乘客如携带无 3C 认证标识的充电宝，将被要求自行带离车站或改乘其他交通方式。工作人员指出，该措施于近期正式实施，部分站点执行不到位的情况将被纠正并加强培训。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a safety notice recently published on Changsha Metro's WeChat official account, the rated energy of a single lithium-ion battery carried by passengers must not exceed 160Wh, and each person may not carry more than 3 such items in total.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据长沙地铁微信公众号日前发布的安全提示，乘客携带的单品锂离子电池额定能量不得超过 160Wh，每人累计不得超过 3 个。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Officials remind consumers that when purchasing power banks, they should choose products from legitimate manufacturers and check the packaging for manufacturer information, anti-counterfeiting codes, and CCC certification marks to ensure quality and safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方提醒，购买充电宝时应选择正规厂家生产的产品，检查包装上的厂家信息、防伪码及 CCC 认证标志，以确保质量与安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Changsha Metro has released emergency response procedures: in case of fire in the station hall or on the platform, use the nearest fire extinguisher and immediately notify staff; in case of fire inside the train car, contact the driver via the emergency alarm or notify the platform, and use the fire extinguishers located under the seats to extinguish the fire. Each train car is equipped with 2 emergency alarms and 2 fire extinguishers to ensure passenger safety.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，长沙地铁公布了应急处置流程：如在站厅或站台发生火情，应使用就近灭火器并立即通知工作人员；如在车厢内发生火情，可通过紧急报警器联系司机或通知站台，并使用座位下方配备的灭火器进行扑救。每节车厢配备 2 个紧急报警器和 2 具灭火器，以保障乘客安全。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The background for this measure is a power bank smoking incident that occurred on Changsha Metro Line 3 on the evening of November 9th. Fortunately, the fire was promptly extinguished on-site, and no one was injured.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次措施的背景是 11 月 9 日晚长沙地铁三号线曾发生一起充电宝冒烟事件，所幸现场被及时扑灭，无人员受伤。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>苹果播客异常推送，疑似遭受恶意攻击</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果播客异常推送，疑似遭受恶意攻击</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f56f5f15-9267-4770-b81b-4e5ec804f65f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 404 Media, Apple's &quot;Podcasts&quot; app has exhibited abnormal behavior over the past few months, with some users finding the app automatically launching and pushing religious, spiritual, or educational podcasts upon unlocking their devices, with no discernible pattern in content sources. At least one case involved a potentially malicious website link, suspected of spreading via a cross-site scripting (XSS) attack.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 404 Media 报道，苹果「播客」App 在过去数月出现异常行为，部分用户在解锁设备时发现应用会自动启动并推送宗教、灵修或教育类播客，且内容来源毫无规律。其中至少有一起案例涉及潜在恶意网站链接，疑似利用跨站脚本（XSS）攻击进行传播。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report indicates that this phenomenon has appeared in both iOS and Mac versions of the Podcasts app. Some podcast pages contain a &quot;View Webpage&quot; hyperlink, which, when clicked, redirects to sites like &quot;test.ddv.in.ua&quot; and displays a prompt &quot;XSS. Domain: test.ddv.in.ua&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，这一现象在 iOS 与 Mac 版本的播客应用中均有出现。部分播客页面包含「查看网页」超链接，点击后会重定向至「test.ddv.in.ua」等站点，并弹出提示「XSS. Domain: test.ddv.in.ua」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Security expert Patrick Wardle stated that this behavior shows attackers can forcibly open the app and load specified podcasts without user confirmation, providing an entry point for exploiting potential vulnerabilities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            安全专家 Patrick Wardle 表示，该行为显示攻击者能够在无需用户确认的情况下强制打开应用并加载指定播客，这为潜在漏洞的利用提供了入口。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wardle emphasized that while no signs of large-scale attacks have been detected yet, this mechanism could become an effective delivery channel for future malicious code. He noted: &quot;This situation is similar to the Google Calendar spam incident a few years ago, where attackers pushed unsolicited content to users through system functions.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Wardle 强调，目前尚未发现大规模攻击迹象，但这种机制可能成为未来恶意代码的有效投递渠道。他指出：「这种情况类似于几年前 Google 日历垃圾信息事件，攻击者通过系统功能将不请自来的内容推送给用户。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            User feedback also confirmed this issue. In the comments section of the podcast app, a user recently left a message saying, &quot;How could Apple allow such an XSS attack?&quot; and gave a one-star rating. The relevant podcast can be traced back to 2019.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            用户反馈也印证了这一问题。在播客应用的评论区，有用户近期留言称「苹果怎么会允许这种 XSS 攻击？」，并给予一星评价。相关播客最早可追溯至 2019 年。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report states that Apple has not yet responded to this anomaly. 404 Media said it has repeatedly sent inquiries to Apple but has not received a reply.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道称，苹果尚未对这一异常现象作出回应。404 Media 称其已多次向苹果发出询问，但未获答复。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>外卖行业竞争加剧，美团 Q3 净亏损 160 亿元</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">外卖行业竞争加剧，美团-Q3-净亏损-160-亿元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9a133318-9a10-4524-8c4b-1dcc06289d9d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Meituan announced its third-quarter financial report as of September 30, showing that the company experienced its first quarterly loss in three years amid fierce market competition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天美团公布截至 9 月 30 日的第三季度财报，显示公司在激烈的市场竞争下遭遇三年来首次季度亏损。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue Performance: Meituan's third-quarter revenue was 95.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 2.0%, lower than market expectations;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Net Profit Performance: Adjusted net loss was 16 billion yuan, compared to a net profit of 12.8 billion yuan in the same period last year; the overall net loss reached 18.6 billion yuan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Business Under Pressure: Local commerce segment revenue decreased by 2.8% year-on-year to 67.4 billion yuan, and the operating profit margin fell from 21.0% in the same period last year to negative 20.9%, recording an operating loss of 14.1 billion yuan;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soaring Costs: Sales and marketing expenses increased by 90.9% year-on-year to 34.3 billion yuan, with its proportion of revenue soaring from 19.2% to 35.9%; increased rider subsidies further pushed up costs;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive Landscape: Alibaba and JD.com have invested huge subsidies in the food delivery and instant retail markets, putting pressure on Meituan's market share. Morningstar predicts that Meituan's share of gross transaction value in the instant retail market will decline from 73% in 2024 to 55% in 2027;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Business Expansion: New business segment revenue increased by 15.9% year-on-year to 28 billion yuan, mainly from grocery retail and overseas business expansion. However, operating losses expanded to 1.3 billion yuan, with a loss rate of 4.6%;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategic Investment: R&amp;amp;D expenses increased by 31.0% year-on-year to 6.9 billion yuan, with a focus on artificial intelligence, including the merchant AI tool 'LongCat' and the user smart life assistant 'Xiaomei' app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            LatePost reported that the surge in sales expenses mainly stemmed from autumn food delivery subsidies, with Meituan's single-quarter sales expenses even exceeding Pinduoduo's, which has nearly double the transaction volume.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            晚点 LatePost 报道认为，销售费用激增主要源于秋季外卖补贴，美团单季销售费用甚至超过了成交额快一倍的拼多多。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, LatePost learned that Taobao Flash Sale will subsidize food delivery during critical periods in the future to further capture market share, and plans to launch another instant retail battle next spring, focusing on subsidizing non-meal items, rather than the previous 'food delivery war'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，晚点 LatePost 获悉，未来淘宝闪购会在关键时段补贴餐饮外卖，以期进一步占据市场份额，并计划在明年春天再次发起即时零售大战，重点补贴非餐货品，而非此前的「外卖大战」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Some Weibo users pointed out that while Meituan's Q3 shift from profit to loss was within expectations, the core issues lie in stagnant revenue and deteriorating UE (unit economics), with the subsidy war leading to 'the more orders, the greater the loss.' At the same time, Douyin's strong growth in in-store services further eroded Meituan's market share.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            有微博网友指出，美团 Q3 由盈转亏虽在预期范围内，但核心问题在于营收停滞与 UE（每单经济模型）恶化，补贴大战导致「单量越多，亏损越大」。同时，抖音在到店业务的强势增长进一步侵蚀美团市场份额。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the other hand, Wall Street Insights analysis believes that Meituan's loss trend is expected to continue in the fourth quarter, especially as the core local commerce segment will still face sustained pressure.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Analysts pointed out that while Meituan's overseas expansion brings growth, high costs make it difficult to alleviate the dilemma of declining domestic market share in the short term.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另一方面，华尔街见闻分析认为，美团亏损趋势预计在第四季度延续，尤其是核心本地商业板块仍将面临持续压力。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             分析师指出，美团海外扩张虽带来增长，但成本高企，短期难以缓解国内市场份额下滑的困境。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During Meituan's third-quarter earnings call last night, CEO Wang Xing stated, &quot;The food delivery price war is a low-quality, low-price 'involutionary' competition, which we firmly oppose. Market results over the past six months have fully proven that the food delivery price war has not created value for the industry and is unsustainable.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在昨晚的美团第三季度财报电话会上，美团 CEO 王兴表示，「外卖价格战是低质低价的『内卷式』竞争，我们坚决反对。半年来的市场结果已经充分证明：外卖价格战没有为行业创造价值，不可持续。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that Meituan is confident in defending its market position in instant retail and creating true long-term value.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他表示，美团有信心捍卫即时零售的市场地位，创造真正的长期价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>需求激增，Google 收紧 Gemini 3 Pro 免费访问权限</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">需求激增，Google-收紧-Gemini-3-Pro-免费访问权限</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7bc9db4a-2cf8-4066-97e5-7ff827538fbc.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 9to5Google, Google recently tightened free user access to Gemini 3 Pro due to surging demand for generative AI tools leading to capacity constraints.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 9to5Google 报道，Google 近期收紧了 Gemini 3 Pro 的免费用户访问权限，原因是生成式 AI 工具需求激增导致容量紧张。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, free users could use Gemini 3 Pro's 'Think' feature for up to 5 prompts per day and generate or edit 3 images, consistent with Gemini 2.5 Pro's limits.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，免费用户每天可使用 Gemini 3 Pro 的「思考」功能最多 5 次提示，并可生成或编辑 3 张图像，与 Gemini 2.5 Pro 的限制保持一致。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, however, Google adjusted free user access to 'basic access,' where daily limits are no longer fixed but dynamically change based on demand, with an overall trend towards tightening.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            然而，最近，Google 将免费用户的权限调整为「基础访问」，每日限额不再固定，而是根据需求动态变化，整体趋势趋于收紧。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Nano Banana Pro's image generation and editing quota has also been reduced from 3 images per day to 2, with a clear note stating 'High demand for image generation and editing, limits may be frequently adjusted and reset daily.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与此同时，Nano Banana Pro 的图像生成与编辑额度也从每日 3 张下调至 2 张，并明确标注「图像生成与编辑需求量大，限额可能频繁调整并每日重置」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the NotebookLM platform has temporarily taken offline its infographic and slideshow features powered by the model, making them unavailable to free users, and Pro users are also subject to additional restrictions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，NotebookLM 平台临时下线了由该模型驱动的信息图与幻灯片功能，免费用户无法使用，Pro 用户也受到额外限制。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Google stated that demand far exceeded expectations, leading to capacity pressure, and they are working to restore services. Pro and Ultra access for subscribed users remains unaffected.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Google 表示，需求远超预期导致容量压力，正在努力恢复服务，订阅用户的 Pro 与 Ultra 使用权限不受影响。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>逐际动力机器人 Oli 建筑工地「越野」成功</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">逐际动力机器人-Oli-建筑工地「越野」成功</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3ade9d0f-1c10-4a2f-b70e-84be57ec2945.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, LimX Dynamics' official video channel updated, showcasing its full-size humanoid robot, LimX Oli, completing complex terrain walking tests in a real construction site's spoil heap area.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，逐际动力 LimX Dynamics 官方视频号更新，展示旗下全尺寸人形机器人 LimX Oli 在真实建筑工地的渣土堆料区完成复杂地形行走测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the video, Oli maintained a stable gait across various unstructured terrains such as sand, rocks, wooden planks, and construction waste piles, demonstrating highly human-like mobility and anti-disturbance performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            视频中，Oli 在沙土、石块、木板及建筑废料堆等多种非结构地形中保持稳定步态，展现出高度拟人的移动能力与抗扰动性能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that Oli stands 165 cm tall and possesses 31 degrees of freedom. LimX Dynamics' whole-body motion control algorithm performs real-time coordinated control over all degrees of freedom, optimizing instantaneous joint output and compensating for inertial shifts, enabling the robot to maintain a stable center of gravity and natural posture in complex terrain, avoiding rigid compensation or unreasonable wobbling, and ensuring continuous, uninterrupted walking rhythm.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据了解，Oli 身高 165 厘米，具备 31 个本体自由度。逐际动力的全身运动控制算法对所有自由度进行实时协同控制，优化关节瞬时输出并补偿惯性偏移，使机器人在复杂地形中保持重心稳定与姿态自然，避免僵硬补偿或不合理晃动，确保行走节奏连续不中断。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the testing process, Oli was able to quickly correct its whole-body posture trajectory and resume a natural gait when faced with sinking into soft sand, transient impacts from rocks, and lateral skidding caused by irregular gravel and slopes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在测试过程中，Oli 面对松软沙土的陷落、石块的瞬态冲击、不规则碎石与斜坡带来的侧滑偏移，均能快速修正全身姿态轨迹，恢复自然步态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            LimX Dynamics emphasizes that stable movement is a prerequisite for full-size humanoid robots to complete operational tasks. Only by achieving reliable movement and posture control in complex environments can robots accurately position their arms at the operating point and maintain work reliability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            逐际动力强调，稳定移动是全尺寸人形机器人完成操作任务的前提。只有在复杂环境中实现可靠的移动与姿态控制，机器人才能将双臂准确带到操作点并保持工作可靠性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            LimX Dynamics was founded in 2022, headquartered in Shenzhen, and focuses on the research and development of embodied intelligent robots, covering products such as full-size humanoids and bipedal robots. Its R&amp;amp;D strategy revolves around hardware design and manufacturing, reinforcement learning-based whole-body motion control, and embodied brain training paradigms, promoting the application of embodied intelligence in scientific research, manufacturing, commercial, and home scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            逐际动力成立于 2022 年，总部位于深圳，专注于具身智能机器人研发，涵盖全尺寸人形与双足机器人等产品。其研发战略围绕硬件设计制造、基于强化学习的全身运动控制及具身大脑训练范式，推动具身智能在科研、制造、商业与家庭场景的应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>辍学生加入 OpenAI：通过 ChatGPT 自学「博士级 AI」</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">辍学生加入-OpenAI：通过-ChatGPT-自学「博士级-AI」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/506c22dd-9339-44fd-82e1-cd4695232a7f.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Gabriel Petersson, a high school dropout, recently stated on the podcast 'Extraordinary' that he self-taught Ph.D.-level AI knowledge using ChatGPT and eventually joined OpenAI's Sora team as a research scientist.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《商业内幕》报道，一名高中辍学生 Gabriel Petersson 近日在播客节目《Extraordinary》中表示，他通过 ChatGPT 自学博士级别的人工智能知识，并最终加入 OpenAI 的 Sora 团队担任研究科学家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After dropping out of school in 2019, Petersson joined a Swedish startup, learning programming based on actual project needs. He emphasized that 'universities no longer monopolize fundamental knowledge' and pointed out that 'you can directly acquire any fundamental knowledge from ChatGPT'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Petersson 在 2019 年辍学后进入瑞典一家初创公司，从实际项目需求出发学习编程。他强调「大学不再垄断基础知识」，并指出「你可以直接从 ChatGPT 获取任何基础知识」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He adopted a top-down learning approach: first proposing project requirements, then having ChatGPT generate code, and when encountering problems, fixing them with the model's help, gradually gaining a deeper understanding of underlying principles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他采用自上而下的学习方式：先提出项目需求，再让 ChatGPT 生成代码，遇到问题则在模型帮助下修复，逐步深入理解底层原理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to his LinkedIn profile, Petersson joined OpenAI last December, having previously worked as a software engineer at Midjourney and Dataland.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据他的 LinkedIn 信息，Petersson 于去年 12 月加入 OpenAI，此前曾在 Midjourney 和 Dataland 担任软件工程师。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He believes companies value results more than academic qualifications, stating, 'Companies just want to make money; if you prove you can write code and create value, they will hire you'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他认为企业更看重结果而非学历，「公司只想赚钱，你证明自己能写代码、能创造价值，他们就会雇用你」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI CEO Sam Altman also stated at the DevDay conference in October that he 'envies the opportunities available to 20-year-old dropouts today,' because AI technology allows young people to quickly build products and enter the industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAI CEO Sam Altman 在 10 月的 DevDay 大会上也曾表示，他「羡慕当下 20 岁辍学生的机会」，因为 AI 技术让年轻人能够快速构建产品并进入行业。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Meanwhile, venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz noted in a March blog post this year that 'the startup environment has provided a more level playing field for young founders,' calling it 'the best time in a decade for dropouts and recent graduates to start companies'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，风险投资公司 Andreessen Horowitz 在今年 3 月的博客中指出，「创业环境已为年轻创始人提供了更公平的竞争舞台」，并称这是「十年来辍学生和应届毕业生创业的最佳时机」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In February this year, Alex Karp, CEO of the American software services company Palantir, stated bluntly in an interview with CNBC that 'the worldview taught in schools is intellectually wrong' and launched a 'Merit Fellowship Program' for high school graduates, directly selecting potential talent from among them.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 2 月，美国软件服务公司帕兰提尔（Palantir）CEO Alex Karp 在接受 CNBC 采访时直言「学校教授的世界观在智识上是错误的」，并推出面向高中毕业生的「优绩研修项目」，直接从高中毕业生中选拔潜在人才。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>阿维塔递表港交所，估值逾 260 亿元</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">阿维塔递表港交所，估值逾-260-亿元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7dd40eee-fce9-4129-8925-c143bfa54352.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Wall Street News, Avatr Technology (Chongqing) Co., Ltd. submitted its IPO application to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange yesterday evening, planning to complete its listing in 2026. This move means Avatr is expected to become the first state-owned enterprise-backed new energy vehicle company to list on the Hong Kong stock market, being hailed as the 'first central SOE new energy stock'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据华尔街见闻报道，阿维塔科技（重庆）股份有限公司已于昨天晚间向香港联合交易所递交 IPO 申请，计划在 2026 年完成上市。这一举动意味着阿维塔有望成为首家央企背景的新势力车企登陆港股市场，被视为「央企新能源第一股」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Avatr, established just seven years ago, is positioned as a high-end new energy brand. It has now formed a 'three years, four cars' product layout, with main models including Avatr 11, 12, 07, 06, as well as limited co-branded editions 011 and 012, covering the high-end market from 200,000 to 700,000 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            阿维塔成立仅七年，定位高端新能源品牌，目前已形成「三年四车」的产品布局，主力车型包括阿维塔 11、12、07、06，以及限量联名版 011 与 012，覆盖 20 万至 70 万元的高端市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Data shows that the company's cumulative sales from January to October 2025 exceeded 100,000 units, with monthly sales surpassing 10,000 for 8 consecutive months. Although there is still a gap with leading brands, the growth trend is evident.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            数据显示，公司 2025 年 1 至 10 月累计销量超过 10 万辆，连续 8 个月单月销量破万，尽管与头部品牌仍有差距，但增长趋势明显。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of financial performance, Avatr's operating revenue for 2023 and 2024 was 5.645 billion yuan and 15.195 billion yuan respectively, representing a year-on-year increase of 169.16%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财务表现方面，阿维塔在 2023 年至 2024 年的营业收入分别为 56.45 亿元与 151.95 亿元，同比增长 169.16%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the first half of 2025, revenue reached 12.208 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of nearly 98.52%. Gross profit in the same period was 1.238 billion yuan, a significant increase compared to 267 million yuan in the same period last year. The company has completed four rounds of financing, raising over 19 billion yuan in total, with more than 11 billion yuan from Series C financing, making it the largest single financing round in China that year. The latest valuation is approximately 26.017 billion yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2025 年上半年营收达到 122.08 亿元，同比增幅接近 98.52%。同期毛利录得 12.38 亿元，相较上年同期的 2.67 亿元大幅提升。公司已完成四轮融资，累计募集资金超过 190 亿元，其中 C 轮融资金额超过 110 亿元，成为当年度国内最大单笔融资。最新估值约为 260.17 亿元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>豆包语音功能更新：新增 4 种方言，识别覆盖达 18 种</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">豆包语音功能更新：新增-4-种方言，识别覆盖达-18-种</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/07014da1-6491-4153-bb3d-6e6df521f9c2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to multiple media reports, the Doubao App recently updated its voice chat function, adding support for four dialects: Cantonese, Sichuanese, Northeastern Mandarin, and Shaanxi dialect.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据多家媒体报道，豆包 App 近日更新语音对话功能，新增粤语、四川话、东北话及陕西话四种方言输出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Users can trigger the dialect conversation experience by entering text or voice commands in the chat box and selecting the default &quot;Gentle Peach&quot; upgraded voice. This function relies on Doubao's voice model's dialect migration technology, enabling a single voice to support multiple dialects and possessing thinking capabilities, allowing flexible switching based on user intent.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            用户在对话框输入文字或语音指令，并选择默认的「温柔桃子」升级版音色，即可触发方言对话体验。该功能依托豆包语音模型的方言迁移技术，实现单音色支持多方言，并具备思考能力，可根据用户意图灵活切换。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            QuantumBit reporters' tests show that Doubao can accurately recognize relevant dialect speech and vocabulary and respond in natural and authentic dialects. This feature is particularly helpful for user groups unfamiliar with Mandarin, improving communication efficiency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            量子位记者实测显示，豆包能够精准识别相关方言语音与词汇，并以自然地道的方言回应。这一功能尤其有助于不熟悉普通话的用户群体，提升沟通效率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to the 4 newly added dialects, Doubao can also recognize 18 other dialects, such as Shanghainese and Nanjing dialect, during conversations. With the help of ASR (Automatic Speech Recognition) technology, transcription accuracy and efficiency have significantly improved.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除新增的 4 种方言外，豆包还可在对话过程中识别上海话、南京话等 18 种方言，借助 ASR（Automatic Speech Recognition）技术，转录准确率与效率显著提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A Doubao representative stated that this update aims to enhance the interactive experience for users in different regions, allowing more people to use voice functions in a more relaxed and natural way and enjoy the convenience brought by technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            豆包相关负责人表示，此次更新旨在提升不同地域用户的交互体验，让更多人能够以更轻松自然的方式使用语音功能，享受技术带来的便利。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vivo 向开放原子基金会捐赠 Rust 自研操作系统内核</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">vivo-向开放原子基金会捐赠-Rust-自研操作系统内核</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f488eed9-3306-410d-ba82-2af590d09039.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            OpenAtom recently published an official account article stating that at the 2025 OpenAtom Developer Conference held recently, vivo announced its official donation of its self-developed operating system kernel, BlueKernel, written in Rust, to the OpenAtom Open Source Foundation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            开放原子近日发表公众号文章称，在日前举行的 2025 开放原子开发者大会上，vivo 宣布正式向开放原子开源基金会捐赠其以 Rust 语言自研的操作系统内核 BlueKernel。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The BlueKernel kernel possesses three major characteristics: security, lightness, and universality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            BlueKernel 内核具备安全、轻量和通用三大特性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its security relies on Rust's compile-time static rules and smart pointer mechanisms, enabling proactive control over memory safety;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of lightness, the minimum kernel memory footprint is only 13KB, significantly reducing hardware resource requirements;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of universality, BlueKernel is compatible with multiple chip architectures such as RISC-V and ARM, and supports the POSIX interface standard library, making it convenient for developers to quickly adapt to existing ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, the kernel has completed adaptation for development boards from multiple chip manufacturers, including GigaDevice GD32, Bestechnic BES, and Rockchip RK, covering Cortex-M, Cortex-A, and RISC-V architectures.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，该内核已完成对兆易创新 GD32、恒玄科技 BES、瑞芯微 RK 等多家芯片厂商开发板的适配，覆盖 Cortex-M、Cortex-A 及 RISC-V 架构。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Concurrently with the conference, the OpenAtom Open Source Foundation announced that OpenHarmony and openEuler have passed the Technical Oversight Committee review, becoming the first batch of graduated projects, marking a new height for the two open-source operating systems in terms of technical maturity, community governance, and ecosystem development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            大会同期，开放原子开源基金会宣布开源鸿蒙 OpenHarmony 与开源欧拉 openEuler 通过技术监督委员会评审，成为首批毕业项目，标志着两大开源操作系统在技术成熟度、社区治理和生态建设方面达到新高度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            As of the end of 2024, the number of active open-source projects in China has exceeded 3 million, with active developers reaching 2.27 million, forming a large-scale and diverse open-source talent pool.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            截至 2024 年底，中国活跃开源项目数量已超过 300 万，活跃开发者达到 227 万，形成规模宏大、结构多元的开源人才队伍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, the conference also unveiled the list of acknowledgments for China's open-source innovation forces, covering 28 pioneering open-source projects and 47 developer representatives in three core areas: operating systems, databases, and artificial intelligence, including industry benchmarks such as OpenHarmony, openEuler, openKylin, and openGauss.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，大会还揭晓了中国开源创新力量致谢名单，涵盖操作系统、数据库、人工智能三大核心领域的 28 个开源先锋项目及 47 位开发者代表，包括开源鸿蒙、开源欧拉、openKylin、openGauss 等业界标杆。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 雷军：未来 5 年人形机器人将大规模进厂</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-雷军：未来-5-年人形机器人将大规模进厂</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/1f2037fc-042b-4d0a-93fb-8228f5f7d8ae.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Beijing Daily, Lei Jun, founder and chairman of Xiaomi Group, stated in an interview, &quot;All industries are worth redoing with AI.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据北京日报报道，小米集团创始人、董事长雷军在接受采访时表示，「所有产业都值得用 AI 再做一遍」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that in the next five years, humanoid robots will be widely deployed in Xiaomi factories, and emphasized the potential of humanoid robots in home scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，未来 5 年，人形机器人将在小米工厂大规模上岗，并强调人形机器人在家庭场景中的潜力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Lei Jun mentioned that recently, Xiaomi Auto achieved its 500,000th vehicle off the production line, setting the fastest record in the global new energy vehicle industry.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            雷军提到，日前，小米汽车实现第 50 万辆整车下线，创下全球新能源汽车行业最快纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He particularly emphasized that Beijing's industrial foundation and innovative environment are the confidence behind Xiaomi's development. During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, Beijing vigorously promoted industrial upgrading, with new energy vehicle production growing from approximately 20,000 units in 2020 to 300,000 units in 2024, and reaching 310,000 units in the first seven months of this year, demonstrating significant achievements in industrial transformation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他特别强调，北京的产业基础和创新环境是小米发展的底气。北京在「十四五」期间大力推进产业升级，新能源汽车产量从 2020 年的约 2 万辆增长至 2024 年的 30 万辆，今年前 7 个月已达到 31 万辆，显示出产业转型的显著成效。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of intelligent manufacturing, Xiaomi's &quot;dark factory&quot; in Beijing has achieved an annual mobile phone production of 1 million units, with production efficiency increased by 60% compared to traditional factories. Subsequently, a large-scale factory built in Changping has an annual production capacity of 10 million mobile phones, further highlighting the advantages of intelligent manufacturing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在智能制造方面，小米在北京投产的「黑灯工厂」实现手机年产量 100 万台，生产效率较传统工厂提升 60%。随后在昌平建设的大规模工厂，年产手机 1000 万台，进一步凸显智能制造的优势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He cited an example: at the Xiaomi Auto factory, large die-casting part inspection, combining AI visual large models with X-ray machines, can be completed in just 2 seconds. This is 10 times more efficient than manual inspection, and accuracy is improved by more than 5 times. This deep integration of AI with traditional industries will open up a new trillion-dollar market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他举例称，在小米汽车工厂，大压铸件检测通过 AI 视觉大模型与 X 光机结合，仅需 2 秒即可完成，效率是人工的 10 倍，精度提升 5 倍以上。这种 AI 与传统产业的深度融合，将开启新的万亿级市场。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GetDraft 上线：「AI 写作天团」重塑协作模式</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">GetDraft-上线：「AI-写作天团」重塑协作模式</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/16ac82c7-9af5-4d16-b7a7-c38001283019.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, AI writing collaboration platform GetDraft officially announced its launch. Positioned as an &quot;AI writing dream team,&quot; its core goal is to help professional writers and enterprise teams achieve more efficient collaboration from conception to first draft.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，AI 写作协作平台 GetDraft 官宣正式上线，定位为「AI 写作天团」，核心目标是帮助专业写作者和企业团队在从构思到初稿的过程中实现更高效的协作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Unlike common &quot;one-click generation&quot; writing tools on the market, GetDraft emphasizes the dominant role of human authors, while the AI team handles executive tasks such as research, expansion, refinement, and proofreading, thereby unleashing human value in creativity and judgment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与市面上常见的「一键生成」写作工具不同，GetDraft 强调人类作者的主导地位，AI 团队则承担调研、扩写、润色和校对等执行环节，从而释放人类在创意和判断上的价值。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            GetDraft's design philosophy is &quot;Humans are the chief editors, AI is the executor.&quot; The platform offers five role divisions:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GetDraft 的设计理念是「人类是主编，AI 是执行者」。平台提供五个角色分工：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Style Polisher A-Zhen is responsible for establishing the writing persona;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Writer A-Qiang leads topic selection and structure design;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Expert Xiao-Mei generates structured reports;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketching Ace Xiao-Shuai quickly completes expansion and standardized copywriting;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Sharp-tongued Editor Sang-Biao performs quality control, pointing out logical flaws and writing style issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This division of labor makes the writing process closer to the collaborative model of a traditional editorial department, but achieves higher efficiency through AI technology.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这样的分工让写作过程更接近传统编辑部的协作模式，但通过 AI 技术实现了更高的效率。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of application scenarios, GetDraft primarily targets professional writers and enterprise teams that need to maintain high-frequency and high-quality content output and ensure consistent content style. The development team emphasizes that this is not a free product; it currently uses a point-based reward mechanism, suitable for professional users who rely on writing long-term.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在应用场景方面，GetDraft 主要面向需要保持高频且高质量的内容输出、确保内容风格一致的专业写作者和企业团队。开发团队强调，这并不是一个免费产品，目前采用积分奖励机制，适合长期依赖写作的专业用户。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            GetDraft states that by letting AI handle repetitive, low-creativity tasks, the tool helps human authors focus their energy on more valuable creative aspects. In the future, the team plans to add more roles, such as AI layout experts and image selection experts, to further expand collaboration features.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            GetDraft 表示，通过让 AI 承担重复性、低创造性的工作，该工具能帮助人类作者集中精力在更具价值的创意环节。未来，团队计划增加更多角色，例如 AI 排版专家和配图专家，以进一步扩展协作功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蜜雪冰城跨界进军早餐市场，官方回应：暂限四城试点</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蜜雪冰城跨界进军早餐市场，官方回应：暂限四城试点</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9d1660fb-d55c-4611-8c0a-eb08686f1257.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to multiple media reports, tea beverage chain Mixue Bingcheng is entering the breakfast market. Currently, Mixue Bingcheng has launched a &quot;Breakfast Series&quot; on its official mini-program, including products like Five Red Milk, Five Black Milk, Corn Milk, and Coconut Milk, all priced at 5 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据多家媒体报道，茶饮连锁品牌蜜雪冰城正在进军早餐市场。目前，蜜雪冰城已在官方小程序上线「早餐系列」，包括五红奶、五黑奶、玉米奶、椰椰奶等产品，售价均为 5 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Furthermore, Mixue Bingcheng recently distributed a breakfast survey questionnaire through enterprise WeChat groups and Moments. The content covers various options such as soy milk, fried dough sticks, tofu pudding, corn, sweet potato, millet porridge, milk, coffee, and sandwiches, and collects consumer information including gender, age, occupation, province, and breakfast consumption habits.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，近日蜜雪冰城通过企业微信社群及朋友圈发布早餐调查问卷，内容涵盖豆浆、油条、豆腐脑、玉米、红薯、小米粥、牛奶、咖啡、三明治等多种选项，并收集消费者性别、年龄、职业、省份及早餐消费习惯等信息。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Jimu News cited sources reporting that the plan is only being piloted in cities such as Dalian, Xi'an, Nanning, and Hangzhou, with no arrangements for large-scale promotion yet.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            极目新闻援引消息人士报道称，该计划仅在大连、西安、南宁、杭州等城市进行试点，暂未有大规模推广的安排。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, Mixue Bingcheng had launched a &quot;Coffee + Bakery&quot; breakfast set in some stores, featuring a latte paired with a sandwich, priced at 10 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，蜜雪冰城曾在部分门店推出「咖啡 + 烘焙」早餐套餐，一杯拿铁搭配三明治，定价 10 元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Similar attempts are not uncommon in the industry. Brands like Heytea, Naixue's Tea, and Guming had already launched breakfast products between 2019 and 2020, with prices ranging from 9.9 yuan to 15 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            类似尝试在行业中并不罕见。喜茶、奈雪的茶、古茗等品牌早在 2019 至 2020 年间已推出早餐产品，价格区间在 9.9 元至 15 元之间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that Mixue Bingcheng has been making frequent moves in its diversified layout. On October 1st this year, the company announced it would spend approximately 297 million RMB to acquire a 53% stake in &quot;Xianpi Fulu Jia,&quot; officially entering the freshly tapped beer market. The brand was founded in 2021 and had approximately 1200 stores as of August 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，蜜雪冰城在多元化布局上动作频频。今年 10 月 1 日，公司宣布斥资约 2.97 亿元人民币收购「鲜啤福鹿家」53% 股权，正式进入现打鲜啤领域。该品牌成立于 2021 年，截至 2025 年 8 月已拥有约 1200 家门店。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Financial reports show that Mixue Bingcheng achieved revenue of 14.87 billion yuan in the first half of 2025, a year-on-year increase of 39.3%; net profit was 2.72 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 44.1%. As of the end of June, its total number of global stores increased to 53,014, covering China and 12 overseas countries.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            财报显示，蜜雪冰城 2025 年上半年实现收入 148.7 亿元，同比增长 39.3%；净利润 27.2 亿元，同比增长 44.1%。截至 6 月底，其全球门店总数增至 53014 家，覆盖中国及 12 个海外国家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>淘宝闪购取消超时扣款扩展至 60 城</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">淘宝闪购取消超时扣款扩展至-60-城</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/dcf76689-d347-4995-af21-3b8c8c9e89fa.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to a report by Bianews yesterday, Taobao Flash Sale announced that its policy of canceling overtime deductions for delivery riders has been extended to 60 cities and will cover all directly operated cities nationwide by the end of the year. This move marks a significant adjustment in the platform's rider service mechanism, aiming to improve fulfillment efficiency and user experience through a point system and positive incentives.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据鞭牛士昨日报道，淘宝闪购宣布取消外卖骑士超时扣款的政策已扩展至 60 城，并将在年底前覆盖全国直营城市。这一举措标志着平台在骑士服务机制上的重大调整，旨在通过积分制和正向激励提升履约效率与用户体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Specifically, Taobao Flash Sale has continued to promote a service score mechanism this year, replacing direct deductions with a system of 'points for good fulfillment and deductions for overdue delivery'. Compared to the previous direct deduction model, the new mechanism is more flexible and gentle:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            具体来看，淘宝闪购今年持续推广服务分机制，以「好的履约加分、超时送达扣分」的方式取代直接扣款。相比此前的直接扣款模式，新机制更具弹性与温和性：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rider's base score is set at 70 points; successful delivery without violations earns bonus points, and exceeding 75 points will also receive additional rewards;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an overdue situation occurs, a maximum of 2 points will be deducted each time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A rider stated: &quot;It's inevitable to encounter unexpected situations when making deliveries, such as detours in residential areas or elevator congestion. Previously, being overdue would result in direct deductions; now, a maximum of 2 points are deducted, making income more stable and eliminating the need to rush and take risks.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            一位骑士表示：「跑单难免遇到突发情况，比如小区绕路、电梯拥堵等，以前超时会直接扣款，现在最多扣 2 分，收入更稳定，也不用为了赶时间而冒险。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reports indicate that this policy will cover cities such as Beijing, Hangzhou, Guangzhou, Wuhan, Chengdu, Xiamen, Xi'an, Shijiazhuang, Hohhot, Changchun, Shenyang, and Dalian starting December 3rd, and will be extended to all directly operated cities by the end of the year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道显示，该政策将在 12 月 3 日起覆盖北京、杭州、广州、武汉、成都、厦门、西安、石家庄、呼和浩特、长春、沈阳、大连等城市，并在年底前推广至全部直营城市。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《最好的朋友》终极预告发布，12 月 5 日上映</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《最好的朋友》终极预告发布，12-月-5-日上映</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c5efc987-9b9a-45df-85b5-b58d27922981.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The youth realism film &quot;My Best Friend&quot; released its final trailer and poster yesterday, simultaneously opening nationwide pre-sales. Directed by young filmmaker Song Zhuofei, the film focuses on the autism community, unfolding a youth narrative about understanding and companionship through real experiences.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            青春现实主义题材电影《最好的朋友》昨日发布终极预告与海报，并同步开启全国预售。影片由青年导演宋卓非执导，聚焦孤独症群体，以真实体悟展开关于理解与陪伴的青春叙事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of the encounter and growth of high school student Zhao Fei (played by Yang Zhihe), girl Xia Qiu (played by Duan Aojuan), and autistic boy Xia Tian (played by Jyo Kairi).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述高中生赵飞（杨智赫 饰）、少女夏秋（段奥娟 饰）与孤独症少年夏天（城桧吏 饰）的相遇与成长。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The three move from their respective predicaments towards understanding and companionship, conveying the theme of &quot;lonely but not alone.&quot; Director Song Zhuofei has long been involved in autism charity services, transforming his real experiences into cinematic language, attempting to break social prejudices and present the unique spiritual world of the autism community.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            三人从各自的困境走向理解与陪伴，传递「孤独却不孤单」的主题。导演宋卓非长期参与孤独症公益服务，他将真实经验转化为镜头语言，试图打破社会偏见，呈现孤独症群体的独特精神世界。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, nationwide pre-sales for &quot;My Best Friend&quot; have begun, and the film will be released on December 5th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，《最好的朋友》全国预售现已开启，将于 12 月 5 日上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《得闲谨制》定档 12 月 6 日</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《得闲谨制》定档-12-月-6-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5f4c6c9c-8eba-4723-8132-40c73bc6256c.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;De Xian Jin Zhi&quot; is set to be released nationwide on December 6th, with pre-sales opening simultaneously.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《得闲谨制》定档 12 月 6 日全国上映，并同步开启预售。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, the film's production team released the &quot;Fighting for Home&quot; trailer and poster, showcasing the story of craftsman Mo Dexian's family facing life-and-death challenges and vowing to protect their homeland amidst the flames of war. The film is written by Lan Xiaolong, directed by Kong Sheng, with Hou Hongliang as chief producer, starring Xiao Zhan, Peng Yuchang, and Zhou Yiran, and with Yin Zheng making a special appearance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，片方发布了「为家而战」版预告与海报，展现了工匠莫得闲一家在战火中直面生死劫、誓守家园的故事情节。影片由兰晓龙编剧、孔笙执导，侯鸿亮担任总制片人，肖战、彭昱畅、周依然领衔主演，尹正特别出演。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film's plot focuses on mechanical factory fitter Mo Dexian (played by Xiao Zhan) and his family, who enter the mountains with a refugee group, living in Gezhi Town with anti-aircraft gun commander Xiao Yan (played by Peng Yuchang) and scattered soldiers. However, the town's tranquility is shattered by Japanese reconnaissance soldiers, and the villagers vow to defend their homeland, engaging in a desperate struggle of folk wisdom against regular armed forces.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片剧情聚焦机械厂钳工莫得闲（肖战 饰）与家人随逃难队伍进入山区，在戈止镇与防空炮长肖衍（彭昱畅 饰）及散兵游勇共同生活。然而镇子宁静被日本侦察兵打破，百姓誓死守护家园，展开一场民间智慧对抗正规武装的殊死较量。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The production team emphasizes that the &quot;meticulous production&quot; attitude runs through the entire creative process, striving to present a new perspective on the people's resistance war in both narrative and visuals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            制作团队强调，「谨制」态度贯穿创作始终，力求在叙事与影像中呈现百姓抗战的新视角。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Fun Thing｜iPhone 17 Pro 全程拍摄，短片《A Critter Carol》获库克好评</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">One-Fun-Thing｜iPhone-17-Pro-全程拍摄，短片《A-Critter-Carol》获库克好评</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/31e224a4-a61a-436e-ac00-980e6d14c48c.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Apple CEO Tim Cook posted on X, praising Apple's 2025 Thanksgiving holiday short film &quot;A Critter Carol,&quot; calling it full of &quot;magic and love.&quot; The short film was entirely shot on iPhone 17 Pro.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，苹果 CEO Tim Cook 在 X 发文，点赞苹果 2025 年度感恩节假日短片《A Critter Carol》，称其充满「魔法与爱心」，该短片全程由 iPhone 17 Pro 拍摄。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The short film is set in a snow-covered forest, with the story revolving around handmade puppets such as raccoons, bears, deer, and owls.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            短片设定在白雪覆盖的森林中，故事围绕浣熊、熊、鹿和猫头鹰等手工木偶展开。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            They accidentally discover a lost iPhone and use it to record a song about friendship. In the climax of the story, the owner locates the phone using the &quot;Find My&quot; feature on their Apple Watch, ultimately discovering the heartwarming video left by the little animals.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            它们偶然发现一部遗失的 iPhone，并用其录制了一首关于友谊的歌曲。剧情高潮部分，失主通过 Apple Watch 的「查找」功能定位手机，最终发现了小动物们留下的温馨录像。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Director Mark Molloy fully utilized the iPhone 17 Pro's 8x optical zoom, Center Stage, and Dual Capture (simultaneous front and rear camera activation) features during the creative process, allowing the film to showcase an immersive and warm atmosphere within its professional narrative.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            导演马克・莫洛伊在创作过程中充分利用了 iPhone 17 Pro 的 8 倍光学变焦、人物居中（Center Stage）以及前后摄像头同时启用的双重拍摄（Dual Capture）功能，使影片在专业叙事中展现出沉浸感与温情氛围。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Cook stated in his tweet: &quot;The festive joy, a touch of magic, and plenty of warmth were all captured by a few handmade puppet friends using iPhone 17 Pro.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            库克在推文中表示：「节日的欢乐气氛，一点点魔法，以及满满的温情，都被几个手工制作的木偶朋友用 iPhone 17 Pro 记录了下来」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>周末看什么｜《怪奇物语》第五季</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">周末看什么｜《怪奇物语》第五季</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a93d205a-73f0-4aa6-af45-c9c6f4f55726.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Stranger Things Season 5, Volume 1, consisting of 4 episodes, continues the dark crisis in Hawkins. Vecna returns, Eleven and Will unleash stronger superpowers, and the main squad must not only face the ultimate showdown but also confront their inner demons.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《怪奇物语》第五季第 1 辑共 4 集，延续了霍金斯小镇的黑暗危机 。威可那再度登场，伊莱雯与威尔释放更强超能力，主角小队不仅要面对终极对决，还需直面心魔。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Max's return in the show becomes crucial; she is trapped in Vecna's memory world and eventually uses music to guide her closer to reality, but remains hindered. Furthermore, the military's intervention in Hawkins failed to provide substantial help, instead intensifying the search for Eleven, further increasing the plot's tension.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            剧中麦克丝的回归成为关键，她在威可那的记忆世界中被困，最终通过音乐指引接近现实，但仍受阻。此外，军方在霍金斯的介入未能提供实质帮助，反而加剧了对伊莱雯的搜捕，使剧情张力进一步提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After its official launch, 'Stranger Things' Season 5 received extremely positive initial reviews on Douban, scoring as high as 9.6 (7810 reviews), with 84.7% giving it five stars. Reviews generally praised the first four episodes for their tight plot, rich information, and more developed character arcs, especially Will's superpower awakening, which became one of the biggest highlights.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            正式上线后，《怪奇物语》第五季在豆瓣平台的开分评价极为正面，评分高达 9.6（7810 人评价），其中 84.7% 打出五星。评论普遍认为前四集剧情紧凑、信息量大，角色成长线更为饱满，尤其是威尔的超能觉醒成为最大亮点之一。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            However, 'Stranger Things' Season 5's media freshness score on Rotten Tomatoes was only 86% (based on 49 reviews), marking the lowest opening score in the series' history, a decline compared to Season 1's 97%, Season 2's 94%, and Seasons 3 and 4's 89%. Nevertheless, the audience score remains high at 91%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不过，《怪奇物语》第五季在烂番茄平台的媒体新鲜度评分仅为 86%（基于 49 篇评论），创下系列历史最低开分，相比第一季的 97%、第二季的 94% 以及第三、四季的 89% 均有所下滑。不过观众评分依然高达 91%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the official schedule, episodes 5 to 7 of Season 5 will air on Christmas Day, December 25th, with the grand finale launching on New Year's Eve, December 31st. Part 2 is set to launch on December 26th.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            根据官方排期，第五季第 5 至 7 集将于 12 月 25 日圣诞节播出，最终大结局将在 12 月 31 日跨年夜上线。而第 2 辑则定于 12 月 26 日上线。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>买书不读指南｜《海上无航标》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">买书不读指南｜《海上无航标》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/894cff99-199c-4ace-bc70-4baa634aa044.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            'No Navigation Marks at Sea' tells the story of journalist Edmond, who, after being diagnosed with a terminal illness, chooses to board an ocean liner and sail into the deep sea with Laura, whom he secretly admires.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《海上无航标》讲述记者埃德蒙在身患绝症后选择登上远洋客轮，与暗中倾慕的劳拉一同驶向深海的故事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The voyage has no clear destination, symbolizing that life, as it approaches its end, no longer needs navigation marks. The work reveals the subtle tremors of human emotion through unspoken words at dusk on deck, standing side by side in foreign ports, and existential questioning in the face of the vast ocean.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            航程没有明确目的地，象征生命在临近终点时已不再需要航标。作品通过甲板黄昏的欲言又止、异国港口的并肩而立以及面对浩瀚海洋的存在追问，展现了人类情感的微妙震颤。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Vita was Virginia Woolf's soulmate and the prototype for 'Orlando'. Her exploration of the literary and emotional worlds reaches its zenith in this work.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            薇塔是弗吉尼亚 · 伍尔夫的灵魂伴侣，也是《奥兰多》的原型人物。她在文学与情感世界的探索在这部作品中达到极致。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            'No Navigation Marks at Sea' explores the selflessness and selfishness of love, the finite and infinite nature of life, ultimately responding to the inevitability of death with the protagonist's silence and restraint.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《海上无航标》探讨了爱情的无私与自私、生命的有限与无限，最终以主人公的沉默与克制回应死亡的必然。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>游戏推荐｜《极限国度》Steam 一折特惠</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">游戏推荐｜《极限国度》Steam-一折特惠</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251129_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/90621563-8a65-4da4-aeb1-a2a1a87705a2.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ubisoft's extreme sports game 'Riders Republic' is set in multiple US national parks, where players can experience sports like cycling, snowboarding, skiing, and wingsuit flying. It supports large-scale racing events with up to 64 players simultaneously, emphasizing free exploration and an immersive multiplayer interactive experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            育碧旗下极限运动游戏《极限国度》背景设定在美国多个国家公园，玩家可体验自行车、单板滑雪、双板滑雪与翼装飞行等运动，并支持最多 64 人同时参与的大型竞速赛事，强调自由探索与多人互动的沉浸式体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of media reviews, IGN gave it an 8, finding it highly entertaining in its arcade-style extreme sports presentation, with rich gameplay and smooth controls. GamingTrend, however, pointed out the weak game plot and lack of competitive drive, but noted that the first-person mode and multiplayer events still provide a highly immersive experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在媒体评价方面，IGN 给出 8 分，认为其在街机化的极限运动表现上极具娱乐性，玩法丰富且操作流畅。GamingTrend 则指出游戏剧情薄弱，缺乏竞争驱动力，但第一人称模式与多人赛事依然能带来高度沉浸的体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Overall, media generally recognized its open world and sports diversity but also pointed out that server stability, bugs, and microtransaction design are still issues needing optimization.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            整体而言，媒体普遍认可其开放世界与运动多样性，但也指出服务器稳定性、Bug 以及微交易设计仍是亟待优化的问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, until December 7th, 'Riders Republic' is available on Steam with a 90% discount, costing only 19.8 yuan to add to your library, and has received &quot;Very Positive&quot; reviews among over 10,000 simplified Chinese players.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前到 12 月 7 日，《极限国度》在 Steam 商店一折特惠，19.8 元即可入库，在 1 万余名简体中文玩家中评价为「特别好评」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
