<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>第十五届全国运动会在广州隆重开幕</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">第十五届全国运动会在广州隆重开幕</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f299f304-2d88-4c60-98f1-09343094e297.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 9, the opening ceremony of the 15th National Games was held at the Guangdong Olympic Sports Center.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 9 日，第十五届全国运动会开幕式在广东奥林匹克体育中心举行。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The cultural and sports performance, themed &quot;Realizing Dreams for the Future,&quot; consisted of three chapters: &quot;Same Roots, Same Origin,&quot; &quot;United Hearts, Shared Destiny,&quot; and &quot;Shared Dreams, Full Circle.&quot; It innovatively utilized sports elements, artistic methods, and cutting-edge technology to vividly interpret the theme of this National Games: &quot;Passionate National Games, Vibrant Greater Bay Area.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中文体展演以《圆梦未来》为主题，整个演出由「同根同源」「同心同缘」「同梦同圆」3 个篇章组成，创新运用体育元素、艺术手段和前沿科技，生动诠释了本届全运会「激情全运会，活力大湾区」的主题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 2, the torch for the 15th National Games was simultaneously relayed across Guangdong, Hong Kong, and Macao, finally converging at the Guangdong Olympic Sports Center. Under the spotlight, 12 torchbearers, including Ma Lin, Chen Ruolin, Wong Kam-po, Fong Man-ho, Guo Jingjing, Wang Xinyu, Wang Liuyi, Wang Qianyi, Liang Weikeng, Lai Xuanzhi, Xian Dongmei, and Rong Zhixing, carried out the relay, with Su Bingtian, Cheung Ka-long, and Li Yi jointly lighting the main torch of the National Games.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 2 日，第十五届全运会火炬在粤港澳三地同步传递，最后汇入广东奥体中心。万众瞩目下，马琳、陈若琳、黄金宝、方文浩、郭晶晶、王欣瑜、王柳懿、王芊懿、梁伟铿、赖宣治、冼东妹、容志行等 12 位火炬手接力传递，最后由苏炳添、张家朗、李祎共同点燃全运会主火炬。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9606e0d9-c60a-40f9-bc68-fecd02092927.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;editor-image-source&quot;&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;Photo courtesy of Xinhua News Agency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At this opening ceremony, the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Joint Grand Orchestra's performance also featured robot musicians playing an array of chimes. According to Xinhua News Agency, at the National Games, the flame from the depths of the South China Sea &quot;burned ice into a torch,&quot; unmanned vehicles and electronic dogs operated without hindrance, and 3D, 5G, and AI technologies provided an immersive viewing experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次开幕式上，粤港澳联合大乐团合奏中还采用了阵列敲击编钟的机器人乐手。据新华社报道，全运会上，来自南海深处的火种「燃冰成炬」，无人车、电子狗无障碍运行，3D、5G、AI 技术满足沉浸式观赛体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             It is reported that this National Games is expected to have over 6,000 participants from the mainland traveling to Hong Kong and Macao, and over 3,000 participants from Hong Kong and Macao coming to the mainland.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             据悉，本届全运会预计内地前往港澳参赛人员超 6000 人、港澳来内地参赛人员超 3000 人。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding venues and viewing experience, over 90% of the venues have been renovated and upgraded for reuse. Photovoltaic power generation enables venues to be &quot;self-sufficient,&quot; and green simplicity runs throughout the event. There is no air conditioning for cooling, AR provides precise navigation to audience seats, and accessible and age-friendly facilities are ubiquitous, with one-click call for sign language interpretation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而在场馆及观看体验上，超九成场馆为利旧改造升级，光伏发电实现场馆「自发自用」，绿色简约贯穿办赛始终；无空调制冷降温、AR 精准导航观众座位；无障碍及全龄友好设施处处可见、一键呼叫手语翻译。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The 15th National Games will conclude on November 21, with over 14,000 athletes participating in competitive events and approximately 11,000 public athletes participating in mass sports activities.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            第十五届全运会将于 11 月 21 日闭幕，共有 1.4 万多名运动员参加竞技比赛项目，约 1.1 万名群众运动员参加群众赛事活动。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;大公司&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/da_gong_si.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>苹果计划对 iPhone 卫星功能进行升级</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">苹果计划对-iPhone-卫星功能进行升级</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/4fb200af-e634-4f50-92ea-ace12a468b50.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Bloomberg reporter Mark Gurman revealed yesterday in his &quot;Power On&quot; column that Apple is accelerating the upgrade of satellite features for iPhone and Apple Watch, planning to introduce multiple new features in the coming years to further enhance device usability in environments without network coverage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            彭博社记者 Mark Gurman 昨日在「Power On」专栏中透露，苹果正在加速推进 iPhone 与 Apple Watch 的卫星功能升级，计划在未来数年内引入多项新特性，以进一步提升设备在无网络环境下的可用性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report states that Apple's satellite strategy initially envisioned replacing traditional cellular networks with satellites, but it eventually materialized as the &quot;Emergency SOS&quot; feature. Since iPhone 14, this feature has gradually expanded to road assistance, non-emergency text communication, and supports Apple Watch Ultra 3.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道称，苹果的卫星战略最初设想是以卫星替代传统蜂窝网络，但最终落地为「紧急 SOS」功能。自 iPhone 14 起，该功能逐步扩展至道路救援、非紧急短信通信，并支持 Apple Watch Ultra 3。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the future, Apple plans to further open up satellite APIs for third-party applications, supporting map navigation, image message transmission, and improving the &quot;natural use&quot; experience, allowing devices to remain connected without needing to point directly at the sky.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            未来，苹果计划进一步开放第三方应用的卫星 API，支持地图导航、图片消息传输，并改善「自然使用」体验，使设备无需直指天空即可保持连接。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that Apple's satellite services currently rely on the Globalstar network, but as operators like SpaceX and T-Mobile accelerate their deployments, industry competition is intensifying. If SpaceX acquires Globalstar, Apple may need to re-evaluate its long-term strategy.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，目前苹果的卫星服务依赖 Globalstar 网络，但随着 SpaceX 与 T-Mobile 等运营商加速布局，行业竞争加剧。若 SpaceX 收购 Globalstar，苹果可能需要重新评估其长期战略。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding Apple AI, the report also mentioned that although it was recently revealed that Siri will be rebuilt using a customized Google Gemini model (with an annual payment of $1 billion), according to leaks, Apple will independently develop a 1 trillion-parameter Apple Intelligence model next year for consumer use.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在苹果 AI 方面，报道还提到，虽然近期被曝将通过 Google Gemini 的定制模型重构 Siri（每年支付 10 亿美元），但据爆料，苹果将会在明年完全自主研发一款 1 万亿参数尺寸的 Apple Intelligence 模型，并供消费者使用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Gurman also stated that the new version of Siri will not be able to utilize this 1 trillion-parameter model. The next generation of Siri is expected to be launched next spring with iOS 26.4, internally codenamed &quot;Linwood.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Gurman 也表示，新版 Siri 吃不上这 款 1 万亿参数的模型。新一代 Siri 预计将在明年春季随 iOS 26.4 推出，内部代号为「Linwood」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, Apple's new customized model via Google boasts a scale of 1.2 trillion parameters, far exceeding the existing Apple Intelligence's 150 billion parameters. Internally, it is referred to as &quot;AFM v10 (Apple Foundation Model v10)&quot; to prevent confusion among employees and customers, emphasizing that the underlying architecture still significantly overlaps with Apple's internal systems.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，苹果通过 Google 定制的新模型规模达 1.2 万亿参数，远超现有 Apple Intelligence 的 1500 亿参数。内部将其称为「AFM v10（苹果第十代基础模型）」，防止员工和客户混淆，并强调底层架构仍与苹果内部系统存在显著重叠。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, Apple has several AI plans scheduled for 2026: Siri may be redesigned in iOS 27; there are plans to launch an AI-powered web search tool; the Health App will also be AI-enabled and will offer a new Health+ service to help users better manage their health.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，苹果还有多项定于 2026 年的 AI 计划：或会在 iOS 27 重新设计 Siri；计划推出一款 AI 驱动的网络搜索工具；健康 App 也将迎来 AI 化，并且会提供全新的 Health+ 服务，帮助用户更好地管理健康。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>我国拟就汽车「开门杀」等做出明确解释</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">我国拟就汽车「开门杀」等做出明确解释</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xinhua News Agency reported yesterday that the Supreme People's Court released the &quot;Interpretation on Several Issues Concerning the Application of Law in the Trial of Cases Involving Traffic Accident Liability Disputes (II) (Draft for Comment)&quot; on November 9, soliciting public opinions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新华网昨日报道，最高人民法院 11 月 9 日公布《关于审理交通事故责任纠纷案件适用法律若干问题的解释（二）（征求意见稿）》，向社会公开征求意见。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that this judicial interpretation intends to make provisions on issues such as &quot;door-opening accidents&quot; and personal injury to the motor vehicle party caused by traffic accidents between electric bicycles and motor vehicles. The deadline for comments is November 15.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，该司法解释拟就「开门杀」、电动自行车与机动车发生交通事故造成机动车一方人身损害等问题作出规定，征求意见截止日期为 11 月 15 日。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The draft for comment stipulates:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            征求意见稿规定：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the owner, manager, and user of a motor vehicle are not the same person due to circumstances such as leasing or borrowing, and a traffic accident causes harm to others, if it is the motor vehicle's fault, and the owner or manager of the motor vehicle is at fault for the occurrence of the harm, and the injured party requests that both the motor vehicle user and the motor vehicle owner/manager bear tort liability, the motor vehicle user who caused the harm shall bear full liability as the tortfeasor. The motor vehicle owner/manager shall bear joint liability with the motor vehicle user within the scope of their fault, but the total amount of compensation actually paid by the responsible parties should not exceed the amount of loss the injured party is entitled to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a motor vehicle passenger opens a door causing harm to others, and the injured party claims that the passenger's liability is part of the motor vehicle's liability, and requests the insurer of compulsory motor vehicle traffic accident liability insurance to compensate within the liability limit and the insurer of commercial third-party liability insurance to compensate according to the insurance contract under Article 1213 of the Civil Code, the People's Court shall support it; if the insurer claims not to bear compensation liability to the injured party on the grounds that the passenger is not an insured person or an authorized driver, the People's Court shall not support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a traffic accident occurs between an electric bicycle and a motor vehicle, causing personal injury to the motor vehicle party, and the motor vehicle party has evidence to prove that the electric bicycle party is at fault and claims that the electric bicycle party should bear compensation liability, the People's Court, in determining the amount of compensation, shall comprehensively consider factors such as the degree of fault of the perpetrator, the consequences of the harm, and the degree of danger of the vehicles involved in the accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, the draft for comment also makes provisions for traffic accidents involving non-commercial motor vehicles causing harm to gratuitous passengers, and traffic accidents involving motor vehicles engaged in road transport operations through affiliation, among other issues. The Supreme People's Court welcomes valuable opinions from all sectors of society and requests that specific reasons be provided when submitting suggestions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，征求意见稿还针对非营运机动车发生交通事故造成无偿搭乘人损害，以挂靠形式从事道路运输经营活动的机动车发生交通事故等作出规定。最高法表示，欢迎社会各界提出宝贵意见，并请在提出意见建议时说明具体理由。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>「杭州六小龙」乌镇同框</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">「杭州六小龙」乌镇同框</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2c4f87d9-2e94-4369-a1b7-063ec70b6388.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 7, at the World Internet Conference Wuzhen Summit, the heads of six &quot;Hangzhou Little Dragons&quot; enterprises—Unitree Robotics, BrainCo, Kujiale, Deep Robotics, Game Science, and DeepSeek—appeared on stage together for the first time, discussing technological innovation and industrial breakthroughs under the moderation of Academician Wang Jian.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 7 日，世界互联网大会乌镇峰会上，宇树科技、强脑科技、群核科技、云深处科技、游戏科学、深度求索六家「杭州六小龙」企业负责人首次同台，在王坚院士主持下探讨技术创新与产业突围。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Wang Xingxing of Unitree Robotics emphasized that robot development stems from &quot;global co-creation&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            —Chinese enterprises provide affordable high-performance hardware platforms, and global developers jointly develop software and algorithms. He believes that embodied intelligence and humanoid robots are closer to realizing dreams compared to technologies like nuclear fusion.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             宇树科技王兴兴强调机器人发展源于「全球共创」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ——中国企业提供廉价高性能硬件平台，全球开发者共同开发软件和算法。他认为相比核聚变等技术，具身智能和人形机器人更接近梦想实现。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Han Bicong of BrainCo shared the productization path of brain-computer interfaces &quot;from pain to widespread adoption,&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            first helping people with disabilities, then expanding to mass markets such like sleep and weight management. The biggest challenge is analyzing data from 86 to hundreds of billions of neurons in the brain. He gave an example: when fitting a prosthetic hand for an uncle who had lost his right hand decades ago, the uncle had completely forgotten the sensation of his fingers, so an AI model had to be used to help him relearn like a baby.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             强脑科技韩璧丞分享脑机接口「从痛到大」的产品化路径
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，先帮助残疾人，再推广至睡眠、体重管理等大众市场。最大挑战是解析大脑 860 亿到上千亿个神经元的数据。他举例说，给失去右手几十年的大伯做假肢时，对方已完全忘记手指感觉，只能用 AI 模型让其像婴儿一样重新学习。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Huang Xiaohuang of Kujiale elaborated on the value of spatial intelligence
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , discovering that the Scaling Law also applies to spatial models. The company's strategy shifted from &quot;charging humans&quot; to &quot;charging machines,&quot; because AI reduces creative jobs, but the number of machines working for humans will increase tenfold.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             群核科技黄晓煌阐述空间智能价值
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，发现 Scaling Law 在空间模型上同样适用。公司战略从「向人类收费」转向「向机器收费」，因为 AI 让创意岗位减少，但替人工作的机器会增加十倍。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Zhu Qiuguo from Yunchen emphasizes application scenario-driven development.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            When robot dogs were used for power inspection in 2018, on-site tests revealed issues such as rubber pad wear, machine overheating, and rain damage. The team continuously improved based on this, and this year released the world's first outdoor-capable protective humanoid robot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             云深处朱秋国强调应用场景驱动。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            2018 年机器狗用于电力巡检时，现场测试发现橡胶垫磨损、机器发热、遇雨损坏等问题，团队据此不断改进，今年发布全球首台可走向室外的防护型人形机器人。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Feng Ji from Game Science points out that the success of &quot;Black Myth: Wukong&quot; is the result of ten years of accumulation in China's gaming industry.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Data shows that among the top 10 global revenue-generating games last year, 4 were developed by Chinese teams, and another 3 had participation from Chinese companies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             游戏科学冯骥指出，《黑神话：悟空》成功是中国游戏产业十年积累的结果。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            数据显示，去年全球收入前 10 游戏中，4 款来自中国团队研发，另有 3 款由中国公司参与。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Chen Deli from DeepSeek states that DeepSeek's core advantage is long-termism
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , insisting on the main line of breakthrough in cutting-edge intelligence, and in this process, DeepSeek has also abandoned many side tasks, not doing those short-term, quick-win side things.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             深度求索陈德里表示，DeepSeek 核心优势就是长期主义
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，坚持做前沿智能突破这条主线，而在这个过程中，DeepSeek 也舍弃了很多支线上的事情，不做那些短平快的支线事情。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding future challenges and social impact,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Wang Xingxing believes the biggest challenge for robots is embodied AI models.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Unlike large language models, the robotics field has diverse hardware, dispersed data, and no unified standard for sensor placement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            就未来挑战和社会影响方面，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             王兴兴认为机器人最大挑战是具身智能 AI 模型。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            与大语言模型不同，机器人领域硬件各异、数据分散、传感器位置无统一标准。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhu Qiuguo further elaborated on two major challenges: embodied mobility (navigation without prior knowledge) and embodied manipulation (completing complex tasks with two hands). He admitted that the path is unclear and requires innovative model architectures to reduce computational and data demands.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而朱秋国细化了两大挑战：具身移动（无先验知识的导航）和具身操作（双手完成复杂任务）。他坦言路径不清晰，需创新模型架构，降低算力和数据需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, Han Bicheng pointed out that 36% of human medical expenses are related to the brain, but diseases like Alzheimer's and autism have no cure. Data collection and analysis for brain-computer interfaces are extremely difficult. He sees a &quot;beautiful closed loop&quot;: AI theory is inspired by the brain, and now AI is in turn helping to overcome brain science challenges.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，韩璧丞指出，人类 36% 医疗花销与大脑相关，但阿尔茨海默病、自闭症等无药可治。脑机接口数据采集和解析难度极大。他看到「美妙闭环」：AI 理论受大脑启发，现在 AI 反过来帮助攻克脑科学难题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>消息称 Meta 产品经理已经用氛围编程开发 App</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">消息称-Meta-产品经理已经用氛围编程开发-App</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Business Insider, Meta's product managers are already using &quot;Vibe Coding&quot; for App prototype development, and the projects will be directly presented to CEO Mark Zuckerberg.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 Business Insider 报道，Meta 的产品经理已经用上「氛围编程」（Vibe Coding）来进行 App 的原型开发，并且项目会直接向 CEO 扎克伯格展示。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that Meta product manager Joseph Spisak recently revealed at the TechEquity AI Summit that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             product managers within Meta are already using &quot;Vibe Coding&quot; for product development, &quot;which allows us to quickly iterate and explore product development.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，Meta 产品经理 Joseph Spisak 日前在参加 TechEquity AI 峰会时透露，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             目前 Meta 内部已经有产品经理使用「氛围编程」（Vibe Coding）进行产品开发，「这使我们能够快速迭代和探索产品开发。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Spisak stated that Meta employees are constantly using Vibe Coding for actual product implementation, and Meta's &quot;internal system&quot; (or referring to Meta's internal Vibe Coding system) is powerful enough to allow non-engineer employees to adjust product interfaces in real-time to meet their ideas.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Spisak 表示，Meta 内部员工已经无时无刻在使用氛围编程进行真正的产品落地，并且 Meta 的「内部系统」（或代指 Meta 内部的氛围编程系统）强大到足以让非工程师的员工也能实时调整产品界面，满足自己的想法。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is understood that Vibe Coding only requires developers to focus on expressing the desired functions and effects, with almost no need to care about the details of code implementation, as AI handles code generation and iterative debugging. Users can use natural language to have AI generate code.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据了解，氛围编程只需要开发者只需专注于表达想要的功能和效果，几乎不需要关心代码实现的细节，由 AI 来完成代码生成和反复调试修改。使用者可以通过自然语言，让 AI 进行代码生成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            And Meta is not unique in the industry. It is reported that Google CEO Sundar Pichai previously revealed that the company requires employees to use AI at all stages of product development, and over a quarter of the internal code is completed by AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而 Meta 也并非行业独一无二。据悉，Google CEO Sundar Pichai 此前曾透露，公司要求员工在产品开发各阶段使用 AI，并且内部超四分之一的代码都由 AI 完成。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>腾势总经理透露超级跑车腾势 Z 正在跑纽北</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">腾势总经理透露超级跑车腾势-Z-正在跑纽北</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7b1ea105-31c2-4218-88a2-f5c8a05177cc.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Li Hui, General Manager of Denza Auto, posted that its supercar Denza Z is currently running on the Nürburgring track in Germany, Europe.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，腾势汽车总经理李慧发文透露，旗下超级跑车腾势 Z 目前正在欧洲跑德国纽博格林赛道。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He stated that the Denza Z will be a top-tier work and a super cool high-performance supercar, embodying years of dedicated design and meticulous craftsmanship by thousands of engineers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其表示，腾势 Z 将是一款顶级作品，并且也会是一款超级炫酷的高性能超级跑车，该车型凝聚了几千名工程师多年的用心设计和精心打造。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that the new car was spotted by media motor.es in October, testing on the Nürburgring track. The car features a wide-body design and a large rear wing, with its overall aerodynamic performance drawing significant attention.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，新车在 10 月被媒体 motor.es 发现，其现身纽北赛道进行测试。该车采用宽体设计，配备大型尾翼，整体空气动力学表现引人关注。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that the new car's front face features double &quot;L&quot; and &quot;V&quot; shaped LED light strips, with the front dominated by three large air intakes, guide vanes on both sides, and an extended lower lip spoiler to enhance downforce. The wide wheel arches house three heat dissipation vents, covering giant brake discs, clamped by large calipers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，新车前脸搭载双「L」与「V」形 LED 灯条，车头由三个大型进气口主导，两侧设有导流槽，下唇延伸扰流板增强下压力。宽大轮拱上布置三个散热口，覆盖巨型刹车盘，并由大型卡钳夹持。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition, openings on the front hood are used to cool mechanical components on the axle, the side skirts are sharp, and air guide openings are present on and behind both front and rear wheel arches. The most striking design is the massive rear wing, further highlighting its high-performance positioning.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此外，前机盖开口用于冷却轴上机械部件，车身侧裙锋利，前后轮拱及其后方均设有空气导流开口。最为醒目的设计是硕大的尾翼，进一步凸显其高性能定位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>王兴兴回应硕士论文上热搜</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">王兴兴回应硕士论文上热搜</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, a CCTV reporter interviewed Wang Xingxing, founder of Unitree Robotics, listening to him recount the story of how his dream of technological innovation grew and blossomed over the past few years.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，央视记者对话了宇树科技创始人王兴兴，听其讲述科技创新的梦想在过去几年成长开花的故事。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, a recent online &quot;archaeological dig&quot; by netizens unearthed Wang Xingxing's master's thesis, which went viral. People discovered that as early as 2016, he already had the prototype of the Unitree robot dog, marveling at his foresight regarding technology and trends. Wang Xingxing also responded to this thesis for the first time.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据报道，最近有网友考古出了王兴兴的硕士论文上了热搜，大家发现原来在 2016 年，他就已经有了宇树机器狗的雏形，大家惊叹于他对技术和趋势的预判力。王兴兴也首次回应了这篇论文。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Xingxing revealed that the idea of making robot dogs came very early. &quot;At that time, the plan for that robot dog was conceived in 2013. When I thought of the plan, I considered dropping out of school to start a business, but it was just a thought at the time because I had nothing. Later, I made the thing.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            王兴兴透露，其实做机器狗的想法是很早的，「当时那款机器狗是 2013 年想到的方案，我想到方案的时候就想着要不要辍学出来创业，但是当时只是想想而已，因为东西都没有，后来就把这个东西给做出来了。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Wang Xingxing stated that
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Unitree Robotics had already conceived and implemented at least parts of its quadruped robot business and development direction in 2014 and 2015.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            王兴兴表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             宇树科技在过去的至少四足机器人的部分业务和发展方向，2014 年、2015 年都已经想过了，然后把它给实现了。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, Wang Xingxing also stated,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;Later, the AI of the entire robot, including the AI technology progress of large models, was obvious to all, reopening everyone's imagination, and we can see that the development speed of humanoid robots has been very fast in recent years.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，王兴兴还表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「后来整个机器人的 AI，包括大模型的 AI 技术进步有目共睹，把大家的想象空间又重新打开了，可以看到最近这些年人形机器人的发展速度非常快。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He believes that,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             the field of technology is always ahead of its time
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            :
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其认为，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             科技领域都是超前的
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;You need to imagine what direction you should take in the future; as long as your direction is correct, you will inevitably succeed. However, precisely because this field is currently quite advanced, you might find it difficult to get started. But difficulty in starting also has its advantages, as others can't easily enter, and perhaps only you can do it in this field, which actually offers great potential for accumulating strength and achieving success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>英特尔前员工被控下载 1.8 万份机密文件，公司索赔 25 万美元</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">英特尔前员工被控下载-1.8-万份机密文件，公司索赔-25-万美元</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             According to OregonLive, Intel recently sued former software developer Luo Jinfeng in a Washington federal court, accusing him of downloading approximately 18,000 confidential documents before and after his dismissal, many of which were marked &quot;Top Secret.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             据 OregonLive 报道，英特尔近日在华盛顿联邦法院起诉前软件开发员罗金峰，指控其在被解雇前后下载了约 18000 份机密文件，其中大量文件被标记为「顶级机密（Top Secret）」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The lawsuit states that Luo Jinfeng worked at Intel since 2014, received a dismissal notice on July 7, and officially left on July 31. Intel did not specify the reason for the dismissal, but the company had already laid off over 15,000 people last year to cut costs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            诉状显示，罗金峰自 2014 年起在英特尔工作，7 月 7 日收到解雇通知，7 月 31 日正式离职。英特尔未说明解雇原因，但去年公司已裁员超过 15000 人以削减成本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Intel stated that Luo Jinfeng was blocked by the security system on July 23 when attempting to transfer files to an external hard drive, but successfully completed the download five days later using another storage device. This action triggered a company investigation, and Intel subsequently made multiple attempts to contact him at his addresses in Seattle and Portland, but all were unsuccessful.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            英特尔称，罗金峰在 7 月 23 日尝试将文件转移至外部硬盘时被安全系统阻止，但五天后成功通过另一存储设备完成下载。该行为触发公司调查，英特尔随后多次尝试联系其在西雅图及波特兰的住址，但均未果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Currently, Intel has applied to the court for at least $250,000 in damages and legal fees, and requested an injunction to prevent the leakage of confidential information. Luo Jinfeng himself has not yet responded, and the company has declined further comment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            目前，英特尔已向法院申请至少 25 万美元赔偿及律师费，并要求发布禁令以防止机密信息外泄。罗金峰本人尚未回应，公司也拒绝进一步置评。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蚂蚁集团 CEO：AQ 承载蚂蚁健康新使命，让看病更简单、生活更健康</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">蚂蚁集团-CEO：AQ-承载蚂蚁健康新使命，让看病更简单、生活更健康</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6bb702a8-2612-4499-a8ae-a1af15b57bf9.jpeg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 8, at the Wuzhen Summit, Ant Group CEO Han Xinyi, as a corporate representative, shared his thoughts and practices in the field of AI medical health.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 8 日，乌镇峰会上，蚂蚁集团 CEO 韩歆毅作为企业代表分享了在 AI 医疗健康领域的思考与实践。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Previously, after its AI health application AQ's monthly active users surpassed 10 million, Ant announced the establishment of a health business group and promoted medical health business to become a strategic pillar of Ant. Han Xinyi stated at the scene that this organizational upgrade carries Ant's new mission: to make seeing a doctor simpler and life healthier.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此前，继旗下 AI 健康应用 AQ 月活用户突破千万后，蚂蚁宣布成立健康事业群，并推动医疗健康业务成为蚂蚁的战略支柱板块，韩歆毅在现场表示，此次组织升级承载了蚂蚁的新使命：让看病更简单、生活更健康。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Han Xinyi stated in his speech that,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             with social development, people's health needs are continuously upgrading
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            . For example, there are over 500 million chronic disease patients nationwide, facing issues of low awareness, low treatment rates, and low control rates, with over 80% of approximately 270 million hypertension patients failing to effectively control their condition. Furthermore, the demand for health preservation, elderly care, and rehabilitation nursing among the approximately 310 million elderly population nationwide has surged, and younger generations like the post-90s and post-00s have also become the main force in health consumption.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            韩歆毅在演讲中表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             伴随着社会发展，老百姓的健康需求正持续升级
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，如全国慢病患者超 5 亿，存在着低知晓率、低治疗率、低控制率问题，约 2.7 亿高血压患者中有超八成未能有效控制病情；此外，全国约 3.1 亿老年人口对养生养老、康复护理的需求激增，90 后、00 后等年轻群体也成为健康消费的主力军。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            AI provides a key path to solve social health pain points – Han Xinyi cited Ant's AI health application AQ, launched in June this year, as an example. This application, built on Ant's medical large model, features core characteristics such as proactive questioning and proactive record-keeping, covering hundreds of AI functions including health popularization, consultation, report interpretation, and health archives.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            AI 为破解社会健康痛点提供了关键路径——韩歆毅以蚂蚁今年 6 月推出的 AI 健康应用 AQ 为例，这款依托蚂蚁医疗大模型打造的应用，具备主动追问、主动建档等核心特点，涵盖健康科普、就诊咨询、报告解读、健康档案等上百项 AI 功能。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is reported that AQ became the first industry-professional AI application in China with over 10 million monthly active users just four months after its launch, rising to the 7th position on China's AI native application list, and its compound growth rate of 83.4% ranked first in the industry. AQ's strong growth momentum confirms the public's urgent demand for AI health tools.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据悉，AQ 上线仅四个月便成为国内首个月活超千万的行业专业级 AI 应用，跃升至中国 AI 原生应用榜第 7 位，83.4% 的复合增长率更是位居行业第一。AQ 强劲的增长势头，印证了公众对 AI 健康工具的迫切需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Based on AQ's technological accumulation and market validation, Ant Group further expands AI medical application scenarios:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            基于 AQ 的技术积累与市场验证，蚂蚁集团进一步拓展 AI 医疗应用场景：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of empowering grassroots medical care, Ant collaborated with Shanghai Renji Hospital to create a urology specialist intelligent agent, which, after evaluation by 150 doctors in real clinical scenarios, can improve the diagnostic accuracy of grassroots doctors by 4%-8%;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the uneven distribution of high-quality medical resources in China, Ant collaborated with top doctor teams from national tertiary hospitals to create over 300 &quot;famous doctor AI avatars&quot; intelligent agents;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the national issue of chronic disease management, AQ also provides &quot;personalized&quot; full-cycle management services for over 500 million chronic disease patients nationwide by establishing AI health archives, integrating smart health devices, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;This upgrade of the health business group is an inevitable choice for the AI strategy and a firm response to societal health needs,&quot; Han Xinyi stated. &quot;In the future, Ant will continue to work hard to make seeing a doctor simpler and life healthier.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             「此次升级健康事业群，是 AI 战略的必然选择，更是对社会健康需求的坚定回应。」韩歆毅表示，「未来蚂蚁将继续努力，让看病更简单、生活更健康。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>百度宣布文心新模型获全球并列第二</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">百度宣布文心新模型获全球并列第二</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 8, Baidu announced that according to the latest rankings from the LMArena large model arena,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Wenxin's new model ERNIE-5.0-Preview-1022 ranked tied for second globally and first in China on the text leaderboard.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 8 日，百度宣布，据 LMArena 大模型竞技场最新排名显示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             文心全新模型 ERNIE-5.0-Preview-1022 登上文本排行榜全球并列第二、中国第一。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, ERNIE-5.0-Preview-1022 performs outstandingly in creative writing, complex long-problem understanding, and instruction following, surpassing many mainstream models both domestically and internationally:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，RNIE-5.0-Preview-1022 在创意写作、复杂长问题理解、指令遵循等方面表现突出，超过多款国内外主流模型：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative writing can be used to generate articles, marketing copy, scripts, and other content, significantly improving content production efficiency, with ERNIE-5.0-Preview-1022 scoring first in the creative writing dimension;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complex long problem understanding is used to handle multi-level logic and long text tasks, such as academic Q&amp;amp;A, report analysis, knowledge reasoning, etc.;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instruction following ensures that the model can accurately understand and execute user intent, suitable for scenarios such as intelligent assistants, code generation, and business process automation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both complex long problem understanding and instruction following dimensions, ERNIE-5.0-Preview-1022 scored prominently, providing efficient support for multi-scenario content generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meta 回应欺诈广告贡献 160 亿美元收入</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Meta-回应欺诈广告贡献-160-亿美元收入</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Reuters, internal Meta documents show that approximately 10% of the company's revenue (about $16 billion) in 2024 came from scam and prohibited product ads.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据路透社报道，Meta 内部文件显示，该公司在 2024 年约有 10% 的营收（约 160 亿美元）来自诈骗和违禁品广告。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             The documents indicate that the Meta platform displays approximately 15 billion high-risk scam ads to users daily, including fake e-commerce, illegal gambling, and prohibited medical products.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             文件指出，Meta 平台每天向用户展示约 150 亿条高风险诈骗广告，其中包括虚假电商、非法博彩以及禁售医疗产品。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             The documents further show that Meta earns approximately $7 billion annually from the scam ad category.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             文件进一步显示，Meta 每年从诈骗广告类别中获得约 70 亿美元收入。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company's internal system only bans advertisers when they are determined to have a &quot;greater than 95% likelihood of fraudulent behavior&quot;; otherwise, higher advertising fees are charged through &quot;punitive bidding.&quot; Once users click on a scam ad, the algorithm will push more similar content.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司内部系统仅在广告主被判定为「95% 以上可能性存在诈骗行为」时才会封禁，否则将通过「惩罚性竞价」收取更高广告费用。用户一旦点击诈骗广告，算法还会推送更多类似内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regulatory pressure is intensifying. The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has launched an investigation into Meta regarding financial scam ads; British regulators noted last year that the Meta platform was involved in 54% of payment-related fraud losses in 2023, exceeding the sum of all other social platforms. Internally, Meta expects to face potential fines of up to $1 billion in the future, but this amount is far less than the related advertising revenue.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            监管压力正在加剧。美国证券交易委员会（SEC）已对 Meta 涉及金融诈骗广告展开调查；英国监管机构则在去年指出，Meta 平台涉及 2023 年支付类诈骗损失的 54%，超过其他所有社交平台总和。Meta 内部预计未来可能面临高达 10 亿美元罚款，但金额远低于相关广告收入。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A Meta spokesperson responded that the documents seen by Reuters were &quot;selectively presented,&quot; and the related estimates were &quot;crude and over-inclusive,&quot; with the actual proportion being lower. The company emphasized that it has reduced user reports of scam ads by 58% in the past 18 months and will delete over 134 million pieces of scam ad content by 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Meta 发言人回应称，路透社所见文件「选择性呈现」，相关估算「粗糙且过度包含」，实际比例更低。公司强调已在过去 18 个月将用户诈骗广告举报量减少 58%，并在 2025 年删除超过 1.34 亿条诈骗广告内容。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Internal strategic documents show that Meta plans to gradually reduce the proportion of scam ad revenue: from 10.1% in 2024 to 7.3% in 2025, and further to 5.8% in 2027. However, the company has also set a &quot;revenue protection line,&quot; requiring the executive team not to take measures that would lead to revenue losses exceeding 0.15% in the first half of 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            内部战略文件显示，Meta 计划逐步降低诈骗广告收入占比：从 2024 年的 10.1% 降至 2025 年的 7.3%，并在 2027 年进一步降至 5.8%。不过，公司也设定了「收入防护线」，要求执行团队在 2025 年上半年不得采取导致营收损失超过 0.15% 的措施。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 高通 CEO：全球低估了 AI 的巨大潜力</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-高通-CEO：全球低估了-AI-的巨大潜力</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Qualcomm CEO Cristiano Amon was interviewed by Bloomberg and stated that &quot;the capabilities of AI may be underestimated globally.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，高通 CEO 安蒙（Cristiano Amon）接受彭博社采访，并表示「AI 的能力可能被全球低估了」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            During the interview, Amon compared the development of AI with the rise of the internet, noting that the internet's scale today far exceeds expectations during the dot-com bubble of 1999. He stated,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             &quot;Today's internet is much larger than people imagine.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            采访中，安蒙将 AI 的发展与互联网的崛起进行对比，并指出互联网的规模如今远超 1999 年互联网泡沫时期的预期。其表示，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             「今天的互联网比人们想象的要大得多。」
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Bloomberg cited Morgan Stanley's forecast that by 2028, major companies will invest $3 trillion (approximately 21.37 trillion RMB) in data centers and other AI infrastructure. This boom, however, has also raised concerns about a potential market collapse.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            彭博社援引摩根士丹利的预测，到 2028 年，各大公司将在数据中心及其他 AI 基础设施上投入 3 万亿美元（约合人民币 21.37 万亿元）。而这一这一繁荣的背后，也引发了对可能出现的市场崩溃的担忧。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Bloomberg noted that this boom is similar to what the tech industry experienced in the early 2000s.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            彭博社指出，这种繁荣与 2000 年代初科技行业所经历的情形类似。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding whether the industry will experience an AI bubble, Amon believes there is no need to worry, stating, &quot;AI needs more computing power.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对行业是否会出现 AI 过度的情况，安蒙则认为无需担心，「AI 需要更多算力。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Amon is optimistic about AI hardware. He is confident in &quot;personal AI devices,&quot; such as Meta's AI smart glasses Ray-Ban Meta.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             安蒙还对 AI 硬件这件事表示乐观看待。其对「个人 AI 设备」充满信心，如 Meta 的 AI 智能眼镜 Ray-Ban Meta 等。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It's worth noting that Ray-Ban Meta uses Qualcomm processors (such as AR1 Gen 1).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，Ray-Ban Meta 用的高通的处理器（如 AR1 Gen 1）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新产品&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_chan_pin.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>京东「国民好车」发布：4.99 万元起</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">京东「国民好车」发布：4.99-万元起</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/226462bc-b1a9-4e8f-9578-87ec74d51ffe.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Last night, JD.com, in collaboration with GAC Group and CATL, officially unveiled the &quot;National Good Car&quot; Aion UT super. Let's look at the price first:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨晚，京东联合广汽集团、宁德时代正式公布「国民好车」埃安 UT super，先看售价：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;The battery rental purchase price is only 49,900 yuan, and the full vehicle purchase price is 89,900 yuan. The monthly battery rental fee is 499 yuan/month (limited-time offer reduced to 399 yuan/month before 24:00 on December 8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The new car's exterior is consistent with the standard Aion UT, built on an A-class car platform with a 2750mm wheelbase, offering features such as automatic headlights and heated exterior mirrors.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新车外观与标准版埃安 UT 保持一致，基于 A 级车平台打造出 2750mm 的轴距，提供自动大灯、外后视镜加热等配置。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Aion UT super is equipped with CATL's chocolate battery, achieving an ultra-long range of 500 kilometers for &quot;one charge per week,&quot; and supports 99-second rapid battery swapping. Additionally, the new car is equipped with a 100kW motor.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            埃安 UT super 搭载宁德时代巧克力电池，以 500 公里超长续航实现「一周一充」，并支持 99 秒极速换电。同时，新车还配备 100kW 电机。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of smart experience, as the first model to feature Huawei Cloud's in-car system, it offers a smart experience with &quot;infinite functions, infinite computing power, infinite storage, and infinite updates&quot;; in terms of safety, it is equipped with class-exclusive reverse sentinel and 540-degree panoramic imaging, truly bringing consumers a national-level high-quality car.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            智能体验方面，作为华为云车机首搭车型，具备「无限功能、无限算力、无限存储、无限更新」的智能体验；安全方面，更配备同级独有的倒车哨兵与 540 度全景影像，切实为消费者带来一款国民级的高品质好车。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>新版长续航 Model Y 上线：821 公里续航</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">新版长续航-Model-Y-上线：821-公里续航</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/573e40c5-547a-45fc-82b5-4b867ad9ead7.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Tesla officially launched the Model Y Long Range Rear-Wheel Drive version,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             starting at 288,500 yuan.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，特斯拉正式上架 Model Y长续航后轮驱动版，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             售价为 28.85 万元起。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, the Model Y Long Range Rear-Wheel Drive version has a CLTC range of 821 kilometers (with 19-inch wheels; 20-inch wheels yield 756 kilometers) and accelerates from 0 to 100 km/h in 5.6 seconds. The peak charging power has been increased to 250kW. It is understood that the new car uses a 78.4kWh battery.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，Model Y长续航后轮驱动版拥有 821 公里 CLTC 续航（19 英寸轮毂成绩，20 英寸轮毂为 756 公里），百公里加速为 5.6 秒。充电 峰值功率提升至 250kW。据悉，新车采用 78.4kWh 电池。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth mentioning that the total weight of this version has also been reduced to 1.891 tons (the rear-wheel drive standard version is 1.921 tons).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得一提的是，该版本整车重量还有所减少，来到了 1.891 吨（后轮驱动标准版为 1.921 吨）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of other configurations, the new version remains consistent with the standard version: it adopts a second-generation suspension system and is equipped with 9 speakers.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其他配置方面，新版本车型与标准版保持一致：采用第二代悬架系统，配备 9 扬声器。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vivo Y500 Pro 今日发布</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">vivo-Y500-Pro-今日发布</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/81979eb6-2c16-4dc9-a328-ba6348e82677.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The vivo Y500 Pro will be officially released tonight at 19:00. The new phone is positioned as a &quot;national small flagship&quot; and offers four color options: Xiangyun Gold, Light Green, Soft Pink, and Titanium Black. The core configurations are as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            vivo Y500 Pro 将于今晚 19:00 正式发布。新机定位「国民小旗舰」，提供祥云金、浅绿、柔粉、钛黑四种配色。核心配置如下：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with Dimensity 7400 processor;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6.67-inch 1.5K eye-protection screen, with a 1.37mm bezel;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a 7000mAh semi-solid-state Blue Ocean battery;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First in its class to feature Samsung HP5 200-megapixel main camera, supporting CIPA 4.0 professional-grade anti-shake and telephoto enhancement algorithms, with a sensor size of 1/1.56 inches, and pixel-merging mode, meeting both daily and professional shooting needs;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports IP68 + IP69 full-level waterproofing;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First batch to feature OriginOS 6, officially claimed to achieve up to 5 years of lasting smoothness;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offers two storage options: 12GB + 256GB and 12GB + 512GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI 上架 GPT-5 Codex Mini</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OpenAI-上架-GPT-5-Codex-Mini</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 8, OpenAI announced the launch of the Mini version of GPT-5 Codex.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 8 日，OpenAI 宣布上线 GPT-5 Codex 的 Mini 版本。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports,
            &lt;strong&gt;
             compared to the standard version, Mini offers a more compact and affordable experience. Although there are slight trade-offs in capabilities, the Mini version provides 4 times the callable volume within the same package.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Mini 相较于标准版，有着更紧凑和实惠的体验，虽然能力略有取舍，但在相同的套餐里，Mini 版可调用量是标准版的 4 倍。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Officials stated that GPT-5 Codex is very suitable for simple types of tasks. It is worth noting that the Codex system will automatically recommend switching to Mini when user usage reaches 90% of the limit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方表示，GPT-5 Codex 非常适合做简单类型的任务。值得一提的是，Codex 系统会在用户使用达到 90% 限额时自动推荐切换到 Mini。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Additionally, OpenAI has increased the GPT-5-Codex API rate limit by 50% for ChatGPT Plus, Business, and Edu users; ChatGPT Pro and enterprise users have priority when queuing requests, allowing the model to respond to such user requests first.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            另外，OpenAI 还把 ChatGPT Plus、Business 和 Edu 用户的 GPT-5-Codex API 速率限制提高了 50%；而 ChatGPT Pro 和企业版用户在排队请求时拥有优先权，模型能够优先响应该类用户请求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;新消费&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/pin_pai.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>央视曝光「被薅羊毛的医保卡」</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">央视曝光「被薅羊毛的医保卡」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 9, CCTV Finance reported that some consumers recently reflected that someone had posted &quot;medical insurance card wool-gathering guides&quot; on online platforms, openly sharing experiences of using medical insurance cards to purchase daily necessities in pharmacies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 9 日，央视财经报道，近期有消费者反映，有人在网络平台上放出「医保卡薅羊毛攻略」，公然分享在药店里刷医保卡购买日常生活用品的经验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             The report pointed out that, according to Article 28 of the &quot;Social Insurance Law of the People's Republic of China,&quot; it is clear that basic medical insurance funds can only be used to pay for medical-related expenses of insured individuals.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             报道指出，根据《中华人民共和国社会保险法》第二十八条可以明确，基本医疗保险基金只能用于支付参保人员的医疗相关费用。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Earlier this year, medical insurance bureaus across the country successively issued warnings prohibiting the transformation of medical insurance cards into 'shopping cards'. The warning explicitly mentioned that some companies, in order to allow products to be paid for using personal medical insurance accounts, applied for non-medical products such as toothbrushes and facial masks to be classified as medical devices, thereby circumventing the issue that daily necessities cannot be paid for with medical insurance cards.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年早些时候，全国多地医保局陆续发布了「禁止将医保卡变为『购物卡』」的预警提示。提示中明确提到，部分企业为了使商品可以刷医保个人账户进行支付，将牙刷、面膜等非医疗作用的产品申请为医疗器械，以此规避生活用品类不能刷医保卡的问题。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This behavior violates the regulations for the proper use of personal medical insurance account funds, which are earmarked for specific purposes and limited to medical-related expenditures. Fraudulent claims will face legal penalties. However, the reporter's investigation shows that, to this day, such illegal activities are still occurring in pharmacies and manufacturing enterprises in some regions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这种行为违反了医保个人账户资金的正当使用规定，医保个人账户资金专款专用，仅限医疗相关支出，骗保行为将面临法律惩戒。但记者的调查显示，时至今日，这样的违法行为，依然在一些地区的药店和生产企业里上演。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, at a certain branch of the Neptunus Star chain pharmacy, a reporter used a medical insurance card to purchase a 'dental brush' classified as a Class I medical device. After confirmation by the staff, this medical device is actually no different from an ordinary toothbrush, but its name is different because it has been included in the scope of medical insurance payment.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道称，在海王星辰连锁药店某门店，记者刷医保卡买到了属于第一类医疗器械的「牙科用毛刷」。经过店员证实，这款医疗器械其实与普通牙刷无异，由于被纳入了医保支付范围，所以名称不一样。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At another chain pharmacy, Dashenlin, a reporter used a medical insurance card to purchase a dental scaler, also a Class I medical device, which the staff said was actually dental floss. According to actual visits, even cosmetic contact lenses and skincare sets can be purchased with a medical insurance card, but the products are also given different names.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在另一家连锁药店大参林门店，记者刷医保卡买到了同样是第一类医疗器械的牙科洁治器，店员称这其实就是牙线。据实际探访发现，甚至连美瞳隐形眼镜、护肤品套装也可以刷医保卡购买，但产品同样被冠以不同名称。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Reporters found that so-called 'medical skincare products' can generate nearly ten million in annual sales through just one channel (such as Foci Pharmacy in Gansu Province). If 60% of this is paid through medical insurance, it means there are
            &lt;strong&gt;
             6 million yuan swiped from consumers' personal medical insurance accounts.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            记者探访发现，所谓「医用护肤品」只需通过一个渠道（如甘肃省佛慈大药房），
            &lt;strong&gt;
             年销售额就将近千万，如果其中六成通过医保进行支付，那就意味着有 600 万元从消费者的医保基金个人账户被刷走。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>米哈游客服回应崩铁新角色争议</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">米哈游客服回应崩铁新角色争议</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/7295c40b-d1fb-4ebb-8abf-3b1647807973.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Xiangyang Video, miHoYo's game Honkai: Star Rail is about to launch a new character, 'Dahlia,' but the character's artwork and in-game video have sparked intense discussion among netizens after their release.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据向阳视频报道，米哈游旗下游戏《崩坏：星穹铁道》新角色「大丽花」即将上线，但这一角色立绘及实机视频发布后引发网友激烈讨论。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Many netizens pointed out that her in-game actions have suggestive undertones, and that Dahlia's name and actions draw inspiration from details of past real cases, thus trivializing the cases and insulting the victims.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            不少网友指认为其实机动作及有擦边嫌疑，以及大丽花的名字、动作借鉴了过往真实案件细节，将案件娱乐化，侮辱了案件受害者。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, miHoYo customer service responded through reports, stating that they have received relevant feedback, 'We are very sorry for the bad experience, but due to process reasons, we are temporarily unable to meet the demands and will continuously optimize and improve the user experience.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近期，米哈游客服通过报道回应称，已经接收到相关反馈，「非常抱歉带来不好的体验，但因为流程原因，暂时没有办法满足诉求，会不断优化提升用户体验。」
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>武铁回应「高铁票买到 19 排但车厢只有 17 排」</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">武铁回应「高铁票买到-19-排但车厢只有-17-排」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Zhongshan.com's Density Finance, recently, a netizen complained about an absurd situation encountered while taking a high-speed train: their ticket showed seat 19, but upon boarding, they found that the single carriage only had 17 rows, sparking heated discussion among netizens.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据中山网密度财经报道， 近日，有网友吐槽乘坐高铁时遇到离谱情况：自己买到的车票显示座位为 19 排，上车后却发现所在单节车厢仅 17 排，引发网友热议。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In response to the above situation, 12306 customer service staff responded that this situation is likely due to a temporary change of train car during operation. According to procedures, relevant changes will be notified to passengers in advance via SMS, reminding them to pay attention to seat adjustment information. If a seat mismatch is still found after boarding, passengers can promptly explain the situation to the train attendant and seek assistance in finding the correct seat.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            针对上述情况，12306 客服工作人员回应称，该情况大概率是列车运行中临时更换车底车厢导致。按流程，相关变动会通过短信提前通知旅客，提醒留意座位调整信息。若上车后仍发现座位不符，可及时向列车员说明情况，寻求协助查询正确座位。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On November 9, 'Wuhan Passenger Transport Section of Wuhan Railway Bureau' issued a statement regarding the situation.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            11 月 9 日，「武铁武汉客运段」发布情况说明。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Wuhan Passenger Transport Section of Wuhan Railway Bureau stated that it organized an investigation into the viral video titled 'High-speed train seat disappeared, bought row 19 but only 17 rows exist.' The specific situation is as follows:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            武铁武汉客运段表示，针对网传「高铁座位不翼而飞，买到 19 排但只有 17 排」视频，其组织开展了核查。具体情况为：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;On November 7, the train model for D3046, operated by our section from Shanghai Hongqiao to Hankou Station, was temporarily changed (from CRH2B to CRH380AL). This resulted in the passenger who purchased seat 4B in row 19 of carriage 4 being unable to find their assigned seat. The railway department promptly sent an SMS to the passenger via the 12306 system, detailing that due to the temporary adjustment of the train model, their seat number had changed from 4B in row 19 of carriage 4 to 4B in row 17 of carriage 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Wuhan Passenger Transport Section of Wuhan Railway Bureau stated that because the passenger did not fully grasp the content of the aforementioned SMS, they searched for seat 19B after boarding without success. Upon seeing this, the train attendant explained the temporary change in train model and the adjustment of their seat, guiding them to sit in seat 17B.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            武铁武汉客运段称，由于该旅客对上述短信内容掌握不全，上车后寻找 19 排 B 座未果，列车员见状后，向其解释了车型临时发生变更、其座位进行调整等情况，引导其在 17 排 B 座就坐。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, the Wuhan Passenger Transport Section of Wuhan Railway Bureau also expressed its deep apologies for the inconvenience caused to the passenger's journey. Furthermore, it thanked the vast number of passengers for their attention and supervision of railway passenger services, stating that it will continue to improve the quality of passenger services to provide passengers with a smooth and comfortable travel experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同时，武铁武汉客运段也表示，由此给该旅客出行带来的不便，其深表歉意。同时，感谢广大旅客对铁路客运服务的关注与监督，其将持续提升客运服务质量，为旅客提供顺畅、舒心的出行体验。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;section&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;好看的&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/common-images/hao_kan_de.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《狂野时代》发布第二篇章预告</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《狂野时代》发布第二篇章预告</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/49c6fbb1-91fa-40a0-918a-b3c104baf6f6.gif&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Sina Film, Bi Gan's film 'A Wild Pomegranate' recently released the second chapter of its five senses series: the 'Auditory' chapter trailer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据新浪电影消息，由毕赣执导的电影《狂野时代》近期发布五感中第二篇章：「听觉」篇章预告。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the trailer, 'The Bewitcher' Jackson Yee transforms into the handsome young Qiu Muyun in this chapter, while Mark Chao, playing an officer, chokes Qiu Muyun's neck, demanding to know what is in the box. 'Sound' is an important clue to unlocking character relationships in this chapter.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            预告中，「迷魂者」易烊千玺在此篇章中化身美少年邱默云，赵又廷饰演的长官掐住邱默云的脖子逼问箱子中为何物。「声音」是此篇章中解锁人物关系重要线索。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of a world where humans no longer dream, yet a monster remains obsessed with dream hallucinations all day, lost within them. A woman, who can see through illusions, then dives into his dreams to find him.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片讲述了在一个人类已经不再做梦的世界里，有一个怪物依然整日沉迷于梦的幻觉中，他迷失了。而一个女人可以看清幻觉，于是她潜入了他的梦中去寻找。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film will be released on November 22; written and directed by Bi Gan, starring Jackson Yee and Shu Qi, with Mark Chao as a special guest star, Li Gengxi as a special star, and Huang Jue and Chen Yongzhong as main cast. It previously premiered on May 22, 2025, at the 78th Cannes International Film Festival in France, where it received a Special Award in the main competition unit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片将于 11 月 22 日上映；由毕赣自编自导，易烊千玺、舒淇领衔主演，赵又廷特邀主演，李庚希特别主演，黄觉、陈永忠主演，此前已于 2025 年 5 月 22 日在法国第 78 届戛纳国际电影节首映，并获得主竞赛单元特别奖。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>电影《柔似蜜》发布预告</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">电影《柔似蜜》发布预告</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/5a50c287-4cec-41bf-aad9-06b0357ea296.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the trailer for the new film 'Rosemead,' starring Lucy Liu and Lawrence Shou, was released. It will premiere in North America on December 5 this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，由刘玉玲、Lawrence Shou 主演新片《柔似蜜》发布预告，将于今年 12 月 5 日北美上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The story is adapted from a true event, where a Chinese mother with terminal cancer faces her emotionally unstable son. Initially, the mother insisted her son was 'fine,' but later she discovered he was deeply entrenched in schizophrenia and becoming increasingly obsessed with mass shootings.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            故事改编自真实事件，一位患上癌症绝症的华人母亲面对情绪不稳定的儿子，起初母亲坚持儿子「没问题」，但此后她发现儿子深陷精神分裂症，且对大规模枪击案越发沉迷。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is the directorial debut of photographer-turned-director Eric Lin, and it premiered globally on June 6, 2025, at the Tribeca Film Festival.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片为摄影师出身的 Eric Lin 执导处女作，已于 2025 年 6 月 6 日在翠贝卡电影节全球首映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>迈克尔杰克逊传记片预告创观看纪录</title>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">迈克尔杰克逊传记片预告创观看纪录</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/11.10_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/8cb43a67-a3a4-491c-8b9b-99c6df5e0aa3.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Hollywood Watch, the Michael Jackson biopic 'Michael Jackson: The Road to Stardom' garnered 116.2 million views within the first 24 hours of its release (across multiple platforms), setting a new record for the highest first-day viewership for a music biopic trailer.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据守望好莱坞消息，迈克尔·杰克逊传记片《迈克尔·杰克逊：巨星之路》在发布首个 24 小时内（统计多平台）观看量达到 1.162 亿次，创下音乐传记电影预告片首日最高观看纪录。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film tells the story of how, under relentless scrutiny, accusations, and dazzling media spotlight, the King of Pop was merely an ordinary person living a complex life. The film recreates MJ's iconic performances and includes 30 songs to fairly tell MJ's story, allowing audiences to gain a deeper understanding of his artistic journey and personal life.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片讲述了在无情的审查、指控和炫目的媒体聚光灯下，流行音乐之王只是一个过着复杂生活的普通人。该片再现了 MJ 标志性的表演，包含 30 首歌曲，以便公正的讲述 MJ 的故事，让观众可以更深入的了解他的艺术历程和个人生活。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is a Michael Jackson biopic officially authorized and supported by the Jackson Estate, directed by Antoine Fuqua, written by John Logan, and starring Jaafar Jackson, Colman Domingo, Juliano Valdi, Miles Teller, Kat Graham, and others. It is set for global release on April 24, 2026.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该片由杰克逊遗产委员会官方授权和支持，安东尼·福奎阿执导，约翰·洛根编剧，贾法尔·杰克逊、科尔曼·多明戈、朱利亚诺·瓦尔迪、迈尔斯·特勒、卡特琳娜·格兰厄姆等主演的迈克尔·杰克逊传记片，于 2026 年 4 月 24 日全球上映。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifanr.com/tags/%e6%97%a9%e6%8a%a5&quot;&gt;
            早报
           &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
