<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily News</title>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>曝字节跳动推进 AI 手机合作：vivo 员工证实，联想密切沟通</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">曝字节跳动推进-AI-手机合作：vivo-员工证实，联想密切沟通</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/346b3461-adec-4ae2-ab2c-38ba278d1128.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, ByteDance is promoting AI phone cooperation with hardware manufacturers such as vivo, Lenovo, and Transsion, pre-installing AIGC plugins in devices to gain user access and improve its passive situation at the execution level.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Multiple vivo employees confirmed that both parties have confirmed the cooperation and are discussing specific details.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，字节跳动正推进与 vivo、联想、传音等硬件厂商的 AI 手机合作，在设备中预装 AIGC 插件以获取用户入口、改善其在执行层面的被动局面。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             多位 vivo 员工证实双方已确认合作、正在讨论具体细节。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Lenovo insiders stated that Lenovo Group has maintained close cooperation with ByteDance-affiliated businesses such as &quot;Doubao&quot; and &quot;Volcano Engine,&quot; and is currently in close communication regarding cooperation with &quot;Doubao&quot; in the smart terminal field.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            Additionally, according to 21st Century Business Herald, Lenovo and ByteDance-affiliated businesses indeed have close dealings in relevant areas.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             联想内部人士称，联想集团与「豆包」、火山引擎等字节系业务一直保持紧密合作，目前在智能终端领域与「豆包」的合作也保持密切沟通。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            另据 21 世纪经济报道，联想与字节系在相关业务上确有密切往来。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Insiders revealed that ByteDance's move is not merely to pursue business growth, but to build new traffic monetization paths, allowing mobile phone manufacturers to participate in revenue from traffic distribution and membership subscriptions.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            知情人士透露，字节跳动此举并非单纯追求业务增长，而在于构建新的流量变现路径，让手机厂商参与流量分发与会员订阅等收益。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The models under discussion include not charging customization development fees or token sales commissions, and giving mobile phone manufacturers a share of secondary traffic revenue. The plan is still in its early stages.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            讨论中的模式包括不收取定制化开发费或 Token 销售分成，并给予手机厂商二次流量的分成收益，方案仍处早期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The project plans to first &quot;invest volume&quot; in mid-range models priced above 2,000 yuan, launching new phones with manufacturers, and then covering more models via OTA updates; after reaching a scale of 150-200 million units, it will then compete with other internet companies.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该项目拟先对 2000 元以上中端机型进行「投量」，与手机厂商发布新机，随后通过 OTA 覆盖更多机型；规模达到 1.5–2 亿后，再与其他互联网厂商竞争。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Sources say ByteDance has an advantage in overseas channels, and AI phone launches will likely prioritize overseas markets; internally, the project is highly valued, with both the system and annotation departments each having over 500 people.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             Previously, ByteDance had communicated with OPPO regarding similar cooperation, but was rejected
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            消息人士称，字节跳动在海外渠道具优势，AI 手机投放大概率也会优先布局海外；内部对该项目高度重视，系统与标注部门各自超过 500 人。
            &lt;strong&gt;
             此前，字节跳动曾就相关合作与 OPPO 沟通，但遭拒绝
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Doubao Mobile Assistant&quot; officially launched its technical preview version on December 1st, and jointly released the nubia M153 engineering prototype with ZTE. This product supports cross-application service calls under user instructions, such as ordering takeout, booking flights, price comparison shopping, replying to WeChat messages, and operating mini-program games.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            「豆包手机助手」于 12 月 1 日正式推出技术预览版，并与中兴通讯联合推出 nubia M153 工程样机。该产品支持在用户指令下跨应用调用服务，如点外卖、订机票、比价购物、回复微信消息及操作小程序游戏等。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Soon after its launch, apps such as WeChat, Taobao, Dianping, and Pinduoduo successively prohibited their use on &quot;Doubao phones,&quot; sparking discussions about the future of the AI terminal business ecosystem.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            问世不久后，微信、淘宝、大众点评、拼多多等 App 相继禁止在「豆包手机」上使用，引发对 AI 终端商业生态走向的讨论。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the same time, IDC data shows that Lenovo's Motorola shipped 16 million units in the third quarter of 2025, with a global share of 4.9%, ranking eighth in the global smartphone market.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同期，IDC 数据显示，联想旗下摩托罗拉在 2025 年第三季度出货量为 1600 万台、全球份额 4.9%，位列全球智能手机市场第八。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            ByteDance previously responded that 'Doubao' is in talks with several mobile phone manufacturers for assistant cooperation and has no plans to develop its own mobile phones; the officially disclosed mobile phone partner is only ZTE Mobile. It is worth noting that Meizu Technology once posted on Weibo expressing its intention to cooperate, looking forward to 'further exploring more user-friendly AI phones'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            字节跳动先前回应称，「豆包」正在与多家手机厂商洽谈助手合作，且没有自行开发手机的计划；官方披露的手机合作方仅有中兴手机。值得注意的是，魅族科技曾在微博发文表达合作意向，期待「进一步探索更好用的 AI 手机」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>小米汽车获北京 L3 自动驾驶测试牌照，已开展常态化路测</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">小米汽车获北京-L3-自动驾驶测试牌照，已开展常态化路测</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/83ac654a-7deb-4c36-b323-dd9c2bd4f149.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to yesterday's report by Beijing Daily, Xiaomi Auto has obtained an L3 autonomous driving road test license in Beijing and has been conducting regular L3 road tests on designated sections.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据北京日报昨日报道，小米汽车已在北京市获得 L3 级自动驾驶道路测试牌照，并已在指定路段开展常态化 L3 级道路测试。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This license is primarily for intelligent connected vehicle high-speed road test sections in Beijing, allowing eligible models to conduct road tests under conditional autonomous driving mode, exploring safer and smarter personal mobility service forms.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这一牌照主要面向北京市智能网联汽车高快速路测试路段，允许符合条件的车型在有条件自动驾驶模式下上路测试，探索更安全、更智能的个人出行服务形态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This test license is limited to the 'Beijing Intelligent Connected Vehicle Test High-Speed Roads' range. According to the application areas of different enterprises, Beijing currently provides road test support on expressways and urban expressways (designed speed ≥ 60 km/h) in areas such as Yizhuang, Shunyi, and Tongzhou.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            此次测试牌照限定在「北京市智能网联汽车测试高快速路」范围内。根据不同企业的申请区域，北京目前在亦庄、顺义、通州等片区的高速及城市快速路（设计时速 ≥ 60 km/h）提供道路测试支持。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            These types of roads have higher vehicle speeds, numerous ramps, and a large proportion of trucks, which test the vehicle's environmental perception distance, longitudinal control capabilities, and redundant safety strategies more than urban main roads, placing higher demands on the overall stability of autonomous driving systems.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            这类道路车速较高、匝道数量多、货车比例大，相比城市主干道更考验车辆的环境感知距离、纵向控制能力以及冗余安全策略，对自动驾驶系统整体稳定性提出了更高要求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi stated that it has been continuously conducting regular L3 road tests on relevant road sections, with vehicles operating on a schedule similar to daily operations, accumulating real road condition data through long-term road tests.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米方面表示，已在相关路段持续开展常态化 L3 级道路测试，车辆以接近日常运营的方式排班行驶，通过长期路测积累真实路况数据。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Continuous regular testing also means that the test fleet, backend monitoring, and data feedback system have been integrated, allowing for iterative verification and optimization of autonomous driving algorithms in real road environments, laying the foundation for subsequent large-scale applications.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            持续常态化测试也意味着测试车队、后台监控以及数据回灌体系已经打通，可以在实际道路环境中对自动驾驶算法进行迭代验证和优化，为后续规模化应用奠定基础。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The report points out that the L3 autonomous driving road test license is an administrative permit, not all car manufacturers can obtain it. This license is jointly issued by relevant departments such as Beijing's Economic and Information Bureau, Traffic Management Bureau, and Transportation Bureau, and is only for models that have completed a series of prerequisite review stages such as closed-field testing, network security assessment, and data compliance review.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报道指出，L3 级自动驾驶道路测试牌照属于行政许可，并非所有车企都能获得。该牌照由北京市经信、交管、交通等相关主管部门联合核发，仅面向已完成封闭场地测试、网络安全评估、数据合规审查等一系列前置审查环节的车型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xiaomi's approval means that its submitted L3 system solution (including software and hardware redundancy, remote supervision, data recording, etc.) has passed Beijing's entry threshold and is qualified to conduct autonomous driving tests on public roads.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小米此次获批，意味着其提交的 L3 系统方案（包括软硬件冗余、远程监管、数据记录等环节）已经通过北京市准入门槛，具备在公开道路上进行自动驾驶测试的资质。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>新华社揭晓 2025 年度字词，「韧」与「深度求索（DeepSeek）」当选</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">新华社揭晓-2025-年度字词，「韧」与「深度求索（DeepSeek）」当选</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/87897ab9-328f-41f6-b690-f9100804a4a4.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Xinhua News Agency unveiled the 'Annual Character and Word' for the 'Chinese Language Inventory 2025' event: the annual domestic character is '韧' (rèn, resilience), and '深度求索 (DeepSeek)' was selected as one of the top ten media hot words and top ten internet popular words, becoming the
            &lt;strong&gt;
             annual domestic word
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            .
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，新华社揭晓「汉语盘点 2025」活动「年度字词」：年度国内字为「韧」、「深度求索（DeepSeek）」入选媒体十大热词和十大网络流行语，成为
            &lt;strong&gt;
             年度国内词
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The event is jointly organized by the National Language Resources Monitoring and Research Center, Commercial Press, and Xinhuanet, reflecting the comprehensive results of netizens' recommendations, corpus big data extraction, and expert evaluations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该活动由国家语言资源监测与研究中心、商务印书馆、新华网联合主办，体现网民推荐、语料库大数据提取与专家评议的综合结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xinhua News Agency pointed out that '韧' (rèn, resilience) emphasizes perseverance, stress resistance, and resilience as core tenets in an era intertwined with political, economic, and technological uncertainties;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新华社指出，「韧」强调在政治、经济与技术不确定性交织的时代，以坚韧不拔、抗压应变与回弹性为核心要义；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            And '深度求索 (DeepSeek)', as a representative of a domestic iconic large language model, is regarded as an important symbol of China's technological sovereignty and independent productivity in the AI field, reflecting the rise of local enterprises in artificial intelligence.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            而「深度求索（DeepSeek）」作为国产标志性大语言模型的代表，被视为中国在 AI 领域技术主权与自主生产力的重要标识，折射本土企业在人工智能上的崛起。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This year marks the 20th anniversary of the event, and the organizers stated that they will continue to use Chinese as a medium to promote cultural inheritance and mutual learning among civilizations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年是该活动举办第 20 年，主办方称将继续以汉语为媒，推动文化传承与文明互鉴。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to the introduction, this 'Chinese Language Inventory 2025' simultaneously released the annual top ten Chinese media hot words, annual top ten internet popular words, and annual top ten new words, outlining an annual language 'panorama' from the dimensions of news value, social life innovation, and youth group internet culture.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，本次「汉语盘点 2025」同步发布年度中国媒体十大热词、年度十大网络流行语与年度十大新词语，勾勒出以新闻价值、社会生活创新与年轻群体网络文化为维度的年度语言「全景图」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, '苏超' (Super League) and '票根经济' (ticket stub economy) are listed as both top ten media hot words and top ten new words, reflecting the intersection of contemporary focus and innovative development.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，「苏超」「票根经济」兼列媒体十大热词与十大新词语，体现时代焦点与创新发展的交汇。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>字节跳动涨薪：奖金投入增 35%，调薪加码 1.5 倍</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">字节跳动涨薪：奖金投入增-35%，调薪加码-1.5-倍</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/25729dc6-ea19-449a-9ad5-4c80ca1f9315.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from The Paper and Jiemian News, ByteDance sent an internal email to its global employees, announcing continued increased investment in talent and incentives in 2025: the total investment in annual performance bonuses (including options) will increase by 35% compared to the previous cycle, salary adjustment investment will increase by 1.5 times, and the lower and upper limits of total compensation packages for all job levels will be uniformly raised to maintain a 'leading position among top-tier levels' in various global markets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据澎湃新闻、界面新闻报道，字节跳动向全球员工发出内部邮件，宣布在 2025 年继续加大人才与激励投入：全年绩效奖金（含期权）总投入较上个周期提升 35%，调薪投入提升 1.5 倍，并统一提高各职级薪酬总包的下限与上限，以在全球各市场保持「领先于头部水平」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company stated that this move aims to strengthen the attraction and retention of high-performing talent and directly address global talent competition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司称，此举旨在强化吸引与保留高绩效人才，直面全球人才竞争。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            ByteDance clearly refined the upper and lower limits of the performance incentive range:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            字节跳动明确细化了绩效激励区间的上限与下限：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upper limit for incentive months for annual performance rated &quot;M&quot; has increased by 1.5 months;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower limit for &quot;M+&quot; has increased by 1.5 months, and the upper limit by 2.5 months;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower limit for &quot;E&quot; has increased by 3.5 months, and the upper limit by 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding semi-annual incentives, the calculation base for employees rated &quot;E&quot; and above has been adjusted from monthly salary to monthly total compensation (including monthly stock options), with a corresponding increase in incentive intensity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            半年激励方面，「E」及以上员工的激励计算基数由月薪调整为月总包（含月期权），对应激励力度同步提升。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of compensation structure, the company has adjusted its job level system from the original &quot;5 levels, 10 grades (1-1 to 5-2)&quot; to a &quot;10-level system (L1–L10)&quot;, merging the original &quot;1-1/1-2&quot; into &quot;L1&quot; and adding &quot;L10&quot;.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在薪酬结构上，公司将职级体系由原「5 级 10 档（1-1 至 5-2）」调整为「10 级体系（L1–L10）」，其中合并原「1-1／1-2」为「L1」，并新增「L10」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Under the new system, even without promotion, employees can gain greater salary increase potential than in the past, and the salary increase brought by promotion has also expanded.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            At the same time, the salary adjustment investment in this cycle has increased to 1.5 times that of the previous cycle, and the upper and lower limits of the total compensation range for each job level have been simultaneously raised, to balance in-service incentives and recruitment competitiveness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             在新体系下，即使不晋级，员工也能获得较过去更大的涨薪空间，晋级带来的涨薪幅度亦扩大。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            与此同时，本周期调薪投入提升至上周期的 1.5 倍，并同步抬升各职级薪酬总包区间的上下限，以兼顾在职激励与招聘竞争力。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In June this year, ByteDance released &quot;6 Talent Principles,&quot; emphasizing maintaining &quot;high talent density&quot; in all aspects of recruitment, employment, training, incentives, and rewards, and iterated its performance and incentive policies in early 2024 to enhance the identification and differentiation of high performance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 6 月，字节跳动发布「6 条人才观」，强调在招聘、用人、培养、激励与回报各环节保持「高人才密度」，并在 2024 年初迭代绩效与激励政策，加大对高绩效的识别与区分度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The company has long conducted two rounds of stock option repurchases annually (usually in April and October), with option prices cumulatively increasing by over 400% since 2019. In October this year, the repurchase price for active employees was US$200.41/share, and for departed employees was US$180.37/share (approximately RMB 1424.01/share and RMB 1281.62/share, respectively).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            公司长期进行每年两轮期权回购（一般在 4 月与 10 月），期权价格自 2019 年以来累计上调超 400%。今年 10 月在职员工回购价为 200.41 美元/股、离职员工为 180.37 美元/股（分别约合人民币 1424.01 元/股、1281.62 元/股）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the same month, the company also launched a protection plan for official employees in mainland China who were passively laid off due to organizational adjustments: in addition to economic compensation, eligible individuals will receive a transitional subsidy of up to 12,000 yuan/month for a maximum of 6 months, with a total amount of up to 72,000 yuan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            同月，公司还针对中国内地因组织调整被动离职的正式员工上线保障方案：在经济补偿之外，向符合条件者提供最长 6 个月、最高 1.2 万元/月的过渡性补贴，总额最高可达 7.2 万元。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding organizational stability, there was a rumor that &quot;ByteDance employees' average tenure is 7 months.&quot; In response, ByteDance disclosed at an internal communication meeting in late July that the median tenure for active employees is 2.9 years. This is the first time the company has internally disclosed this data, aiming to clarify related false rumors and strengthen external expectations of talent stability.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            关于组织稳定性，坊间曾有「字节员工平均在职时间 7 个月」的说法。对此，字节跳动在 7 月底的内部交流会上披露在职员工工龄中位数为 2.9 年，这是公司首次内部披露此项数据，以澄清相关不实传闻并强化对外的人才稳定预期。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>拼多多实行联席董事长制度：锚定中国供应链，目标「3 年再造一个拼多多」</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">拼多多实行联席董事长制度：锚定中国供应链，目标「3-年再造一个拼多多」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/0b047c06-6e3d-41f3-b3d1-1fea6fbc3214.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Phoenix Network Technology, Pinduoduo Group announced an upgrade to its governance structure at yesterday's annual general meeting, implementing a co-chairmanship system. Zhao Jiazhen was appointed Co-Chairman, serving alongside Chen Lei as Co-Chairman and Co-CEO. Concurrently, the company appointed Wang Mi as Senior Vice President of Group Engineering and Li Jiong as Group Financial Controller.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据凤凰网科技报道，拼多多集团在昨天的年度股东大会上宣布升级治理架构，实行联席董事长制度，赵佳臻获任联席董事长，与陈磊共同担任联席董事长兼联席 CEO。同时，公司任命王密为集团工程高级副总裁、李炯为集团财务总监。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhao Jiazhen stated that co-governance is conducive to the group entering &quot;the next stage of upgrade and re-creation,&quot; and will promote the implementation of the overall strategy centered on &quot;focusing on and heavily investing in supply chain upgrades for high-quality development.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            赵佳臻表示，联席治理有利于集团进入「下一个阶段的升级再造」，并围绕「聚焦、重投供应链升级，高质量发展」的整体战略推进落地。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the meeting, Chen Lei revealed that Temu has achieved a certain market scale in various countries, &quot;covering Pinduoduo's 10 years of domestic e-commerce development in 3 years.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            会上陈磊透露，Temu 已在不同国家形成一定市场规模，「3 年走完了拼多多国内电商 10 年的路」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhao Jiazhen stated that this year marks Pinduoduo's tenth anniversary, with continuous accumulation in business, technology, and services, and its business has reached most countries globally; the company's next phase will focus more on the Chinese supply chain.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            赵佳臻称，今年是拼多多创业第十年，业务、技术与服务持续积累，业务已触达全球大部分国家；公司下一阶段的核心将更聚焦于中国供应链。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He emphasized that Temu's rapid growth stems from the dividends of China's supply chain industry, bringing opportunities for the development of the domestic supply chain and the re-creation of Pinduoduo and Temu.
            &lt;strong&gt;
             The group will concentrate resources to promote the overall upgrade of the supply chain operating model, moving towards high quality and branding, with the goal of &quot;re-creating another Pinduoduo in the next 3 years.&quot;
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他强调，Temu 的快速成长源于中国供应链产业红利，为国内供应链发展与拼多多、Temu 的再造带来契机，
            &lt;strong&gt;
             集团将集中资源推动供应链运营模式的整体升级，向高质量与品牌化方向迈进，目标是在「下一个 3 年再造一个拼多多」。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chen Lei also pointed out that with expanding scale and rapidly changing regulatory environments in various regions, compliance is the bottom line. E-commerce platforms must &quot;meet social needs, return to their original aspirations, stick to their duties, and contribute to society.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            陈磊同时指出，伴随规模扩大与各地监管环境快速变化，合规是底线，电商平台需「符合社会需要、回归初心、固守本分、为社会做贡献」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhao Jiazhen (nickname &quot;Winter Jujube&quot;) is a founding team member of Pinduoduo, initially responsible for agricultural product operations and supply chain construction. Since 2018, he has served as Senior Vice President, promoting the rollout of &quot;Duoduo Maicai&quot; model cities, ranking first in internal community group-buying competition, and expanding business to multiple provinces including Henan, Jiangxi, and Hunan.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            赵佳臻（花名「冬枣」）为拼多多创始团队成员，早期负责农产品运营与供应链搭建；2018 年起任高级副总裁，推动「多多买菜」样板城市落地，在社区团购内部竞争中排名第一，并拓展河南、江西、湖南等多省业务。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the second half of 2022, he led the team to promote the upgrade of the supply chain system, while also participating in overseas e-commerce expansion, responsible for Temu's US market merchant acquisition, helping to kickstart overseas business. In April 2023, he was appointed Executive Director and Co-CEO, overseeing supply chain management and China business operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2022 年下半年带队推动供应链体系升级，同时参与海外电商布局，负责 Temu 美国市场招商，助力海外业务起步；2023 年 4 月获任执行董事与联席 CEO，分管供应链管理与中国业务运营。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Chen Lei co-founded Pinduoduo with Huang Zheng and others in 2015, serving successively as CTO and CEO, and took over as Chairman in 2021, driving the company's transformation from social fission to technology-driven. This time, Chen Lei and Zhao Jiazhen jointly serve as Co-Chairmen and Co-CEOs, establishing a co-governance mechanism.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            陈磊 2015 年与黄峥等人共同创立拼多多，历任 CTO、CEO，并于 2021 年接任董事长，推动公司由社交裂变向科技驱动转型。此次陈磊与赵佳臻共同担任联席董事长兼联席 CEO，构建联席治理机制。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《科学》杂志评选 2025 年度突破：可再生能源登顶，中国引领全球转型</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《科学》杂志评选-2025-年度突破：可再生能源登顶，中国引领全球转型</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/60167bd6-ba5d-4016-98ca-5f770b527abb.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the 18th local time, the American journal &quot;Science&quot; selected the &quot;Top 10 Scientific Breakthroughs of 2025,&quot; with &quot;Unstoppable Global Renewable Energy Growth&quot; ranking as the top breakthrough of the year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            美国《科学》杂志于当地时间 18 日评选出「2025 年度十大科学突破」，其中「全球可再生能源增长势不可当」位列年度头号突破。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            A *Science* article states that by 2025, renewable energy will surpass traditional energy in multiple sectors, with China leading this transition.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《科学》刊文称，2025 年可再生能源在多个领域超过传统能源，且这一转型由中国引领。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The article points out that this year, global renewable energy generation has for the first time exceeded coal; the growth rate of solar and wind energy is sufficient to cover the world's new electricity demand in the first half of this year.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该刊文指出，今年全球可再生能源发电量首次超过煤炭；太阳能与风能的增长速度足以覆盖今年上半年全球新增用电需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            *Science* further emphasizes that China's robust industrial system has driven this reshaping of the energy landscape: approximately 80% of the world's solar cells, 70% of wind turbines, and 70% of lithium batteries are produced by China, with a cost advantage.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《科学》进一步强调，中国强大的工业体系推动了此次能源版图重塑：全球约 80% 的太阳能电池、70% 的风力涡轮机及 70% 的锂电池由中国生产，且在成本上具备优势。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            China's green technology exports are changing the energy structures of European and Global South countries, with rooftop photovoltaics rapidly gaining popularity in Africa and South Asia, becoming a low-cost option that immediately improves energy usage experience.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国绿色技术出口正在改变欧洲及全球南方国家的能源结构，屋顶光伏在非洲与南亚加速普及，成为低成本、可立即改善用能体验的选择。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of emissions reduction, China's renewable energy development this year has brought its domestic greenhouse gas growth almost to a halt and made the global carbon emissions peak more attainable. However, *Science* also warns that to achieve substantial emissions reductions, this year's crossed threshold must still be regarded as a starting point.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在减排层面，今年中国的可再生能源发展使本国温室气体增速几近停滞，并使全球碳排峰值更接近可及，但《科学》亦提示，要实现实质性减排，仍需将今年跨越的门槛视为起点。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to energy transition, the other nine annual breakthroughs listed by *Science* cover fields such as life health and basic science, including:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除能源转型外，《科学》列出的其他九项年度突破涵盖生命健康与基础科学等领域，包括：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Custom gene editing** bringing hope for ultra-rare diseases;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two **new drugs for gonorrhea** proven effective in large clinical trials;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovery of how nerve cells &quot;supercharge&quot; cancer cells by transferring mitochondria;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historic progress in xenotransplantation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A **new type of telescope** built on a Chilean mountaintop, dubbed the &quot;all-seeing eye&quot; of the sky;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New findings in Denisovan research;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Performance of **large language models** for scientific research;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New progress in computational assistance for particle physics;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on heat-tolerant rice (with Denisovan and heat-tolerant rice research led by Chinese teams).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>飞书在广州峰会发布「粤企一齐飞」计划，物理 AI 企业加速组织升级</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">飞书在广州峰会发布「粤企一齐飞」计划，物理-AI-企业加速组织升级</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/9fe05f4d-9f8a-4b8c-b06a-7bcc986c98b1.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, the 2025 Feishu Advanced Productivity Summit · Guangzhou Station was held at Xpeng Motors Guangzhou Headquarters, with the theme &quot;Advanced Organizational Power in the AI Era,&quot; focusing on organizational upgrades for the physical AI industry in the Greater Bay Area.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            日前，2025 飞书先进生产力峰会 · 广州站在小鹏汽车广州总部举行，主题为「AI 时代的先进组织力」，聚焦大湾区物理 AI 产业的组织升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This summit attracted hundreds of enterprise executives, government representatives, and industry experts, including companies such as Xpeng Motors, Pony.ai, UBTECH, Sunwoda Energy, and Leju Robotics.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            本次峰会吸引数百位企业高层、政府代表与行业专家参与，包括小鹏汽车、小马智行、优必选、欣旺达动力、乐聚机器人等企业。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Zhang Di, General Manager of Feishu's Manufacturing Industry, stated that Feishu hopes to enable organizational AI to match the development speed of physical AI through a &quot;software-defined organization&quot; approach.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            飞书制造行业总经理张棣表示，飞书希望通过「软件定义组织」的方式，让组织 AI 能够匹配物理 AI 的发展速度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            At the summit, several physical AI companies shared their practical experiences with Feishu. Xpeng Motors showcased the application results of its enterprise-level Agent &quot;IRON.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            峰会现场，多家物理 AI 企业分享了其在飞书上的实践经验。小鹏汽车展示了其企业级 Agent「IRON」的应用成果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tan Weihua, Deputy General Manager of Xpeng Motors, stated that after IRON went live, its intelligent data query function can save 1 million yuan in costs annually, which is equivalent to adding 128 AI employees to work each month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            小鹏汽车副总经理谭蔚华表示，IRON 上线后，智能问数功能每年可节省 100 万元成本、整体相当于每月新增 128 名 AI 员工投入工作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The summit concluded with the release of the 'Guangdong Enterprises Soar Together' efficiency acceleration plan, aiming to promote the large-scale intelligent upgrading of the manufacturing industry through benchmark leadership and AI inclusivity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            峰会最后发布了「粤企一齐飞」效能加速计划，旨在通过标杆引领与 AI 普惠推动制造业的规模化智能化升级。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OPPO x 小红书发布 2026 影像趋势</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">OPPO-x-小红书发布-2026-影像趋势</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/a92abc2b-66d2-4936-abe5-2658494255bf.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, OPPO, in collaboration with Xiaohongshu, released the 2026 Annual Imaging Trend Report. Based on Xiaohongshu's internal creation data, both parties summarized 9 major mobile imaging trends and, using the OPPO Find X9 series and OPPO Reno15 series as representative models, attempted to answer 'what the next generation of mobile phone imaging should look like'.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，OPPO 联合小红书发布 2026 年度影像趋势报告，双方基于小红书站内创作数据，总结出 9 大移动影像趋势，并以 OPPO Find X9 系列与 OPPO Reno15 系列为代表机型，试图回答「下一代手机影像应该长什么样」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The core proposition of the report is 'what you see is what you get,' allowing every frame to reveal its natural essence. It emphasizes that mobile imaging no longer creates scenery but rather replicates as accurately as possible the real moments users are in, allowing every rewatch to relive the truly natural scene.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            报告提出的核心命题是「所见即所得」，让每一帧都长出自然本色，强调手机影像不再创造风景，而是尽可能精确复刻用户置身其中的真实瞬间，每一次回看都能重温自然本真的画面。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The main trends can be summarized into the following categories:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            主要趋势可归纳为以下几类：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evolution of portrait styles: The demand for film portraits, lifestyle portraits, and atmospheric portraits continues to grow, with a significant increase in attention to natural skin tones, light and shadow layers, and emotional expression;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changes in social recording methods: Wide-angle selfies, live images, and multi-person group photos have become mainstream, with the rapid rise in the use of features like 0.5x photography and 0.6x front-facing wide-angle;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rise of dynamic content: Live photos and travel vlogs have seen significant growth in views, with users preferring recording methods that convey the passage of time;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integration of urban and travel photography: City streets have become new travel photography scenes, and the demand for compositions that blend people and scenery drives the upgrade of natural color and tone algorithms;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increased demand for color consistency: Uniform color presentation across photos, videos, and live content has become a key focus for creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XR 专利「第一案」宣判：XREAL 专利诉讼一审胜诉，VITURE Pro 欧盟九国禁售</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">XR-专利「第一案」宣判：XREAL-专利诉讼一审胜诉，VITURE-Pro-欧盟九国禁售</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/51af6356-abba-4c9b-b3e8-4d4fbf00d5bf.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports from 'STAR Market Daily', VR Tuoluo, and EO Intelligence, the First Regional Court of Munich, Germany, issued a first-instance ruling yesterday, finding that VITURE's products, including VITURE Pro, infringe upon a European patent (Patent No.: EP3754409B1) held by XREAL.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《科创板日报》、VR 陀螺及亿欧报道，德国慕尼黑第一地区法院已于昨日作出一审裁决，认定 VITURE 公司旗下 VITURE Pro 等产品侵犯闪耀现实（XREAL）持有的欧洲专利（专利号：EP3754409B1）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The court approved an enforceable preliminary injunction, requiring VITURE's sales hub in Germany — Hong Kong distributor Eden Future HK Limited — to immediately cease offering, marketing, using, or importing the infringing products within Germany.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            法院批准了具强制执行力的临时禁令，要求 VITURE 在德国的销售枢纽 —— 香港经销商 Eden Future HK Limited 立即停止在德国境内提供、投放市场、使用或进口相关产品。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            This ruling means that VITURE Pro has lost its legal sales qualification in the German market. Currently, the products in question have been delisted from 9 EU Amazon sites, including Germany, France, Italy, Spain, Poland, the Netherlands, Ireland, Sweden, and Belgium.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该裁决意味着 VITURE Pro 在德国市场已失去合法销售资格。目前，涉诉产品已在亚马逊德国、法国、意大利、西班牙、波兰、荷兰、爱尔兰、瑞典、比利时等 9 个欧盟站点下架。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that this case marks the first time in the XR industry that a substantial 'sales ban' has been encountered due to core technology patent infringement.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，此案是 XR 行业首次因核心技术专利侵权而遭遇实质性「禁售」的案例。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>追觅手机 E1 通过欧盟认证：1.08 亿主摄、还有 3.5 mm 耳机孔</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">追觅手机-E1-通过欧盟认证：1.08-亿主摄、还有-3.5-mm-耳机孔</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/71b109d3-f6b4-42c5-9c6e-ce20dd6e3fbb.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Tech media MT.today recently reported that Dreame's first smartphone, the Dreame Smartphone E1 (model W5110), has passed EU energy efficiency label certification, and its user manual has also been leaked.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            科技媒体 MT.today 近日发文称，追觅首款智能手机 Dreame Smartphone E1（型号 W5110）已通过欧盟能效标签认证，用户手册同步流出。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features a 6.67-inch AMOLED screen with under-display fingerprint recognition support;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equipped with a 108-megapixel main camera, a 2-megapixel depth sensor, and a 2-megapixel macro lens on the rear, and a 50-megapixel front camera; the manual also mentions a 'decorative lens';&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Built-in 5000 mAh battery, supporting 33W wired charging;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports 5G and NFC, featuring a 'two-in-one' card slot design, allowing choice between dual Nano-SIM or 'single SIM card + microSD storage card';&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The body supports IP64 dust and water resistance, and retains a 3.5 mm headphone jack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The device's declared repairability and drop resistance ratings to the EU are both B-grade, its energy efficiency rating is A-grade, and its nominal battery life is 54 hours and 35 minutes.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            该机向欧盟申报的维修性等级与抗跌落等级均为 B 级，能效等级为 A 级，标称续航时间为 54 小时 35 分钟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            It is worth noting that Dreame described the battery as &quot;user-replaceable&quot; in the EU energy efficiency label certification, but the user manual clearly warns, &quot;Do not attempt to remove the battery yourself.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            值得注意的是，追觅在欧盟能效标签认证中将电池描述为「用户可自行更换」，但用户手册明确警示「请勿尝试自行取出电池」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In September this year, Dreame officially announced its first smartphone, Dreame Space, teasing its &quot;astronomical-grade&quot; camera system, emphasizing its ability to easily capture nebulae, galaxies, and other deep-sky objects even in light-polluted urban environments, and stating that it will launch an interconnected ecosystem of &quot;people, cars, homes, and all things in the universe.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            今年 9 月，追觅官宣首款智能手机 Dreame Space，预热其搭载「天文级」摄像系统，强调在光污染严重的城市环境中也能轻松拍摄星云、银河等深空天体，并表示将推出「人车家宇宙万物」互联生态。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>男子一年退 12 部手机起诉被驳回，法院：违背诚信原则</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">男子一年退-12-部手机起诉被驳回，法院：违背诚信原则</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f9087688-2296-4402-b933-f4e81c12646d.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV News, the Songjiang District People's Court in Shanghai recently rejected a consumer's return lawsuit against an e-commerce platform, ruling that the consumer's long-term practice of repeatedly purchasing for experience and returning within the &quot;seven-day no-reason return&quot; period constituted an abuse of civil rights.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视新闻报道，上海市松江区人民法院近日驳回一名消费者针对电商平台的退货诉讼，认定其长期以体验为目的反复购买并在「七天无理由退货」期限内退货，已构成民事权利滥用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Consumption records show that the consumer purchased 12 mobile phones through 12 orders between April 2023 and March 2024, and applied for returns and refunds within 7 days for all of them.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            消费记录显示，该消费者在 2023 年 4 月至 2024 年 3 月期间通过 12 笔订单购买了 12 部手机，并均在 7 天内申请退货退款。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The phone in question was the fourth purchase of the same model by the consumer, with the previous three having been successfully returned. This fourth return request, citing &quot;too heavy, too thick,&quot; was rejected, and the consumer only filed a lawsuit for a refund after continuing to use it for about a month.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            涉案手机为其第 4 次购买的同款机型，前三次均已成功退货。此次第 4 次以「太重、太厚」为由提出退货遭拒，继续使用约 1 个月后才起诉要求退款。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The court pointed out that the consumer, as a digital product enthusiast, repeatedly purchased online for the purpose of playing with and experiencing products after activation and then applied the &quot;seven-day no-reason return&quot; policy; their practice of repeatedly buying and returning deviated from the original intent of the system, violated the principle of fairness and good faith, harmed the legitimate rights and interests of the platform, and was not conducive to creating an orderly online shopping environment. Therefore, it should be given a negative evaluation, and the appeal was ultimately rejected.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            法院指出，该消费者作为数码产品爱好者，存在激活使用后以把玩、体验为目的多次网购并适用「七天无理由退货」的情形；其反复购买并退货的做法偏离该制度设立初衷，违反公平诚信原则，损害平台合法权益，不利于营造有序的网络购物环境，因而应予否定性评价，最终判决驳回诉求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>💡 LinkedIn CEO：AI 时代「五年职业规划」已过时，短期学习更有效</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">💡-LinkedIn-CEO：AI-时代「五年职业规划」已过时，短期学习更有效</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/6cdeefa9-cc20-4173-bc85-2be4845aa645.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Fortune, LinkedIn CEO Ryan Roslansky stated that in the context of accelerating workplace changes, &quot;five-year career planning&quot; is no longer applicable. He pointed out that in an environment where technology and the labor market are continuously evolving, setting learning and experience goals on a monthly cycle is more practical.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据《财富》报道，LinkedIn CEO Ryan Roslansky 表示在职场变化加速的背景下，「五年职业规划」已不再适用。他指出，在技术与劳动力市场持续演变的环境里，以数月为周期设定学习与体验目标更加务实。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since becoming LinkedIn CEO in 2020, he has long observed that factors such as pandemics, tariffs, inflation, and layoffs have made career paths increasingly nonlinear, and he explores diverse growth trajectories through his podcast, The Path.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他自 2020 年起担任 LinkedIn CEO，长期观察到疫情、关税、通胀与裁员等因素令职业路径愈发非线性，并以播客 The Path 探讨多元化的成长轨迹。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Roslansky emphasized that instead of pre-setting multi-year routes, it's better to focus on what to learn and what experiences to gain in the near future, opening up broader career possibilities through accumulated short steps.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Roslansky 强调，与其预设多年路线，不如聚焦近期要学习什么、获取哪些经验，靠累积的短步进打开更广的职业可能性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            He pointed out that many people still believe education and career follow a linear path, but platform data and interviews show that the reality is more complex, and individuals need to actively seize opportunities and remain agile.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            他指出，很多人仍相信教育与职业是线性路径，但平台数据与访谈显示真实情况更复杂，个体需要主动抓住机遇并保持敏锐。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The World Economic Forum predicts that by 2030, approximately 39% of core skills will be reshaped or eliminated; vocational and educational institution TAFE Gippsland reports that people experience an average of 3–7 career changes and 16 job changes in their lifetime; the latest report from recruitment agency Randstad shows that Gen Z changes jobs every 1.1 years on average, driven more by &quot;growth hunting&quot; than by traditional &quot;job hopping.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            世界经济论坛预计，到 2030 年，约有 39% 的核心技能将被重塑或淘汰；职业与教育机构 TAFE Gippsland 报告称，人们一生平均经历 3–7 次职业转换与 16 次工作变动；招聘机构 Randstad 的最新报告显示，Gen Z 平均每 1.1 年换一次工作，其动因更多是「成长捕猎」而非传统意义的「频繁跳槽」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Although some experts still believe that medium-to-long-term planning helps systematically advance goals and retain room for adjustment, Roslansky believes that in the rapidly changing era driven by AI, the iteration of short-term learning and experience is more aligned with reality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            尽管仍有专家认为中长期规划有助于系统化推进目标并保留调整空间，但 Roslansky 认为在 AI 驱动的快速变革期，短期学习与体验的迭代更符合现实。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;No one will plan your path for you; only by establishing a self-driven mechanism centered on skills and experience as early as possible can you enhance career resilience and opportunities amidst uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>字节 92% 工程师在用，TRAE CN 企业版正式推出</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">字节-92%-工程师在用，TRAE-CN-企业版正式推出</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/56aced5a-01a4-4b91-b824-be5c5c16ca09.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, ByteDance's AI programming tool &quot;TRAE CN Enterprise Edition&quot; was officially released. The official announcement emphasized its positioning for scaled and in-depth application in enterprise R&amp;amp;D, offering two deployment modes—Enterprise Edition and Enterprise Exclusive Edition—to meet different security and management needs.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，字节跳动旗下 AI 编程工具「TRAE CN 企业版」正式发布。官方强调其在企业研发中的规模化与深度化应用定位，并提供企业版与企业专属版两种部署模式，以满足不同安全与管理需求。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of core capabilities, TRAE CN Enterprise Edition has been optimized for ultra-large repository scenarios: it supports indexing 100,000 files and 150 million lines of code, combined with an ultra-long context window and enterprise-grade GPU clusters, achieving millisecond-level responses under high concurrency.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在核心能力上，TRAE CN 企业版针对超大仓库场景进行了优化：支持 10 万文件、1.5 亿行代码索引，配合超长上下文窗口与企业级 GPU 集群，实现高并发下的毫秒级响应。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            By integrating with enterprise knowledge bases and specifications, and leveraging unified tools and data source calls based on MCP (Model Context Protocol), code generation, review, and testing achieve a process-level closed loop and comply with team &quot;rules.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            通过接入企业知识库与规范、以及基于 MCP（模型上下文协议）的统一工具与数据源调用，使代码生成、审查与测试实现流程级闭环并符合团队「规矩」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The official statement also emphasized that data is not used for training, code is encrypted throughout the entire link, there is zero cloud storage, and a &quot;burn after use&quot; mechanism is in place, enhancing the security and controllability of enterprise code assets.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方同时强调，数据不用于训练、代码全链路加密传输、云端零存储与用后即焚机制，提升企业代码资产的安全性与可控性。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of performance and management, TRAE CN Enterprise Edition provides dashboards for metrics such as AI generation rate and AI code volume, supports cost caps and real-time usage monitoring, and can integrate with SSO for unified authentication and permission boundary management.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在效能与管理方面，TRAE CN 企业版提供 AI 生成率、AI 代码量等指标看板，支持费用上限与实时用量监控，并可接入 SSO 实现统一鉴权与权限边界管理。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            After deep integration with Volcengine, developers can call cloud resources and services in a one-stop manner within the IDE, covering computing power scheduling, runtime environments, and release pipelines, achieving an end-to-end closed loop from &quot;writing code&quot; to &quot;running it.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            与火山引擎深度打通后，开发者可在 IDE 内一站式调用云端资源与服务，贯穿算力调度、运行环境与发布流水线，实现从「写代码」到「跑起来」的端到端闭环。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to reports, 92% of ByteDance's internal engineers already use TRAE for R&amp;amp;D collaboration. In high-concurrency businesses like Douyin Life Services, official case studies show that AI code contribution exceeds 43%, test case generation saves 44.56 person-days per week, and unattended releases save 25 minutes per instance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据介绍，字节内部已有 92% 的工程师将 TRAE 用于研发协作。在抖音生活服务等高并发业务中，官方案例显示 AI 代码贡献率超过 43%，测试用例生成每周节省 44.56 人/天，无人发布单次节省 25 分钟。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of engineering quality, TRAE supports automatic generation and repair of unit tests, compressing unit test generation time to within 18 minutes, with a first-compile pass rate exceeding 70%.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在工程质量方面，TRAE 支持单元测试自动生成与修复，单测生成时间压缩至 18 分钟以内，首编译通过率超过 70%。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 Related Reading:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/YaC2qYm3HhfoVE4MvCL1KQ&quot;&gt;
             TRAE, used by 92% of ByteDance engineers, is now targeting the enterprise market
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 相关阅读：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/YaC2qYm3HhfoVE4MvCL1KQ&quot;&gt;
             字节 92% 工程师都在用的 TRAE，这次瞄准了企业级市场
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google 开源「小钢炮」端侧 Agent 模型</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">Google-开源「小钢炮」端侧-Agent-模型</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/607eee20-9219-4e77-8976-30cabcc33840.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Recently, Google launched two lightweight models for edge devices and developers: the new multimodal, long-context encoder-decoder family member
            &lt;strong&gt;
             T5Gemma 2
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , and
            &lt;strong&gt;
             FunctionGemma
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            , optimized specifically for function calling scenarios.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            近日，Google 推出两款面向端侧与开发者的轻量模型：多模态、长上下文的编码器—解码器家族新作
            &lt;strong&gt;
             T5Gemma 2
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            ，以及专为函数调用场景优化的
            &lt;strong&gt;
             FunctionGemma
            &lt;/strong&gt;
            。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Both models continue the technical roadmap of the Gemma 3 series; the former focuses on structural efficiency and multimodal understanding, while the latter aims to reliably map natural language to executable API actions, targeting local, low-latency agent applications.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            两者均延续 Gemma 3 系列的技术路线，前者主打结构效率与多模态理解，后者聚焦把自然语言稳定映射为可执行的 API 动作，面向本地、低延迟的智能体应用。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            T5Gemma 2 adopts &quot;shared word embeddings&quot; and &quot;decoder self-attention—cross-attention merging&quot; at the architectural level to reduce parameters and complexity, offering three scales of pre-trained models: 270M–270M (approximately 370M total without vision encoder), 1B–1B (approximately 1.7B), and 4B–4B (approximately 7B).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            T5Gemma 2 在架构层面采用「词向量共享」与「解码器自注意—交叉注意合并」以缩减参数与复杂度，提供 270M–270M（不含视觉编码器约总计 370M）、1B–1B（约 1.7B）与 4B–4B（约 7B）三种规模的预训练模型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Google states that T5Gemma 2 shows significant improvements over Gemma 3 in multimodal and long-context tasks, and its pre-trained base is already available on platforms like Kaggle and Hugging Face for subsequent task customization; it also provides a path for inference via Vertex AI.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            Google 表示，T5Gemma 2 在多模态与长上下文任务上相较 Gemma 3 显著提升，且预训练基座已开放在 Kaggle、Hugging Face 等平台供后续任务定制；同时提供通过 Vertex AI 推理的路径。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            FunctionGemma is a 270M model based on Gemma 3, specifically fine-tuned as a function-calling agent. Its goal is to reliably translate user instructions into structured function calls on local devices, and then summarize the execution results in natural language.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            FunctionGemma 基于 Gemma 3 的 270M 模型专门微调为函数调用代理，目标是在本地设备上把用户指令稳定转译为结构化函数调用，再以自然语言总结执行结果。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The model's size and vocabulary design are adapted for edge devices, allowing it to run on NVIDIA Jetson Nano and mobile phones. It can also serve as an offline agent or a &quot;smart router&quot; for larger systems, delegating complex requests to more powerful models like Gemma 3 27B.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            模型体量与词表设计适配边缘设备，可在英伟达 Jetson Nano 与手机端运行，并可作为离线代理或大型系统的「智能路由」，把复杂请求转交至 Gemma 3 27B 等更强模型。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Xinzhiyuan believes that T5Gemma 2, with its structural and capability upgrades, provides a more efficient encoder-decoder option for multimodal, long-context, and multilingual tasks, making it suitable as a pre-trained base for research and downstream applications;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            新智元认为，T5Gemma 2 以结构与能力升级为多模态、长上下文与多语言任务提供更高效的编码器—解码器选项，适合研究与下游应用的预训练基座；
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            FunctionGemma, on the other hand, targets scenarios with clear API interfaces and local-first priorities, achieving more deterministic function call reliability through fine-tuning, supporting &quot;offline-instant-privacy&quot; edge-side agents. Together, both point to a deployment path from cloud-based &quot;giant models&quot; to edge-based &quot;specialized small models.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            FunctionGemma 则面向明确 API 面与本地优先的场景，通过微调获得确定性更强的函数调用可靠性，支撑「离线‑即时‑隐私」的端侧代理。二者共同指向开发与部署从云端「巨模型」向边缘「专精小模型」的落地路径。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T5Gemma 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🤗 Hugging Face:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/collections/google/t5gemma-2&quot;&gt;
             https://huggingface.co/collections/google/t5gemma-2
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🤗 Hugging Face:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/collections/google/t5gemma-2&quot;&gt;
             https://huggingface.co/collections/google/t5gemma-2
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            💻 Colab:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/Research/&quot;&gt;
             https://colab.research.google.com/github/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/Research/
            &lt;/a&gt;
            [T5Gemma_2]Example.ipynb
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            💻 Colab:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://colab.research.google.com/github/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/Research/&quot;&gt;
             https://colab.research.google.com/github/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/Research/
            &lt;/a&gt;
            [T5Gemma_2]Example.ipynb
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style=&quot;text-align: left;&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FunctionGemma:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🤗 Hugging Face:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/google/functiongemma-270m-it&quot;&gt;
             https://huggingface.co/google/functiongemma-270m-it
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🤗 Hugging Face:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://huggingface.co/google/functiongemma-270m-it&quot;&gt;
             https://huggingface.co/google/functiongemma-270m-it
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;text-align: left; line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            💻 GitHub:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/FunctionGemma/%5BFunctionGemma%5DFinetune_FunctionGemma_270M_for_Mobile_Actions_with_Hugging_Face.ipynb&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/FunctionGemma/%5BFunctionGemma%5DFinetune_FunctionGemma_270M_for_Mobile_Actions_with_Hugging_Face.ipynb
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            💻 GitHub:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/FunctionGemma/%5BFunctionGemma%5DFinetune_FunctionGemma_270M_for_Mobile_Actions_with_Hugging_Face.ipynb&quot;&gt;
             https://github.com/google-gemini/gemma-cookbook/blob/main/FunctionGemma/%5BFunctionGemma%5DFinetune_FunctionGemma_270M_for_Mobile_Actions_with_Hugging_Face.ipynb
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>中国气象局推出气象 AI 科学模型「风源」</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">中国气象局推出气象-AI-科学模型「风源」</guid>
      <description>&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to CCTV News, yesterday, the China Meteorological Administration released the meteorological artificial intelligence scientific model &quot;Fengyuan&quot; in Xiong'an New Area, Hebei. It is positioned as an open-source and open scientific innovation platform base, aiming to enhance AI meteorological forecasting model capabilities and related scientific research levels.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据央视新闻报道，昨天，中国气象局在河北雄安新区发布气象人工智能科学模型「风源」，定位为开源开放科创平台底座，旨在提升 AI 气象预报模型能力与相关科研水平。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Fengyuan&quot; marks that China's meteorological department now possesses an end-to-end scientific model base with independent intellectual property rights, achieving technological autonomy and control in key links and having a continuous iteration engineering foundation. &quot;Fengyuan V1.0&quot; includes two major modules: data assimilation and forecasting, which can directly conduct global weather forecasting based on observational data.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            「风源」标志着我国气象部门拥有自主知识产权的端到端科学模型底座，在关键环节实现技术自主可控，并具备持续迭代的工程基础。「风源 V1.0」包含数据同化与预报两大模块，可基于观测数据直接开展全球气象预报。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Compared to previous AI forecasting methods that relied on numerical prediction models to analyze data, &quot;Fengyuan&quot; can directly read real-time observational data from satellites, radar, weather stations, etc., and provide global forecasts after independent analysis. Its forecasting performance is among the top tier in relevant fields both domestically and internationally.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            相比以往依赖数值预报模式分析数据的 AI 预报方法，「风源」可直接读取来自卫星、雷达、气象站等实时观测数据，独立分析后给出全球预报，预报效果处于国内外相关领域第一梯队。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Regarding future plans, &quot;Fengyuan&quot; will focus on improving its ability to capture extreme weather, especially short-term imminent weather, and develop vertical AI models around scenarios such as low-altitude economy, energy supply, transportation and logistics, and health meteorology, serving economic and social development. It will also expand international application space, promote the implementation of results in countries co-building the &quot;Belt and Road,&quot; and strengthen key team collaboration through the Meteorological Science and Education Integration Innovation Alliance.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            未来规划方面，「风源」将重点提升对极端天气、尤其是短时临近天气的捕捉能力、围绕低空经济、能源保供、交通物流、健康气象等场景开发垂类 AI 模型，服务经济社会发展，同时拓展国际应用空间，推动成果在共建「一带一路」国家落地，并通过气象科教融合创新联盟加强重点团队协作。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The meteorological AI models previously launched by the China Meteorological Administration have also been upgraded this year:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            中国气象局此前推出的气象 AI 模型也在今年完成升级：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global short-to-medium-term forecasting system &quot;Fengqing&quot; has been put into business application and promoted nationwide. After upgrading to &quot;Fengqing v1.5&quot;, forecasts are more accurate and cover longer periods, with more professional and extensive services;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The severe convective weather imminent disaster warning precipitation model &quot;Fenglei v1.1&quot; significantly enhances the warning capability for extreme heavy rainfall, with more intuitive and practical results;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The global sub-seasonal to seasonal prediction system &quot;Fengshun v1.5&quot; has been enhanced in regional depiction, expansion of elements related to agriculture/new energy, and reliability of 3 to 5-week long-term forecasts. Its overall performance has reached an internationally advanced level and has been running stably for over a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>雀巢评估出售蓝瓶咖啡实体业务，瑞幸被传参与竞购</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">雀巢评估出售蓝瓶咖啡实体业务，瑞幸被传参与竞购</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/871e8e5c-a1de-4998-830e-63a9a8ebe796.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to Jiemian News, Nestlé Group is reportedly considering selling the physical cafe business of Blue Bottle Coffee, with potential buyers including Luckin Coffee and its backer Centurium Capital.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据界面新闻报道，雀巢集团或考虑出售蓝瓶咖啡（Blue Bottle Coffee）的实体咖啡馆业务，潜在买家名单出现瑞幸咖啡及其支持者大钲资本（Centurium Capital）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In 2017, Nestlé acquired approximately 68% of Blue Bottle's equity for about $500 million. Blue Bottle entered mainland China in 2022, currently operating 15 stores in Shanghai, Shenzhen, and Hangzhou, and globally has 140 stores in 6 countries and regions as of August 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            2017 年，雀巢以约 5 亿美元收购蓝瓶约 68% 股权；蓝瓶于 2022 年进入中国内地，目前在上海、深圳、杭州共开设 15 家门店，全球截至 2025 年 8 月在 6 个国家和地区拥有 140 家门店。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Market sources indicate that Nestlé may retain the intellectual property of the Blue Bottle brand to continue selling products, only selling the physical cafe business. This move is seen as part of new CEO Philippe Navratil's strategic evaluation to streamline operations and exit physical retail store operations.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            市场消息称，雀巢可能保留蓝瓶品牌的知识产权以继续销售产品，仅出售实体咖啡馆业务，此举被视为新任 CEO 菲利普・纳夫拉蒂尔推进业务精简、退出实体零售门店运营的战略评估的一部分。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In addition to aggressively expanding Chinese coffee brands, potential buyers also include %Arabica and its backing capital (PAG, General Atlantic, etc.), as well as traditional private equity funds (such as KKR, Carlyle).
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            除激进扩张的中国咖啡品牌外，潜在买家还包括 %Arabica 及其背后资本（ PAG、General Atlantic 等），以及传统私募股权基金（如 KKR、凯雷）。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>犯罪电影《96 分钟：列车爆炸案》定档 1 月 10 日</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">犯罪电影《96-分钟：列车爆炸案》定档-1-月-10-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/c8274ded-7711-45cf-8dfb-845eff09f566.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The crime film &quot;96 Minutes: Train Bombing&quot; was officially announced yesterday to be released in mainland China on January 10, simultaneously unveiling its &quot;Extreme Survival&quot; trailer and &quot;Justice Decision&quot; poster.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            犯罪电影《96 分钟：列车爆炸案》昨日官宣将于 1 月 10 日内地上映，并同步发布「极限存活」版定档预告与「正义决策」版海报。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film is set as a twin-train bombing: two trains traveling from Taipei to Kaohsiung, a 96-minute journey, are fitted with special bombs. If one train stops, the other explodes, forcing hundreds of passengers to face life-or-death decisions within a time limit.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            影片设定为双列车捆绑爆炸：两辆自台北开往高雄、行程 96 分钟的列车被安装特殊炸弹，任一列车停下，另一列即爆炸，数百名乘客被迫在限时内直面生死抉择。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The story revolves around former bomb disposal expert Song Kang-ren (played by Lin Po-hung) and his police officer fiancée Huang Xin (played by Vivian Sung) accidentally boarding a train carrying a special bomb, leading to a 96-minute extreme bomb disposal and a test of humanity.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            故事围绕前拆弹专家宋康任（林柏宏 饰）与警员未婚妻黄欣（宋芸桦 饰）意外登上载有特殊炸弹的列车，展开 96 分钟极限拆弹与人性拷问。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>《情圣 3》定档 12 月 27 日</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">《情圣-3》定档-12-月-27-日</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/67b98601-c7ac-4d48-b4de-7b6abc1c3e0a.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The film &quot;The Love Guru 3&quot; released a new poster yesterday, confirming nationwide sneak previews starting December 20 and a nationwide release on December 27. The film continues the series' IP with &quot;marital farce&quot; as its core narrative, with creators stating it will use contrasting relationships and ensemble comedy to enhance viewing experience and topicality.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            电影《情圣 3》昨天发布新海报，确认将于 12 月 20 日起全国点映、12 月 27 日全国上映。影片延续系列 IP 并以「婚姻闹剧」为核心叙事，主创称将以反差关系与群像喜剧推进观感与话题度。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The poster uses a giant sandy &quot;LOVE IS HARD&quot; composition to depict character relationships and dramatic tension, revolving around the trust crisis of &quot;spouses tricking each other&quot; and the trial and error of &quot;36 stratagems of love.&quot; It emphasizes the interaction and rhythm of the ensemble cast as &quot;all comedians,&quot; with series symbols and nostalgic elements preserved and strengthened.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            海报以巨型沙质「LOVE IS HARD」构图呈现人物关系与戏剧张力，围绕「夫妻互坑」的信任危机与「爱情三十六计」的试探磨合展开，强调群像「全员喜剧人」的互动与节奏，系列符号与情怀元素被保留并强化。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Fun Thing｜阿里千问辟谣「干死豆包」：假的，图片系 AI 生成</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">One-Fun-Thing｜阿里千问辟谣「干死豆包」：假的，图片系-AI-生成</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/2b9467de-0d85-401e-85f0-2d288fe4d017.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, a purported image of an &quot;Alibaba Qianwen All-Hands Meeting&quot; circulated online, claiming someone held a &quot;doubao&quot; (bean bun) in the square and shouted &quot;Kill doubao.&quot; Alibaba sources debunked the image to a Cailian Press reporter, stating it was &quot;fake&quot; and denying any such all-hands meeting or incident involving holding a doubao.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，网络流传一张所谓「阿里千问全员会」现场图片，称有人在广场上手举豆包并高喊「干死豆包」。阿里相关人士向财联社记者辟谣称该图为「假的」，并否认所谓全员大会及现场举豆包等情节。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            According to 21st Century Business Herald, Alibaba further pointed out that all Qianwen logos in the image were incorrectly generated; many netizens also questioned whether the image was synthesized by generative AI, as the scene resembled an offline morning meeting, inconsistent with internet R&amp;amp;D or AI business scenarios, with obvious flaws from visual elements to watermark processing.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            据 21 世纪经济报道，阿里方面进一步指出该图中的千问 logo 均生成错误；多位网友也质疑该图疑似由生成式 AI 合成，场景更像线下晨会，与互联网研发或 AI 业务场景不符，从视觉要素到水印处理均存在明显破绽。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             Yesterday afternoon, Alibaba Qianwen officially responded on its official WeChat public account with an article titled &quot;Heard I Was Tricked by AI,&quot; explicitly stating that the so-called &quot;square meeting&quot; was purely fictitious, the related images were entirely AI-generated, and both employee badges and logos were incorrectly synthesized.
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;
             昨天下午，阿里千问在官方微信公众号发文《听说我被 AI 整了》正式回应，明确表示所谓「广场大会」纯属虚构，相关图片完全由 AI 生成，工牌与 logo 均为错误合成。
            &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/3c8b0501-a9e7-4eec-b56d-46cfb9d41614.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In the article, the official account lightheartedly joked, &quot;We're all in AI, why the internal strife?&quot; and took the opportunity to showcase Qianwen's AI image generation feature, encouraging users to create fun images using templates and prompts, even simulating scenarios like &quot;Chef King Competition,&quot; &quot;Time Travel to Eastern Han Dynasty,&quot; or &quot;Santa Claus.&quot;
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            官方在文中以轻松语气调侃称「大家都是干 AI 的，相煎何太急」，并借机展示千问的 AI 生图功能，鼓励用户通过模板与指令生成趣味图片，甚至可以模拟「厨王争霸赛」「穿越到东汉」或「圣诞老人」等场景。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>周末看什么｜《阿凡达 3：火与烬》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">周末看什么｜《阿凡达-3：火与烬》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/f76bfa81-1b76-4f1f-ae0b-f6ac2c91ef38.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            &quot;Avatar 3,&quot; the third installment in James Cameron's &quot;Avatar&quot; series, was released in cinemas nationwide yesterday. The plot continues the aftermath of the previous film, with Jake Sully and Neytiri's family plunged into grief after losing their eldest son, Neteyam.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《阿凡达3》作为詹姆斯 · 卡梅隆执导的《阿凡达》系列第三部作品，已于昨天上线全国院线。剧情延续前作余波，杰克 · 萨利与奈蒂莉一家在失去长子奈特言后陷入悲痛。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The core conflict of the story comes from the newly introduced &quot;Ash People&quot; tribe, who live by plunder and violence, led by High Priestess Varang, becoming a key antagonistic force driving the plot. The film also reveals Pandora's new tribe, the &quot;Wind Traders,&quot; who nomadically traverse between tribes, forming a stark cultural contrast to the Ash People.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            故事核心冲突来自新登场的「灰烬之民」部族，他们以掠夺和暴力为生，由女祭司瓦琅领导，成为推动剧情的关键反派势力。影片同时揭示了潘多拉新的族群「风之商人」，以游牧方式在部落间穿梭，形成与灰烬族截然不同的文明对照。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On a technical level, Cameron's team continues to break new ground: the precision of volcanic eruptions, smoke, and micro-expression capture has significantly improved, special effects algorithms have achieved complex interactions of fire, ash, and static electricity, and actor facial capture precision has been enhanced to 60,000 micro-triangles per second at 1200 frames, making the Na'vi's subtle expressions more realistic.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            技术层面，卡梅隆团队继续突破：火山喷发、烟雾与微表情捕捉的精度显著提升，特效算法实现了火焰、灰烬与静电的复杂交互，演员面部捕捉精度提升至 6 万个微三角面片，每秒 1200 帧，使纳威人的细微表情更具真实感。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In terms of reviews, the film received a 69% positive rating on Rotten Tomatoes and a score of 61 on Metacritic, falling into the 'generally favorable' range.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            评价方面，影片在烂番茄获得 69% 的正面评价，在 Metacritic 上收获 61 分，属「普遍好评」区间。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            On the Douban platform, as of publication, over 23,000 people have given it an average score of 7.6, with 24.7% giving five stars and 39.9% giving four stars, indicating general audience approval for the visual effects but a clear divergence in opinions on the plot.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            豆瓣平台上，截至发稿有超过 2.3 万人打出 7.6 的平均分，其中 24.7% 打出五星，39.9% 打出四星，显示观众对视觉效果普遍认可，但对剧情评价分化明显。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 Related reading:
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/PjcodQ6V0UG0SiBarrDUtw&quot;&gt;
             &quot;Avatar 3&quot; Cinema Hall Selection Guide: Stop Mindlessly Choosing IMAX (with cinema list)
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            🔗 相关阅读：
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/PjcodQ6V0UG0SiBarrDUtw&quot;&gt;
             《阿凡达 3》电影院选厅指南：别再无脑选 IMAX 了（附影院名单）
            &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>买书不读指南｜《电影院精神》</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">买书不读指南｜《电影院精神》</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/e4c078fa-c40a-4857-bf05-8652c7fcd734.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The Spirit of Cinema, written by film scholar Wang Xiaolu, focuses on the current era dominated by streaming and algorithms, proposing concepts such as the 'era of cinematic maturity' and 'the spirit of cinema.' It attempts to reflect on real life through the space of the cinema, and through the pulse of a sluggish industry, to mirror the common dilemmas of modern people and the imagination of rebuilding publicness.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《电影院精神》由电影学者王小鲁撰写，聚焦流媒体席卷与算法主导的当下，提出「电影完熟时代」「电影院精神」等概念，试图以电影院空间观照现实生活，通过行业疲软的脉象折射现代人的普遍困境与公共性再建的想象。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The book concludes that the film market has become saturated, stating that 'the best humanist films have already been made.' It places the impact of technology on the essence of cinema within the coordinates of academic criticism and symbolic games, emphasizing the industry's twilight mood after the pandemic and the call for physical presence, presenting a 'history of the soul' approach aimed at cinephiles.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            书中判断电影市场已趋饱和，并指出「最好的人文主义电影都已经拍出来了」，将技术对电影本体的冲击置于学院批评与符号游戏的坐标中，强调疫情后行业的迟暮心境与身体在场的召唤，呈现一部面向迷影群体的「心灵史」取向。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>游戏推荐｜《羊蹄山之魂》夺 PS Blog 2025 九项大奖</title>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">游戏推荐｜《羊蹄山之魂》夺-PS-Blog-2025-九项大奖</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&quot;font-size: 80%; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem; margin-bottom: 5%;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://s3.ifanr.com/images/ep/uploads/20251220_%E6%97%A9%E6%8A%A5/777a3bf6-99dd-4ede-9b08-0995139a220e.jpg&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Yesterday, Sony PlayStation announced the results of the PS Blog 2025 Game of the Year Awards, featuring 19 categories. All awards were determined entirely by player votes, with nearly 1.5 million player votes accumulated.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            昨天，索尼 PlayStation 公布 PS Blog 2025 年度游戏大奖结果，共设 19 个类别，所有奖项完全由玩家选票产生，累计近 150 万张玩家投票。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Among them, Sucker Punch Productions' new PS5 exclusive title, Ghost of Yotei, won 9 awards, becoming the biggest winner of this year's event.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            其中，Sucker Punch Productions 的 PS5 独占新作《羊蹄山之魂》夺得 9 项大奖，成为本届最大赢家。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Looking at the specific award distribution, Ghost of Yotei secured Platinum Awards in 9 key categories, including 'Best New Character,' 'Best Visuals,' 'Best Art Direction,' 'Best Audio Design,' 'Best DualSense Controller Implementation,' and 'Best PS5 Game.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            从具体奖项分布看，《羊蹄山之魂》拿下「最佳新角色」「最佳画面表现」「最佳美术指导」「最佳音效设计」「DualSense 手柄最佳应用」「最佳 PS5 游戏」等共 9 个关键类别白金奖。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Ghost of Yotei, developed by Sucker Punch Productions and published by Sony Interactive Entertainment, is a sequel to Ghost of Tsushima and was released on PS5 on October 2, 2025.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            《羊蹄山之魂》由 Sucker Punch Productions 开发、索尼互动娱乐发行，是《对马岛之魂》的续作，于 2025 年 10 月 2 日登陆 PS5。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            The game is set in Hokkaido, Japan, in 1603, with the protagonist being a female warrior named 'Atsu,' portrayed by Erika Ishii. The work received extensive player votes of affirmation across dimensions such as art, sound, and DualSense controller utilization.
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            游戏背景设定在 1603 年的日本北海道，主角为女性武者「笃」（Atsu），由 Erika Ishii 饰演；作品在美术、音效、DualSense 手柄运用等维度均获大量玩家投票肯定。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            Since its launch, 'Ghost of Yotei' has sold 3.3 million copies, and IGN rated it a perfect 10/10, calling it a 'masterpiece.'
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            上市以来，「羊蹄山之魂」已售出 330 万份，IGN 评价为 10 分满分「大师之作」。
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p ondblclick=&quot;toggleLang(this)&quot; style=&quot;line-height: 1.375rem&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-en&quot; style=&quot;display:inline; letter-spacing: .001rem; font-size: .875rem;line-height: 1.375rem;&quot;&gt;
            In this year's awards, other games/studios also performed remarkably:
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;lang-zh&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
            在本次大奖中，其他游戏/工作室的表现也同样亮眼：
           &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light and Shadow: Expedition 33 won Platinum Awards for 'Best Story,' 'Best Score,' and 'Best Independent Game';&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genshin Impact took home the Platinum Award for 'Best Ongoing Game';&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kojima Productions received the Platinum Award for 'Studio of the Year';&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvel's Wolverine claimed the Platinum Award for 'Most Anticipated';&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death Stranding 2: On the Beach ranked highly in multiple technical categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;entry-content__tags clearfix&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
